<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>usa &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/usa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.  Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?  So, where to start?  &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah. <br />
Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City? <br />
So, where to start? <br />
<span id="more-1199"></span>We didn&#8217;t want to stick around the hotel any longer &#8212; the breakfasts here are so darned expensive considering the quality you get. So we opted to head off to a place Alex wanted to see: Alice&#8217;s Teacup, a teahouse up on 64th. Sadly, despite the published opening time at 8:00, the place wasn&#8217;t opening until 10:00. So we adjourned to the French restaurant we spotted along the way. <br />
By the time we got back to the hotel, Mom was trying to check in. (Such began the longest check-in process I have ever experienced at a hotel.) We gathered together, chatted, and almost immediately put Mi Peque침a Ni침a to bed. It was nap time, and she was getting a little cranky. She didn&#8217;t wake up again until we stirred her until just after noon, at which point we all headed out for lunch. <br />
My bright idea? Finding an eatery at Grand Central Terminal. <br />
Yes, it&#8217;s the train thing. Suck it up. I haven&#8217;t seen a real train in months. <br />
We found Michael Jordan&#8217;s (I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s related to the basketball player) where we endulged in some seriously tasty edibles. (I think MPN got the best of all of us &#8212; her macaroni and cheese was fantastic). While we were there, we were entertained by a lightshow that was going on in the main concourse, which kept MPN completely fascinated. <br />
We strolled a bit, but ended up back at the hotel before long, about in time for MPN to crash again. Which was about the time Alex and I started planning our night out. It&#8217;s part of the reason Mom came down &#8212; to keep an eye on MPN while Alex and I tried to paint the town &#8230; well, maybe not red so much as pink. <br />
We walked to Times Square (again) and started our task at finding a place to see a movie, which was a lot harder than it seems. There are two movie theatres in the area (Regal and AMC), and you have to figure out which movie that you want to see is at which theatre. Which was about when Alex made it clear to me that she needed to eat dinner. That led us to some diner just south of Times Square with the driest chicken I ever ate. (But, admittedly, I&#8217;ve had worse.)<br />
The movie, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was Bedtime Stories. Overall, a well done movie. And I&#8217;m still giggling at Russell Brand&#8217;s rendition of Sleep Panic Disorder. Then we hit the Virgin Megastore for more movies. I had a serious need for a movie fix. <br />
This morning started a little different, and much more slowly than the previous mornings. We headed off to the Waldorf Astoria (the next block south) for breakfast, and then returned for MPN to have another nap. By the time she awoke, it was time for luch, which was at Au Bon Pain a couple of blocks away. We hopped a cab and about 25 minutes later we were at the Cloisters Museum, a branch of the Met up at the north end of Manhattan island. <br />
Barely 2 minutes after arriving, Alex realised in a panic that the little backpack that she uses to carry MPN&#8217;s stuff (and her wallet) were in the bag, and the bag was still in the taxi, now departed from the Cloisters. That sent me to a phone to cancel the credit card, and list a missing bag with the Taxi and Limosine Commission. That said, I was also told that it&#8217;ll be a cold day in hell before we get this stuff back, due to the way that the taxis run in this city. Which, I have to admit, is a little odd. <br />
The Cloisters, for the record, is one of New York City&#8217;s unspoken gems. It&#8217;s out of the way, admittedly, which is why, but it is gorgeous. It was like the churches I saw in England, Scotland, and Ireland (although most of it came from France). Absolutely wonderful! I can see why Mark has said that he wants to hold his wedding there. (Well, when he gets around to getting married, that is.) <br />
The driver of the hired car we took on the way back really didn&#8217;t listen to me and ended up taking us through Times Square. The hard way. (Believe me, there are easier ways.) He apologised for the mistake, and didn&#8217;t charge us what he should have charged us if he&#8217;d had a meter running. <br />
Dinner was at a place called Bobby Van&#8217;s, a steakhouse on 54th between Lexington and Park Ave. We were perhaps a bit underdressed, but the meal was fantastic. I&#8217;m going to have such a steak hangover in the morning. And I&#8217;m going to revel in it as much as possible. <br />
But until then, I&#8217;m exhausted, and looking forward to going home. (That&#8217;s Costa Rica, in case you&#8217;re not sure.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 03:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Peque침a Ni침a if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Peque침a Ni침a if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking about. (Considering that was her only nap of the day, that&#8217;s not a bad thing, either.)<br />
The way started out as a rough plan to go to the Empire State Building, and check out the view of Manhattan. But our plans here are very flexible. Aside from the fact that I&#8217;ve been to New York City twice before, we&#8217;re travelling with a napping toddler, who is apt to change our plans at a moment&#8217;s notice for any number of reasons. So I try not to go too crazy when plans are forced to change. <br />
(Emphasis on the word &#8220;try&#8221;.)<br />
<span id="more-1194"></span>Following a decent breakfast, we dressed for our run out to the CitiGroup building, and hop the E train eastwards to the 7th Ave station, where we switched to a northbound B train to 81st St. The stop, for those of you who don&#8217;t know, for the American Museum of Natural History. I&#8217;d seen it once before from the outside, but had really wanted to visit it since seeing &#8220;A Night At the Museum&#8221;. <br />
A couple of things about the New York Subway system:<br />
 </p>
<ol>
<li>Accessibility. Not everyone has two capable feet. Some people require wheels, from those in wheelchairs to parents who try to get around with strollers. I&#8217;m amazed that not only are many stations on the system not equipped with ramps and elevators, in order to get in or out of the system, you need a station attendant to unlock the &#8220;service&#8221; gates (or trip the alarm on your way out). </li>
<li>Not every person riding the subway is from the United States of America. So asking for a ZIP code when you want to use a credit card to purchase tickets is really short-sighted. (A note for those of you in our boat: punch in &#8220;99999&#8221;, &#8216;cuz it&#8217;s not posted anywhere.)</li>
<li>Allow people to purchase more than one ticket at a time, or at least suggest how you can use the same Metrocard for more than one person. Take a few lessons from the London Underground, who have this down to an artform. </li>
<li>There is no better place to find amateur musicians. Why most of these people don&#8217;t have music on iTunes for sale is beyond me. </li>
</ol>
<p> <br />
The main entrance to the AMNH is made up of three small revolving doors. Not suitable for all strollers, certainly not ours. I had to go in through the planetarium entrance and work my way back to the main entrance. Which wasn&#8217;t easy due to malfunctioning elevators (and a near total lack of signage for alternatives). I&#8217;m certain that Alex (who went in through the main entrance) was wondering where Mi Peque침a Ni침a and I were. <br />
When we did finally meet up in the main entrance hall, I was supremely disappointed. That massive entranceway in &#8220;A Night At The Museum&#8221;? About a third of that size. No statue of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback. No round front desk. There is a dinosaur &#8212; three, actually. But it&#8217;s just not as impressive. (Other things that seemed to be missing: Dioramas of railway builders and Roman legions, Civil war soldiers, and an Egyptian wing with a golden plaque that brings things together at night. But I digress.)<br />
Our first stop was at a temporary exhibit &#8212; a butterfly garden. It is with supreme irony that we flew five hours from Costa Rica to visit a butterfly garden with specimens from Costa Rica. (And in greater numbers than we&#8217;ve experienced before.) MPN was enthralled with all the butterflies, with them fluttering all about. The guides there (all volunteers) were all really well-educated about butterflies, too. <br />
We moved on from there, moving to the 1st floor, in search of the Spitzer Hall of Human Evolution. (Alex would have a PhD in Anthropology by now if she&#8217;d known about anthropology before going into university.) To get there, we went through the Hall of Biodiversity, the Environment of New York State (featuring exhibits that hadn&#8217;t been dusted in at least 40 years &#8212; and looked about that dated), before passing a caf칠 on the south-west side. <br />
It gave us a chance for a quick bite (I eschewed the $10.50 sandwiches), before we entered the Spitzer Hall. That was about when MPN finally passed out. Alex read every letter of every sign in the hall. I scanned many of them, reading more into the things that interested me more (e.g. the various branches of evolution that led to homo sapiens, and especially those branches that turned out to be dead-ends. (I still want to know where Neanderthals came from, and why they died out.) <br />
While Alex continued to review evolution, I strayed along, eventually finding my way into another &#8220;hall&#8221; (the Arthur Ross Hall) dedicated wholly to meteorites. In the centre of the room was a particularly large specimen, Ahnighito (so dubbed by the Inuit of Greeland), is effectively a massive chunk of iron clocking in at a serious 34 tons. (That&#8217;s Imperial tons, by the way &#8212; some 68,000+ pounds.) It doesn&#8217;t look like it weighs 34 tons when you first see it. But when you touch it, you suddenly feel the weight of its mass and the distance it&#8217;s travelled. I also ducked into the hall of minerals next door (at one point, I was a budding geologist) before returning to Alex and we continued our excursion around the museum. <br />
The Hall of North American Mammals, the Hall of North American Tourists (otherwise known as 맚he gift shop), and finally the exit back to the subway to return to the hotel. <br />
This being Christmas Eve, we planned to hit a Christmas service. I suggested St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, a particualrly wonderful example of gothic architecture just across the street from Rockefeller Center. But when we arrived, we found that we weren&#8217;t the only ones with the idea. Most of Manhattan gets this idea. Tickets for the event were apparently sold out by Labor Day. <br />
Fortunately, there&#8217;s a non-denominational church nearby (though I think its roots are in the Anglican church) called St. Bart&#8217;s. We popped in there to find plenty of seating. The only problem with the service, sadly, was MPN, who would have none of this sitting still crap. Alex and I ended up having to take turns keeping her pinned down (or occupied) as not to disturb the entire church. Murdo&#8217;s talk of hearing MPN&#8217;s &#8220;music&#8221; was not echoed here. <br />
When we left, it was raining. Yes, raining. It&#8217;s Christmas in New York, and it&#8217;s raining. The chill we first felt at landing is now gone, and I find the weather much warmer. Why didn&#8217;t we stay at home in Costa Rica?, you&#8217;re asking, I&#8217;m sure. <br />
Alex made a desperate last-dash to a nearby CVS (drugstore) for some Christmasy things, such as a string of lights (very important), some decorations (right out of the classic &#8220;Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer&#8221; TV special), and the only tradition that we&#8217;ve had every year thus far &#8212; Turtles (the chocolate kind). <br />
And on that note, it&#8217;s now time for us to go to bed. So to all of you, Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1194</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 1 &#8230; Part 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 03:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alex found Barnes and Noble without difficulty. Choosing what to buy? Now that&#8217;s difficult.  Upon her return, Mi Peque침a Ni침a and I suited up for our little excursion &#8212; the &#8220;other&#8221; major toy store in Manhattan. I speak, of course, of none other than the new Apple Store.  I jest. (Slightly.) It was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 1 &#8230; Part 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex found Barnes and Noble without difficulty. Choosing what to buy? Now that&#8217;s difficult. <br />
Upon her return, Mi Peque침a Ni침a and I suited up for our little excursion &#8212; the &#8220;other&#8221; major toy store in Manhattan. I speak, of course, of none other than the new Apple Store. <br />
I jest. (Slightly.)<br />
<span id="more-1192"></span>It was FAO Schwartz. The toy store. The place that kids dream of going to, of going completely bonker inside with the sheer pletora of toys. (Parents tend to go bonkers for the same reason, if not necessarily the same cause.) <br />
MPN went almost insane the moment we rolled in the doors: she saw piles of stuffed animals. She immediately began blirping (my name for the noise she makes that&#8217;s half-bark, half chirp, and is always accompanied with an outstretched arm pointing (gnerally) at the thing she wants) constantly, indicating she wanted most of the store. <br />
This wasn&#8217;t gonna be pretty. <br />
I learned, the hard way, the first tenant of being a parent: Never take your kid into a toystore alone. Especially if you have to keep track of the stroller. Yes, sis, I know understand. MPN had half the store bundled up in her arms in mere moments. When forced to return these things to their respective piles, she merely ran off to get more of them. It was a losing battle. The only way to &#8220;win&#8221; it was to put her back in the stroller, which she rather reluctantly gave into. But that didn&#8217;t stop the roaming hands trying to grab anything and everything. <br />
In the end, I acquired a Christmas present for her &#8212; one of the FAO Schwartz puppies, that&#8217;s about 3/4 her size. (Alex sort of scolded me for getting something so large, but even Alex fell in love with it when she saw it.) It saved me from also going into the Lego section, and plunking down some serious cash on a Lego Millennium Falcon or a Lego Death Star. That would be &#8230; painful. And not to the pocketbook, let me tell you&#8230; <br />
Dinner was at a nearby TGI Fridays. Not for any real reason than it was the nearest thing we knew of, and it was already passing MPN&#8217;s bedtime. Sadly, we haven&#8217;t gotten ourselves into a good rhythm here yet. Not due to jet lag, I assure you &#8212; just because it&#8217;s New York City, and sleeping just seems to be such a tragedy. <br />
I went out after dinner to get some night photos, but I&#8217;m not sure how they&#8217;re going to turn out. My autofocus is still broken, and I don&#8217;t know how it&#8217;s going to work out for me until I can get it fixed. But at least the long-exposure shots should turn out well. <br />
Reasonably well. <br />
Well, at least you&#8217;ll see a blurry something that resembles what I was trying to take a picture of. <br />
And on that note, it&#8217;s bed time. Tomorrow, with luck, the Empire State Building. And apparently, I have to do some shopping on my own. [Insert manical laughter here.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is America ready for Obama + Clinton?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 22:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love American politics. It&#8217;s my form of WWE &#8212; all the cheers and jeers with all the spectacle to go along with it. One day, I think the American presidency will go the way of the President of the Galaxy from Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy and be little more than a distraction from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Is America ready for Obama + Clinton?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love American politics. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.wwe.com/">my form of WWE</a> &#8212; all the cheers and jeers with all the spectacle to go along with it. One day, I think the American presidency will go the way of the <a href="http://hhgproject.org/entries/president.html">President of the Galaxy</a> from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker's_Guide_to_the_Galaxy"><em>Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy</em></a> and be little more than a distraction from the real power.<br />
Heck, it could be like that already, for all we know.<br />
Today, it was announced that <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2008/POLITICS/06/03/election.democrats/index.html">Hillary Clinton would be willing to consider a Vice-Presidency</a> with Barak Obama as top billing. But here&#8217;s a thought: Are Americans ready for this?<br />
<span id="more-983"></span>Let&#8217;s review the American presidential history, shall we?<br />
43 Presidents. Every single one of them a white male. The closest the United States has ever gotten to breaking that mould was with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geraldine_Ferraro">Geraldine Ferraro</a> in 1984 &#8212; an election I remember well, notably due to her Presidental candidate <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mondale">Robert Mondale</a>. (Refer to a previous post featuring [[The Shrub is back|lack-lustre Democratic nominees]].) It was a risky time to attempt such a running mate. Abortion was a hot topic of the day, and the United States was a lot more conservative back then.<br />
A black man (or African-American male, if you prefer)? The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Jackson">Rev. Jesse Jackson</a> tried twice, in 1984 (defeated mostly as a result of himself) and 1988 (defeated by, of all people, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Dukakis">Michael Dukakis</a>). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:African_American_United_States_presidential_candidates">He wasn&#8217;t the first African American to try</a>, but he&#8217;s been the only one until Obama. And by far the most successful. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_Powell">Colin Powell</a> declined not to run, though he might have done well.)<br />
But the question remains: Given the history of the last two elections (one being a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_presidential_election,_2000">near-travesty of democracy</a>), will this work? I think that both Obama and Clinton could stand on their own. They&#8217;ve broken through the problem of charisma (they&#8217;ve both got it in spades, which accounts for the delay in getting the nomination pinned down), and could stand well against <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_mccain">John McCain</a>.<br />
But together on the same ballot?<br />
It almost seems too liberal to me. Personally, I&#8217;d love to see it, but I have my doubts that even after eight years of Bush&#8217;s rather dubious leadership that they would turn to an idea that radical. (Remember the United States&#8217; tendency for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_states_and_blue_states">Red vs. Blue states</a>, and a number of states that <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/6383353/">voted out gay marriage</a> in pure terror of change.)<br />
Maybe I&#8217;m being too cynical. Maybe I&#8217;m not giving enough credit.<br />
I know this much, though: McCain had better watch himself. The mere second he even thinks of using race or sex as part of his stance, he&#8217;ll immediately alienate a huge section of voters. If nothing else, this will be the most politically-correct election you&#8217;ve ever seen. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="游땔" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ah, snow, my old friend</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/ah-snow-my-old-friend/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ah-snow-my-old-friend</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/ah-snow-my-old-friend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 04:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/04/21/ah-snow-my-old-friend/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Late arriving in San Francisco, no thanks to an incoming snowstorm in Calgary. The deicing truck broke down mid-hose, and we had to wait 30 minutes for another one. But it gave me more time to have an interesting chat with my seatmate, who works for Wind River. Software, not the outdoors stuff. The flight &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/ah-snow-my-old-friend/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Ah, snow, my old friend"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late arriving in San Francisco, no thanks to an incoming snowstorm in Calgary. The deicing truck broke down mid-hose, and we had to wait 30 minutes for another one. But it gave me more time to have an interesting chat with my seatmate, who works for Wind River. Software, not the outdoors stuff.<br />
The flight was pretty good &#8212; drinks were actually free! Nothing to eat, though. Not even pretzels. Watched Golden Compass. Did some post-vacation photo editing. Both toilets on the train broke down 30 minutes before we landed.<br />
Just waiting for the BART to leave the station. Won&#8217;t likely see the guys tonight, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/ah-snow-my-old-friend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">924</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On my way home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=on-my-way-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 07:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/10/on-my-way-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me. It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On my way home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was definitely more expedient than most of the ones I&#8217;ve seen. That said, it was still a lovely ceremony.<br />
<span id="more-910"></span>I followed Tamara most of the day, her unofficial tied-to-the-hip photographer. Hair, make-up, nails, ceremony preparation, and post-professional pictures, before all heading off to dinner. I was fortunate enough to be treated almost like the wedding party without actually being one of them. It was nice to be considered in such a way, especially when it wasn&#8217;t really place.<br />
Yes, Tamara cried. So did I. (I cry at every wedding.) It&#8217;s hard not to when things turn out that well. The wedding chapel at the Mandalay Bay might be a bit &#8220;assembly line&#8221;-ish, but it&#8217;s really a nice way to have weddings. It&#8217;s definitely not your stereotypical Vegas chapel. Not an Elvis to be seen.<br />
Following the ceremony and the post-professional pictures, we all went to Chinois at the Forum Shops. It&#8217;s a Wolfgang Puck restaurant. Very tasty. Our &#8220;private room&#8221; was a great balcony overlooking the mall itself. It wasn&#8217;t loud at all, and much rejoicing was had.<br />
But now I stand in Maccaran International, awaiting my flight home at 2:10. Yes, that&#8217;s 02:10, as in AM, after midnight. I land in Calgary just before 6, then head right into work. Yes, I&#8217;m insane. But you already knew that.<br />
So to the newly-minted couple, I offer only my best hopes and wishes for life, love, and happiness. The minister was right &#8212; there is no gambling in love. There are no &#8220;ifs&#8221; or &#8220;in case of fires&#8221;. There is compromise and understanding, but love has a way of making that almost easy. May your remaining days in Las Vegas be full of fun and rest (you guys need it), and we all look forward to seeing you in Calgary.<br />
Congratulations my friends. And thank you for letting me be a part of your day in the sun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Vegas</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-in-vegas</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 21:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/08/back-in-vegas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back in Vegas"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for the good, I should say.<br />
If you&#8217;ve watched CSI, you&#8217;ve seen a stylised version of Las Vegas. And it ain&#8217;t the one that&#8217;s here. This is half gambling, half drunken idiots, half shopping, half selling sex, with some shows tossed in for fun.<br />
Yes, I know that adds up to well more than 100%. But this is a city of excesses.<br />
<span id="more-909"></span>Why am I here? My friend Tamara is getting married. It&#8217;s hard having been Tamara&#8217;s friend for the last year. Technically, I&#8217;m her boss. So I have to keep a &#8220;respectful distance&#8221;. Which sucks, since I&#8217;ve known her nearly eight years &#8212; nearly three of which we were housemates. We know each other pretty well. But I can&#8217;t act around her the way I would normally at work, since it might cast a light of favouritism.<br />
But when she asked me to come to her wedding, there was no question. None. Well, except whether or not Alex and the Wee One would come. As it is, they didn&#8217;t, and I&#8217;m running solo. Yeah, I know what you&#8217;re thinking: woo hoo, a weekend in Sin City for Geoff!<br />
I have a 7-month old and a wife, both of whom I love more than life itself. Do you really think I&#8217;m going to do something stupid?<br />
Besides, I&#8217;m too old to drink to the point of being sick (which I saw more than once yesterday), I never gamble with my money &#8212; only my life, and frankly I really don&#8217;t want to find out what weird diseases the hookers in this city pass around.<br />
That was a part of this city I&#8217;d forgotten about. It&#8217;s not just the newspaper box-like containers that distribute catalogues for hookers (no, I&#8217;m not kidding), it&#8217;s all the people who stand along the sidewalks, picking off all the guys (solo or in groups) to hand them cards. They flick them in their fingers like a nervous poker player. But instead of a royal flush, it&#8217;s a royal &#8230; well, y&#8217;know. It&#8217;s pathetic to see, and I actually feel sorry for these people.<br />
The Vegas of old where everything is cheap is long gone, too. Everything here is insanely expensive. It was $15 just to travel the 1.5 kms from the airport to my hotel. And that was moving pretty darn zippily, I might add. Meals are insanely expensive, too. Although I managed to find the Tea House in the Imperial Palace. A roast beef meal with all-you-can-drink lemonade for $20 with tip. At the newer hotels, that&#8217;s just your drink.<br />
I&#8217;m staying at the Tropicana, in a hotel room that hasn&#8217;t seen a renovation in about three decades. The maintenance hatch to the bathroom plumbing is rusting at the edges, the silicone seals have dried and peeled away, and the sink doesn&#8217;t drain worth a damn. The bed must be wrapped in plastic from what I could feel.<br />
Tamara and Dan, by comparison, are in the 18th floor of the Mandalay Bay. Their place is bigger and nicer than most of the apartments I&#8217;ve stayed in. It&#8217;s almost criminal. But they&#8217;ve never been here before, so they&#8217;re allowed the experience. Besides, it&#8217;s their wedding, right?<br />
I spent today shopping. Clothes for the Wee One, a trinket or two for Alex. I tried to find a cheap camera flash for me, but be darned if there isn&#8217;t a single freakin&#8217; camera store closer than a $20 cab ride. I&#8217;ve done enough cab rides for now. I&#8217;ll stick to the monorail.<br />
Tonight is the &#8220;night before&#8221;. Tamara and her crew are going to the Stratosphere to have fun. Dan&#8217;s at a show until 22:00 or so, so I&#8217;ll run around and get some night pictures (would you expect any less of me?)<br />
Well, only 1 minute left on this internet cafe computer, so I&#8217;ll wrap up this entry. Tomorrow&#8217;s the wedding, so with luck I&#8217;ll hammer something more out. And yes, pictures will come once I can get them all uploaded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">909</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech Summit, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-summit-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 05:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/12/tech-summit-day-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Tech Summit, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know how they affect me, and I know how to handle them.<br />
This thing &#8212; whatever it was &#8212; knocked me flat on my back and sent me back to bed for the rest of the morning. Fortunately, I didn&#8217;t feel like I missed too much.<br />
<span id="more-902"></span>The day was spent completing the tasks from yesterday, and working to our department strategy. That meant debate. And a lot of it. But when you&#8217;re changing the way you work, you&#8217;re more concerned with change, rather than status quo. Still, it does raise blood pressure in a few.<br />
At the end of the day, we started to try define the qualities and responsibilities of Technology Directors. It&#8217;s harder than it sounds. Especially since those of us who are Technology Directors have found that we don&#8217;t always see things the same way. It&#8217;s why Cory and I proposed the exercise in the first place.<br />
Afterwards was the Technology Lead event: we got to go see Da Bulls. (That would be the Chicago Bulls NBA franchise, in case you completely missed the late 1980s of Saturday Night Live.)<br />
I&#8217;d never been to a basketball game before. I wasn&#8217;t sure what to expect, and honestly believed that I wouldn&#8217;t really like it. I&#8217;m not a sports nut. I like hockey, and I used to love baseball, but I don&#8217;t really follow sports in any appreciable way. My last stint at a football game was underwhelming (I left the game early), and wondered how bored I&#8217;d be at this one.<br />
Turns out that you don&#8217;t get the option. The game is &#8212; likely due to television contracts &#8212; very ADD-oriented. Every so often (likely about the time of a commercial break), they game stops and there&#8217;s dancing (the cheerleaders went through three costume changes), games (Benny the Bull &#8212; the Bulls&#8217; mascot &#8212; had his birthday and several of the other NBA mascots came out to celebrate), random t-shirt throwings, and these weird little CG &#8220;races&#8221; on the JumboTron.<br />
All at the same time.<br />
No, I&#8217;m not kidding.<br />
It was hard to figure out what you should be looking at. It was almost confusing.<br />
But &#8212; I&#8217;ll give it this &#8212; it was entertaining. The Bulls lost, but it was easy to miss that fact.<br />
Afterwards, we had to figure out how to get from the United Center back to our hotel. Easier said than done. Couldn&#8217;t find a taxi. Anywhere. And when we did, they were all taken.<br />
The 11 of us traipsed down West Madison, Bill nearly freezing a jacket not made for the cold weather (he had literally flown in from Costa Rica and had not planned on such frigid temperatures) and all of us sliding around in the slush and snow (Chicagoans appear to not want to shovel walkways or sidewalks).<br />
Aside from a 1.5 hour stop at the Third Rail bar to &#8220;warm up&#8221;, we walked most of the way back. Scott, Allard, Sep, and Joe were the first to bail out when we finally saw a cab. Bill, Torin, Johnathan, and Cory took the second cab a couple of blocks later. Dave took a cab (he had a long way to drive home). Only Reid and I walked the entire way back (his apartment is barely a block from the hotel).<br />
And now, to bed. It&#8217;s been another long day. Looking forward to going home. I have a pair of babies at home that I miss dearly.<br />
[flickr]tag:chicago+february+&#8221;12&#8243;+2008@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Up-coming travel</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=up-coming-travel</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 20:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[england]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/22/up-coming-travel/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it. So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months. First, the family is off to Scotland &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Up-coming travel"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it.<br />
So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months.<br />
<span id="more-894"></span>First, the family is off to Scotland again. This time, more Scotland than England. And no Ireland. Allen and Alex want to visit Iona. A week on a small rural island with ancient churches. I can&#8217;t think of a better place for a photo essay, myself. Then off to the Inverness area (hello, Nessie!), through York for a couple of days (a <em>whole day</em> in the National Railway Museum!), then home again. That&#8217;ll be early April.<br />
And, yes, El Bebe is coming with us. Not sure how this is going to work &#8212; both Alex and I are a bit apprehensive about the time difference. Alex has trouble with the shift &#8212; I can only imagine how the wee one will handle it. We&#8217;ve heard that this is the best time to travel with children, so they (kind of) get used to it. But it does mean we can&#8217;t move at my preferred break-neck pace. Instead of going right to Iona, it&#8217;s going to take two days from the time we land. I can hack that, though.<br />
Next up is a business trip to Chicago, which is actually first in the list, coming up in the second week of February. The Technology Department leadership (which includes me) will be trying to figure out our long-term plans and aspirations. It&#8217;s going to be an interesting session.<br />
Finally &#8212; at least currently on the radar &#8212; is a weekend in Las Vegas. I&#8217;m going down for Tamara&#8217;s wedding. That&#8217;s the second weekend in March. I haven&#8217;t been there in 12 years, so this should make for an interesting experience.<br />
I can&#8217;t wait to get back on the road again!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">894</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colbert no longer for President</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/colbert-no-longer-for-president/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=colbert-no-longer-for-president</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/colbert-no-longer-for-president/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 23:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/01/colbert-no-longer-for-president/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, yes, everyone&#8217;s heard about Stephen Colbert&#8216;s run for the presidency. Those of you who watch his show regularly (sadly, I do not; though Alex is becoming a massive fan) know what Colbert is like. Perhaps not the most serious &#8212; or informed &#8212; person to be on the ballot. And let&#8217;s be sure we&#8217;re &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/colbert-no-longer-for-president/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Colbert no longer for President"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, yes, everyone&#8217;s heard about <a href="http://www.comedycentral.com/shows/the_colbert_report/">Stephen Colbert</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.stephencolbert08.com/">run for the presidency</a>. Those of you who watch his show regularly (sadly, I do not; though Alex is becoming a massive fan) know what Colbert is like. Perhaps not the most serious &#8212; or informed &#8212; person to be on the ballot.<br />
And let&#8217;s be sure we&#8217;re talking here &#8212; he was aiming to be on the ballot in South Carolina. But <a href="http://www.mtv.com/news/articles/1573288/20071101/id_0.jhtml">the Democrats down there decided to throw him off</a>.<br />
Big mistake.<br />
<span id="more-855"></span>The Democrats have had some serious issues getting the right people in front of the American public for President. The last two have gone down in infamy, having lost due to a legal decision, and the second time because &#8230; well, we&#8217;re not really sure why. But I&#8217;ve got my own thought on that.<br />
Simply put, they were boring.<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Al_Gore">Al Gore</a> wasn&#8217;t exactly noted for being rambunctious, flamboyant, or extraverted. More alone the lines of &#8220;dull as a rock&#8221;. Smart, yes. Became a <a href="http://www.climatecrisis.net/">wonderful defender of the environment</a>. But that was <em>after</em> losing to someone who shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to run with scissors, let alone a country.<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Kerry">John Kerry</a> became famous for changing direction like the wind. That, and he didn&#8217;t seem physically capable of being interesting. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howard_Dean">Howard Dean</a>, by comparison, was great until he shoved his foot so far in his mouth he could stand on his own colon.<br />
The key here is that boring doesn&#8217;t win. If you think it&#8217;s about putting in the right person, you&#8217;re missing the point. It&#8217;s about who has more charisma. (Throw in whatever conspiracy theory you want, the reality is that government is done largely by committee, no matter country and/or political system.) Subconsciously, everyone wants a President who represents the spirit of the United States. Dubya didn&#8217;t win because he was the right one (he&#8217;s proved that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Movement_to_impeach_George_W._Bush#Rationales_for_impeachment">several times over</a>) &#8212; it&#8217;s because he at least had some form of presence.<br />
I know this because I look at Canadian politics. If we had to elect our own Prime Minister, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_humour">we&#8217;d be screwed</a>. Most of them have no more excitement than a stick. So thankfully, we just vote for the party we think is right. They sort the rest of that crap out for us. Doesn&#8217;t always work, but then we just vote them back out again the next time.<br />
Colbert would have been a great candidate. He would have won the Presidency, too. Tell me that he wouldn&#8217;t have buried every other candidate by throwing them oddball questions that they wouldn&#8217;t know how to answer. No script in the world could account for someone who talks on his feet. Think <a href="http://us.imdb.com/title/tt0483726/">Man of the Year</a> is pure fiction? I&#8217;m willing to bet Colbert could have taken South Carolina without trying.<br />
<a href="http://www.webware.com/8301-1_109-9805080-2.html">A million people already support him.</a>  That&#8217;s grass roots support. Sure, <a href="http://my.barackobama.com/page/group/BarackObamaOneMillionStrongforBarack">Obama&#8217;s got that, too</a>, but it took him several times longer to get it.<br />
After eight years of Bush, the world needs someone to laugh at for a while. If nothing else, it would make for the most interesting (if not funny) election ever seen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/colbert-no-longer-for-president/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">855</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
