<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>phones &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/phones/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 16:39:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Steve Jobs blows it. Again.</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=steve-jobs-blows-it-again</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 16:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sigh.  There&#8217;s nothing more frustrating than watching Apple come so close to finally tying the knot, only to leave threads dangling.   I speak, of course, of yesterday&#8217;s Let&#8217;s Rock event where the apparently-not-dead (but much gaunter-looking) Steve Jobs talked at length about iTunes and iPods. And they played Jack Johnson, who is somehow the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Steve Jobs blows it. Again."</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sigh.  There&#8217;s nothing more frustrating than watching Apple come so close to finally tying the knot, only to leave threads dangling.  <br />
I speak, of course, of yesterday&#8217;s <a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/0809dt4bs89/event/index.html">Let&#8217;s Rock</a> event where the <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5047484/steve-jobs-responds-to-accusations-of-dying">apparently-not-dead (but much gaunter-looking) Steve Jobs</a> talked at length about iTunes and iPods. And they played Jack Johnson, who is somehow the most popular male performer on iTunes to this point in history. (Yeah, I don&#8217;t get that either. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, Jack, you&#8217;re a great performer &#8212; just didn&#8217;t see that coming.)  <br />
But why &#8212; oh why! &#8212; does Apple have to continually deny us a complete entertainment experience?  <br />
<span id="more-1091"></span><a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/2007/09/13/the-iphone-is-obsolete/">I blogged about the iPhone shortly after its launch</a> (well, I&#8217;d written the blog entry, just took a couple of months to get posted &#8212; long story) about how I felt that Apple had missed a killer opportunity. Like, as in a killing-the-competition-kind-of-killer.  <br />
I still feel that way. It&#8217;s been over a year and a half, now. And still, Apple plain refuses to pick up that ball.  <br />
Let&#8217;s review. Apple has the following in their product and service lines:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes</a>: a massive database of media (music, video, podcast) that now includes HD video and the ability to get movies without leaving your house</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/mac/">Powerful computers</a> (with ample disk space) to store your collected content from iTunes, and serve it out to&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">Apple TV</a> (version 2; version 1 was a dud), which serves beautifully as a device to put your iTunes-served content onto your 50&#8243; HD television. (It&#8217;s even kept under the <a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes section on the website</a>, for crying out loud!)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/macmini/">Mac Mini</a>, which could serve as a node on an internal network to receive content from a central server and sent to Apple TV, providing additional functionality (such as web browsing &#8212; can you say &#8220;interactive television&#8221;?)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/">AirPort Extreme</a> (Wi-Fi, which I&#8217;m getting to)</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Front_Row">Front Row</a>, which allows easy access to any of your content through a simple remote (which is the way it should be &#8212; one device, not 10). And for the love of all things geeky, amp this up, will ya? You downplay it too much. It&#8217;s slick. It&#8217;s nice &#8212; give it more presence!</li>
<li>And of course, the <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> and <a href="http://www.apple.com/ipodtouch/">iPod Touch</a>, both Wi-Fi internet-capable devices that sync with iTunes</li>
</ul>
<p>So, Steve, where is my home entertainment environment?  <br />
You&#8217;ve got all the pieces. They&#8217;re right there. Sure, with enough work I could figure it out on my own &#8212; it&#8217;s not that hard. But you&#8217;re missing a killer market here. You&#8217;re an experience-based company, for Pete&#8217;s sake! You know all about experience, because that&#8217;s what you sell.<br />
Apple makes hardware and software. Big frickin&#8217; deal &#8212; so do all of your competitors. But you spent the time to make them work well, and in a way that users don&#8217;t just love, you turn them into rabid fanboys. (Sorry, Microsoft, but your fanboys don&#8217;t come close.)<br />
And while you&#8217;re at it, how hard would it be to make an app for the iPhone / iPod Touch that would allow you to flip audio/video between nodes in your house? To allow you to &#8212; literally &#8212; carry a tune from your node in your kitchen to your bedroom via your Wi-fi device (iWhatever) without skipping a beat. Video, too &#8212; so my wife can continue to watch her favourite movie in bed without missing anything.  <br />
While I&#8217;m at it, I have a couple of other requests I want to add:</p>
<ul>
<li>Let me rip my DVDs into iTunes. DCMA be damned &#8212; I bought the movie, and I want to use it on my devices. There is no <em>reasonable </em>explanation for why I shouldn&#8217;t be able to do this.  </li>
<li>50&#8243; <a href="http://www.apple.com/displays/">Cinema Display</a>. People would give up vital parts of their anatomy to have one of these. Imagine how an iTunes-served movie would look on one. Just sayin&#8217;.  </li>
</ul>
<p>C&#8217;mon, Steve. Don&#8217;t make me beg. It&#8217;s not a pretty sight.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1091</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The phones I ordered finally showed up</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-phones-i-ordered-finally-showed-up/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-phones-i-ordered-finally-showed-up</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-phones-i-ordered-finally-showed-up/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 22:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Augh. I called it yesterday, when I got my new cell phone. A month ago, we ordered phones over the internet. They were shipped US Postal Service. They entered Costa Rica on 8 July. And then sat in customs. When I got my Nokia, I said (knowing this was truth) that our eBay-ordered phones would &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-phones-i-ordered-finally-showed-up/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The phones I ordered finally showed up"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Augh.<br />
I called it yesterday, when I got my new cell phone. A month ago, we ordered phones over the internet. They were shipped US Postal Service. They entered Costa Rica on 8 July. And then sat in customs. When I got my Nokia, I said (knowing this was truth) that our eBay-ordered phones would show up today.<br />
I hate it when I&#8217;m right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-phones-i-ordered-finally-showed-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1030</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My new 1998-era Nokia TDMA cell phone</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/my-new-1998-era-nokia-tdma-cell-phone/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-new-1998-era-nokia-tdma-cell-phone</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/my-new-1998-era-nokia-tdma-cell-phone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 15:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gsm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Note today&#8217;s date: 8 August 2008. That&#8217;s (almost) two months since we first came to Costa Rica. Two months ago, we tried to start getting things like cars, bank accounts, work visas (a fairly significant need), and cell phones, as these were the things we felt were necessary to be able to do our jobs &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/my-new-1998-era-nokia-tdma-cell-phone/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My new 1998-era Nokia TDMA cell phone"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Note today&#8217;s date: 8 August 2008. That&#8217;s (almost) two months since we first came to Costa Rica. Two months ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/">we tried to start getting things</a> like cars, bank accounts, work visas (a fairly significant need), and cell phones, as these were the things we felt were necessary to be able to do our jobs effectively.<br />
To date, we&#8217;ve all managed to get bank accounts. Only <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2723556436/">Mark has successfully bought a car</a> (Jason and Jen are still looking, and we&#8217;re <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/statuses/879475198">still waiting for our money to arrive from Canada</a>), and the work visas are in the application process (read: not completed).<br />
Yesterday, despite phones ordered via eBay still being stuck in Costa Rica customs, we finally got cell phones.<br />
<span id="more-1028"></span>Well, Jason+Jen and I did, anyway. The third phone was a dud and wouldn&#8217;t work. Mark has to wait another day or two to get his. Mind you, he still has an iPhone that sorta works here. Better than nuthin&#8217;, right?<br />
[flickr]photo:2742047579(small)[/flickr]<br />
The phone, as you can plainly see, is nothing fancy. It&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.nokia.ca/A4489303">Nokia 1220 TDMA</a>, built in 2001 (according to the all-Spanish manual in the box), and resembles phones you could get in the late 1990s. It uses a technology that is not only antiquated, but also no longer supported by Nokia. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_division_multiple_access">TDMA is dead</a>, folks. But here in Costa Rica, it&#8217;s not only the most reliable network (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GSM">GSM</a> barely covers the city San José and a few other pockets of the country consistently), but it&#8217;s also the only one we can even get phone numbers for (there are no available GSM numbers right now).<br />
<a href="http://www.therealcostarica.com/technology_costa_rica/cell_phones.html">GSM in this country</a> is &#8230; well, it&#8217;s pathetic. Beyond pathetic. When Apple launched the 3G iPhone, we were unsurprised to find that <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/countries/">Costa Rica was not one of those countries</a>. ICE (<a href="http://www.grupoice.com/">Instituto Costaricense de Electricidad</a>) is the sole provider of phone service in Costa Rica. It&#8217;s a government monopoly. The term &#8220;glacial&#8221; should be coming to mind, here, folks.<br />
Supposedly the monopoly needs to change due to the new <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_American_Free_Trade_Agreement">CAFTA agreements</a>, but the government&#8217;s not exactly embracing the change at light-speed. That means no advanced service (the most recent attempt was rebuffed when <a href="http://www.costaricapages.com/blog/business/chinese-cellphone-bid/1285">the sole bidder came in way over projected costs</a>), and limited range.<br />
So we&#8217;re stuck with TDMA. Voice only. Not even text messages (I&#8217;ve tried to send them, and they don&#8217;t come through). But the voice does at least work.<br />
The first call? We ordered a pizza for dinner last night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/my-new-1998-era-nokia-tdma-cell-phone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#039;s Mañana Time!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-manana-time</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s Mañana Time!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of shape only makes things go more slowly. (And no, totally slacking off doesn&#8217;t cause the reverse.)<br />
For us up-tight North Americans, this is the single hardest thing to contend with. Uncertainty is the name of our game, so unknown things aren&#8217;t a problem. It&#8217;s the ability to do simple little things.<br />
Like call each other. Hard to do when you have no phone.<br />
<span id="more-1008"></span>For those of you old enough to remember, it&#8217;s like when you were in high school, and couldn&#8217;t use the phone to call your friends (your sister/brother/parents were hogging it or you were grounded) and had to wait until <em>the following day</em> to talk about anything. Oh, the days of yore!<br />
When &#8212; like us &#8212; you&#8217;ve become accustomed to always-on internet access and cellular phones, it&#8217;s really hard to go back to having nothing. Literally nothing. Jason and I have to &#8220;borrow&#8221; internet from unsecured sites around our respective complexes; Mark is left high and dry. Planning requires an intricate set of where we&#8217;re going and when, and plans in the event we don&#8217;t exactly meet up as planned.<br />
(It also doesn&#8217;t help that we&#8217;re wholly reliant on taxis for now &#8212; we haven&#8217;t been able to figure out the bus system &#8212; which are notoriously unreliable for being available in all places, or being anywhere near punctual. It&#8217;s especially bad if you&#8217;re out late, such as we were Monday night when we tried to catch a taxi after going to the grocery store. It was almost an hour before we could find one.)<br />
At the office, we were struggling to get anything to work, stealing internet from an adjacent office (given, we were told the password). With Lee here, we had carte blanche to purchase a wireless router (yes, Clay, it&#8217;s a D-Link) and a printer. The router allows us to use an existing connection (which only started working properly this morning), and the printer is WiFi-enabled so we can put it wherever it makes sense to put it.<br />
And the speed at which it takes to get them done. We&#8217;re used to &#8220;right away&#8221;. Here, it&#8217;s &#8220;mañana&#8221;, which requires a lot of grains of salt. There&#8217;s just so many things that we would like to have happen now, so we don&#8217;t have to worry about them for long periods of time. But no, it don&#8217;t work that way.<br />
Take Mark, for example. He&#8217;s been in his condo since Monday afternoon. He still doesn&#8217;t have air conditioning installed (despite being told it would be done the day he moved in) and his dryer doesn&#8217;t work yet. It&#8217;s happening, just really slowly.<br />
It&#8217;s not uncommon for someone&#8217;s email system to fill because there just isn&#8217;t a rush to empty it.<br />
Collectively, we&#8217;ve got a whack of things we need done, and we&#8217;ve no idea how fast/easy these will happen. And believe me, this is causing us concern. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>How do we open a bank account? It&#8217;s not as easy as walking into a bank with a few bucks in your hand.</li>
<li>How do we purchase a car? Apparently, it&#8217;s like buying a house in North America, complete with lawyers.</li>
<li>How do we get a driver&#8217;s license? And get one of those fancy &#8220;medical&#8221; certificates?</li>
<li>How do we get the insurance? And handle the annual mechanical inspection?</li>
<li>How do we get cell phones? More importantly, how do we get the number for any phone? Unless you&#8217;re a permanent resident, you can&#8217;t get a number (although you can get the phone).</li>
<li>What health care will we get?</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there&#8217;s the visa process. This is really an entirely separate topic, which I&#8217;m not sure I can really do justice. The whole process is a living nightmare, which Jason and Jen have been trying to wrangle to the ground. Sadly, the consulate keeps giving us new information which amounts to &#8220;oh, by the way, you need to do this too, which I realise totally throws off everything you were already doing&#8221;. More on that later, though.<br />
So this is live in Costa Rica. No, I&#8217;m not complaining. I&#8217;m not changing my mind. But a lot of people wanted to know how it&#8217;s going. Now you know.<br />
Which begs the question: If knowing is half the battle, what the heck is the other half?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello, unlimited wireless data in Canada!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/hello-unlimited-wireless-data-canada/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hello-unlimited-wireless-data-canada</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/hello-unlimited-wireless-data-canada/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 20:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blackberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/03/hello-unlimited-wireless-data/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Until today &#8212; 12:42 MT, to be exact &#8212; I had a particularly negative view of the Canadian mobile market. Generally, I expected the Big 3 telcos to basically keep screwing over us little folk, and continue to treat Canada as a lovely little cash cow where there&#8217;s no competition. Anyone who&#8217;s on Telus, pay &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/hello-unlimited-wireless-data-canada/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Hello, unlimited wireless data in Canada!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Until today &#8212; 12:42 MT, to be exact &#8212; I had a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2007/09/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/">particularly negative view of the Canadian mobile market</a>. Generally, I expected the Big 3 telcos to basically keep screwing over us little folk, and continue to treat Canada as a lovely little cash cow where there&#8217;s no competition.<br />
Anyone who&#8217;s on Telus, pay attention! The game has changed.<br />
<span id="more-886"></span>Over the Christmas break, my friend (and co-worker) Marcie bought a Blackberry Pearl. I&#8217;d originally wanted a Pearl &#8212; it&#8217;s smaller, and it has a digital camera. But Telus didn&#8217;t offer it (at the time), so I went with a Blackberry 8830 World Edition. For the record, I&#8217;m not complaining &#8212; the lack of a camera isn&#8217;t the end of the world for me. [[I&#8217;m on crack|And I love being on crack.]]<br />
But what I didn&#8217;t like was the data rates.<br />
I was paying $25/month to get 4 MB of data. Four megs. Paltry. I go through that with one breath. I&#8217;m a data whore, I admit it. Give me data or give me death. It drives Alex crazy that I spend as much time as I do on computers. But I love the connectivity. It&#8217;s what I do. It&#8217;s what I am.<br />
Marcie told me that she signed onto an unlimited data plan. I scoffed &#8212; no such thing in Canada! None of the carriers would be that nice, c&#8217;mon! She swore up and down the wall that it was legit. And she called Telus to prove it. She weren&#8217;t lyin&#8217;.<br />
So I called Telus. Mostly because, as a nigh-on-eight years loyal customer, I want unlimited data! Sure enough, the plan is legit.<br />
The details:</p>
<ul>
<li>You have to have at least a $30/month plan. (Hey, Telus might be willing to change the game, but they&#8217;re not stupid.)</li>
<li>The contract applies for all text, email, and non-tethered browsing.</li>
<li>It doesn&#8217;t cover access outside of Canada.</li>
<li>You connect your phone to your computer, you&#8217;re back to paying high rates.</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8220;Sign me up!&#8221; I cried in delight. I had to up my plan (previously on Talk 25, I&#8217;m now on the Favs plan), but in the end &#8212; get this &#8212; I&#8217;m saving $15/month in fees, and that&#8217;s not even covering the overages I was heading for (I was already double my limit, and I was trying to play it safe).<br />
Thank you, Telus. You&#8217;ve partially restored my faith in the fact that maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; the Canadian mobile market isn&#8217;t as screwed up as I thought it was.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/hello-unlimited-wireless-data-canada/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">886</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple doesn&#039;t hate Canada &#8230; Rogers, Bell, and Telus do</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 22:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gsm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/09/20/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those of us who&#8217;ve paid not only close attention to the rollout of the much-anticipated Apple iPhone but also to the Canadian mobile market don&#8217;t find this surprising. But we&#8217;re in the minority. A significantly larger portion of the Canadian iPhone-hungry masses are incensed by Apple&#8217;s announcement of the iPhone&#8217;s release in the UK. Why &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Apple doesn&#039;t hate Canada &#8230; Rogers, Bell, and Telus do"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Those of us who&#8217;ve paid not only close attention to the rollout of the much-anticipated Apple <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> but also to the Canadian mobile market don&#8217;t find this surprising. But we&#8217;re in the minority. A significantly larger portion of the Canadian iPhone-hungry masses are incensed by Apple&#8217;s announcement of the <a href="http://uk.gizmodo.com/2007/07/06/o2_wins_iphone_uk_contract.html">iPhone&#8217;s release in the UK</a>.<br />
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_RdHv9jw84k">Why do you hate us Apple?</a> Why do you not let us poor Canucks use your wonderful product?<br />
Guess what, my fellow Hosers, it ain&#8217;t Apple. You want the culprit? Look at your cell phone for a hint.<br />
<span id="more-823"></span>We are captives north of the border. We are barely 35 million people, about half of which use cell phones regularly (I&#8217;ll assume more than a mere 17 million cell phones.) We have three major telecommunications companies. I say &#8220;major&#8221; as in &#8220;operate nationally&#8221;. And they&#8217;re all about raking in the dough.<br />
Look at your cell plans. They&#8217;re pretty expensive compared to our cousins south of the border. Those of you with data devices know what I mean. What Americans pay for unlimited data on AT&amp;T, we pay for a mere 4 MB.<br />
Four megs. A handful of images. Maybe 20 short emails (or two of ones I write). God forbid you try to install and use Google Maps on a regular basis.<br />
It&#8217;s highway robbery, but where else do you go? Short of moving south of the 49th, you&#8217;re stuck.<br />
Why am I picking on the <a href="http://www.rogers.com/">Rogers</a>, <a href="http://www.telusmobility.com/">Telus</a>, and <a href="http://www.bellmobility.com/">Bell</a>? Because they&#8217;re the ones standing in your way to getting a properly supported iPhone in the Great White North. For the record, you can get an iPhone right now. AT&amp;T&#8217;s biggest blunder was not forcing Apple to let them sell the iPhone only in AT&amp;T stores, requiring activation before you walk off with it. Because you can buy the phone at any Apple Store (or online), nothing is preventing Canadians from buying the phones, taking them home, <a href="http://www.iunlock.com/">unlocking them,</a> and using them.<br />
Well, unless you happen to be the poor schmuck stuck on Telus, where GSM seems to be a three-letter word. Like me.<br />
It&#8217;s because of the Big 3 that we don&#8217;t have iPhones, and will be a while before we do. Rogers rules the roost of GSM. (Bell has limited support.) So from a hardware platform, only one of the three can carry the iPhone.<br />
Then remember that Apple is all about experience. They want to ensure that their products are more than mere devices or tools. It has to be something extraordinary. And for the iPhone, that means data. Lots of it. They negotiated the unlimited data rate with AT&amp;T to make that experience work.<br />
That needs to happen here, too. So long as we&#8217;re paying obscenely high fees for minuscule amounts of data, the iPhone is really only cool when you&#8217;re near an available Wi-Fi network. <a href="http://www.canada.com/nationalpost/financialpost/printedition/story.html?id=e91c2b95-2140-434d-b10c-97c689f1b773">Or you&#8217;re stinking rich and able to afford $300+/month bills.</a><br />
A note to Telus, Rogers, and Bell: DATA IS NOT JUST FOR BUSINESS. Greedy jerks&#8230;<br />
So no iPhone. I&#8217;m sure Apple&#8217;s talked to the carriers (Rogers, in particular), but until that rate comes down, we have to suffice with hacked iPhones, or remain on our other less-cool devices.<br />
The future is elsewhere, for now. We&#8217;ll see if things change&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/apple-doesnt-hate-canada-rogers-bell-and-telus-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">823</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The iPhone is obsolete</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/the-iphone-is-obsolete/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-iphone-is-obsolete</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/the-iphone-is-obsolete/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 22:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience matters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/09/18/the-iphone-is-obsolete/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unless you’ve been living in the middle of Mongolia for the last six months, you know that Apple’s iPhone is one of the hottest products of 2007. It’s heralding a new breed of mobile devices. It’s forcing dramatic changes in the wireless landscape. It’s expensive, but to almost everyone who uses one, it’s worth the cost. It’s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/the-iphone-is-obsolete/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The iPhone is obsolete"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unless you’ve been living in the middle of Mongolia for the last six months, you know that Apple’s <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> is one of the hottest products of 2007. It’s heralding a new breed of mobile devices. It’s forcing dramatic changes in the wireless landscape. It’s expensive, but to almost everyone who uses one, it’s worth the cost. It’s generated at least one <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2007/08/29/nokias-iphone-no-seriously/">phone copy cat</a> (and even<a href="http://www.belkin.com/n1vision/intro/"> a router</a>).<br />
It’s all that and a bag of chips.<br />
Only one problem: it’s already obsolete. Gathering dust. Old news. How did it become passé so quickly? Because Steve Jobs said so.<br />
<span id="more-850"></span>You weren’t listening, were you? You’re allowed. He said these things months ago when the phone was announced. Like the rest of us, you were too entranced with the shiny iPhone and its glorious interface. Oh, the features! And there was that guy in black talking about something…<br />
Allow me to provide two very specific quotes:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re introducing three revolutionary products. The first one is a widescreen iPod[,] the second is a revolutionary mobile phone[,] the third is a[n] Internet communications device. These are not three separate devices. This is one device.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Making calls is the killer app.</p></blockquote>
<p>So what should we be reading out of that? That the iPhone is expandable , and phone calls are just a <em>feature</em>.<br />
Okay, yes, the iPhone has been noted as having a number of issues, especially when looking at its API (nor notably, the <a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/posts/459-iphone-sdk-its-called-safari">lack thereof</a>) and that it’s effectively hard-coded to AT&amp;T (I’m surprised it <a href="http://www.iphoneworld.ca/news/2007/08/14/unlock-iphone-for-any-carrier-with-turbosim/">took so long to come out with a reliable crack</a>). But if you honestly think that Apple hasn’t looked that far ahead, then you haven’t looked far enough, either. The Good Ship Jobs hasn’t gotten this far without keeping whole decks of cards up its sleeves.<br />
Here’s the real secret that Steve Jobs isn’t talking about: the iPhone is not about reaching out and touching someone, it’s about Apple’s entertainment ecosystem. It’s about the experience of media going with you wherever you go.<br />
Yes, entertainment. Apple Inc. (the company <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/16563426/" rel="nofollow">formerly known as Apple Computer Inc.</a>) has slowly been chipping their way into the entertainment market for years. They do it slowly, carefully, and with far more ability than Hollywood cares to admit.<br />
<a href="http://www.apple.com/quicktime/">QuickTime</a>. <a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes">iTunes</a> and the <a href="http://www.apple.com/ipod">iPod</a>. <a href="http://www.apple.com/ilife/">iLife</a> and <a href="http://www.apple.com/macmini/frontrow.html">Front Row</a>. Noticing a pattern yet?<br />
If you aren’t, here’s a simple way to see all of these products: integrated. And that’s the key to most of Apple’s success: integrated experience. This is what Apple does better than any other media company. Take an ordinary task, and make it an extraordinary experience. There’s a reason Apple has sold <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2007/01/09itunes.html">two billion songs, 50 million television shows, and 1.3 million movies</a> in under four years.<br />
And such was the reaction when Apple announced the iPhone. It’s a platform that Apple can use to extend their entertainment experience in and out of the home.<br />
Here’s how they’ll do it.<br />
First off, there’s all the pieces you might already have at home: like an iMac or a Mac Mini. (There’s a surprising amount of stuff under that hood fresh out of the box.) The newest ones are untethered from the wired ‘net, and come armed with enough software to drive a lot of media.<br />
Next, add a missing piece that will put your Mac past the 17″ LCD screen to that lovely 50″ you have hanging on your wall: <a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">Apple TV</a>. Right now, it’s not the product it needs to be, but even the first iPod wasn’t an immediate success. Apple TV was a surprisingly underwhelming product from Apple for its initial launch, but at least its heart and mind are in the right place — expect this to meet the desires of everyone in a successive version.<br />
In Apple’s (ultimate) world, your setup would look like this:<br />
iTunes + iLife + Mac Mini or iMac + Apple TV = Pure entertainment<br />
Your Mac becomes your media centre, storing, organising, and delivering your music, photos, and video to your device of choice. It’ll be wonderfully elegant and (dare I suggest) fun to use.<br />
What’s missing? A remote control. A complete <em>multimedia</em> control. Remember: “Making calls is the killer app.” It’s way more than that.<br />
Try this scenario on for size:<br />
You’re listening to your jazz playlist on the way home. When you come within range of your home WiFi network, the iPhone syncs up with your entertainment system — the song’s playing in sync with your iPhone when you open the door.<br />
You feel the urge to watch a movie. You flip through your movie list on your iPhone, which has an up-to-date list from your home system, and start playing your newest download on your TV. After dinner, you feel the urge to exercise. You “drag” the video from the TV to your iPhone, which continues playing without pause and go on your treadmill. (For the record, this is nothing new — Sony had this figured out five years ago.) You “flick” the video from your iPhone to the TV in the workout room, not missing a beat of the action.<br />
Your friends come over later in the evening. You select pictures from your iPhone, synced with your iLife system, and “flick” them to your TV. The iPhone controls what you see, so zooming in specific areas is no different than if it were on your iPhone. You send a couple pictures to your printer so they can go home with your friends.<br />
Is this too fantastic? Perhaps, but it shouldn’t be. The technology exists. The platform exists. It’s only a minor leap to fill in the blanks in the iPhone (namely a wireless connection to a home computer) to make it a powerful remote control. You’d never look at a plastic box with numbered buttons the same way again.<br />
And if you’re not thinking about this, Steve, you should be. Talk about building a better experience, where you are already controlling all the disparate pieces. I smell a better mousetrap…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/the-iphone-is-obsolete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">850</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#039;m on crack</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/08/im-on-crack/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=im-on-crack</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/08/im-on-crack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 20:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blackberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/08/18/im-on-crack/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it&#8217;s happened. I am now officially on crack. Crackberry, that is&#8230; Yes, I&#8217;ve bought a Blackberry. A model 8830 to be specific. Alex is calling it my delayed father&#8217;s day present. I can live with that. No, it&#8217;s no iPhone, but it&#8217;s a pretty good solution. Better keyboard, too. Alex and I are currently &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/08/im-on-crack/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I&#039;m on crack"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, it&#8217;s happened. I am now officially on crack.<br />
Crackberry, that is&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-812"></span><br />
Yes, I&#8217;ve bought a Blackberry. A model 8830 to be specific. Alex is calling it my delayed father&#8217;s day present.<br />
I can live with that.<br />
No, it&#8217;s no iPhone, but it&#8217;s a pretty good solution. Better keyboard, too.<br />
Alex and I are currently sitting in the Devonian Gardens playing with our new phones (she got a Chocolate Flip).<br />
And yes, I posted this from the Crackberry!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/08/im-on-crack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">812</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
