<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>quebec &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/quebec/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 15:59:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Touring Montreal</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=montreal-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-touring/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 15:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/04/23/united-kingdom-2006-montreal-touring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We woke late. Had it not been for Allen returning from the office to prepare for Sunday service, I would might have slept entirely though my only chance to actually see him in action. It wasn&#8217;t the service that interests me &#8212; it was seeing Allen doing his thing. If it hadn&#8217;t been for him &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Touring Montreal"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We woke late. Had it not been for Allen returning from the office to prepare for Sunday service, I would might have slept entirely though my only chance to actually see him in action. It wasn&#8217;t the service that interests me &#8212; it was seeing Allen doing his thing. If it hadn&#8217;t been for him returning to the apartment, causing a ruckus loud enough to wake the dead (which we almost were), we&#8217;d have slept right through everything. Thankfully, we woke with about 45 minutes to spare, forcing a hurried dressing.<br />
Knox Crescent Kensington &amp; First Presbyterian church sits at the opposite end of Godfrey St. from Allen&#8217;s apartment. It takes only a few minutes to walk that distance &#8212; Godfrey is only four blocks long. The neighbourhood is wonderful to walk through, with its old duplex and triplex buildings, some attached and semi-detached houses, and huge trees that have witnessed countless hundreds of seasons and countless people walking under them. Like the trees south of Montreal, these have yet to sprout their leaves (though some are trying as hard as they can).<br />
<span id="more-436"></span>KCKF is a collection of three buildings. The original Kensington Church, a hall built about 20 years later, and the massive prayer building erected in the late 1940s. The church itself has a long, sordid history of mergings and separations, leading to the existing church community that exists today. I&#8217;d try to recover the entire tree, but it was confusing to see the map and be guided through it by two kind gentleman trying to explain it, let alone try to remember the path and explain it again. The same pattern is repeated through many churches in Montreal and across Canada, as various congregations merge to keep their communities alive. Although most Canadians might report that they are religious, many of them are not practicing, so the communities and edifices that would normally represent them are disappearing.<br />
Such is the case with KCKF. The prayer hall can seat over 800. The most Allen has seen in his tenure here (now over a year) is about a tenth of that. Today, we barely got to 50 people. Massive churches were not meant for so few people. Only 15 years after the new hall was built, attendance started to decline, and it hasn&#8217;t stopped. Although many of the congregation do not want the church to close, this is what Allen is recommending. The building is too expensive to operate and needs many repairs, and the money isn&#8217;t there. Many attach themselves to the building however, which makes it hard to do what has to be done. Despite the fact that the people are what make a church a community, the building is seen as too much of an important factor to sway opinion. These are challenges that are often hard to overcome.<br />
The prayer hall was built at the tail end of the gothic era of church building. A few of the key elements in a good gothic church &#8212; vaulted ceilings with arched supports, real stained glass windows (instead of painted glass), and a large altar area &#8212; are present in KCK&#8217;s hall. However, there are a number of more &#8220;modern&#8221; elements such as industrial lighting and fibreboard ceilings that seem to detract a bit. The fibreboard is also waterstained, a sure sign of needed repairs.<br />
Seating near the front of the pews, we had a good view of the &#8220;stage&#8221; where the service would be conducted. Lynn was also there, functioning as the Outreach Minister. She was chatting with several others in the assembled congregation. Being &#8220;Low Sunday&#8221; (the Sunday after Easter), the assembly was even lower than usual. I can only imagine how hard it much be for ministers on those days. There&#8217;s hardly anyone there &#8212; is it a good use of your time and a potentially great sermon? But that&#8217;s not your call &#8212; you have to do your job.<br />
Allen marched out of a door to the left of the altar, dressed in his ceremonial robes. Each sleeve of the flowing black gown bore three black chevrons bordered in red. Apparently, these show Allen&#8217;s doctorate in Ministry, which he obtained shortly after Alex and I met. (I had told myself that the first time I met him I would call Allen &#8220;Rev. Dr.&#8221; as a form of respect. But he beat me to the punch, caught off-guard when I returned from a conference in San Jose, defeating my plan.)<br />
The music &#8212; a much larger organ than Knox Presbyterian&#8217;s in Calgary &#8212; burst to life, followed by the choir who slowly walked up the aisle. A different approach, and I saw the reason why. With so few members in such a large space, you had to make sure people would engage themselves in singing. (Which, as I realized at the same time, is why choirs exist &#8212; to help encourage people to sing and lead the group as a whole.) A sad irony of KCK&#8217;s choir was that they have to hire professional singers. Which explains the professional-looking men in the back. I certainly understand the reasoning, even if it does seem a little desperate.<br />
Allen started at the back, with the traditional opening to a Presbyterian service. Normally, a good congregation will answer the minister&#8217;s opening with &#8220;And Peace be with you&#8221;, though I could barely hear anyone else. Allen must have had a similar problem as he immediately said: &#8220;Let&#8217;s try that again&#8221; and repeated the opening. Then he walked up the aisle and took his place at the altar to begin.<br />
Initially, I didn&#8217;t think he&#8217;d be doing much in the service, as Lynn seemed to be doing much more. In particular was the children&#8217;s segment, where Lynn tried to teach the children that if humans kept taking up all the space on Earth with our stuff and (most important) our waste that there won&#8217;t be enough room for trees, birds, and animals. Lynn did not elaborate that unless we changed we would ulimately be harming the human race by killing off all the birds, trees, and animals.<br />
The Presbyterian Church is an interesting group. I don&#8217;t know if the entire Church is like this across Canada, but certainly Allen and Lynn are, and most of the other Presbyterian ministers that I&#8217;ve met. Allen&#8217;s almost rabid about environmentalism. His house is greener than most, and he&#8217;s certainly inspiring to listen to about trying to be even greener. The desire to be green even goes so far as to encourage the purchase of Fair Trade coffee, and do to away with sytrofoam cups &#8212; everyone was encouraged to bring in a mug.<br />
I&#8217;m told the children&#8217;s segments tend to scare others. They don&#8217;t see the status quo, perhaps, and the focus on another group is something different. Different is uncomfortable, even if necessary. During Allen&#8217;s sermon (which was quite long, but well written; he really needs to write a book), he told a story where his friend Glynnis once saw a never-ending flow of children enter a church. The point, of course, is that the church needs to look not as its current membership, but it&#8217;s newer members to make changes and set the direction for the future. The church is dying amongst white Canada, and without new blood the organism itself will die. (Okay, my paraphrasing, but I assume I&#8217;m not far off.)<br />
It&#8217;s funny &#8212; I sit in my job, listening and talking daily about the online communities that bring together many people from many different backgrounds to form a specific group. The Flickrs, the Del.icio.uses, the mailing lists, and the MySpaces. They were all predated by the churches. Certainly they were more geographically-limited (online communities have restrictions, but they are more self-imposed than their ability to reach others). I find it interesting how the human race manages to reinvent things such as community over a period of time.<br />
With the service over, we stuck around a while to engage in the post-service activities, namely coffee. I still don&#8217;t drink the stuff, but Allen needs to be present as the church minister. That gave me time to take pictures in the prayer hall and about. It&#8217;s a truly wonderful space. The coffee period didn&#8217;t last long, though, and we were soon on our way back to the apartment. Allen disrobed and acquired something more comfortable, and the three of us headed out to Chinatown.<br />
I love trains. If you&#8217;ve ever read these journals with any regularity, you know that. However, there are limits. Montreal has a great subway system. Far better and more extensive than Toronto&#8217;s. You&#8217;d think Canada&#8217;s largest city would address that issue, but they haven&#8217;t really figured that out yet. Montreal wins, hands down, the public transit award for me. But what I don&#8217;t really like is the Metro. I like how well it works and its basic planning, I just don&#8217;t like how it&#8217;s implemented. If you&#8217;ve never been there, it&#8217;s on tires. Rubber tires. It&#8217;s like a series of automobiles all strung together. They run fast, but are noisy and bounce around a lot. Some say it&#8217;s a better ride, but I can say with a great deal of confidence that I&#8217;ll take a steel wheel-on-rail version any day.<br />
The goal was to meet up with Therese and Stuart for dim sum, something I haven&#8217;t had for a while (especially with them), let alone in Montreal. The Montreal public transit system is quite good, and a short bus ride to the Metro had us at Furama (which Stuart refers to as &#8220;Futurama&#8221;, for no reason other than it sounds funnier) a few minutes ahead of our scheduled arrival. Stuart, Therese, and a sound-asleep Allison arrived about 20 minutes later.<br />
No ginger beef (a Calgary-only specialty) and a few different approaches on familiar dishes were a change, but the overall meal was quite good. I certainly had little to complain about, as the food was still excellent quality. Allison was a little grumpy when she woke up, though. When we were all done, we headed down to the lobby (after fighting over the bill; if Therese can&#8217;t move fast enough to grab it from me, that&#8217;s not my problem &#8212; I love being stubborn) and headed our separate ways. I&#8217;m not sure when I&#8217;ll see them again, but hopefully it won&#8217;t be too long. Like I said, I don&#8217;t get to see my friends often enough. And good friends are hard to find.<br />
The rain had let up a little bit, so walking down to Notre Dame wasn&#8217;t too bad. I had thought we&#8217;d go inside, but apparently the goal was just to see the cathedral. So off we headed to the Metro and back to the Benny apartment. The stop was short-lived as we then headed out for Mont Royal and a little walk-about.<br />
We &#8220;detoured&#8221; at Second Cup. I&#8217;m not exactly how we got onto that topic, but the apparent need for a chai tea was overwhelming. [[Starbucks discontinues Chanticos?|I still miss Chanticos]], and regular hot chocolate just doesn&#8217;t cut it for me at all these days. If it&#8217;s not the good stuff, it&#8217;s just not worth it. I&#8217;m going to have to switch to tea, I know it. The detour was extended to acquire sugar pie, which I&#8217;ve never actually had before. The pie ended up being a maple sugar pie, which was even more appealing in the long run.<br />
The trip up to Mont Royal suggested that we were going to have some difficulty with staying dry.<br />
The rain had picked up significantly. But rain is just water, and unless you happen to be the Tin Man or the Wicked Witch of the West, there&#8217;s little to fear. The walk up and down the hill to the look out was quite pleasant, though damp. And I spend most of the time looking down at the sidewalk as not to smuck the worms scattered about trying to breathe. I have nothing against worms, and do my best not to step on them.<br />
The view over Montreal was expectedly cloudy and you couldn&#8217;t see very far. The last time I saw that view was in 1993, with my friends James, Kathryn, and Chris. The view had been much nicer then, as the rain hadn&#8217;t been an issue. I could barely see across the river, let alone the mountains in the distance. Perhaps next time I&#8217;m out&#8230;<br />
My memory of the last time on mountain is fuzzy. I remember climbing in shorts on the melting snow. I remember laughing myself silly when it went up to my knees (it&#8217;s not the only time that&#8217;s happened, incidentally). I remember Kathryn doubled over when I told her the story of how Mom and Cathy had thought I was gay. I remember introducing James to St. Joseph&#8217;s Oratory. What I didn&#8217;t remember was the distance between the lookout and the Oratory. I&#8217;d remembered it being much closer. It worries me a bit, since I wonder how much else I&#8217;ve forgotten.<br />
By the time I got back to the car, I was soaked. Thoroughly. But the joys of traveling pants &#8212; they dry very quickly. By the time we&#8217;d gotten down the mountain, passed by the Royal Victoria Hospital, and returned to the Benny apartment, most of the pants had dried. There I acquired all the fixings for a spaghetti primavera (with chicken) &#8230; and realized that my trusty traveling pants had developed a massive hole in the arse, just under the left butt cheek. How and where, I have no idea. But the pants were dead. I need to buy replacements tomorrow, lest my sole remaining pair of pants meet a similar fate, rendering me pantless.<br />
Dinner was wonderful, and the pie was borderline lethal. We watched &#8220;<em>Fargo</em>&#8220;, Allen giggling like a little kid throughout the movie. For a minister, he has a really dark sense of humour. Must be why I like him so much. Tomorrow we meet up with Glynnis for breakfast, and fly out to London. As much as I like Montreal, I really want to get on with this trip.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">436</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Earth Day in Montreal</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-earth-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=montreal-earth-day</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-earth-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2006 15:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/04/22/united-kingdom-2006-montreal-earth-day/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were a little slow waking up this morning. Might have been due to the change in time, or possibly due to the fact that we&#8217;re beginning to relax on this vacation, or because we simply didn&#8217;t get out of bed. All the crashing and banging however, conspired us out into the day. Earth Day &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-earth-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Earth Day in Montreal"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were a little slow waking up this morning. Might have been due to the change in time, or possibly due to the fact that we&#8217;re beginning to relax on this vacation, or because we simply didn&#8217;t get out of bed. All the crashing and banging however, conspired us out into the day.<br />
Earth Day 2006 would not go unnoticed. Normally, I don&#8217;t really acknowledge Earth Day. The first one was a novel idea, but years later it&#8217;s just something for people to murmur about much as they would about that odd uncle who wears underwear on the outside of his pants. It&#8217;s not something that most people &#8212; myself included &#8212; take seriously.<br />
Today would be different.<br />
<span id="more-435"></span>The trip down to Franklin was long. Getting out of Montreal was the hard part. The local native tribe on the south shore effectively cut down one of the two spans of the Mercier bridge to show solidarity to their cousins battling in Ontario for their rights and privileges. Admittedly, I didn&#8217;t know too much about the affair, only that it was echoing the Oka standoff of a decade ago &#8212; though without the deaths and the famous native-mountie face-to-face pictures.<br />
In principle, I respect and support the natives in what they&#8217;re doing by cutting down access across their lands (Highway 138 runs right across their territory). In reality though, I can&#8217;t quite get why it would make sense to tick off Montrealers when it&#8217;s Torontonians they should be going after. Maybe the Ottawa crowd. Montreal isn&#8217;t exactly insular, but they get along with their native neighbours a lot more friendly than those in Ontario.<br />
The shutdown also caused us to miscalulate the directions. We missed the Highway 30 turnoff and took a bit longer to get where we were going. But eventually, we did manage to pull into Phil and Lynn&#8217;s driveway shortly after the Vinyl Cafe had signed off for another week.<br />
The lane was lined with trees still barren of leaves. It&#8217;s still early spring here in the Chateauguay area, and leaves are only starting to bud. Things won&#8217;t likely green up here for a couple of more weeks. The farm yard was greening after a long winter, and would be the precuror to the rest of the massive property. A large two-storey white and green farm house recently clad with what appeared to be aluminum siding stood on the west side; an old dilapitated barn on the east. The barn had obvious extensions. The laneway snaked around the barn on the north side and continued into the orchards beyond the living portion of the land.<br />
Phil was out back of the house pressing fresh apple juice with some apples that had been stored for the winter. The apples were grown fresh on the farm &#8212; a former apple farm turned hobby farm. Phil was tossing apples into small hopper while the kids were running around him, the press, and the young girl turning the crank that chewed up the apples and dropped them into a cheesecloth-lined bin underneath. When there was enough apple mulch in the bin, Phil would place the pressing lid in, and the press crank turned until the pulp-laden amber juice flowed into a plastic bucket. Not the most elegant operation, but boy did that juice taste good.<br />
There were four families there, including ours and Phil&#8217;s. Several children, including a very young girl, barely two years old. The group of us wandered about back and forth, in and out of the house meeting one another, until Cole (one of the boys) called out that there was a baby pigeon in the barn loft. This propagated a temporary mass migration into the barn for a look. No pigeon, but a wonderful opportunity for photographs! I love old buildings. There is not a better subject than man-made architecture.<br />
When I finished my run, I called Therese to arrange for a meeting time with her and Stuart (and their daughter Allison) later that afternoon. We talked for quite a long time before I finally had to put an end to the call, lest we run out of things to discuss later on. I resumed the group running a scavenger hunt on the east side of the property, just as the topic of conversation was the price of apples from China and how they were killing off the local apple growers who can&#8217;t compete.<br />
It&#8217;s a familiar tune lately. China does everything cheaper than North America. Most of the goods we buy are made or grown in China. The United States has a massive trade deficit with China. I don&#8217;t know what Canada&#8217;s is, but I suspect it&#8217;s a little lopsided. Being affluent North Americans, we are prone to buying a lot of cheap stuff.<br />
The price of gas &#8212; competely unrelated to Phil and Lynn&#8217;s farm &#8212; is also causing consternation lately. The price of oil is now over US$70 a barrel, which is causing gas prices to spike again. North America still has among some of the lowest prices in the world, and we freak out when gas is over $1.00 at the pumps (in Canada, anyway). Today, the car was filled at a station priced at $1.20. $60 in total. I&#8217;ve never paid that much for gas. I have to use premium in the Mini and I&#8217;ve never paid over $45. My next fill up is going to hurt. A lot.<br />
But I have to agree with Allen &#8212; gas prices need to keep going up. Canada needs the $1.50/litre price &#8212; and higher. Those prices will drive us out of complacency and start to look at alternative sources for the wasteful energy that we&#8217;re always using. It&#8217;ll make us choose between the smaller efficient cars and the monstrosities that Detroit is still producing. If it weren&#8217;t for the fact that I need to start looking at cars like the Honda Fit or the Mazda 3 Sport (not because it&#8217;s a &#8220;Sport&#8221;, but because of storage), I&#8217;d buy a Smart car. Family is everything though.<br />
Phil and I had a conversation about how prices will eventually reset in the apple world once everyone starts buying from China. Distributors will get in the way, as they always do, and the old case of supply and demand (a.k.a. greed and price gouging) will eventually put things back in order, restoring balance to the force and ensuring that prices are approximately in competition. But it won&#8217; happen quickly, and the local farmers will still take a hit in the short term. It&#8217;s just a sad fact.<br />
While the others finished the scavenger hunt, Phil and I turned to politics for a while. I&#8217;m no expert, but I have developed an interesting memory of politics, which has formed a few opinions. Phil and I discussed Alberta&#8217;s future now that King Ralph is headed out the door, and what will become of the federal Liberal party if Bob Rae successfully wins a potential bid for the leadership. We almost missed the cue to head in for pancakes.<br />
While the outside of Phil and Lynn&#8217;s house would look appropriate in pretty much any city, the inside is pure farm house. Wooden floors cut from wide boards, country-style cupboards, benches instead of seats around the table. A very warm, homey feeling that you just don&#8217;t get with the most recent set from IKEA. All of us were crammed in the kitchen, waiting for the onset of the pancakes, which Allen had been preparing almost since we arrived. Whole wheat with sesame seeds, fruit salad, and real maple syrup. (We are in maple syrup territory, after all.)<br />
I think I ate about eight of them. Delicious, fluffy &#8212; but not too thick &#8212; and lots of fruit. Phil and I got into a discussion of making websites. (You can take the habit out of the boy, but you can&#8217;t take the boy out of the habit.) One of the neat things about working for Critical Mass is that you inevitably learn all the &#8220;right&#8221; ways about making a website, which are largely transferrable to others who operate on much smaller scales. I have no compunction about doing that, either. Best practices are aways good to hand down, especially to those who&#8217;ll never directly compete with you. It makes the entire industry better and stronger.<br />
Following the pancakes, we all ventured out for a wagon ride. This being a farm, there was a tractor and a flatbed wagon ideal for hauling things around the yard. I gather Phil&#8217;s still learning the trade, but he seems to have the idea down. The tractor moved without much difficulty, and huddled up for warmth (I neglected to bring my jacket, and brought only my fleece), we went off for a ride.<br />
Phil and Lynn&#8217;s farm is 110 acres. It&#8217;s hard to imagine a piece of property that size. The footprint of their house alone is the size of our entire property, and the house is dwarfed by the farmland. The parcel is over a kilometre in length, and about 250 metres wide (that&#8217;s a guess &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you can do the math to figure the rest out). The massive chunk of paradise cost $60k less than our tiny place in Calgary &#8212; we&#8217;re living in the wrong place. Only the south quarter is the farm area, though &#8212; the rest is all densely wooded, part of a nature preserve. Phil&#8217;s even found deer antlers out there. A beaver lodge is setting up domain not far into the forest, damming the small creeks there, and cutting down trees normally vulnerable only to chainsaws. Short stone walls define areas for long-forgotten reasons. A turn of the last century thresher rusts away amongst the trees, wheels half sunk into the ground.<br />
Lynn and Phil make the whole event educational. I don&#8217;t know if their kids are home-schooled &#8212; if so, they are in good hands. They are exceptionally intelligent and very good teachers. It started to rain as we started to head back towards the wagon along a well-rutted dirt road that leads to a sugar shack somewhere deep in the woods, hastening our retreat to the house. From there, we said our &#8220;goodbyes&#8221; and retraced our path back to Montreal, sitting in the lineup over the Mercier bridge for almost 3/4 of an hour.<br />
At least the protest is passive. It could quite easily get a lot uglier.<br />
It was almost 17:45 before we arrived at Stuart and Therese&#8217;s. Allison, their barely 2-year old daughter, is still scared of me, even when presented with a peace offering of a small teddy bear. Therese, pregnant with their next child, received chocolates. Stuart only got me. I think he got shafted out of that deal.<br />
While Allison romped around the room, the four of us chatted around the kitchen table, eating guacamole and chips, and catching up after six months of rare chatting. I miss my friends a lot. I don&#8217;t see them often, and when I do see them it never seems to be long enough. I barely saw them in August at the wedding, and wished I had spent more time with them.<br />
Things hadn&#8217;t changed too much since I&#8217;d last seen them. One of their two siamese cats had died in February. Therese is still heartbroken over the loss, which I competely understand. I still miss Spaz, and it&#8217;s been two and a half years. Siamese have a way of getting into you, and it&#8217;s hard to get them out.<br />
Dinner had been a debate, but eventually we settled on Central Pizza, about two blocks from their townhome. Stuart and I scooted quite literally around the block to pick the pizzas (two of them) and returned before they got cold. Allison dove into the olives on the vegetarian pizza while Stuart and I laid seige to the hawaiian.<br />
Allison went to bed not long afterwards, and it took a while for her to finally got to sleep. Therese and Stuart had to tag-team trips up before Allison finally dropped off like a rock. That left the rest of us to chat, eat chocolate, and recount various tales of whatever that came to mind. And we chatted about whatever until well after 23:00, when I realized that it was key for Therese and Stuart to go to bed and get some rest. After finalizing the plans for dim sum, we headed back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/04/montreal-earth-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">435</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIA Train from Montreal to Toronto</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2004 22:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via rail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/23/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Morning came early. (When your hosts have to get up early to go to work, you get up early, too.) The plan was simple: on their way to work, Therese and Stuart would drop me off at Central Station where, like when I arrived in Montreal, I would proceed to kill a couple of hours &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "VIA Train from Montreal to Toronto"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Morning came early. (When your hosts have to get up early to go to work, you get up early, too.)<br />
The plan was simple: on their way to work, Therese and Stuart would drop me off at Central Station where, like when I arrived in Montreal, I would proceed to kill a couple of hours before my train boarded (around 11:00).<br />
<span id="more-326"></span>I skipped breakfast yet again (this whole vacation thing leaves me feeling not so hungry as usual), and showered for the day. I packed up the things I had unpacked for Montreal (basically, my toiletries bag and a couple items of clothing), and waited until it was time for us to leave.<br />
Traffic in Montreal is pretty easy, at least by my standards. Other cities, such as Toronto and Vancouver, are near-nightmares in some areas. Calgary, of course, is laughable, but then I don&#8217;t drive in Calgary rush-hour anyway. It didn&#8217;t take long until we&#8217;d arrived at Gare Central. I hopped out, bade a fond farewell (it will be several months, at least, before I see them again &#8212; and next time, they will be full-bore parents).<br />
Central Station is/was the Canadian National Railway&#8217;s hub in the Montreal area, as Windsor Station was Canadian Pacific&#8217;s. I strongly suspect Central Station is a lot more recent than Windor Station &#8212; Windsor was built in the 1800s, while Central Station is more reminicent of the 1940s. It&#8217;s not the most attractive station, sadly &#8212; Gare du Palais, Toronto Union, Winnipeg Union, Pacific Central, and Waterfront are fore more appealing, at least in my eyes. But it&#8217;s a busy station &#8212; a couple of the AMT lines use Central Station as their main hub, it&#8217;s the main hub for VIA Rail east of Toronto, and Amtrak&#8217;s Adirondack train terminates at Central Station.<br />
I was rather amazed (and a bit dismayed) to find that Gare Central has no lockers. Hence, no place to put my bag away while I went off wandering. Le sigh. The thing isn&#8217;t really that heavy &#8212; about 18 lbs (according to WestJet&#8217;s baggage scale), but heavy enough that I don&#8217;t really want to lug it around everywhere.<br />
While trying to determine how to kill about an hour and a half of time, I realized that my body did in fact want to eat. I opted for what I think was a square cream cheese croissant. Odd, but still tasty. I relaxed a while, ate, and read my new book, <em>The Party Monster</em>.<br />
I eventually tired of sitting and went wandering. I headed into the various hallways that lead to the Metro, thankfully avoiding the CAW picket lines in front of CN&#8217;s headquarters (adjoining Central Station). It seems half of downtown Montreal is on strike for something. The Metro station didn&#8217;t really offer me any inspiration &#8212; I could go places, yes, but what did they offer me in the end? Deciding to head back, I realized that a map showed not only Gare Central, but also Gare Windsor. This was when I realized that they were merely a couple blocks apart.<br />
So off I went, in search of Windsor Station. But not so much for the station itself, but because like Central Station, the owning railway&#8217;s headquarters adjoined. Or rather, <em>were</em> adjoining. (Canadian Pacific relocated to Calgary back in the mid 1990s, but left offices in Montreal.) The buildings are original from the start of the CPR, and while there might not be much else to see, I had to take a look.<br />
There wasn&#8217;t much else to see. Not surprised, though a little disappointed, I returned to Central Station to await Train #61 for Toronto. It gave me a chance to buy some provisions for the trip: a sandwich, bag of chips, oatmeal chocolate chip cookie, and a bottle of Coke. Not one of them approved for my diet. But hey, I&#8217;m on vacation, like I could give a damn.<br />
The train boarded a little late, but not so much as to cause concern. Those of us going direct to Toronto and not riding in VIA 1 were herded to the sixth and last car of the train. Despite all being on one car, I managed to get two seats all to my lonesome. It&#8217;s nice when that sort of thing happens.<br />
The attendant started going through the car, informing people about the safety devices they were seated next to. Then, for reasons I don&#8217;t totally understand, she came to me and asked if I would come with her so I could learn how to open the doors. Needless to say, this was an odd thing to hear.<br />
Out of everyone in the car to receive the briefing on how to manually open the door, who gets called? Me, of course. Probably the only person in the car with an iota of railroad experience outside of the staff, who has any inkling about how this stuff works, or would want to find out in the first place.<br />
The standing rule, so I gather, is that one of the passengers must learn how one opens the LRC car doors so people can get out. It&#8217;s fairly simple, actually. Slide open the door, and flick a switch on the ceiling that will keep it from closing. Then go to one of the doors (one facing away from any other tracks, if at all possible), pull back on a lever that releases the door, pull the door open, and pop the catch over the stair well.<br />
I sat there, half-giggling to myself about the odds of that sort of thing happening to someone like me. I would suspect it&#8217;s pretty rare. The train pulled out and headed out from the labyrinth beneath Montreal and out into the daylight. You wanna talk odds? Complicate the above with what I saw next&#8230;<br />
Another VIA train, backing into Gare Central. The locomotive on the train was none other than VIA #6403 &#8212; the CBC locomotive (see the <a href="/index.php/category/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/">CBC Television 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train</a>), still dressed in it&#8217;s 50th Anniversary glory. The only thing that could have been weirder is if it had been the locomotive on my train (as it stands, we had one of the newer P42s).<br />
The train passed by Point St. Charles. Somewhere out there was Stuart and Therese&#8217;s house. I couldn&#8217;t see it, of course, but I knew it was in there, somewhere. If only that could be used as a flag stop on the line so I could get on or off. Oh well.<br />
Our first stop was at Dorval Station. While a physically separate station from the AMT station (VIA runs on the CN line, whereas the AMT runs on the adjacent CP line), it still marked my entry into Montreal &#8212; not counting the airport, of course. It would now mark my exit.<br />
As the train exited Montreal, I became acutely aware of something men are not supposed to have &#8230; biological clocks. Visiting with Stuart and Therese, and being witness to their impending parenthood, really began to make me think more about the things that might be lacking in my life. I&#8217;m 31. By this time, my mom was a mother. By this time, ancient humans were considered to be well into old age. I could actually hear my clock ticking. It&#8217;s hard to admit, but I want kids.<br />
The train was soon rocketting off towards Toronto. We had stops at Cornwall, Kingston, Guildwood, and Toronto Union. It would keep the trip blissfully short (only about four and a half hours, though we ended up coming in a little late) and quite nice. Although I was on the sunny side of the train, it wasn&#8217;t hard to catch a nap as the train&#8217;s motion lulled me into submission. Thankfully, the sound of bratty children didn&#8217;t let me sleep well. [Insert sarcasm here.]<br />
The train pulled into the Toronto Terminal Railway system, and suddenly everything was familiar again. Although I&#8217;ve only pulled into Toronto Union from the east a bare two or three times, the view is equitable with the one from the highway. You don&#8217;t miss much.<br />
Hopping off the train, I speedily bypassed the slower-walking passengers, and hurried into the GO Concourse to purchase my ticket to Oakville. A train was leaving in about 10 minutes, which was timed perfectly for me. Once on the train, I called mom and let her know that I was on my way. She would meet me at the Oakville station about 30 minutes later, and take me to Cathy and Craig&#8217;s.<br />
Upon arrival, I had a beer thrust into my hand. Now normally, I wouldn&#8217;t complain about that. However, it was Carlsberg Light. There are two problems with this. First, it&#8217;s a mega-brewery beer, which just their own nature, I don&#8217;t like. They generally have little flavour and aren&#8217;t worth the water they were brewed with. Second, and much more obviously, IT&#8217;S A LIGHT BEER. Blech.<br />
We chatted a while, discussing my trip, Montreal, Therese and Stuart (and Kicker), before heading out to dinner. Craig had to work that night, so we needed to go out before it was too late for Craig to eat. We opted for Milestone&#8217;s, which was part of the way there for him, and not too far for us.<br />
I haven&#8217;t had a meal at Milestone&#8217;s in years, and haven&#8217;t had their hot artichoke and spinach dip in years more. Theirs is the only one I like. Most other companies dump in huge gobs of sour cream or cream cheese, which ultimately ruins the flavour of both the artichoke and spinach.<br />
We had to be out of the restaurant by 21:00, as there was a private party taking over. Near as we could tell, it was a staff party. There didn&#8217;t seem to be anything more special to it. But I&#8217;m far from complaining &#8212; staff always needs to be recognized for the work they do. If you don&#8217;t recognize staff, you get disgruntled staff. And that&#8217;s not a good thing at all.<br />
Craig went off to work, Cathy and I returned to her place, and mom went home. And so began part three of my vacation. I hope the rest of this week goes nice and easy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Touring Montreal, Schwartz&#039;s Deli</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2004 22:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/22/touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept not as long as the previous night, but enough to feel suitably rested. I wanted to make sure that I didn&#8217;t sleep too long &#8212; this was my last full day with Therese and Stuart, and I didn&#8217;t want to waste it. We had originally planned to do the breakfast thing, perhaps find &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Touring Montreal, Schwartz&#039;s Deli"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept not as long as the previous night, but enough to feel suitably rested. I wanted to make sure that I didn&#8217;t sleep too long &#8212; this was my last full day with Therese and Stuart, and I didn&#8217;t want to waste it.<br />
We had originally planned to do the breakfast thing, perhaps find a nice dim sum in Chinatown, or make use of one of the French cafes. But after a bit of discussion, we realized that it wasn&#8217;t breakfast that we were particularly interested in, it was lunch. And not any ordinary lunch, we needed one of Montreal&#8217;s legendary delis.<br />
<span id="more-325"></span>I skipped breakfast, not feeling particularly hungry. So I probably fed some urgency at finding a deli &#8212; and not just some bagel place. Stuart knows Montreal well enough to find the Jewish quarter (traditionally, the area known as The Plateau), and it wasn&#8217;t long before the streets were lined with bagel shops. I could feel my mouth beginning to water at the mere thought (I <em>love</em> Montreal-style bagels, they&#8217;re far better than their poor cousin, the New York-style). But I wasn&#8217;t alone in the desire to find an actual deli.<br />
This brought us to the King of all Montreal delis &#8212; Schwartz&#8217;s. This establishment has been feeding Montreal since the early 1930s (even has what appears to be original equipment &#8212; a coal-fired stove for cooking beef and liver steaks). It has legendary smoked meat. Gerry even had one of his relatives bring some to his wedding (see [[Gerry and Sam&#8217;s Wedding in Ottawa, VIA Train to Toronto]]). We decided that it was something to try (and they had alternatives for Therese).<br />
The first thing that truly surprised me about Schwartz&#8217;s was the size. Despite being a legend in the biz, the place is tiny. There are about 10 &#8220;rows&#8221; of tables, jutting out from the north wall. The south wall is the take-out counter and the coal-fired stove. The west side is the entrance, and the east side is the kitchen. This place is so tiny that you don&#8217;t wait for a table &#8212; you wait for a seat. You don&#8217;t care who sits next to you.<br />
Language here has no meaning. French, English, Yiddish, Spanish &#8212; the staff seems to speak it all without blinking an eye. The menu is in French and English, but assumedly, you know what you want when you come to Schwartz&#8217;s. It took only moments for me to figure out what I wanted. If you go into a Montreal deli, unless you don&#8217;t eat beef, you order a smoked meat sandwich.<br />
I was given three options. And they&#8217;re not &#8220;small&#8221;, &#8220;medium&#8221;, and &#8220;large&#8221;. The options are &#8220;lean&#8221;, &#8220;medium&#8221;, and &#8220;fatty&#8221;. I have to admit a brief hesitation as I mentally drooled at the thought of the fatty, but opted for the medium instead. Stuart and I went the same, but Therese went for the turkey (though we thought that it might be the stuffed chicken; she didn&#8217;t seem to care, it was still good).<br />
The sandwiches are so large that it usually falls apart, the top slice of rye falls to one side. A side of coleslaw is optional, but you really do need to eat something than just a sandwich (Therese had a salad, Stuart and I endulged our cabbage desire). The sandwich was massive, messy, and magnificient. I was tempted to even go so far as to say it made the trip to Montreal all the more worth it. But let&#8217;s be honest &#8212; IT&#8217;S A SANDWICH. Okay, yes, it&#8217;s as close to sex on a slice of bread that you can get, but it&#8217;s still just a sandwich.<br />
After our brief lunch (you don&#8217;t laze around Schwartz&#8217;s after you&#8217;re done eating &#8212; there&#8217;s usually a large number of people waiting to take your seats), we stopped into a nearby drugstore to pick up a couple of things, and then headed on our way.<br />
Not that we really had a way we were going in. We had no specific plans of any kind, and driving around more or less aimlessly became something to do. We went through the Latin Quarter, past the National Theatre School (where our friend Kathryn went to hone her stage management skills), down through the Gay Village, down to the river and through Vieux Port, before finally ending up at Central Station.<br />
I had to pick up my train ticket for tomorrow. Mostly because I couldn&#8217;t remember what time the train was at.<br />
We drove around blindly for a while longer before a supreme need to use a toilet (one of Kicker&#8217;s favourite games is to play &#8220;Bladder Bounce&#8221;, much to Therese&#8217;s discomfort) took precedence. The nearest thing at the time that seemed to offer us some respite was none other than the Montreal Forum.<br />
But this ain&#8217;t your father&#8217;s Forum. If you&#8217;ve been living under a rock (or rough equivalent thereof), you probably haven&#8217;t heard that the forum is no longer the home of the Montreal Canadiens &#8212; they now play at the Bell Centre. The Forum, their former home, was completely gutted and rebuilt into an entertainment complex. The inside is now dominated by AMC movie theatres, a three-story sports bar, a two-storey Future Shop, and a couple of restaurants.<br />
Centre ice, or what is supposedly centre ice, still exists, though it is paint on concrete. Still, it is the main item that harkens to the Forum&#8217;s glory days at the Mecca of Montreal hockey.<br />
After making use of the facilities, we went to the AMC theatres to see if there was anything we wanted to see that was playing at the time. Sadly, not much, though we thought if stuck around a while, something might strike our fancy. So to help pass the time, we raised a nearby dessert shop.<br />
Did I mention that this trip is going to be abject *murder* on my diet?<br />
A trip through Future Shop proved one thing: doesn&#8217;t matter what province you live in, the store is still a bit of a pain in the ass. You always have those dorky customers who insist on cranking the volume on the ghettoblasters to see how loudly they can play hip hop without it distorting. Like you&#8217;re going to use them for a house party&#8230;<br />
The Forum was loosing appeal. Being across the road from (yet another) mall, we decided to pop over to see what we could find. Specifically, the still-illusive white cap for Kicker&#8217;s take home outfit. A visit to three stores, including the Zeller&#8217;s, proved unsuccessful. So back to the Forum.<br />
Nothing had changed insofar as the movies were concerned. By that point, we&#8217;d just decided not to bother, and instead, headed off in search of something for dinner.<br />
We ended up at the Loblaws store I&#8217;d seen from the AMT train on my way in on Friday. While Therese rested in the car, Stuart and I picked up two salmon filets, a cod filet, half a dozen scallops, a clump of asparagus, a carton of rice, some waxed paper, and a couple of other things we needed. Tonight, I was cooking dinner.<br />
The coolest part was when we went to the checkout. This store is one of the newer kind that has the self-checkout system. It&#8217;s pretty neat, really. You pass your items under the scanner, and it automatically punches it in as a purchased item. I couldn&#8217;t get the scan to work for the life of me, so it was up to Stuart to ring it all in. If gave me a chance to figure out how they prevent theft using this system &#8212; there&#8217;s a scale on the bags to see if the item you just scanned is put inside, or if something else goes in that wasn&#8217;t scanned. Kinda sneaky, if you ask me.<br />
Food in hand, we returned home. Now if you&#8217;re wondering what I was making, the recipe is pretty simple: seafood pinwheels. I got this from watching &#8220;Good Eats&#8221; on the Food Network. Take the filets (deboned and deskinned, if not already done), and lay them out on a long piece of waxed paper, salmon side-by-side but overlapping, with the cod at the bottom. Then lay the scallops (skewered together) at the head of the salmon. Spice with pepper, salt, and dill (or other spices of choice). Using the waxed paper to help, roll into a very right roll, making sure the waxed paper doesn&#8217;t get rolled inside.<br />
Okay, so it&#8217;s not *that* simple. But it&#8217;s not that hard.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t my best attempt, I must admit. But since it was my first try, I can&#8217;t be totally faulted for not doing a perfect job on it. I&#8217;m not a chef, after all.<br />
The rest of dinner was quite simple: a multigrain rice and a wonderful blanched asparagus that Stuart whipped together (out of one of the Best of Bridge cookbooks). Therese was relegated to &#8220;poor person&#8217;s mimosa&#8221; (gingerale and orange juice), while Stuart and I enduged in a little red wine. Over all, a very tasty meal, even if the fish was a tad messy.<br />
Following our repast, we watched the weekly episode of <em>Star Trek: Enterprise</em>, which I had missed earlier in the week. This was the kind of show that the three of us had watched together since we were in high school. It if wasn&#8217;t <em>Star Trek</em>, it was the <em>X-Files</em>. Over 15 years, it was one of many things that had brought us all together.<br />
Therese went to bed shortly afterwards. Stuart and I continued chatting and watching movie trailers until after midnight. At that point, the both of us had to go to bed. Stuart has to work tomorrow.<br />
And I have a train to catch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/touring-montreal-schwartzs-deli/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">325</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shopping in downtown Montreal</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/shopping-in-downtown-montreal/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=shopping-in-downtown-montreal</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/shopping-in-downtown-montreal/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2004 22:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/21/shopping-in-downtown-montreal/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept nearly 12 hours. I woke up sporadically, hearing the odd noise of running water and cats playing. Simply put, though, I was too damn tired to care. I hadn&#8217;t slept that well in ages. I woke up in time for lunch, which was convenient, since both Therese and Stuart were ready for additional &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/shopping-in-downtown-montreal/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Shopping in downtown Montreal"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept nearly 12 hours. I woke up sporadically, hearing the odd noise of running water and cats playing. Simply put, though, I was too damn tired to care. I hadn&#8217;t slept that well in ages.<br />
I woke up in time for lunch, which was convenient, since both Therese and Stuart were ready for additional sustinence themselves. It was the first weekend since Thanksgiving that they didn&#8217;t have specific plans, since they didn&#8217;t have to worry about something having to happen or having to do. No plans, no predefined ideas, no nothing. And it was driving them nuts to not have specific things to do.<br />
<span id="more-324"></span>Maybe I planned it that way, I don&#8217;t know. Certainly, I lucked into arriving into a situation where they had more or less finished everything they had to do. All previous guests had been looped into shopping sprees or painting or something specific. But not me. I was the first. And knowing it or not, I was going to suck them into my vacation world, whether they liked it or not.<br />
We ended up at the malls downtown, the same ones I had been running around the day before. This time, I didn&#8217;t have to deal with the 18.5-pound back slung around my shoulder &#8212; just two friends I had to tag along with.<br />
Now, there were some things they wanted to do. First, they needed the &#8220;take home&#8221; outfit for the baby. This is the first outfit the baby wears when it comes home for the first time. For someone not in the position of being a parent, I have to say that the fuss seems a bit much (even Stuart had his &#8230; concerns about Therese&#8217;s mission), but I will also freely admit that given similar circumstances, I could see myself being as sentimental.<br />
Therese&#8217;s still about six weeks away from the Big Day. At this point, she claims she&#8217;s well into the &#8220;Nesting Stage&#8221;, which means she needs a lot of things. Actually, I debated that statement with her. Are they &#8220;needs&#8221;, or &#8220;wants&#8221;? Cornered, Therese did what Therese does best. &#8220;Wants&#8221;, yes &#8230; &#8220;needs&#8221;, all depends on perspective.<br />
I can hardly argue with that.<br />
I did a little shopping of my own, specifically two copies of the special edition of <em>Star Trek VI: The Undiscovered Country</em>. Why two copies? One for me, and one for them. I used to watch <em>Star Trek</em> and <em>X-Files</em> with them religiously, so this was a partial &#8220;thanks&#8221; for letting me stay, and also so I could watch it that night.<br />
Fleeing from the mall, we went over to the Atwater Market in search of things that we could potentially have for dinner. Marche Atwater, like most markets of its type, houses many different vendors under its roof. Several butchers, cheese shops, even a seafood seller. But nothing that particularly appealed to us. Wandering through the market, we ended up at the local IGA to stock up on groceries before heading home.<br />
Pizza ended up the meal of choice, though it took nearly an hour to make up our minds. If there&#8217;s one thing about Montreal restaurants, it&#8217;s that you can get nearly every major kind of fast food from one place. I&#8217;ve never seen a menu that offers full choices of Italian, Greek, Chinese, Thai, and sushi before. It&#8217;s a little odd, but quite interesting.<br />
Pizza, beer, and Captain Kirk. Can it get any better? Well, of course it can. Only a die-hard Trekkie would say &#8220;no&#8221;, but then, I&#8217;m not a die-hard Trekkie. Stuart and I both fell asleep during the movie, if that gives you any indication.<br />
Pregnant Girl gave us no end of grief for that little transgression.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/shopping-in-downtown-montreal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">324</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying to Montreal to visit friends</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2004 22:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/20/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I honestly couldn&#8217;t wait for 5:00 to come this morning. Today is the start of my first break longer than a long weekend in almost a year. I&#8217;ve been working away on my job, barely taking time off, slaving through one of the hardest Christmases I can remember, and wondering whether anyone&#8217;s really noticed. I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Flying to Montreal to visit friends"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I honestly couldn&#8217;t wait for 5:00 to come this morning.<br />
Today is the start of my first break longer than a long weekend in almost a year. I&#8217;ve been working away on my job, barely taking time off, slaving through one of the hardest Christmases I can remember, and wondering whether anyone&#8217;s really noticed.<br />
I won&#8217;t even mention my lengthy list of non-work activities.<br />
<span id="more-323"></span>I&#8217;ll be quite happy to leave my job, my house, even my life behind in Calgary for a week and forget for a while that I&#8217;m Geoff Sowrey and have any responsibilities whatsoever. I&#8217;m *so* looking forward to this.<br />
I arrived at the airport just after 6:00 and immediately got into the WestJet check-in line. Despite all of Air Canada&#8217;s attempts to shut down the smaller airlines, WestJet continues to pack &#8217;em in. Some people were off to Vancouver, some off to Edmonton, and some off to Toronto. Others to parts unknown. Me? I was off to Montreal.<br />
Why Montreal? Well, as you might recall (see [[Friends move away to Montreal]]), my friends Therese and Stuart moved there a few months back. Since then, they&#8217;ve established themselves, bought a home, and prepared for the arrival of their first child (currently monikered &#8220;Kicker&#8221;) who appears at the end of March.<br />
The flight was easy. I&#8217;ve flown far too much for my own good. I&#8217;ve flown around North America, across the Atlantic, and across the Pacific. After a flight to Japan, flying a few hours to Hamilton and a bare hour to Montreal after that is practically a milk run.<br />
I spent most of the flight (both legs) reading. Normally, it&#8217;s magazines, specifically my favourite &#8212; Wired. This time was different. This time, I was reading <em>Clan of the Cave Bear</em>, loaned to me from Kristen. It&#8217;s a fascinating novel, describing the life of a cro-magnon woman who comes to live with neanderthals, and the differences they face with the integration of the woman into their clan. I&#8217;m not sure how accurate it is from an anthropological perspective, but it is still quite an interesting read.<br />
But then, I&#8217;ve always been a fan of science.<br />
I arrived at Pierre Trudeau International Airport (previously known as Dorval Airport) about 10 minutes ahead of schedule, despite running late coming into Hamilton. As soon as I was out in the lobby, past security, I pulled out my cell phone to let Stuart know that I was in town, and was in the process of finding my way downtown. Dorval is on the isle of Montreal, but is quite some distance from the downtown core.<br />
Finding the bus stop for the #204, and finding the change I needed for bus fare ($2.50), I awaited the arrival of the bus to take me to Gare Dorval. There, I would either switch to another bus (the #221) or to an AMT train, either of which would take me into downtown Montreal and the Metro system.<br />
Dorval Station is a bare kilometre from the airport. You can see it clear as day, and it looks like you can walk from one to the other (it&#8217;s a little difficult because there are no sidewalks that I can see, and it&#8217;s mostly highway in that area). It took me a few minutes to figure out what my best options were, but luckily for me, it turned out that the train was the fastest way to get downtown. And the system allowed me to upgrade my bus ticket with a mere $0.75 addition ticket.<br />
If only Calgary were that intelligent.<br />
Montreal is an interesting place for languages. It skates the thin line of the two official national languages, and incorporates countless others. It is without a doubt the most multicultural city in Canada, at least in my opinion.<br />
What brought this into clear view was when I was trying to buy my new ticket. It was because a man at the top of the stairs, awaiting the train, suddenly asked:<br />
&#8220;Excuse moi &#8212; quelle heure et il?&#8221;<br />
For those of you who don&#8217;t know French (or even the Quebecois dialect), this is how you ask what time it is. This beckons back to my days of taking French in school. And despite many years of not taking French, I was able to immediately reply:<br />
&#8220;Deux heures et huit minutes.&#8221;<br />
I was beside myself. How the heck was I able to do that? How the heck was I able to even remember how to interpret what he&#8217;d said? Either way, I wasn&#8217;t about to object, because it meant that for a few precious moments, it meant that someone who spoke only French thought I could understand them.<br />
Hey, it happens.<br />
The train arrived about 30 minutes later. Montreal&#8217;s AMT system had originally inherited most of its equipment from GO Transit &#8212; the locomotives and the original passenger cars. To be honest, that&#8217;s what I expected to see. So needless to say, I was a tad disappointed to see a Genesis-class locomotive, and a set of somewhat flashy passenger cars.<br />
I boarded the train and took a set along the bench (the car has seats of two on one side, and a long bench on the other), with the six other people on the car. At that time of day, the train was mostly empty.<br />
I was reminded of my last train trip into Montreal when I was with the CBC (see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Montreal]]). I even tried to spot landmarks and figure out where I was. But before long I realized that I wasn&#8217;t on the rail line I thought I was on. VIA trains run on the CN line, whereas AMT trains seem to run on the old CP line.<br />
Before long, the train reached Gare Lucien L&#8217;Allier, which is the terminus for the AMT line I was on. From there, I would have to turn to the Metro. But first, I needed to find a bathroom, which proved a lot more difficult than I had thought &#8212; the one near the station was closed due to renovations.<br />
I ended up walking through the Bell Centre, the new home for the Montreal Canadiens in search of a toilet. The path wound around the south side of the Bell Centre and then down a hall that looked like a walled-in side of a railway station. Funny that, because it *was* a railway station &#8212; Gare Windsor.<br />
Windsor Station was CP&#8217;s Montreal hub for 100 years. It was where countless thousands started their journeys west into fame, fortune, ignaminy, and/or poverty. Today, it is little more than a room attached to the former headquarters of Canadian Pacific (some offices are still there, but there is little else), and trains haven&#8217;t arrived at that station since Lucien L&#8217;Allier took over at the terminus of the line, and the Bell Centre severed the corridor connection.<br />
Returning to Lucien L&#8217;Allier, I found my way deep into the labyrinth of stairwells to the Metro tunnels. My instructions, having arrived in downtown, where to go to the Peel station, and find a way to kill time for a few hours. I love the Metro, and I love riding it, but killing that much time isn&#8217;t easy.<br />
Reading. After patrolling the stores of three malls that interconnect downtown, that&#8217;s pretty much all I could find to do in the last hour of waiting. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, that&#8217;s fine with me. But I did feel a little peculiar sitting on a bench while the security staff walked by, wondering what I was up to.<br />
Stuart called about 17:15, letting me know that he was on his way to pick up Therese, and would be picking me up not long after. I gathered my things and headed up to the Famous Players theatre (on the upper floors) to await the call. I would meet up with them across the street, throwing my bag in the back seat of their Jetta, and taking off down St. Catherine into chaos of downtown Montreal.<br />
We chatted about my trip in, but before long settled into the regular banter that has defined the last 15 years of our relationship. We continued this as Stuart weaved in and out of traffic, and through neighbourhoods until we arrived at their townhouse, in the Point St. Charles area of Montreal.<br />
Their home is a new development, built in a two-unit construction to look and blend in with the older units on either side. It&#8217;s exceptionally nice. Two storey, plus basement, three bedroom, two bathroom, all open-concept on the main floor. The basement has a den/office, and a workshop the previous owner used to completely rebuild the interior (for example, all the doors, while standard-size, are custom-built). The decoration is immaculate. I have to say, I was envious. I wish my place looked that good.<br />
Therese is eight months pregnant at this point, which was a huge part of the reason I wanted to come out. I wanted to see them one last time before they become parents. I needed to have that moment with them, and just them. This far along in her pregnancy, Therese gets tired a lot more easily (when you pack on 40 pounds of kicking parasite, let&#8217;s see how well you do). This evening, Therese felt well enough that we could go out and explore a little.<br />
We ended up in the Verdun area, which is &#8220;west&#8221; of where Stuart and Therese lives. We were scooting along Wellington St., looking at the various restaurants that Therese and Stuart had eyed for a few months, but hadn&#8217;t had time to visit. So finally, we ducked into one place, which we discovered was Peruvian, and endulged ourselves in food and conversation.<br />
And it felt good. Not just that I got to eat for the first time in hours, but because I got to spend time with my friends, whom I love dearly.<br />
Not ending the evening too early, we headed over to the local video store and rented <em>Spellbound</em>, which is a documentary of the American spelling bee championships (an odd thing to have, to be sure). A couple six-packs of beer certainly made Stuart and I feel a lot better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">323</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
