<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>manitoba &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/manitoba/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 04:55:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 8</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-8/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-8</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-8/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 04:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were up perhaps a bit earlier than I&#8217;d thought we&#8217;d be up, but I&#8217;d also forgotten we were stopping in Redcliff to visit Marnie and her kids. Thankfully, Grandpa had enough sense to jumpstart us for the day. That didn&#8217;t necessarily mean we were moving particularly quickly, but at least early enough to make &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-8/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 8"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were up perhaps a bit earlier than I&#8217;d thought we&#8217;d be up, but I&#8217;d also forgotten we were stopping in Redcliff to visit Marnie and her kids. Thankfully, Grandpa had enough sense to jumpstart us for the day. That didn&#8217;t necessarily mean we were moving particularly quickly, but at least early enough to make a difference.<br />
That, and two cups of coffee, of course&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2723"></span>Although Swift Current was inundated with fog when we got up, the sun had burned its way through before we hit the road for Alberta. The sky didn&#8217;t look threatening, but there was enough doubt there to suggest we might see some rain along the way. As I stands, the only things that hit the windshield today were bugs.<br />
A curious thing I&#8217;ve noticed about Saskatchewan, and I&#8217;d love to know the reason for it. East of Swift Current, there are lots of little towns scattered along the Trans Canada (keeping in mind that the Trans Canada more-or-less follows the route of the Canadian Pacific mainline, which was how people got out here in the first place way back when). West of Swift Current, however, there ain&#8217;t much. It&#8217;s almost a void. It could because the terrain transforms from grasslands to scrublands, and eventually to badlands. Even parts of Alberta were settled only when Canadian Pacific built a water viaduct through Brooks to bring water to an otherwise desolate area.<br />
A little over two hours after leaving Swift Current, we passed across the border into Alberta. Oddly enough, I felt really good about that, even though we still had over three hours to get to Calgary. We were still far from home.<br />
We shot through Medicine Hat, and turned into the town just east of it called Redcliff. Mommy&#8217;s friend Marnie lives there, and she&#8217;d dropped a hint (through Facebook &#8212; I wonder if it&#8217;ll still be around when you get around to reading this) that we should stop in on our way back. Marnie was pregnant with her third baby at the same time Mommy was pregnant with Choo Choo, so there was some desire to meet the newborns.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883914753[/flickr]<br />
Monkey, we didn&#8217;t see much of you. You played with Marnie&#8217;s two older daughters. Sadly, I think this officially turned you into a little girl, too. Until now, Mommy and I have done our best to try and butch you up. You have a grand total of two dresses &#8230; one of which was actually a gift for Choo Choo, but you fit it (until recently, anyway). But you discovered the joy of dress-up, and ran around as a princess. You were beyond happy, so much so I&#8217;m certain you were sad to leave. But we had to get back to Calgary in time to pick up Asia from her kitty hotel.<br />
Grandpa had told me on the way out that the worst stretch of the entire Trans Canada Highway is the part between Calgary and Medicine Hat. At the time, I&#8217;d disagreed, having an albeit vague memory of Medicine Hat to Swift Current. I drove the final stretch home, and I have since apologised to Grandpa &#8212; he&#8217;s right, that three hours is terribly long and dull. It&#8217;s flat, featureless, nearly devoid of any towns, and the only real sense of you moving is the endless stretches of telephone poles and/or electrical towers.<br />
Oh, and something else I noticed. When you see a dimensional load on trucks in Saskatchewan, it&#8217;s farm equipment. In Alberta, it&#8217;s oil equipment.<br />
We screamed into the Rainbow Pet Centre around 16:15, and retrieved our poor lonely kitty. We did our best to shoot across Calgary in building rush hour traffic, and arrived home just after 17:00. Monkey, you were quite content to stay outside and read, rather than go in the house. Though when you did, you really wanted to just get into your own bed. I don&#8217;t blame you in the slightest.<br />
We had our first (mostly) home-cooked meal since leaving town a week ago, and it felt good to sit at our own table.<br />
On a positive note, this was an excellent first family trip. It wasn&#8217;t an easy one, by any means, but both of you kids did very well in the car for such long times. It&#8217;s not easy being stuck in those seats with so little to do. (Well, for Monkey, anyway. Choo Choo, you tended to sleep. Which is exactly the right thing.) We&#8217;ll have to see how we do these in the future, as I&#8217;m not sure we&#8217;re going to be going such a long distance again for a while. I&#8217;m of the opinion that the trek to the homestead should wait until you&#8217;re both quite a bit older, and would appreciate it a lot more.<br />
Like, 10 years or so&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2723</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 7</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-7/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-7</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-7/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 03:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the nice appearance and newness of the hotel, the Canalta has stiff beds that are really meant for only one person &#8212; any movement is felt by the other person on the bed. The pillows are massive and overstuffed (please, hotels, understand that not everyone wants these &#8212; please provide a few thin pillows), &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-7/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 7"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite the nice appearance and newness of the hotel, the Canalta has stiff beds that are really meant for only one person &#8212; any movement is felt by the other person on the bed. The pillows are massive and overstuffed (please, hotels, understand that not everyone wants these &#8212; please provide a few thin pillows), and the air-conditioning in our massive room simply made things awkward. It would appear that neither Mommy or I slept well.<br />
Monkey, you slept like a log. We had trouble waking you up.<br />
<span id="more-2722"></span>Today was relatively uneventful. Saskatchewan, as those who have travelled across it will also likely tell you, is filled with farms, the odd grain elevator, a few lakes, and not a heck of a lot else. (I should add that the eastern part of Alberta is much the same, and actually a little worse.) Our trip was from Moosomin in the east, to Swift Current in the west. Like I said before, we&#8217;re keeping it light in the interests of not overdoing it.<br />
It had rained last night, and was still spotty as we headed out onto the highway. A few times the rain came and went, and it remained mostly cloudy until we were well past Regina. The storm looked pretty nasty, and apparently did a number to Regina, which we saw when we arrived. Our major stop was Regina, incidentally, for lunch. We ate near Victoria Mall, at a Mr. Sub (we&#8217;re swearing you off sandwiches for a while, Monkey &#8212; you just ain&#8217;t eating them anymore).<br />
[flickr]photo:4883910951[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883911943[/flickr]<br />
We then went off in a very painful search for coffee. Tim&#8217;s won&#8217;t apparently do, so we tracked down what I can only take to be the single Second Cup in the entire city. Which of course, is in a mall. Downtown. Right off a pedestrian area. With no place to park.<br />
With coffees in hand, we headed back to a playground we&#8217;d seen on the way in so you could burn off a little steam before we hit the road. You ran around quite happily in what apparently was known as Core Park, until it was time for us to leave. You were asleep not long after hitting the ring road. Choo Choo, you were out pretty much the same time.<br />
We drove to Largest Extant Species of the Deer Family&#8217;s Lower Mandible (Moose Jaw), where we had to stop for gas. Monkey, you woke up. Surprisingly, Choo Choo, you did not. We stayed only long enough to get gas, a snack, some juice, and we were gone. We were in Speedy Creek (another name for Swift Current) just around 17:00. The first thing we did was all go for a swim.<br />
Dinner was at a place called &#8220;TNT Family Restaurant&#8221;. We&#8217;ve discovered that eating at anything listed as a &#8220;family restaurant&#8221; is generally a bad idea. The iced tea was powdered and the pasta sauce tasted like Chef Boyardee. The service, at least, was familial.<br />
Sleep well, my pretties. Tomorrow, we go home!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2722</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 6</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-6/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-6</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-6/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 03:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were all slow to rise today, but we made quick work of breakfast. You said goodbye to your Great Uncle Ken and Great Aunt Marilyn before we headed to the car. Our first stop was to drop off Granny at the airport. She wasn&#8217;t driving back with us, which I take to be a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-6/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 6"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were all slow to rise today, but we made quick work of breakfast. You said goodbye to your Great Uncle Ken and Great Aunt Marilyn before we headed to the car. Our first stop was to drop off Granny at the airport. She wasn&#8217;t driving back with us, which I take to be a very wise decision on her part.<br />
Then we headed back down to Portage, which is one of the main roads in Winnipeg. After a stop at Timmy&#8217;s for a coffee recharge, we set our sights for Saskatchewan and our overnight stop at Moosomin.<br />
The question was what were we going to do in between&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2721"></span>The answer is &#8220;not much&#8221;. Our only stop was in Brandon. Which is actually grossly understating the stop in general. While I would have been happy to stop on the highway (Choo Choo, you were extremely hungry at the time, and were very intent on making sure there was no doubt in anyone&#8217;s minds of that fact), Grandpa found a restaurant on the GPS further in town. While I admit I&#8217;m gaining a general dislike of restaurant suggestions on that thing, the fact that we went into town is proving to be very handy.<br />
Lunch was at a place call Cranberry&#8217;s Family Restaurant. Overall, your basic average restaurant, nothing fancy by any means. Very strict on their menu, too. Mommy asked for a tuna melt, which was technically feasible since they had other melts on the menu and were offering a tuna salad sandwich, but there was just no leeway at all.<br />
We decided to look for a park that had a playset so you could get out and run around a bit, Monkey. You&#8217;ve been really cooped up, and when you run around, you&#8217;re generally happier. We found one between 13th and 15th St, a couple blocks north of Victoria. At first, we saw only the park. Then the playset. Then we saw the water park. Given the 35-ish degree temperature, this seemed like the perfect thing for you to go running around in.<br />
No sooner had we set up at a picnic table that an ice cream cart came by. Talk about your fortuitous timing! But you only had a little bit of the fudge bar before you wanted to go running about.<br />
It took a fair amount of coaxing on my part, but I finally got you to run into the water, Monkey. The park itself was pretty simple: a red ring that sprayed, two big blue poles that jetted upwards, a purple candy cane-shaped pole that sprayed downwards, and some sprayed right out of the ground. Kids ran from spray to spray, as they all seemed to turn off and on in a slow cycle. Eventually, you were running in and out, too.<br />
Shortly after 15:00, we started to load back up, and headed out of town. You were both asleep before we got to the Trans Canada again. From there, our trip went quietly until we got to Moosomin. There, we checked into the Canalta Hotel, a very new establishment &#8212; so new, the road is still gravel. Granny had spotted it on our way out from Whitewood, and I&#8217;d remembered the word &#8220;waterslide&#8221;. It&#8217;s a working hotel, meaning you get work crews in there a lot. That was obvious from the room we got &#8212; three queen-sized beds.<br />
After charming the heck out of the clerks at the front desk, you and I went swimming, Monkey. Unlike the Holiday Inn in Winnipeg, the Canalta&#8217;s pool is cool. Not &#8220;cold&#8221;, but it didn&#8217;t take long for you to start shivering. And, like me, you don&#8217;t like hot water pools, so I couldn&#8217;t get you to warm up in the big pool. So, instead, I took you on the waterslide.<br />
The waterslide is clearly meant for kids, because neither I or one other daddy could fit very well inside it (though we did manage to get down pretty easily). I&#8217;ve also determined with absolute certainty that I need new swim trunks for waterslides &#8212; the ones I have only seem to stick, so we didn&#8217;t get a lot of speed. We went down together many times before you went on your own, with the help of the other daddy (I waited at the bottom to catch you). You came down feet first, but on your belly. Although you would later said the waterslide was scary because it was all dark, you also said it was a lot of fun!<br />
We had dinner at the Red Barn Restaurant, which is one of the oddest restaurants I&#8217;ve eaten at in a long time. The outside makes it look like a diner-style restaurant, the interior almost makes it look like a higher-end trendy restaurant (and the menu isn&#8217;t far off), but you order at it like a McDonald&#8217;s. My food was good, so I couldn&#8217;t slag the quality, though Mommy said her pasta wasn&#8217;t so good.<br />
[flickr]photo:4884509604[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883909521[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884510496[/flickr]<br />
Bed comes early. Tomorrow&#8217;s another long day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2721</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 03:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2720</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were supposed to go out to a lake near the Ontario border today, but Mommy and I threw up the white flag and declared us all &#8220;done&#8221;. We need a break. Monkey, you&#8217;ve been very patient being trapped in the car seat for hours upon hours. We&#8217;ve heard &#8220;I want to go home&#8221; a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were supposed to go out to a lake near the Ontario border today, but Mommy and I threw up the white flag and declared us all &#8220;done&#8221;. We need a break. Monkey, you&#8217;ve been very patient being trapped in the car seat for hours upon hours. We&#8217;ve heard &#8220;I want to go home&#8221; a few times, but we suspect it&#8217;s more about wanting to get out and run around than anything else. (It&#8217;s been proven pretty much every time we&#8217;ve let you out.)<br />
As for you, Choo Choo &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not really sure what to make of your thoughts. Aside from the fact that you&#8217;re only 4.5 months old, there&#8217;s also the consideration that, unlike your sister, you don&#8217;t sleep a lot. So we&#8217;re never really sure if you&#8217;re generally unhappy with being in your seat, tired, or hungry. I suspect at some level you&#8217;re probably all three at the same time.<br />
Still it was absolutely necessary that we take the day off and not really go anywhere. So we went to The Forks.<br />
<span id="more-2720"></span>I&#8217;d first seen The Forks back in 2002, when I was in Winnipeg with the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/">CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train</a>. I&#8217;d been quite impressed with them at the time, not the least of which was when I learned of their railway heritage. After learning that the Manitoba Children&#8217;s Museum was there, The Forks suddenly became my favoured destination. Mommy felt we should go to a place called Tinkertown, which although further away, had far more to do. In the end, it came down to the fact that Tinkertown didn&#8217;t open until noon.<br />
Grandpa and Granny came with us, having decided that they would not go to the cottage at the lake, either. We drove quickly downtown, and found a parking spot right next to the entrance. We all walked around inside for a bit, before we went over to the museum. Here we divided. Choo Choo, you went with Mommy and Grandpa back into the market to look around; Monkey, you came with Granny and I into the museum. You literally ran over to the train first.<br />
The Manitoba Children&#8217;s Museum has a train inside it. A real one. Ex-CN 9161, and what looks like a passenger/mail combine, which were (and still are) common on the Winnipeg-Churchill run (which this train was representing). The train no longer works, of course. The museum is closing in September for a rebuilding, and I hope they keep the train &#8212; it really is a nice centrepiece, and as a railfan, it would be terrible to lose it. I suppose if worse comes to worse, the railway museum isn&#8217;t far away, and I imagine they&#8217;d like to have it.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883891171[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883892581[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884496572[/flickr]<br />
You ran around the train, although you were initially scared to go in the locomotive&#8217;s cab for some reason. Then you were off down to the wall of long pegs that you can make impressions with. I found a set of tubes that ran on a blower: you put in a shower loofa in one end, it ran through the tubes (depending on how you set the valves), and it popped out of one of three places. That didn&#8217;t hold your interest as long as I thought it would, Monkey.<br />
[flickr]photo:4884497796[/flickr]<br />
Around the corner was a big tree that you could climb inside, and come down a built-in slide. You did this repeatedly, and almost made friends with some of the other kids while doing it. Then it was back to the train for a while, when you suddenly realised you needed to pee. You&#8217;re getting very good at letting us know when you need to go, kiddo &#8212; you&#8217;re almost totally free of diapers (except at night).<br />
We had lunch at the market. While waiting for Choo Choo, Mommy, and Grandpa, a busker drew a quick sketch of Monkey with her fingers in her mouth. We offered a donation, and he drew another one of Choo Choo sleeping in the stroller. You had a berry crepe, Monkey. Not quite as good as the one you regularly eat at the Farmer&#8217;s Market back home (in my opinion, anyway), but you didn&#8217;t seem to mind.<br />
I had a roti. The last time I had a roti, I still worked in Toronto. This was 1997. It was at a place either called Coconut Grove or Crystal Grove (I can&#8217;t remember for sure). It was on Dundas Road just east of Yonge Street. The site is now the location of Dundas Square. My friend Mike introduced them to me, and I&#8217;d been on the lookout for roti ever since. I was surprised to not readily find any in Vancouver, and I haven&#8217;t really been searching too hard in Calgary. So this was a treat for me, and it was very good. Although I will say that goat generally tastes better than beef in a roti.<br />
After lunch, Monkey, you and I went back to the museum for a while. We passed by a First Nations group that was dancing in a circle nearby, beating their drum and singing. You&#8217;ve never seen this before, so we spent a while watching. It was very, very hot (even hotter than on the coast of Costa Rica, as I recall) so we took refuge in the shade of one of the sculptures there.<br />
You played with the pegs, ran around the train, played with the chalk, but soon it was time for us to go back. You didn&#8217;t want to leave. In fact, you put up a bit of a fight. I suspect that was mostly due to exhaustion. I suspect this because you fell asleep before we were out of downtown Winnipeg, and slept another two hours back at the hotel. It was your first proper nap since we left home.<br />
We all went swimming when you both woke up. We splashed and played. Choo Choo, you seem to like the water &#8212; a lot more than when you have a bath, lemme tell ya. We swam for about an hour before we packed up to go have dinner.<br />
Tomorrow, we begin our long trek home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2720</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 4</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-4/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-4</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 03:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wow, I wasn&#8217;t kidding, was I? It was a long day. A really, really, really long day. We were up and running and gone by just after 8:15 this morning, trucking our way up to an RV park just north of downtown along Main Street, right next to Shooter&#8217;s Golf (which I am convinced is &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-4/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 4"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wow, I wasn&#8217;t kidding, was I? It was a long day. A really, really, really long day. We were up and running and gone by just after 8:15 this morning, trucking our way up to an RV park just north of downtown along Main Street, right next to Shooter&#8217;s Golf (which I am convinced is named and designed after elements of Happy Gilmore). We met up with the rest of the family who were along for the ride, and then planning to meet at the ESSO station in Eriksdale, headed north.<br />
Granny drove with Great Uncle Ken and Great Aunt Marilyn so she &#8220;would have all-new material&#8221;, and likely because after a while, you just can&#8217;t stand being around us Sowreys any longer.<br />
<span id="more-2719"></span>At Eriksdale, we stocked up on coffee and a couple of snacks, and then were off again in search of an unnamed and otherwise unmarked access road (I couldn&#8217;t even call it a rural road), which would lead us towards the old homestead site. We were working off the collective memory of Grandpa, and his brother (your Great Uncle Paul), and a couple of others who&#8217;d been to the site before. In addition, we were also looking out for an old teapot, hung there some 30 years previous by your Great Great Grand Uncle Frank, who would have also been on this trip, but sadly only passed away the day we left home.<br />
I suppose in many ways this is an auspicious trip, though you kids won&#8217;t understand that for a few years to come; for you in particular, Choo Choo. You are the fifth generation of Aicken (the fact that you have my last name is mere legality), and this is your heritage. Choo Choo, you&#8217;re the most recent direct-line descendant of your great-great grandfather.<br />
We almost didn&#8217;t make it. About 3/4 of the way there, we found the road had been flooded by the rising of Stewart Lake, likely as a result of all the rain Manitoba has been receiving this year. We weren&#8217;t sure how deep it was, or even it we could ford it. Thankfully, members of the Webster family, who now farm the area, showed to us that the water was really quite shallow, and even regular city cars wouldn&#8217;t have a problem. Even then, quite a few people took to the back of Paul&#8217;s pickup truck, which was the first across the 500-600 metre stretch. We followed soon after.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883833731[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883835409[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883837265[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883838769[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883850197[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884453948[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883852187[/flickr]<br />
Rounding a few corners, and fording another flooded section, we found the teapot, <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=51+04.332'+n,+98+06.145'+w&amp;sll=51.045,-114.057222&amp;sspn=0.436883,1.017609&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=51.07174,-98.102975&amp;spn=0.013645,0.0318&amp;t=h&amp;z=15">right where Frank had left it</a>. It&#8217;s rusted considerably over the years, but it&#8217;s still recognisable. You&#8217;d never be able to boil water in it, though.<br />
[flickr]photo:4884457622[/flickr]<br />
Despite being prepared to be eaten alive, especially by deer flies (I think this scared you most of all Monkey &#8212; you&#8217;re a bit of an insectophobe right now, except for ants), we saw virtually nothing. All of us, except maybe myself (I can&#8217;t really tell) were bitten. Choo Choo has a nasty one on her wrist, but doesn&#8217;t seem to notice.<br />
The ground was wet and very marshy, and the near-constant plodding of cows turned the wet soil into a very unstable and icky mess. Still, we managed to get into the homestead site, and Grandpa gave us the tour as he understood it. He even explained a story of some stone markers they&#8217;d once found, and now believe to be the grave of an unnamed sibling to Frank, who likely died as a baby. Given their location &#8212; roughly 12 kilometres from anything &#8212; it&#8217;s amazing they lost only one child, and seven lived to ripe old ages.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883857153[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884465580[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883867401[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883868507[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884472618[/flickr]<br />
A little further down the road, we came to a corner, where Grandpa said we would find the northeast marker of the original homestead land. There&#8217;s a survey pole there, but the plot marker seems to be buried under considerable amounts of grass and mud, and none of us had brought a shovel to find it. A stand of poplars, which thrive throughout the area, offered a fair amount of shade from the heat. It seemed like as good a place as any for a picnic.<br />
[flickr]photo:4884473714[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884481818[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883872429[/flickr]<br />
After lunch, a group headed further up the road to find the site of the old schoolhouse (gone probably almost as long as the homestead). The five of us (Granny was still with Ken and Marilyn) started towards Teulon, where we would have a big ol&#8217; family dinner. It seemed like a great opportunity for both of you kids to get some sleep &#8212; you didn&#8217;t get any yesterday, and it showed.<br />
At Eriksdale, I was more-or-less forced from the van to get coffee for Mommy and Grandpa. He drove down a sideroad for a couple of kilometres to keep you both asleep, then turned around to pick up the coffee and me. Then it was off again towards Teulon.<br />
We had a pre-dinner party at Dennis and Daphne&#8217;s house, which was a wonderful setting: a huge yard, and lots of space for you to run around in, Monkey. You played with Rachel, Hunter, and Micah, as well as ran around with some of the bigger kids. Hunter shared all her dolls with you. You found a Woody doll (from Toy Story, currently one of your favourites) and were thrilled. Mommy and I were thrilled, too &#8212; we got to have a drink!<br />
[flickr]photo:4884483986[/flickr]<br />
Just after 18:00, we all took off into central Teulon (basically, right next to the long-abandoned CP Arborg subdivision line), and had dinner at the Teulon Rockwood Centennial Centre. This was the best meal we had since leaving home, and possibly the best we&#8217;ve had in a month! (Well, for us, Choo Choo &#8212; you&#8217;re still breastfeeding at the moment.) Afterwards, Monkey just played with all the other kids.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883885379[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883886517[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884491006[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4884491758[/flickr]<br />
We returned to Dennis and Daphne&#8217;s for a short prayer service (led by Grandpa), while you kids ran around. Sadly, that&#8217;s when you got whacked in the head, Monkey, and I lost my temper with Micah (after telling him to put the badminton racquets down before he did hit someone). It wasn&#8217;t pretty after that, and I was fairly relieved to be leaving after making an ass of myself.<br />
The drive back to our hotel was about an hour. We had to stop at one point because Choo Choo simply couldn&#8217;t wait to get back to the hotel for her nightly feed. Monkey, you passed out (as usual) just before we got to the hotel. We unpacked quickly and got everyone to bed. I think we all passed out before our heads hit the pillows.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2719</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 3</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-3/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-3</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 03:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At least we didn&#8217;t have to get up too early today, Choo Choo, and you let us sleep a bit longer. That helped rest away the many kilometres behind us. We hit breakfast, also at the Chicken Chef (there ain&#8217;t a lot of option in Whitewood), and then loaded up once more for our push &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-3/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 3"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least we didn&#8217;t have to get up too early today, Choo Choo, and you let us sleep a bit longer. That helped rest away the many kilometres behind us. We hit breakfast, also at the Chicken Chef (there ain&#8217;t a lot of option in Whitewood), and then loaded up once more for our push to Winnipeg.<br />
It took a lot longer than I thought to get here.<br />
<span id="more-2717"></span>We kept our stops few. Beyond the stop at the Manitoba border (where we should have turned our watches forward, but forgot), we stopped only in Brandon for coffee and our sandwiches for lunch, and in Portage la Prairie to eat our lunch. The last stop was far too short, as we had very little time left to get to Winnipeg before our evening event. That was a shame, since Island Park is truly a wonderful place for a picnic, mosquitos notwithstanding. You got to play there a bit, Monkey. Maybe on our way back, you&#8217;ll get a chance to play a bit more.<br />
[flickr]photo:4883824203[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883824281[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4883825887[/flickr]<br />
It was after we left Brandon that you had your first real problem with the trip, Monkey. You&#8217;ve spent nearly half of the time since we left Calgary in your car seat. Sometimes, it&#8217;s hard for a little Monkey to be patient. You&#8217;ve been so patient on this trip, honey, but eventually you have to hit a limit. You were, shall we say, upset. It took a few minutes for you to calm down so that we could drive again.<br />
You didn&#8217;t have a nap today, either, which would lead to your second problem &#8212; a real full-scale meltdown at bedtime. It just reinforces the need for you to sleep during the day. I&#8217;m not sure how much you&#8217;ll sleep in the days to come with all the activity that&#8217;s planned, but hopefully we&#8217;ll find a way.<br />
With some direction from Grandpa&#8217;s cousin (and the man who had married Mommy and I), we found our way to our hotel in Winnipeg, the Holiday Inn on Pembina Highway. It was only when we got inside that I realised that it was the same hotel I&#8217;d stayed at in 2002 when I was last in Winnipeg, with the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/">CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train</a>. I&#8217;d had a drink in the hotel&#8217;s lobby bar after a hard day, just before our worst day of the tour.<br />
Mommy suggested that I have a shower. Almost right afterwards, we all hopped back in the Sienna again (sometimes, I&#8217;m sure it feels like we never get out of the car, kids) and drove out to the Immanuel United Church on Kimberley Ave. in eastern Winnipeg. There was the first of three Aicken-Campbell family reunion events. This is important for you two, since you&#8217;re descended from the Aicken family, and this year is the 100th anniversary of the Aicken family in Canada. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re out here.<br />
Choo Choo, you became the Belle of the Ball, being handed from person to person without so much as a single sound. Monkey, you made near-instant friends with Rachel, who is your third or fourth cousin (we&#8217;re not really sure) and followed her around almost like a little puppy. You also made friends with Micah, Mary&#8217;s little boy, and the two of you squealed as you rolled around on the carpet.<br />
Dinner was simple, yet scrumptious: skewers of lamb and chicken, salad, and potatoes, all from a local Greek restaurant. You had KD, Monkey &#8212; the elders had enough sense to know you weren&#8217;t going to eat Greek.<br />
Tomorrow is another big day. We&#8217;re off way up north to find the old Aicken family homestead, which is where much of the Canadian branch of the Aicken family began. Sleep well, I think it&#8217;s going to be a long one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2717</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 03:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Choo Choo, I don&#8217;t think you yet have a real understanding of time. And certainly, you don&#8217;t understand the idea of letting Mommy or Daddy sleep in. Today, I&#8217;ll admit, that wasn&#8217;t something we would fault you for, since we all had to be up early. Grandpa wanted us on the road by 7:00. That &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Choo Choo, I don&#8217;t think you yet have a real understanding of time. And certainly, you don&#8217;t understand the idea of letting Mommy or Daddy sleep in. Today, I&#8217;ll admit, that wasn&#8217;t something we would fault you for, since we all had to be up early. Grandpa wanted us on the road by 7:00. That meant getting up, dressed, fed, packed, and loaded.<br />
And as Mommy and I have noticed, neither you nor your sister, Monkey, really understand the idea of &#8220;quickly&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2716"></span>While you kids might have slept well, none of we adults did. Some hotels seem to have a bizarre need to cram pillows as full of stuffing as possible, as to utterly negate the ability to sleep easily. (I&#8217;ve slept on rocks that were more comfortable.) Breakfast was a nice buffet, though shockingly short of bacon, in my opinion. We packed up, loaded up, buckled in, and hit the road.<br />
The trip out of Medicine Hat was fairly quick, and we were at the Saskatchewan border fairly soon. We stopped for a quick picture, and then continued eastward. The land got flatter and flatter, and we soon hit the terrain where you could see your kids running away for days running in a straight line. (Thankfully, Monkey was buckled in her seat, and Choo Choo can&#8217;t even crawl yet.)<br />
We drove past countless tiny little towns until we felt a need to stop for a quick break. Morse is a tiny town, founded in 1912. The Lutheran Church appears to not have been used in a couple of decades (even the power lines are cut), and the school closed sometime in the last decade or so. The original school, built when the town was founded, is now a museum. And an eclectic museum it is&#8230;<br />
Monkey, you got to play here. You ran out across a wide field &#8212; formerly the school yard &#8212; and to an older, but still well-loved collection of swings and slides and half-buried towns. Long freight trains announced their passing from kilometres away, their horns echoing across the open spaces, and then flying across the plains between the playground and Reed Lake.<br />
[flickr]photo:4865508483(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866129210(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4865516025(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866136886(square)[/flickr]<br />
We stayed a while, long enough for you to get worn out a bit, Monkey, before we returned to the highway. More small towns, even a Potash mine, heading to Moose Jaw. There we stopped for lunch (although it took us a while to figure out where we were stopping) at the McDonald&#8217;s. Not my first choice, but was something we determined would be quick and easy &#8230; and it had a playplace, which you were actually a little scared of.<br />
[flickr]photo:4866141346(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866138448(square)[/flickr]<br />
I took over driving from Grandpa, who had driven until that point, and we continued east. I had hoped to put in a bit of a surprise and take a detour, but apparently I had forgotten an earlier conversation where we&#8217;d already agreed to such a detour. We turned southeast onto Highway 39, heading for the small town of Rouleau.<br />
For those of you not living in Canada (or for Canadians living either without cable, or under a rock), the CTV network used to air a show a couple of years ago called &#8220;Corner Gas&#8221;, which was set in the fictional town of Dog River, Saskatchewan. The real location of Dog River is Rouleau, which is about 50 kilometres southwest of Regina. It&#8217;s the pure definition of small-town Saskatchewan: founded by the railway, with a few brick buildings, and a big grain elevator. The buildings built for Corner Gas &#8212; the gas station and the adjoining Ruby cafe, actually sit about a kilometre up Highway 39 from the townsite (which played into one of the show&#8217;s plotlines about Corner Gas actually being out of town). The grain elevator still bears the name &#8220;Dog River&#8221;.<br />
We stopped for pictures, of course. Then we went into Rouleau for a quick run around. We saw the Dog River Howler, and the &#8220;Municipal Police Station&#8221;, which is actually a cafe. The inside of the cafe was an attraction all its own. Rouleau gets up to about 500 visitors a day during the summer; when Corner Gas was being filmed, it was over 5,000. And those people signed the walls. The plethora of signatures is astounding. Even more astounding are the maps with their pins. I was amazed to see people from all over the world having visited &#8212; especially from Canada, and moreso the prairies.<br />
[flickr]photo:4866143836(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4865527087(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866149210(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866152128(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866154978(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866158014(square)[/flickr]<br />
We scooted back north to Regina, and continued eastward to Whitewood, arriving a few minutes after 17:00. Whitewood is another railway town, like so many in the prairies, and still hosts the Canadian Pacific mainline. The Whitewood Inn was our stop, and was also Grandpa and Granny&#8217;s stop when they crossed the prairies 20 years ago. As we would find out, not much about the Whitewood Inn had changed in those 20 years. To call the place a &#8220;dive&#8221; would almost be considered an insult to dives around the world.<br />
[flickr]photo:4865543565[/flickr]<br />
(A bit unfair. In truthfulness, the Whitewood Inn is really not too bad a place.)<br />
We all dressed to jump in the indoor pool, only to be thankfully thwarted at the last second. As it turned out, the pool was undergoing a maintenance cleaning, and was full of acid. You were highly disappointed, Monkey, and I think we all wanted to go for a swim after such a long drive.<br />
We ate dinner at the Chicken Chef restaurant in the hotel. It was far from fancy. The chicken had clearly been cooked a couple of hours earlier and kept warm in an oven, the yellow kernels had clearly been corn once upon a time but had been cooked beyond their capability to retain flavour or texture, but you at least liked the chicken fingers.<br />
At least we had adjoining rooms, which really only seemed to allow Monkey to run between the rooms well past your bedtime. I took a little walk after you went to bed, mostly to take a picture of the grain elevator. It seemed to me that the single biggest thing to do in Whitewood was drive donuts in the gravel parking lot of the Esso station, before blasting down the road.<br />
[flickr]photo:4866163824(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4866166780(square)[/flickr]<br />
Tomorrow, we&#8217;re off to Winnipeg.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2716</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 03:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manitoba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winnipeg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, kids, today was a slow start to our cross-prairie adventure. The morning was otherwise ordinary, rising and having breakfast and dressing. But then I climbed into the car and took Asia away to her hotel for the next week. I know this caused a little concern for you, Monkey, because you were worried about &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Great Family Roadtrip 2010, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, kids, today was a slow start to our cross-prairie adventure. The morning was otherwise ordinary, rising and having breakfast and dressing. But then I climbed into the car and took Asia away to her hotel for the next week. I know this caused a little concern for you, Monkey, because you were worried about her.<br />
Grandpa and Granny arrived after lunch. We loaded up the minivan (which had a fair amount more cargo space than Mommy and I thought there might have been), loaded up you kids, and hit the road for a town called Medicine Hat.<br />
The beginning of our first great family road trip.<br />
<span id="more-2718"></span>It&#8217;s a short beginning, I confess. We&#8217;ve got a long way to go. Winnipeg is over 1,000 kilometres from Calgary (note to those of you who don&#8217;t know Canadian geography: it&#8217;s far less than half the distance across the country &#8212; yes, Canada really is that big). You can do it in a day, driving for around 13 hours straight. But we&#8217;re not going to subject everyone to such a long day. That&#8217;s a little on the cruel side.<br />
So we&#8217;re making a few stops. Our first is in Medicine Hat. Our next is almost an entire province further away in Whitewood, Saskatchewan. It&#8217;s going to be our furthest drive since Monkey was born. We&#8217;re not too sure how it&#8217;s going to go, since having you both locked in your seats will be a bit of a challenge. The third day is the trip out to Winnipeg.<br />
Today&#8217;s trip was, well, a good start and a good test.<br />
[flickr]photo:4866116798[/flickr]<br />
We left town going south to 22X, which is a little different than most people, who take 16th Ave N (which is the Trans Canada Highway through town) heading east. 22X continues into a provincial highway, and connects back to the Trans Canada near Bassano. I think if we feel the need to go east again, I might suggest it &#8212; for a drive, it is far more interesting than taking the Trans Canada right out of Calgary.<br />
Once you get to Bassano, though &#8230; well, it gets kinda dull. We stopped at the Esso station there, mostly because Choo Choo was hungry and made sure everyone knew. Monkey had a chance to run up and down the aisles of the convenience store. I&#8217;ll admit that it worried me a little, since we were barely over an hour into the journey, and stopping another 12 times on the way to Winnipeg didn&#8217;t fill me with hope.<br />
[flickr]photo:4866119190(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4865503147(square)[/flickr]<br />
But we persevered, and made it all the way to Medicine Hat. We drifted through town until we got to the east side, and found our way to the Medicine Hat Lodge, a four-floor hotel casino. Checking in proved a little difficult, as there was a considerable amount of difficulty in the staff understanding the term &#8220;adjoining&#8221;. Granpa managed to get the problem sorted out, and soon we were checked in, and then eating a long-overdue dinner.<br />
Our our meal, Mommy and Choo Choo headed to bed, while I took Monkey to the pool with Granny and Grandpa. We didn&#8217;t get to splash for very long, unfortunately, as it was already well past your bedtime, Monkey, and I wasn&#8217;t sure that taking you on the waterslide was a great idea. Still, you had fun. Then we went back upstairs to our rooms.<br />
You slept with Granny and Grandpa, Monkey. You were very good, and did as you were told.<br />
Tomorrow should be an interesting, albeit long day. I hope we all enjoy it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/08/the-great-family-roadtrip-2010-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2718</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
