<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 03:15:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>10th Anniversary of the CBC 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/09/10th-anniversary-of-the-cbc-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=10th-anniversary-of-the-cbc-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/09/10th-anniversary-of-the-cbc-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 03:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ten years ago today, I boarded a shuttle bus from a hotel in Vancouver, and met some of the most amazing people I&#8217;ve ever had the pleasure &#8212; nay, honour &#8212; to know and work with. (Believe me, I&#8217;ve worked with a lot of people over the years. This does not come lightly.) It was a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/09/10th-anniversary-of-the-cbc-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "10th Anniversary of the CBC 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ten years ago today, I boarded a shuttle bus from a hotel in Vancouver, and met some of the most amazing people I&#8217;ve ever had the pleasure &#8212; nay, <em>honour</em> &#8212; to know and work with. (Believe me, I&#8217;ve worked with a lot of people over the years. This does not come lightly.)<br />
It was a chance of a lifetime &#8212; something I knew then, and greatly appreciate now. A chance to connect with thousands of fellow Canadians, and experience our nation in a now-unique way. The memories were fond when it ended, and they&#8217;re stronger and more wonderful with every new day.<br />
I&#8217;ve had people ask: Would I do it again? Damn right, I would!<br />
<span id="more-3146"></span>That first day was a weird one. I was an outsider. I was brought in as a contractor, helping my friend Brenda (although, let&#8217;s be honest, here &#8212; she helped <em>me</em>) with a project that was dropped on her lap. She needed someone to spend (at the time) two months on a train, taking pictures, writing journals, and shooting video. Who the hell was she gonna find crazy/dumb enough to do that?!<br />
(I owe Brenda huge, still, to this day. I mean, there&#8217;s just no other way to express the debt of gratitude that she would trust me with something such as that.)<br />
So I boarded that bus, knowing no-one, realising very quickly that what was about to unfold was going to be a challenge unlike any I&#8217;d seen (and I&#8217;ll be damned lucky if I ever see it again). We unloaded at the Pacific Central Station, walked through to the platform, and prepared ourselves for &#8230; well, the unknown.<br />
We didn&#8217;t know what was going to happen. We didn&#8217;t know if we&#8217;d all get along. But we had to. For over a month, we&#8217;d live in cramped quarters (often in the train itself), work under extreme deadlines, learn to love each others habits and quirks, make fun of each other, laugh, cry, tell stories, lend a helping hand, and share some very heavy loads. We had a crash course in friendship.<br />
The thing I find most amazing is that everyone put up with me. First, the outsider &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t with the CBC. I was an unknown to nearly every group. The teams were fairly set: News, Sports, CBC Kids, the Boutique, and of course the ever-present and highly-awesome technical crew who made sure shit got done. (I was tapped with being responsible for New Media; my &#8220;team&#8221; was myself and one other, who changed three times during the course of the journey.) I was in everyone&#8217;s faces with my camera, and wrote extensively about almost everything we did (the CBC wisely cut down some of my blog posts, which periodically had an air of &#8220;Trans-Canada Pub Crawl&#8221; about them). Everyone put up with my incessant obsession with trains.<br />
The video, thankfully, was turned over to someone else with considerably more experience.<br />
We survived remnants of tropical storms, killer mosquitoes, diverted trains due to derailments, bears (in the railyards), trains (in the railyards), cold showers, intolerant visitors, periodically hostile local &#8220;assistance&#8221;, virulent viruses that took out nearly everyone at least once, broken feet, hangovers (see above note about the pub crawl), and lack of sleep. It created the kind of camaraderie you can&#8217;t explain to anyone who wasn&#8217;t there. There&#8217;s no analogy, no metaphor that can come close.<br />
At the end, I think we all realised that we were in a mystical fog, a crazy daze that comes only from doing truly wonderful things. And on that fateful night, when the last call bell sounded and the lights came on, we all realised &#8212; very horribly &#8212; that our near-fantasy was over, and we had to return to a harsh reality that we had conveniently forgotten for a while. It&#8217;s a moment that rings as clear today as it did nearly 10 years ago &#8230; complete with the tears.<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/">We all met up a year later</a>, at the Elephant and Castle in downtown Toronto. We reminisced, we laughed, (we drank,) and many of us wished we could do it all over again.<br />
Nine years later, I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;m not the only one.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
For more details, should you be so crazy as to want them, I suggest <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/?orderby=ID&amp;order=ASC">reading a bit more</a>. Like, a <em>lot</em> more.<br />
And, of course, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/tags/cbctv50thanniversaryviarailtrain/" target="_blank">there are plenty of pictures</a>.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/09/10th-anniversary-of-the-cbc-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3146</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#039;ve been logging on the railroad</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/06/ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/06/ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2006 03:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/12/17/ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2006 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Sometimes, you get those strange little burps in life that turn into the greatest of experiences. Ones that you don&#8217;t pass up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/06/ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I&#039;ve been logging on the railroad"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite>[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2006 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.]</cite><br />
Sometimes, you get those strange little burps in life that turn into the greatest of experiences. Ones that you don&#8217;t pass up for anything &#8212; not for all the challenges you might face or things you might lose.<br />
In late summer of 2002, the CBC needed an unusual person. They needed a computer geek. They needed a writing geek. They needed a photography geek. And they needed a true rarity, a train geek: Someone who knew the difference between a U-1-f or a F40PH2 rolling down the tracks; someone who could determine where he or she is in the Prairies by reading railway mileposts, someone who&#8217;d love being on a train for a month.<br />
I was that geek.<br />
<span id="more-3668"></span>The CBC was planning to celebrate 50 years of television and had created a travelling exhibit that would voyage from the Pacific to the Atlantic. Trains, of course, have been used that way before. But this trip would be different because it would also be appearing on the internet. For one month, while living on the CBC Television 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, I&#8217;d be responsible for all things technical while keeping track of the events in words and pictures. My journals were posted to the CBC&#8217;s website almost daily, to showcase the experience to the country and the world.<br />
The vision had been to take the best of the CBC Museum in Toronto and roll it across the country. Two baggage cars held the museum. But they also held other things we wanted to show Canada: CBC Sports, Newsworld, the CBC Shop, and the new kid on the block, CBC.ca. Twenty-eight of our staff handled event management and the other exhibits, leaving me and one other person to run the computers.<br />
My internet work had four criteria:</p>
<ol>
<li>It had to be fast;</li>
<li>It had to be simple;</li>
<li>It had to represent what was online;</li>
<li>And, here&#8217;s the kicker &#8212; it had to work without actually using the internet.</li>
</ol>
<p>Long before the days of Wi-Fi, we weren&#8217;t going to have continuous access to the World Wide Web &#8211; at least not good enough access to allow nine computers to find a connection. And certainly not from places like Biggar, Sask., or Campbellton, N.B. Actually, London, Ont., wasn&#8217;t easy either, now that I think of it.<br />
So we decided to cheat, a bit. If we couldn&#8217;t connect to the CBC website, we decided to take chunks of it and copy it onto our computers so we could simulate the experience for visitors to the train. Not as easy as it sounds when you have to display a complicated, database-driven piece of work like the CBC Archives site.<br />
Our deception went largely unnoticed. Everywhere the computers were set up, people were surfing to their hearts&#8217; content. (And making off with free mouse pads and pens, but I digress.)<br />
The only place where our substitution was really noticed was when we were mobbed by a few hundred school kids on a field trip in Winnipeg. A bit young for the typical CBC demographic but, hey, they seemed enthusiastic.<br />
Within mere seconds, they had flipped out the keyboards we had hidden under the tables and were hacking their way into what they thought was free access to the World Wide Web. Little did they know they were trapped on a non-existent network. They left almost as fast as they arrived once they&#8217;d learned that the computers were not, in fact, online. Who knows what interesting things we would have found on the monitors if there had been an internet connection?<br />
Winnipeg was one of our hardest events: lots of people visiting a small space, all trying to do the same thing at once. In Montreal, we ran into the tail end of tropical storm Isidore, which effectively washed us out of our outdoor event at Le Vieux Port. (Rain and computers don&#8217;t mix very well.) In Moncton, the power went out for several blocks around the train station, shutting down most of the exhibits yet by some twist of fate, the electricity to the New Media exhibit continued unaffected. And there were the hoards of mosquitoes that descended upon us in Melville, Sask., as the sun set &#8211;no amount of clothing or bug spray could fend them off.<br />
Though I wrote daily journals about all of these happenings, they didn&#8217;t always appear online at the touch of a button. Sadly, the technology wasn&#8217;t where the CBC (and I) needed it to be. Even the newest technologies of the new millennium barely allowed me to connect half the time on the road, including one near-panicked last-second-before-losing-signal upload as the train departed Edmonton. Southern Ontario was usually OK; the Prairies were not. There was no signal through most of the Atlantic Provinces, and I swear there are no internet cafés between Quebec City and Halifax!<br />
And then there was the writer&#8217;s biggest fear: was anyone actually reading this stuff? But validation came in the most unlikely of places.<br />
Due to an organizational gaffe, when the train rolled into Toronto, the New Media exhibit ended up shunted into a dark corner of Union Station, away from everyone else during the meet and greet event. Let&#8217;s just say the visitors weren&#8217;t streaming in &#8212; no one knew where we were.<br />
So imagine my surprise when I met Emily, a young woman who had travelled from Hamilton for one reason &#8211;to meet me. Emily had come (with her fiancé) to thank me for the journals. Emily is visually impaired. She&#8217;ll never see the white-capped Rockies, the endless horizon of the Prairies, or the glint of the Northern Ontario lakes.<br />
But she told me that things I had written on the website allowed her to see what I saw, do what I did.<br />
Humbled barely scratches the surface. Shocked is putting it mildly. It taught me that what I was doing did matter. Even if it was just to one person, it mattered. That was enough for me.<br />
That experience changed the way I wrote. I thought more about what I was seeing and how to express it, bringing my experiences to others not fortunate enough to go where I was going. And if it takes a few extra words, then so be it.<br />
Today, I still write journals. My blogs don&#8217;t appear daily but the locales certainly have been exotic, including remote places like Kazan and Ulan Ude, Russia; Ulaan Baatar, Mongolia; and Xi&#8217;an, China.<br />
Times have changed since my adventure by rail. If the CBC were to run the museum tour by train again now, we&#8217;d find the wireless internet a little easier to use, at least where cellular technology allows for high-speed data connection. And now there are even internet-enabled VIA Rail trains that would solve all our problems for us.<br />
I look back at the experience and wonder how we did it. Little did any of us know what we were getting into. We boarded as strangers in Vancouver and left Halifax 30 friends richer and thousands of encounters wiser. We&#8217;d go our separate ways, and all we&#8217;d have are the memories of what we did.<br />
But it won&#8217;t be soon forgotten. The journals still exist online, as do the pictures. The internet has a long memory, and with luck will still be around when it comes time for CBC New Media to celebrate its own 50th anniversary. And I plan to be there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/06/ive-been-logging-on-the-railroad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3668</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 22:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/10/04/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend, I visited southern Ontario. Even though I&#8217;ve only just left, it almost feels like I was never even there. A few weeks back, Critical Mass announced (to the employees) that it was in the process of pitching a very large client (see [[Friends: Visiting and moving away]]). And no, I still can&#8217;t tell &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend, I visited southern Ontario. Even though I&#8217;ve only just left, it almost feels like I was never even there.<br />
A few weeks back, Critical Mass announced (to the employees) that it was in the process of pitching a very large client (see [[Friends: Visiting and moving away]]). And no, I still can&#8217;t tell you who it is.<br />
Anyway, at the time, there was the great expectation that I&#8217;d be coming out to Toronto to help interview people and (ultimately) help set up the team in the Toronto office &#8212; assuming that we won the work.<br />
<span id="more-300"></span>About two and a half weeks ago, though, I found out that I wasn&#8217;t going after all. I was quite disappointed, since I&#8217;d actually been looking forward to helping with the groundwork.<br />
What happened? Well, as you might recall, there was the opportunity for me to move to Toronto for about two years for this particular client. (You might remember this from a previous journal entry.) I had a big decision to make &#8212; to go, or not to go.<br />
This was a decision I did not make lightly. In fact, I had so much trouble trying to make a decision that I couldn&#8217;t make one at all. There was no clear benefit to staying in Calgary, and no clear benefit to going to Toronto.<br />
And before you think about it, the decision-making process began before I met Erin, and was finally decided with Erin not being a significant factor. In fact, it was the company that finally made my decision, when I asked it where it felt it wanted me most. The general consensus was to keep me in Calgary.<br />
This is why I had to buy my own way to Toronto this weekend. But why this weekend? Two reasons: 1) I hadn&#8217;t seen my sister or brother-in-law for almost a year, which isn&#8217;t easy; and 2) because the CBC 50th Anniversary Train crew were holding their first year anniversary.<br />
I&#8217;ll come out and say, for the record, that the CBC reunion was the one thing that really got my heiny in gear to flying out east. I hadn&#8217;t seen these people in almost a year (except for Angela and Tracy &#8212; see [[CBC documentaries at the Glenbow Museum]] &#8212; and Julie and Enza in early June), and living in Calgary left me feeling very separated from the rest of them.<br />
Besides, Amy and Stefani were refusing to take &#8220;no&#8221; for an answer.<br />
Friday, 3 October was a complete blur (not that this entire weekend hasn&#8217;t ended up that way). I awoke at 5:00, showered, dressed, drove to the airport, checked in, fell asleep during the flight, got picked up at the airport, went to Cathy&#8217;s house long enough for a couple of beers before getting on the train to Toronto Union, almost sprinting down the street to CBC headquarters to meet with Stefani, and then bolted over to the Elephant and Castle to start the party.<br />
Stefani was the first CBC crew member I saw that day. I had been staring at the trophy case, waiting for her to come down. Suddenly, there was a &#8220;Geoff!&#8221; from behind me, and there she was.<br />
It was two days shy of a year from the last time I&#8217;d seen Stefani. Nothing had changed. She had the same great smile, the same joyous laugh, and the same great conversation. Already, I felt like the train hadn&#8217;t really ended.<br />
When we arrived at the Elephant and Castle, we weren&#8217;t the first. There was already one person waiting for us &#8212; Richard, the bass player with the band. The last time I&#8217;d seen Richard was in Ottawa (see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Ottawa]]), not long before he suffered an aortic dissection &#8212; the same disease that killed John Ritter. Richard (obviously) survived, owing to being extremely close to a major hospital at the time.<br />
We moved into the backroom where we would meet everyone, and started chatting. For a while, it was just the three of us. But as 17:00 rolled around, more and more people started to show up. Chris was the first, followed soon after by Tracy and Angela. Gerry and Bill C. appeared soon after.<br />
That&#8217;s about where the accuracy of my memory starts to break down. Exactly who appeared in what order is a bit fuzzy, even more so when you ask what order they left in. Needless to say, I was having a good time.<br />
Neil and Julie both appeared at the same time, and stayed about as long &#8212; not even 10 minutes. Neil had to run to be with his family, and Julie had a wedding. Analisa was around quite a bit longer. Roger, thankfully, hadn&#8217;t gone to Halifax yet, so was able to drop by before going home. Emma, despite her own personal hell, burst into the room like she&#8217;d always been there, and had to run a short time later. Bill S. would stay to the end, as would Amy when she finally arrived. Cliff, whom none of us thought would come, came for a brief while, about long enough for Rob W. to remember who was Cliff and who was Geoff (apparently, we look too much alike).<br />
Admittedly, I&#8217;m not too sure if anyone else came out. Towards the end of the night, I was feeling pretty lousy. Though I would later realize that it wasn&#8217;t due to the drink &#8212; it was all the smoke in the tavern (it make several others feel pretty lousy, and is probably the root cause of a new illness I seem to have acquired).<br />
I fled just after 23:15 for the GO Train. I needed sleep, I needed greasy food (luckily, there&#8217;s a McDonald&#8217;s in the train station), and if I&#8217;d had anything else to drink or stayed any longer, I&#8217;d probably have had to expel the contents of my stomach at least once.<br />
(Such as it is, I didn&#8217;t, nor did I wake up with a hangover the next day.)<br />
Friday night was great. It was reminiscent of parts of the Great Trans-Canada Pub Crawl, er, the CBC Train.<br />
Waking far earlier than I&#8217;d planned on Saturday, I proceeded to help Cathy with some home improvement. Not anything like renovations, but Cathy had a desire to hang a series of pictures in her bedroom, and it was just a matter of which ones.<br />
This is where being an amateur photographer and watching far too many movies for my own good. I was able to help Cathy choose a series of pictures that (when some were cropped) provided a great series of shots to hang on the wall.<br />
Mom arrived about 11:15 and proceeded to reorganize the furnace/storage room. This is what Mom does well &#8212; organizing things. We all freely acknowledge that she&#8217;s extremely good at it, And regularly raise the point of her keeping her tax returns from 1965 just to make sure that this success doesn&#8217;t all go to her head.<br />
We lunched on &#8220;Cheese and Bacon Dreams&#8221;. I suspect there&#8217;s a more mature name for these, but that&#8217;s all I know it as. Basically, it&#8217;s a piece of bread (usually a quartered slice of loaf bread), a piece of process cheese (though we had to use real cheese this time) and a small piece of bacon. They&#8217;re definitely the sort of thing that would receive a blistering glare from Arthur for eating them, but they&#8217;re a piece of my childhood that I hadn&#8217;t experienced in a long time.<br />
Following lunch, I had to take a nap. I was wiped. The previous day had been so energetic that it had taken until after lunch the following day for my body to wind down. A couple of hours later, and I was preparing to go back into Toronto.<br />
This particular night was a dinner with Amy. She was determined, beyond any doubt, to have a dinner party. (Amy seems to do this when someone from out of town manages to come in.) She had gone completely overboard: paella, octopus in red wine sauce, marinated asparagus and eggplant, organic spinach salad, cheeses, and a raspberry/almond Grenadine cake.<br />
I arrived downtown well of the scheduled 20:00. Amy wasn&#8217;t quite ready yet, so I returned to the nearby Yonge and Dundas area to investigate.<br />
It&#8217;s been quite a while since I was last at that intersection. I don&#8217;t honestly know how long, but it&#8217;s been at least four years. At the the time, the only thing I&#8217;d known was the demolition of two buildings, on either side of Dundas on the east side of Yonge. In that time, little change been done, save for the creation of Dundas Square.<br />
The face of Yonge has received a good scrubbing. New facades to the Eaton Centre, combined with with hew stores have polished the Old Girl up nicely. When I came up from the subway, I had for a flittering moment thought I was in Tokyo. It&#8217;s far from perfect, but it&#8217;s a start.<br />
Returning at 20:00, I found Chris already in attendance. (Amy was still in finishing touches.) Stefani would arrive soon afterwards, completing what would become the foursome. (We had hoped for more, but ended up with a great number for conversation and reflection.)<br />
Topics periodically turned to the more recent, but we talked mostly about the train: our experiences, our favourites, our horrors. You can wash well in those memories without feeling like you&#8217;ve sat in the bathwater too long.<br />
Amy had gone far above and beyond the call for dinner. The opener of squash soup (only the second time I&#8217;d had it &#8212; I&#8217;d thought it was the first until Mom reminded me about Mark&#8217;s wedding) was outstanding, the paella luscious, the octopus so thoroughly intriguing that I might have to obtain the recipe, the salad devine, and to describe the dessert would require a few modifications to certain complimentary phrases in the English language. All of it washed down with some of the best sangria I&#8217;ve ever had.<br />
Time, it seems, either moves far too quickly or not fast enough. And it&#8217;s always contrary to what you want. Before I knew it, midnight had arrived, and I was only getting warmed up. But I had to get home, and the last GO Train was at 00:43. (Actually, I would find out later that, at least on Saturdays, the last train is 01:30.)<br />
&#8220;Parting is such sweet sorrow&#8221; doesn&#8217;t cut it. I didn&#8217;t want to leave. I wanted to stay up until the trains ran again the following morning, being with Amy, Chris, and Stefani. But I knew my family had plans for the following day, and I wanted to be with them as much as I did with the CBC crew. A bit rushed, I acquired a few quick photographs of my friends before running out into the Toronto night. I saved the tears of goodbye until I was safely on the train home.<br />
When I woke up this morning, I knew I was coming down with a cold. It never fails. Every time I come to Ontario, I seem to get one. I don&#8217;t know why. It bugs the hell out of me. Tylenol Cough and Cold seems to help, but I&#8217;m going to need some Contact C when I get home.<br />
Cathy and Craig were already up when I rolled out of bed. They were listening to the radio in the living room, having had their morning coffee and TimBits. I sat and read the paper a bit while we took turns showering before heading down to pick up Mom.<br />
In what&#8217;s become a sort of tradition, we went for brunch. While we love going to the Water Street Grill in Burlington, a running race of some kind would have kept us from enjoying brunch due to shortened hours. Instead, we went to Glen Abbey. The food there is excellent, though the attendance is perhaps a tad too upscale for me.<br />
Brunch aside, we toured through town to go look at Mark and Darla&#8217;s new house. We didn&#8217;t know which one it was exactly (the one we thought it was didn&#8217;t seem right, and had people there who weren&#8217;t Mark and Darla).<br />
We eventually ended up back at Mom&#8217;s. Cathy and Craig finally decided on a long-overdue computer, and I did some maintenance work on Mom&#8217;s system. (Hopefully it helps speed it up a wee bit.)<br />
Soon after, we were back at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s. Richard dropped by to pick up the CDs for the band. We talked a bit. I saw their dog Bear probably for the last time (he has bone cancer, and will likely pass away before I return again).<br />
Next thing I know, I&#8217;m waiting for my Jetsgo flight. And I mean waiting &#8212; at least 30 minutes late leaving, for some reason. It&#8217;s cramped, hot, and I just want to get some Contact C to combat this freaking cold.<br />
It&#8217;s been another blitz visit of Toronto. I do these far too often. Maybe next time I can spend longer there &#8212; maybe with Erin. But hopefully it won&#8217;t be too long until I see my friends again.<br />
Hopefully, all of them &#8212; because I don&#8217;t see them nearly as much as I should.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-reunion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">300</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Anniversary!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/09/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/09/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 22:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/09/07/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to believe that it&#8217;s only been a year since the day the CBC Television 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train departed Vancouver on its epic 33-day trip across Canada. It seems like it&#8217;s been a lot longer. I suppose part of that is because I live in Calgary, isolated from nearly everyone else on &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/09/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Anniversary!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s hard to believe that it&#8217;s only been a year since the day the CBC Television 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train departed Vancouver on its epic 33-day trip across Canada. It seems like it&#8217;s been a lot longer.<br />
I suppose part of that is because I live in Calgary, isolated from nearly everyone else on the trip. (Enza&#8217;s very close to me, living in Banff, but I don&#8217;t have the luxury of working in the same building, as most of the Toronto folk do.) I&#8217;ve been lucky enough to see a couple of people &#8212; Angela and Tracy when they stopped through on a documentary tour (see [[CBC documentaries at the Glenbow Museum]]), and Julie and Enza when Julie came out on a conference (we met in Banff). Beyond that, the only contact I&#8217;ve had is through email.<br />
<span id="more-293"></span>As was proclaimed in the movie &#8220;American Pie&#8221;, God bless the Internet! Without it, I&#8217;d probably lose track of almost everyone I&#8217;ve ever met. And ironically, it was the Internet that got me on the CBC train in the first place!<br />
I can look back on the experience now with the wisened knowledge that I&#8217;ll probably never have another experience like that ever again. (I should be so unbelievably fortunate if I do.) The trip might not have been all sunshine and roses (Winnipeg was not on our &#8220;most favourite&#8221; list), but now I can look back on even the low points and see good things. It&#8217;s not a case of time healing all wounds, but more of seeing things for what they really were.<br />
I&#8217;ve had a lot of people ask me what the trip was like. As I said last year (see [[Home for a rest]]), there is just no way to fully describe it. My journals only cover aspects, Daryl&#8217;s videos don&#8217;t show the things that went on behind the scenes, and while the photos do show some &#8220;behind the scenes&#8221;, the can&#8217;t tell you the story. It&#8217;s a much hated term, but you really had to be there.<br />
A lot of people also ask me: &#8220;what&#8217;s the one thing you&#8217;ve taken away from that trip?&#8221; Now that&#8217;s a much harder question, although it is easier to answer. For me, experiences and laughter aside, it was the ideal concept of a &#8220;team&#8221;. You can laugh all you want at the saying &#8220;there&#8217;s no &#8216;I&#8217; in &#8216;team'&#8221; (note: there are two in &#8220;homicide&#8221;), but this was, I think, the perfect team. No prima donnas, everyone helped everyone else, and aside from the odd spat (one of which was my fault, which stemmed from really poor communications and that I very much regret having started) everyone got along very well. And at the end, were all sad to see it all end.<br />
I&#8217;ve looked at the CBC team and tried to use it in my daily life. Well, the ideas, anyway. I&#8217;d like to think it&#8217;s helped make my job better (and easier), but that&#8217;s something that only time will tell. We don&#8217;t have the pressure cooker of constant togetherness and tight daily deadlines to fuse everything together.<br />
To all of this, I have to continually thank my friend Brenda. Were it not for her thinking of me, I wouldn&#8217;t be where I am now. I would not have gone on the trip, would not have met the people I now know and call &#8220;friend&#8221;, I would not have the experiences that have made me a better person. It&#8217;s a debt I doubt I&#8217;ll ever be able to fully repay.<br />
I haven&#8217;t been on a train since last year, and it&#8217;s not looking like I&#8217;ll be on one this year. (The first time in five years.) I hope to see some of the CBC crew later this year, as I&#8217;m tentatively slated to be in Toronto 1 October &#8211; 5 October on business, but like everything else in my life it seems, that remains to be seen. It would be neat to do a reunion on a train, but I think that is more of a personal wish than a possibility. Still, dreams do have a way of coming true sometimes.<br />
It&#8217;s hard to believe it&#8217;s only been a year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/09/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-anniversary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">293</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Bay of Fundy</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2002 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/06/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 30 This is an entry I dreaded writing from the beginning. It&#8217;s the last one. It&#8217;s the last day. Today, people &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Bay of Fundy"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 30<br />
This is an entry I dreaded writing from the beginning. It&#8217;s the last one. It&#8217;s the last day. Today, people begin their trips home. Some are staying around for a little tourism, but they are few.<br />
I joined up with Duffy, Gerry, the Bills, the Robs, and Trish for a little excursion to the Bay of Fundy. Loading up into the crew&#8217;s two rented minivans, we took off out of the city for parts unknown. Gerry drove the first van, Trish navigating. Duffy followed in the second van.<br />
I sat next to Bill C. and behind Rob N. Bill, the crossword king, scribbled on his newspaper for most of the trip out. Our van was quiet, unlike Gerry&#8217;s. But it gave me time to think about how lucky I was. A small handful of people were given the chance to make this trip. Sure, it was hard and at times very frustrating, but in the end it was all worth it. This is an experience that I cannot imagine having passed up.<br />
<span id="more-242"></span>We drove through Nova Scotia&#8217;s countryside, passing rolling hills carpeted with luscious trees, just beginning their autumn explosion of colour. In a couple of weeks, this area will be spectacular.<br />
I fell asleep. The constant white noise of the car&#8217;s engine, the slight rocking, and quietness of the interior mimicked the train. I was still tired the night before. I woke up when I felt the car cease forward motion. We&#8217;d left the highway, and were now weaving down sideroads for a destination unknown.<br />
Originally, we were heading for Digby. (Daryl had suggested Parsboro.) But, as with everything else with this trip, plans change. We pulled into a tiny picturesque village called Harbourville. There are more boats than houses. The harbour is the centre, with houses scattered around the sides, and up the sides of the steep hills.<br />
Just over a short ridge of stones was the Bay of Fundy. So wide that the horizon eventually hides the opposite side. We arrived at high tide. The scene was normal &#8212; nothing that you wouldn&#8217;t expect. What we wouldn&#8217;t see was the 27 foot drop by 18:30 that night. And that&#8217;s not the largest difference in the Bay area.<br />
Returning to the cars, we plunged back into the backroads, trying to find an apparent road that ran down the west coast of Nova Scotia. Trish was using two maps as her guide, both from car rental agencies. Neither are terribly accurate, as we would later find out. A distance that should take only 15 minutes to traverse took nearly two hours as we zig-zagged up and down roads that almost didn&#8217;t look like roads. Bill S. in the lead van suggested that we stick only to paved roads.<br />
Trish eventually led us to Annapolis Royal, one of Canada&#8217;s oldest communities, founded in 1605. It&#8217;s a gorgeous little town, featuring national historic sites, preserved buildings, some odd sculptures made entirely out of bicycles, and the smallest pub in Nova Scotia&#8217;s history. We stopped for a much-needed lunch.<br />
The pub wasn&#8217;t that small &#8212; no smaller than an average-sized coffee shop. That either speaks to the size of buildings in the province, or the tendency to congregate and drink. We&#8217;re still not sure which.<br />
After our repast, we walked around the town. The tide was well on its way going out &#8212; there was already a 10-15 foot drop visible on the shore. There were still three hours until the water would reach its lowest level. One boat owner took the opportunity to paint part of his hull. On our way back, we stopped briefly at Canada&#8217;s only tidal power generator, just to the north of Annapolis Royal.<br />
Tided out, we started heading east. I think I slept. Both Rob and Bill dozed for a while. How Duffy stayed awake the entire time is admirable. Even with all the trouble following Gerry&#8217;s van, we eventually found ourselves in Mahone Bay. Another very picturesque town, it&#8217;s the home of the Scarecrow Festival. (Similar to farming scarecrows, the coastal scarecrows were historically used to keep birds off the boats.)<br />
We spent a little more time in Mahone Bay, mostly to stretch our legs. (The vans weren&#8217;t very comfortable.) As we reloaded, Bill S. jogged over to join us &#8212; he needed Bill C.&#8217;s help with a crossword. This caused some confusion. The two vans drove out unsure of exactly who was where. A kilometre down the road, we realized that we&#8217;d left Rob N. behind. We found poor Rob standing in the parking lot, two coffees in hand, wondering what the heck was going on.<br />
We were back at the hotel an hour later. With an hour break, we left again with Amy and Chris to have our last (partial) team dinner in Halifax.<br />
And then there were eleven. Ten of us ate at the Upper Deck, and Roger floated in an out, entertaining clients and suppliers. Roger was already hard at work again. Everyone else had left town.<br />
Thoroughly sated at the restaurant, we met up with Roger at the Economy Shoe Shop, a very eclectic bar a few blocks away. It would not be a repeat of days past. A final drink, and the crew headed out. Soon, Amy, Chris, and I returned to the hotel.<br />
I sat, looking out my window at the Halifax Citadel. Tomorrow, I will not likely see anyone else from the team. I will miss them all. Each was a unique, unstereotypical person. Each was a friend and teacher. How I will fill the void their departures leave behind is anyone&#8217;s guess.<br />
I have spent my last. But I have no regrets, and given the chance, I&#8217;d do it all again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-bay-of-fundy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Halifax finale</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2002 05:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/05/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 29 Early morning call. The last one. Breakfast, grab things for the day, taxi to the station, and begin final set-up. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Halifax finale"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 29<br />
Early morning call. The last one. Breakfast, grab things for the day, taxi to the station, and begin final set-up. New Media didn&#8217;t change from the day before, but others were moving around in the station to better locations. Luckily, it wasn&#8217;t too much work, and fairly expeditiously handled. When the CBC Halifax staff event began (it was our first of the day), we were all ready.<br />
So began a day that, at least for me, was little more than a blurry dream. It was pockmarked with little things, like each of us getting our chance at Be An Anchor, or exchanging addresses. The production was slowly running out of steam. One more event would have been too much.<br />
<span id="more-241"></span>The Be An Anchor was perhaps one of the sillier parts of my day. Roger had decreed that everyone was doing Be An Anchor before the end of the day. When I was down at the museum car (for what reason I can&#8217;t really remember &#8212; I was probably hunting something down in the coach car), Roger abducted me for my session. Neil was just coming out of his. I suppose I should have played it &#8220;normal&#8221; and just read the script. But there was a part of me that just refused to go down without goofing off. So I dropped my voice, upped the cheese-factor, and played it like an over-the-top newscaster wannabe. Then, inspired by Irene&#8217;s song back in Campbellton, I finished with a high-pitched squeaky-voice version of &#8220;Little Bunny Foo Foo&#8221;.<br />
According to rumour, Neil caught wind of my little performance and immediately wanted to redo his. He hunted all around for something to improve facial scars so he could do the reading as Dr. Evil. I can&#8217;t wait to see it.<br />
This Hour Has 22 Minutes made good use of our train. When we were setting up yesterday, one of the 22 Minutes crew came and &#8220;borrowed&#8221; Ron Maclean. At first, we thought he was stealing it. (Luckily, Rose was able to straighten us out.) Mary Walsh arrived before the public event started and did her run through the museum &#8230; as Marg Delahunty, Princess Warrior. She conned (or convinced, not sure which) Ivan to let her wear the Friendly Giant&#8217;s boots for part of her segment. I was fortunate enough to watch the filming, snapping the odd picture or two for the website. Then it was off to Be An Anchor, where she filmed a segment (though didn&#8217;t read our script), and then wandered into the baggage car. But not for a part of her segment. It was to take a picture with the crew. Then, it was back into the station for the last bit.<br />
I spent far too little time at the New Media display. Today will be the last time I see this train, the last time I could take pictures of the events and the crew. It was also the last time I&#8217;d have to repackage things going back to Toronto. That was a heap of fun. Luckily, I had kept most of the New Media stuff in one place, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad putting it all back together. I had two laptops to take care of: the Dell (a mirror of Daryl&#8217;s computer) and an IBM ThinkPad which was an emergency backup system (I never used it). The Dell was staying with me an extra week (with Brenda&#8217;s blessing), so I packed the laptop with everything else. [Ed. Note: In hindsight, I should have hung onto both of them. When the train arrived back in Toronto, the IBM had gone missing.]<br />
Koceila seemed not to mind being regularly abandoned as the day went on. He&#8217;s been a total trooper since he joined us in Montreal, and loves interacting with the public. Which was good, because I think I&#8217;ve actually lost the taste for it for a while.<br />
As I was packing away in the coach car, and chatting with my project lead regarding the return of certain pieces of equipment (specifically, the laptop), I got a call on the walkie-talkie: &#8220;She&#8217;s here.&#8221; &#8220;She&#8221; is Michelle, a fellow train enthusiast, and someone who&#8217;s been following our journey online. (You&#8217;ll remember her from yesterday. Michelle&#8217;s the one from Indian Head, Saskatchewan, who flew to Halifax to visit her friend, and to come out and see us in our last venue.)<br />
I left the train (and Koceila again) to talk with Michelle and her friend Pam, about the reasons why they came out, how they knew each other, and what they thought of our exhibit. Michelle has loved trains her whole life, something she got from her mother. She has been writing her own daily journal since graduating from university. The mix of the two created an irresistible urge to come out and see what we were doing. Pam didn&#8217;t even know we were coming to Halifax. The three of us ducked out of the show for a little while into the hotel bar. (Relax, I don&#8217;t drink on the job &#8230; often. I had ginger ale.)<br />
The last hour and a half of the show passed quickly. Roger filmed the rest of the train crew (except Duffy) at Be An Anchor. The filming had turned from a chance to do something interesting into a contest to who had the best reading. We all played at our own sets: colouring at the tables, playing with the kiosks, and getting dressed up in the Noddy mascot costume and wandering around. It was probably the most fun we had at an event.<br />
I spent the last minute of our show in the mobile, taking Dan&#8217;s picture for the staff scrapbook. Then, without fanfare or celebration, it ended. When I got back into the station house, the extra lighting was already off and sets were coming down.<br />
Packing wasn&#8217;t as fast as Moncton &#8212; that will remain the shortest time. We really weren&#8217;t in any rush, though. There were plans for the evening, yes, but we&#8217;d given ourselves plenty of time. New Media&#8217;s final strike had a couple of special requirements, as two computers, two monitors, and a sign had to go to Toronto ahead of everything else. The Queen&#8217;s visit at CBC&#8217;s Broadcast Centre needed New Media representation. (Originally, the plasma screen was to go as well, but a coordinated effort between Brenda, Julie, and myself pretty much killed that idea.)<br />
As we shuttled boxes, tables, and portable walls up and down the platform, a pop-hiss announced the departure of our sleeper cars. The Chateau Denonville, Chateau Lauzon, and Chateau Rigaud pulled away with another train. Only the Skyline 8502 remained, along with the Banff Park, museum cars, baggage car, and coach car on another track. A few of us just stared and watched as our home slowly drove away.<br />
Darkness descended with the stowing of the last few items. Almost everyone (without prompting) came out onto the platform to watch the last packing &#8212; the stairs we used for climbing in and out of the baggage car. Another ending, as the doors to the cars were closed for the last time. We headed into the station for our last crew picture.<br />
Earlier in the day, Emma had made reservations for dinner at Hamachi House, the best sushi restaurant in town (so far as she could find out). After making a trip back to the hotel to dump the things we didn&#8217;t want (and change, in a couple of cases), we grabbed taxis to the restaurant. We were going to finish this trip as we&#8217;d started it: with raw fish. We weren&#8217;t alone, followed by Julie, Julie&#8217;s husband, Koceila, Lisa, Ivan, Analisa, Neil, and Daryl (though not all at the same time). Emma and I certainly got our money&#8217;s worth, especially with the uber-fresh tuna.<br />
The restaurant had sushi boats, which we sat around. We didn&#8217;t get to use them for food (billing would have been a problem), but we used them for passing around origami animals and haikus:</p>
<blockquote><p>Sea to sea sushi<br />
Endless lifting of stanchions,<br />
The train rolls away.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Mountains and prairies<br />
Glistening lakes, loyal fans<br />
Great teams do great things.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>A rolling stone<br />
Gathers no moss!!<br />
Keep rollin&#8217;!</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>The start of the end<br />
A new day approaches soon<br />
Great friends forever</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>It&#8217;s only a paper moon<br />
Hung in a cardboard sky<br />
But, it&#8217;s only make believe</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>The start of the end<br />
A new day approaches<br />
Good friends forever</p></blockquote>
<p>Everyone headed over to Ginger&#8217;s Tavern afterwards for a post-show libation. It was our last hurrah. Even the various VIA staff who had been on and behind the front lines came out. Papers were sent around collecting email addresses. Cards were exchanged. But it didn&#8217;t have the air of finality. It felt no different than every other time we&#8217;d gone to dinner, drinks, or gone shopping with each other. There were tears when Stefani left, as she flies out early tomorrow for England.<br />
We abandoned Ginger&#8217;s Tavern and walked down the road to a club (the name of which I&#8217;ve forgotten) that is supposed to be really good. It was crammed to the walls, and the band playing wasn&#8217;t particularly good. We opted for a place across the road, the Party House. (I wasn&#8217;t choosing these places. If I had, we&#8217;d have ended up at a place where you could conduct a civilised conversation.) Analisa worked that magic we&#8217;d seen in Saskatoon, and got almost the whole lot of us into the club without paying cover.<br />
Lisa and Chris found just how stubborn I can be when it comes to dancing (namely that I dislike dancing to club music). Some danced. Some shouted at each other over the music. Last call came over the speakers. We paid no attention. Daryl headed out into the night, deciding it was time for him to exit. I wasn&#8217;t sure if I&#8217;d ever see Daryl again, and thanked him not only for doing a great job, but also for being a patient person and offering all the suggestions he had over the course of the month. Originally, when I was do have done the video, Daryl was to be my teacher. In the end, he taught me more than I could have thought.<br />
Far too soon than any of us would have liked, the music stopped, the lights came on, and we woke from our month-long collective dream. The CBC 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train was over. Our last hurrah was now quiet. We all knew it was time. &#8220;Goodbye&#8221; truly is the saddest word.<br />
For most of the team, it&#8217;s &#8220;see you back in Toronto&#8221;. Patrick and Koceila return to Montreal. Stefani goes to England. Daryl drives home to Frederickton tomorrow. I will remain in Halifax for a few more days, but I begin my trip home on Saturday. Standing in the brightly lit interior of the club suddenly made that fact very real. I was about to never see these people again. Julie and I tried to say things to each other, but we both ended up crying. The end was so chaotic that there were those I never said farewell to. I don&#8217;t know if they were there, or if I just missed them.<br />
The team scattered into the night. Some I would see again the following day, some not. We all walked into the darkness not knowing what would happen next. For the first time in a month, the future is unknown.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-finale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">241</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Halifax VIP</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2002 05:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/04/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 28 A maternity ward of babies didn&#8217;t sleep as well as I did last night. I stirred only once, when the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Halifax VIP"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 28<br />
A maternity ward of babies didn&#8217;t sleep as well as I did last night. I stirred only once, when the cleaning staff tried to come in the room. I woke late, but feeling more awake and alert than I have since this trip started.<br />
We arrived at the Halifax station to find it a hive of activity. It seemed that there would almost be no room for us to set up. Tonight was a VIP event, signifying the end of our odyssey.<br />
It was our last time unloading the train. But despite the finality, we had no lack of drive. The train was dutifully unpacked, and items drawn into the station. The fit was a little tight with some items, such as the centre triangle for New Media and &#8220;The Beast&#8221; from the Boutique.<br />
During set-up, I had yet another partial run-in with fame. Julie pulled me aside to tell me of a woman who had been following our journey through my daily journal. What blew me away was that she&#8217;d tried to catch up with us in Melville. Over half the country away. She had flown from Indian Head, Saskatchewan to see us here in Halifax. Both Julie and I were beside ourselves.<br />
By 2:00, everything was almost ready. That&#8217;s when we were told of touch-ups. This is our second-to-last event. We&#8217;ve spent 27 days on the road, and our equipment isn&#8217;t exactly looking new. (The fact that it looks good at all is amazing.) For our final events, the tables received a new coat of paint.<br />
We literally ended up watching paint dry. The Halifax station is quite active &#8212; VIA&#8217;s Ocean train departs and arrives every day. Busses are also a constant source of traffic. The last thing you want is for things to go missing. We don&#8217;t expect theft, we just don&#8217;t want to encourage it.<br />
One of our group activities was a group photograph. We&#8217;ve taken two already, one in Jasper and another in Winnipeg. We now have our final crew, and it should be immortalized. However, due to some rather odd scheduling, not everyone was around when we got to taking the picture. We&#8217;ll shoot another picture tomorrow, but we&#8217;ll already be short one person.<br />
Today, Angela left us for home. She is the first of the original crew arriving in Halifax to leave. It was a sad occasion, though for most people it will only be a short time until they see her in Toronto. I will be lucky if I see Angela again. On Sunday, many others will take their leave. Today was but a hint of what is to come.<br />
The VIPs started arriving just after 5:00. For the next four hours, we wandered about, handing out giveaways, and trying to be helpful. It&#8217;s not our favourite kind of event. It requires a lot of work, and doesn&#8217;t produce benefit. Most of the visitors are here to see other visitors, not us. We&#8217;re window dressing. We&#8217;d rather add extra hours onto the public events.<br />
Barely a month ago (see [[CBC 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Opening Event Pacific Central Station|5 September 2002]]), I thought VIP events were pretty neat. I guess it doesn&#8217;t take long to get jaded.<br />
Speeches were a key focus. It gave time for CBC to bring up the Executive Vice-President, Harold Redekopp for a chance to talk about what the 50th Anniversary meant, and what part the train played. I personally preferred the speech by the Honourable Myra Freeman, the Lieutenant-Governor of Nova Scotia.<br />
The single best speech was a rant by Rick Mercer, shown on video (Rick himself was present). It echoed another shorter rant he had done for the 50th anniversary, but with a more political slant. It was extremely funny, especially when he illustrated just how Canadians view the CBC. I would repeat examples, but they would likely be edited for content.<br />
Back in the hotel following the event, I would see Rick again on &#8220;Tuning In&#8221;, one of the 50th anniversary shows. I caught the very end of the show, and saw little. But what I did see were the credits. For the first time, I knew the names that went by on the screen. I didn&#8217;t just know who they were, I had worked with them. They were friends and comrades. The credits had meaning.<br />
After a month on the road with the CBC, I now understand the appeal of working in television.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-halifax-vip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Peggy&#039;s Cove</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2002 05:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/03/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 27 The trip portion of this journey is officially over. The train rolled into Halifax early this morning while we slept. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Peggy&#039;s Cove"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 27<br />
The trip portion of this journey is officially over. The train rolled into Halifax early this morning while we slept. We awoke slowly, and moved sluggishly. While many are looking forward to going home, most of us are sad that we&#8217;ve come to the end of the line. Appropriately, it was raining.<br />
Packing up our train lives was no easy task. We&#8217;ve accumulated a surprising amount of stuff over the last month &#8212; bags were literally bursting. We had about two and a half hours to clean our stuff out, which seemed ample enough to find everything. I wandered about the train a bit, sometimes tripping over others in the midst of finding all their clothes.<br />
It almost felt like I was moving out of a favourite apartment and moving away from old friends. There was a certain sombre sadness of leaving the train after being on it for so long. We&#8217;ll only be using the train in coming days as a place to take meals. From here on, we&#8217;ll be staying in a hotel. We&#8217;re done riding trains. Not counting public transit, I don&#8217;t figure on taking a train until next year.<br />
The time came, and VIA came around with a tractor to collect our bags. They&#8217;d arrive with the vans at the hotel later on. We gathered in the station in anticipation of our shuttles. Roger and Trish vanished to rent a car, as did Duffy and Gerry. While waiting, one of the VIA crew from our train (I think his name is Carl) handed me an envelope. He told me not to tell anyone, and not to open it until I got to the hotel.<br />
We loaded our shuttle bus for our last hotel, a bare block from the CBC Halifax office. The driver lost me in the maze of turns. And I don&#8217;t get lost easily. The hotel is a fair distance from downtown, but it&#8217;s actually not too bad. We can feasibly walk the distance. The hotel is quite large, which is nice. It even has a small lounge. Something I&#8217;m sure the crew will make repeated use of.<br />
We were unable to check into our rooms right away. Some managed to get rooms, but the majority of us stuffed our baggage into an unused conference room. Some simply crashed and relaxed for the afternoon. Some of us were more interested in adventure.<br />
Roger, Trish, Amy, Stefani, Analisa, and myself piled into Roger&#8217;s rented Lincoln Navigator (upgraded thanks to several nearly-expired upgrade coupons) and bolted for Peggy&#8217;s Cove. The Bills, the Robs, Gerry, Duffy, Emma, and Lisa followed in two minivans. We arrived quite a bit ahead of them, no doubt in part to Roger&#8217;s ability to traverse distances in safe haste. Although we took the &#8220;long&#8221; route, we arrived in under 45 minutes.<br />
It&#8217;s been about 22 years since I last set foot in Nova Scotia. Yet I remembered the area as we approached Peggy&#8217;s Cove. I wondered if I would, considering how young I had been at the time. As we exited the forest for the coastal spaces, I started to recognize a few things. Then a faint memory came to me &#8230; one I hadn&#8217;t thought of in years. A little over two decades ago, I got carsick into one of the many little bays. I dreaded a repeat show &#8212; my sister would never let me live it down.<br />
Peggy&#8217;s Cove was, unsurprisingly, crowded with tourists. The streets were full of them, making driving a little treacherous. We finally arrived at the parking lot at the edge of the coast, next to the famous Peggy&#8217;s Cove Lighthouse and Post Office. It&#8217;s something to have postcards with a Peggy&#8217;s Cove cancellation.<br />
Exiting from our safe, warm vehicle, we found the he wind was biting. Perhaps not as bad as the previous night&#8217;s mosquitoes, but it was still breath taking. Especially when, like myself, you&#8217;re wearing shorts. (Actually, I wasn&#8217;t that cold, but hopping from a warm car to the chilly air was pause for thought. Amy and I were a little cool, but didn&#8217;t suffer as much as Roger, Stefani, and Trish. Analisa played it smart and stayed in the gift shop most of the time we were there.)<br />
We hopped over the rocks like mountain goats. Some hid behind them periodically, due to the cold. I marvelled at the water-rounded rocks, the cracks, the seaweed, the sky, the waves, and the undeniable smell of fresh saltwater. A month ago, I marvelled at a similar scene on the west coast. This was simultaneously similar, yet completely different. (And despite that the two massive oceans are connected, the Atlantic has a decidedly different smell than the Pacific. I&#8217;d love to know why.)<br />
The two other vans appeared about 20 minutes after we arrived. Soon the rocks were swarming with CBC train staff. We would congregate in small groups, filter out across the rolling waves of stone, and regroup in other places. At a distance, we probably looked no different than seagulls as they ride the ocean.<br />
We left about an hour after arriving. The goal was also to see Lunenburg during our tour of the province. As we left town, we started to look for the Flight 111 Memorial. On the night of 2 September 1998, Swissair Flight 111 crashed into the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Peggy&#8217;s Cove. All 229 passengers and crew were lost. The tragedy put the small town of Peggy&#8217;s Cove on the world map for a time, and has left a mark ever since. Only a few short kilometres away, visible from Peggy&#8217;s Cove, is a simple memorial to those who lost their lives, and those who were first on the scene: the fishers of Peggy&#8217;s Cove.<br />
You can&#8217;t see the memorial from the road. It requires a bit of a walk down a gravel path until you reach a stone platform upon which are two stone discs, mounted perpendicular to the platform, at an angle to each other. One side of the discs is rounded, the inside flat. The inside faces out to the ocean, the surfaces engraved. One of the discs has three notches out of the top &#8212; 111. Supposedly, the notches look towards where the plane went down. You can&#8217;t see it from shore. The crash site is just over the horizon. Over three years have passed since the tragic events, but flowers still arrive here.<br />
The two vans did finally arrive in Lunenburg &#8212; we did not. Although we had been headed in that direction, we hadn&#8217;t gone out to the highway (the fastest method), and were in no real hurry. In fact, we were sidetracked by an overwhelming need to eat. Luckily for us, you often find the best meals when you&#8217;re on the verge of getting totally lost.<br />
Lost was exactly was I was beginning to feel like. With Trish navigating, Roger was bombing up and down hills in search of &#8230; well, probably not really in search of anything. That&#8217;s half the fun of exploring &#8212; knowing you really don&#8217;t need to find anything. That&#8217;s how we ended up in the middle of nowhere (actually, it was somewhere around Upper Tantallon, wherever that is). We stopped at a general store, where we got directions to the nearest good restaurant. Luckily, it was just around the next bend.<br />
The Pilot House Cafe is definitely off the beaten path. So far off, in fact, that it was empty save for the sole waitress. The inside was cottagey, looking (somewhat) recently renovated. Apparently, the cafe is primarily for the lodgers of the adjoining cabins. When the tourist flow is slow, rogue travellers are eagerly welcomed. The first question was &#8220;who wants chowder?&#8221;.<br />
The chef, Billy, knows his food. Seafood chowder so thick you could spackle a house (and came in the most darling bowls); calamari so fresh, soft, and tangy as to almost pierce the soul; and if you&#8217;d told me that you could put scallops on a pizza, I&#8217;d have called you crazy. The taste is otherworldly. I won&#8217;t mention dessert. Trust me, you&#8217;ll only drool over your keyboard, and that just doesn&#8217;t look attractive.<br />
Packed to the rim, we rolled out of the restaurant and found our way back to Halifax. The trip took barely 20 minutes &#8212; we took the highway. We didn&#8217;t make a beeline back to the hotel, though. Tonight was our last (planned) full team dinner, at a restaurant called Soho Kitchen downtown. Analisa wanted to acquire a new pair of shoes for the event. This led to almost everyone thinking they could use something. Everyone except me. My bag are already too full &#8212; I simply can&#8217;t pack anything else in. If I buy any souvenirs in this city, it&#8217;s going to have to be small.<br />
We sidled into one of the local malls, and we ducked into a Sears Outlet store. I hadn&#8217;t been in an outlet store for a while. I remembered why. Nothing to be found in sight. At least for Roger and I. Amy, Trish, and Analisa hunted around. Stefani didn&#8217;t seem all that enthralled, admittedly. Finding the store a bit of a washout, we returned to the car and pulled around front to the rest of the mall complex. This time, I stayed in the car. I was tired from all the activity (and the food). I slept for a few minutes while the others shopped.<br />
We were a little slow recongregating. Roger and Trish were back early. Stefani was maybe a minute or two late. Analisa took considerably longer. But we could not find Amy. She&#8217;d vanished. We patrolled the mall, at first with our eyes, and then with the car. No sign of her anywhere. We checked the stores she&#8217;d said she was going to check. Nothing. We were getting a little worried. We thought that perhaps we had somehow managed to miss each other, and Amy had taken a cab back to the hotel. As we were making our last pass to make sure we hadn&#8217;t missed something, Amy walked out of the mall&#8217;s entrance. Relieved that we&#8217;d found her, we returned to the hotel. Tonight was our wrap party.<br />
In theatre, you&#8217;d normally wait until the end of the production to hold the festivities. Our last show is Saturday, 5 October. But starting tomorrow, we start losing our staff. Lives need to be lived, and almost all of us have taken a month&#8217;s leave of absence from them. With our time together rapidly closing, it&#8217;s our last chance for a full team dinner.<br />
We went to Soho Kitchen, on a recommendation from Daryl, a former and still-periodic Halifax resident. It&#8217;s a more local haunt, and definitely not a tourist trap. Crammed into a side room that barely fit us all, we outnumbered the remaining patrons. We easily overpowered them with volume. The menu items were so tantalising that it was extremely difficult to choose. Lisa took it upon herself to choose for me (I didn&#8217;t offer a lot of resistance). Thai scallops. Quite tasty.<br />
Speeches that weren&#8217;t meant to be speeches followed dinner. Neil wanted to thank a few people who had made the trip happen, and memorable. Unfortunately, he went down the slippery slope of inclusion, and found himself having to thank everyone. It&#8217;s a dicey problem any of us could have walked into. If you don&#8217;t make just the right speech, you run the risk of offending someone &#8212; either by understating something they think was more important, or perhaps forgetting them all together. Still, I have to give Neil credit for at least trying to say something about everyone. No-one else had tried by that point, and I doubt ever will. It was a more emotional event than I think any of us really realized.<br />
Following our repast, we adjourned to the Seahorse Pub, a local legend since 1948. The interior was &#8230; in transition. Renovations in the corner seemed to indicate that the bar had some work planned. It was almost impossible to tell when the last time the renovations had even been touched.<br />
We toasted our success, and the people who would soon leave. Emma convinced me to join her in a game of darts. That was her first mistake. She suggested a game called &#8220;cricket&#8221;. That was her second mistake. I must laud Emma&#8217;s patience as she repeatedly taught me the rules, which seemed so complicated at the time. (In all honestly, speaking becomes complicated after enough pints of beer.) We never finished the game &#8212; neither of us could hit the bullseye after a while &#8212; but I still lost.<br />
It was then back to the hotel. I don&#8217;t really remember the walk back, other than I felt a draining urge to get to my room as quickly as possible. We don&#8217;t have an early morning tomorrow, but sleep is still a wonderful thing.<br />
Oh, what was in the envelope you ask? Hmm&#8230; I forgot to mention that, didn&#8217;t I? Well, Carl and I had talked a bit on the train on our way from Montreal. He, like the other regional managers for VIA, could spot a railfan around the next corner. He could also tell that I was far from worn out from our little jaunt across the country. He had asked if I would be interested in riding the Bras D&#8217;or, VIA&#8217;s rail cruise from Halifax to Sydney, on Cape Breton island. I had replied at the time that I would love to go, but simply couldn&#8217;t afford it. Carl said he would see what he could do. In the envelope was a round-trip pass on the Bras D&#8217;or.<br />
Who said there&#8217;s no such thing as a free lunch?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-peggys-cove/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Moncton</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2002 22:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/02/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 26 There was apparently a bit of activity last night. Early in the morning, Julie came up to me and asked &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Moncton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 26<br />
There was apparently a bit of activity last night. Early in the morning, Julie came up to me and asked if I&#8217;d heard anything during the night. Aside from the train itself, I heard little. Julie seemed &#8230; undecided, and then walked away. That, my friends, is a mystery just screaming to be solved. I had to know what happened last night. I checked with Emma, my guaranteed source for information. She didn&#8217;t know. The both of us were now insatiably curious. The investigation would continue most of the day.<br />
One of the things we were told early on, long before we left Vancouver, was that we were never, ever to drink on board. This was explained away as insurance reasons. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s the truth or the story, but the fact was that we were not to drink. Officially, the rule was followed. Unofficially, we broke every single rule we were given within the first two days of the trip. Both VIA and the CBC turned a blind eye to almost everything. At least until last night.<br />
While breaking the rule (for the umpteenth time) of not staying in the baggage car while the train is in motion, several people (whose names I shall not divulge) indulged in another forbidden activity: alcoholic consumption. All of this was known, common, and though not accepted, tolerated. However, being the second-to-last night on the train, a couple of people got &#8230; happy. And perhaps a little sloppy. One of them, staying in a room in my Chateau car, accidentally went into Julie&#8217;s room, which was on the following Chateau car. I can&#8217;t really imagine what took place at that exact moment. When I finally heard the story, I couldn&#8217;t stop laughing.<br />
Today was almost a repeat of yesterday, just with a shorter event. And a different city. And different event layout. And different performers. And no rain, with lots of wind. And it was hot. Okay, today has no semblance to yesterday, except the province, arrive, set-up, event, tear-down, pack-up, and leave.<br />
Today was Moncton. Most of us had never been here before (like any of us had been to Campbellton &#8212; except Marc).<br />
We had no Internet access. Quel surprise. A little miffed since I could see a huge NBTel tower about a kilometre away. I can only assume that either NBTel doesn&#8217;t have a 1x network, or doesn&#8217;t have a deal with Bell Canada to rebroadcast users onto Bell&#8217;s network. It didn&#8217;t change the fact that I had to find an Internet Cafe. I wandered east through town on directions from local VIA staff. Up and down streets I went, but no Internet to be found. Not even a hint of Internet. For all I could tell, Moncton was digitally isolated from the rest of the world. The only thing I found of note were three churches sitting kiddie-corner to each other, at the corner of Church and Queen: United, United Baptist, and Anglican. Connectivity, yes, but with the wrong deity.<br />
Deprived of Internet, I returned to the train to begin our set-up. The weather was windy, but promised little chance of rain. We went for the entire New Media configuration. Some of the other tents skipped some of their items: Sports dropped the cut-outs, and the Boutique opted not to use &#8220;The Beast&#8221;. All the tents were heavily staked down, and remaining signage weighted down with sandbags and tied up. Our loose items (such as the bookmarks) had to sit carefully on the tables so a strong gust wouldn&#8217;t blow them off into oblivion. Sports, at least, had a small mountain of fridge magnets to hold their pages in place.<br />
Although we didn&#8217;t officially open until 15:00, people were already arriving by 14:30. Early arrivals weren&#8217;t a problem &#8212; we were all ready to go live with the show. Our friend Murphy, mostly silent throughout the trip, decided we&#8217;d become too smug in our preparations. That&#8217;s probably why the power went out at 14:58. Apparently the entire neighbourhood lost power, not just us. Most of the tents, half of the VIA station, most of the mobile, and the entire train went without power. At first I was confused, since we normally run off our generator, and our cars off the locomotive&#8217;s HEP generator. It would figure that the first time we run everything off shore power that there&#8217;s a blackout.<br />
Somehow, the New Media tent &#8212; the one with the largest power requirements of any tent &#8212; was unaffected. News, Sports, half of the mobile, the museum, and half the train station were completely in the dark. Within twenty minutes, the engine was switched to HEP, and power ran back through the train. The museum came back to life, and visitors finally started to walk through. News and Sports would be without power until much later in the afternoon, when the power company finally fixed the problem.<br />
The lack of electricity didn&#8217;t dampen any spirits, however. Visitors created a near two-hour line to see the museum. Every tent had a swarm of visitors. Koceila and I were on our toes most of the time. Koceila talked mostly about the Archives site &#8212; I talked to people who have been reading my journals online. It&#8217;s still really bizarre being a virtual pseudo-celebrity. I&#8217;m truly amazed at the number of people who read these things. I&#8217;d always thought it would be kind of neat to do. That people would not only read it, but try and find me was something I honestly hadn&#8217;t expected.<br />
Later in the afternoon, we had to temporarily close the museum. This time, it wasn&#8217;t due to errant electricity. It was due to the scheduled arrival of VIA&#8217;s Ocean train. The Ocean runs from Halifax to Montreal, and is the oldest scheduled train in Canada. It will have run for 100 years of service in 2004 &#8212; a trip I might have to make for myself. As it is scheduled (runs every day except Tuesday), we had to temporarily shut down for about 40 minutes while the Ocean did its thing. Then it was off to Montreal, and we got back to entertaining.<br />
Speaking of entertaining, there were a few live acts floating around. But not on a stage outside. Due to problems with the site layout and the potential weather, the stage was inside. That&#8217;s where you could find Anthony McLean, a couple of bands, and the Moncton Ballet. Yes, the ballet. Believe me, we scratched our heads at that one, too. They were good, even crammed into the wee spaces of the station.<br />
About a half hour before we began tear-down, I had a woman approach me. I haven&#8217;t seen a smile that large since we&#8217;d started. Her first words were &#8220;thank you for coming&#8221;. She then detailed almost everything in our museum, and how wonderful it was to see it all. &#8220;You should be proud of the work you&#8217;ve all done here. The team must be so amazing to make this all work. You should congratulate yourselves on a job well done!&#8221; Just as calmly as she appeared, she vanished into the crowd.<br />
It&#8217;s people like her that kept us going after our longest, hardest days. They&#8217;re the people we want to reach out to. Not because we want the congratulations, but because they&#8217;ve supported the CBC over the years. Public company or not, without loyal viewers (and listeners), the CBC would not exist.<br />
As the sun went down, we started to strike our sets. For the tents, it would be the last time &#8212; we won&#8217;t be using them in Halifax. Things went back in boxes, tables were collapsed, monitors packed away, and things carted back to the train. When it finally got dark, we noticed something. Mosquitoes. The last time we&#8217;d seen insects was Melville. We&#8217;d had to close early due to marauding hoardes of the bloodsuckers. There weren&#8217;t as many in Moncton. Probably because the air traffic controllers had to line the beasts up in order to get near us. And unlike their Melvillian cousins, these little buggers actually hurt!<br />
Our strike was faster than previous ones, probably the fastest we&#8217;ll ever do. Whether or not it was due to experience, or due to the overwhelming flood of giant mutant mosquitoes is up for debate. Either way, our second-to-last pack job was done in record time, which was fine for us &#8212; the faster we could lock the doors, the less painful the bites would be.<br />
On [[CBC 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Opening Event Pacific Central Station|5 September]], we had our first full-scale strike of our sets. It took us over three and a half hours. We joked that we would have it down to an hour and a half when we got to Halifax. We broke the time tonight, our last item loaded into the baggage cars barely an hour and a half after starting. It was reason to celebrate.<br />
But it&#8217;s a bittersweet celebration. Our time together is rapidly ending. Tonight will be our last on the train. As I write this, we are rolling steadily closer to Halifax. Tomorrow we leave our home of the last month for the last time. We take with us the strange stories that can only be created when living in the conditions as those on our train. We will miss it dearly.<br />
I spent some time in the Banff Park&#8217;s dome, watching the train weave its way through the canyon of trees. The only light came from the lead locomotive&#8217;s headlamps, and from the odd light buried in the forests. I will only be hearing the mournful blats of the horn for a little while longer. I&#8217;m still debating on whether I want to go to sleep tonight.<br />
On [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Vancouver|7 September]], I said I would have a difficult time leaving this train. I&#8217;m not the only one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-moncton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Campbellton</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2002 22:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail Train]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/01/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] Day 25 No-one slept well last night. It was too hot, too bouncy, too loud. I think it was also because the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Campbellton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite> [This entry written by Geoff Sowrey, ©2002 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC). Text used with permission of CBC. The opinions expressed within do not necessarily reflect those of the CBC, employees, affiliates, or subsidiaries.] </cite><br />
Day 25<br />
No-one slept well last night. It was too hot, too bouncy, too loud. I think it was also because the last night we slept on the train was 18 September. Since then, we&#8217;ve slept in large beds in hotels, or at home. Our first night on the train was exciting, so we didn&#8217;t notice the change. After over a week in controlled conditions, the erratic environment of the train is a little unsettling. Today, we get back into the groove we had when we started almost a month ago.<br />
Today is what used to be a typical day for us: arrive in the early morning (usually in the wee hours), set up the displays, entertain and inform the local populous, pack up, leave late in the evening. We&#8217;re all looking forward to the regularity for the next couple of days. Most of us seem to like this pattern. We&#8217;ve officially become the Cirque du CBC.<br />
I awoke to an announcement suggesting we eat breakfast and get ready to unload the train. For only the second time since the trip started, and the first on the train, I&#8217;d overslept. As I walked down the length of our Chateau cars, I could see the river, or the Gulf of St. Lawrence (a significant body of water, regardless). Admittedly, I&#8217;d never been to Campbellton before, so I wasn&#8217;t sure what it was, and I never did find out. [Ed. Note: It was neither. Campbellton sits on the south shore of the Restigouche River, west of the river mouth, south of the Gaspé Peninsula.]<br />
Gulping down breakfast in record time, I ran outside to catch up with the rest of the team already beginning to unpack the baggage car. Set-up was almost too easy. We&#8217;ve done these so many times that the problems are reduced to predicting the weather. (No wireless connection in Campbellton &#8212; no surprise, there &#8212; so we couldn&#8217;t check the online weather forecast.)Koceila had little trouble, learning the ropes extrememly fast. As usual, crowds were forming long before the doors were officially open. We&#8217;ve never turned people away, just so long as we can accommodate them. Our official start was 12:00, but we were entertaining long before then.<br />
Roger was running around with the Polaroid camera while everyone assembled their sets. I think Roger either got too much sleep last night, or has gone certifiably insane. Either way, his smile and laughter is becoming infectious. (Hmm&#8230; maybe we&#8217;re all going insane&#8230;) His jovial condition proved advantageous when a car drove right into the barricaded parking lot we were using for our show. Roger looked a little ticked at first. He went to talk to the driver, an elderly woman, and pointed the direction out of the lot. Then he took a picture of the passenger. He came over and told me, giggling the whole time, that the passenger was Hazel McCallion, the mayor of Mississauga, ON. Apparently, she was visiting her sister &#8212; the driver.<br />
As usually, we received our volunteers a few minutes into the game. Normally, we&#8217;re given students or local CBC employees. I can only assume that students of sufficient age were hard to come by. This time, we received two of the oldest and kindest ladies in Campbellton. Neither really knew how to use a computer. I stood there and laughed to myself at the idea, but I knew by this point that I really didn&#8217;t matter. It&#8217;s about servicing people, not computers. So long as they reached out to those who came around, we would be successful. And since these women knew almost everyone in town (it seemed), success came easily. (The volunteers would change partway through the afternoon, and we&#8217;d get late-teenaged volunteers.)<br />
The weather had been iffy from the moment we started &#8212; cold, damp, and threatening rain &#8212; but we risked a full New Media set-up. It was the small towns that we loved all through our trip. We were hoping Campbellton would be as much a success. I kept one eye on the sky at all times.<br />
Just after noon, we already had a large crowd. We were off to a strong start. We were feeling very positive about the event (the previous two hadn&#8217;t really done anything for our self esteem). Then came a sound that we hadn&#8217;t been expecting, and initially worried us tremendously. Protesters. A large group of them marched up the street, whistling, chanting, and waving signs. I think everyone in our group froze, wondering what kind of trouble we were going to get ourselves into. At first, we thought they were protesting something we had done, or that CBC didn&#8217;t resign Ron MacLean. (Hey, some hockey fans are that devoted.)<br />
It turned out to be the local CUPE union, striking due to a lack of a contract. Some of their signs showed slogans, while others wished CBC and Radio-Canada a happy 50th birthday. In both languages! (We can only assume they did that so they would be &#8220;accepted&#8221; at the event, rather than politely asked to leave. As they caused no trouble, we didn&#8217;t see a need to have them removed. They stayed for about an hour, mingling with the crowd, seeing our displays, cheering for whomever was on stage. Eventually, they gathered back together and returned to their march.<br />
Rain came again, as dreaded. There were the odd deluges, but nothing as serious as Montreal, and all fairly brief. Also, we were on a parking lot, so we didn&#8217;t have to worry about mud. Except for Children&#8217;s, that is &#8212; they were in the low part of the parking lot. Lake CBC formed under their tent after a while, and the tent ended up having to shut down (the Mural was moved inside the VIA station to remain available). The Boutique also had to close early due to rain falling on their spare supplies.<br />
Throughout the day, we had people of all ages, all walks of life, and speaking both languages, come out to see our displays. All of them, regardless of language, loved everything. Not a single disparaging word. Even the weather didn&#8217;t seem to stop anyone from coming out.<br />
One woman in particular was one of our volunteers, Irene. She was perhaps the single most energetic person I&#8217;ve seen since leaving Vancouver. Although as part of her volunteering she made an effort to promote us, I think there was a lot of self-interest. Even when Irene&#8217;s time helping out was over, she hung around. She saw the museum, even did a stint at Be An Anchor, where she entertained the crowd by adding on the first verse of &#8220;Are You Lonely Tonight (for Seniors)&#8221; &#8230; after a lot of goading from me and several of her friends.<br />
During a lull in the activities, I made an effort to wander around Campbellton. Having never been there before, and not having been particularly on the ball (Marc&#8217;s father is from Campbellton, so assumedly, Marc knows something), I didn&#8217;t really know what too look for. The only real thing I could find was the bridge linking Campbellton with the opposite shore of the river. That, and a small, rusty narrow-gauge railway whose lineage I couldn&#8217;t figure out. (It&#8217;s not in my Trackside Guide.) Things I need to remember to research when I get home&#8230;<br />
In other places, we&#8217;ve had little trouble closing down at the end of an event. Campbellton was just such an example, until Koceila and I started turning off computers. First, all our volunteers suddenly vanished, leaving Koceila and I to tackle it alone. Also, Koceila can&#8217;t see well in the dark. And having a the local CBC station doing a broadcast next to our tent introduced issues of ownership. I think we lost a powerbar or two tonight.<br />
Even with our difficulties, we were headed for a new record for packing the train. Although the Boutique was already well away, packing up in less than two hours was still something to celebrate. Then the most stunning show of the Northern Lights sidetracked us. (The technical crew says that the lights in Biggar were better.) We stopped our heaving and shoving, and for the next half hour watched the celestial curtains flow back and forth across the sky. I know how the Northern Lights are formed, but that doesn&#8217;t take away one speck of wonder while watching them.<br />
Our train was to leave at 22:30. That left us over an hour to visit Dooley&#8217;s next door. (Literally next door &#8212; the rear entrance of the bar comes out onto the station platform.) We talked about the fun we&#8217;ve had, the show&#8217;s we&#8217;ve done, and the people we&#8217;ve met. We didn&#8217;t talk about the three remaining shows. A lot of us want the shows to be over, but a few of us don&#8217;t want this to end. This train is about to reach the light at the end of the tunnel.<br />
Three of the VIA staff were in Dooley&#8217;s with us, assumedly against rules. (I get the feeling the Service Manager didn&#8217;t know they were in the bar.) They signalled us a few minutes before 22:30, and suggested we settle the tab and get back on board. There were a few people who seemed to think we weren&#8217;t leaving on time. The train left at 10:30, as planned.<br />
After weeks of negotiation and agreements, Daryl finally got the change to climb into the cab of #6403 to film our progress as we headed east. The whole process has been ridiculous, bordering on insanity. Daryl&#8217;s filmed in the cockpits of fighter jets while in flight &#8212; something far more dangerous that sitting in the cab of a locomotive. But VIA has their rules. It wasn&#8217;t until Montreal that wheels really started turning, apparently. Only now did things finally pay off. We climbed into the Skyline dome to watch &#8220;Lord of the Rings&#8221; on DVD. Several of the others climbed into their rooms, roomettes, and berths to sleep.<br />
When I finally turned in, I rolled up my window blind to watch the passing vista. Like when we left Vancouver, it was pitch dark outside. But the sky was on fire &#8212; the Northern Lights made the heavens look like they were being ripped apart. The waves of light undulated rapidly, weaving in and out of each other, appearing suddenly and disappearing just as fast.<br />
I fell asleep watching the celestial ballet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train-campbellton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">237</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
