<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>year in review &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/year-in-review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>2012, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2012-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2012, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an unfulfilled burning need to travel, it&#8217;s truly a wonder I got out of bed in the morning.<br />
So it wasn&#8217;t with any reservation that 2012 walked out of my life on Monday night, yet it still managed to leave me rather depressed. Sadly, 2013 woke me up looking already a lot like 2012, so I&#8217;m not sure if I&#8217;m able to look at this new year with much hope yet. Instead, I suppose I shall have to try harder to make things work more my way.<br />
This not to say that I &#8220;didn&#8217;t like&#8221; 2012. It&#8217;s hard not to like an entire year in one&#8217;s life, especially one that brings so many new things to learn and experience. I just wish it hadn&#8217;t been so darned painful&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3208"></span><br />
Like I said, 2012 was a busy, busy year. So there&#8217;s no way to know if I&#8217;m going to miss anything, because I did a pretty lousy job of documenting it. I can only hope that through extracting details from Twitter, Facebook, Flickr, and my blog, that I can stir enough memories to get this all straight.</p>
<ul>
<li>Experienced our first New Year&#8217;s Tea not at the Banff Springs</li>
<li>Learned that my youngest, Choo Choo (no more than 2), was a lot smarter than I thought she was &#8230; and she only got smarter (and more defiant)</li>
<li>Saw far too few friends for far too short a time</li>
<li>Worked a lot, but not painfully so &#8212; I still had a (family) life outside of it. YAY FOR BALANCE!</li>
<li>Developed a vicious cold that led to &#8212; no word of a lie &#8212; pulled rib muscles. Owie.
<ul>
<li>Had my first chest x-ray, taken by &#8212; drum roll, please &#8212; my wife, Alex!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Discovered that Monkey loves shrimp, especially at dim sum</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t go to dim sum nearly enough</li>
<li>Had some fairly steep automobile expenses (block heater for the Jetta, and a new car for Alex)</li>
<li>Renewed a mortgage for the first time ever (instead of selling the house)</li>
<li>Continued hating, loathing, and despising having to deal with the Facebook API</li>
<li>Went through the agony, grief, despair, anger, bargaining, and acceptance of a major home renovation, as we redid our kitchen (and subsequently, floors and bathrooms)
<ul>
<li>I do so love our kitchen, though&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Found my cooking skills steadily improving
<ul>
<li>Need to watch more cooking shows, and figure out some different techniques</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Broke my little toe. Why do the little bones always hurt more?</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time ranting about how badly our Federal Government seems to want to drive Canadians to be not Canadian (specifically through bills C-11 and C-30, the ever-present Big Telco lobbies, revisiting the abortion laws, and Rob Anders)</li>
<li>Disposed of my giant water jug container of coins (6,400+ of &#8217;em)</li>
<li>Realized that building a &#8220;mobile&#8221; site is a pointless exercise, and that the design needs to adapt for all devices &lt;&#8211; my professional epiphany of the year</li>
<li>Lived (very basically) out of my contractor&#8217;s rental home for a month while our home was being torn apart</li>
<li>Celebrated Choo Choo&#8217;s 2nd Birthday</li>
<li>Cancelled TV at home, and went to internet-only for video content (still a work-in-progress)</li>
<li>Saw the original cast of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em> on stage</li>
<li>Had my first ambulance ride, my first shot of morphine, and my first (and thankfully last) bout of appendicitis
<ul>
<li>Also had a sponge bath; nowhere near as much fun as it sounds</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw <em>Avenue Q</em>. Hurt myself laughing.</li>
<li>Tried not to laugh when Monkey decided to cut Choo Choo&#8217;s hair. I failed.</li>
<li>Learned that I cannot work from home, without breaking my children&#8217;s hearts</li>
<li>Showed my children the &#8220;hole in the sun&#8221; as Venus transited our star &#8212; I think Monkey started to understand heliocentrism&#8230;</li>
<li>Exited the year wondering how RIM/Blackberry is still a going concern, and why Microsoft hadn&#8217;t fired Ballmer</li>
<li>Went to Fairmont Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Oakville</li>
<li>Went to Banff</li>
<li>Aaaaand that&#8217;s it, folks. Depressingly boring year for travel.</li>
<li>Turned 40. Or as I like to call it, &#8220;4, with an extraneous zero&#8221;.</li>
<li>Watched in real-time (delayed by 7 minutes) as Curiosity landed on the surface of Mars using the single most insane landing procedure ever conceived</li>
<li>Monkey became a 5 year old. I&#8217;ve been a parent for over <em>five years</em> now. And the world has not fallen apart (entirely). Who knew?</li>
<li>Tried to stop drinking coffee. Boy that was dumb.</li>
<li>Reminisced about being with the CBC TV 50th Anniversary project 10 years ago</li>
<li>Took Monkey to her first day of kindergarten; oddly, I didn&#8217;t cry</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that our family cannot operate without a second car</li>
<li>Made jam for the first time, and I shall do it again!</li>
<li>Made tomato sauce and tomato paste from scratch; there&#8217;s a reason they&#8217;re cheaper to buy in cans, sadly.</li>
<li>Made a &#8220;perfect&#8221; prime rib. Now I need to make it again.</li>
<li>Figured out how to make gluten-free stuffing for turkey (just need to tone down the spices a bit, as I discovered at Christmas)</li>
<li>Used a roto-tiller for the first time. Sadly, it had very dull blades, so using it hurt. A lot.</li>
<li>Felt my gut in my stomach as a man stood on the edge of the stratosphere. Then he jumped.</li>
<li>Somehow acquired strep</li>
<li>Got taken down, not by the strep, but by the stupid antibiotics I took to get rid of the strep. Go figure.</li>
<li>Had a very long night of trying to get my frozen, snow-bound car out of the airport parking lot.</li>
<li>Had a vicious cold knock me down for two days (minor flu?)</li>
<li>Got a re-learning of high school physics when I tried to vacuum up a box of baking soda. (Try it yourself, if you dare.)</li>
<li>Rode the new West LRT on the first day! Love that I take a train to work, now.</li>
<li>I saw <em>The Hobbit</em>. Yes, I liked it.</li>
<li>Had a minor outpatient surgery that didn&#8217;t exactly jingle my bells; made for an uncomfortable Christmas</li>
<li>Got an iPad mini for Christmas from my company. Had to admit that the Mini is actually a good idea.</li>
<li>Got (and installed) a Nest thermostat. I can&#8217;t stop fiddling with it.</li>
<li>Finally went sledding for the first time in two years.</li>
</ul>
<p>That brings me to the end of the year. So: busy, interesting, painful, trying, educational, somewhat wistful, and definitely productive. We&#8217;ll see what 2013 brings.<br />
I just hope it means no more trips to hospitals&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3208</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2010-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Man, it feels like a year ago since I last wrote one of these &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;) 2010 was the year we made contact &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2010, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, it feels like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/">a year ago since I last wrote one of these</a> &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;)<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_(film)">2010 was the year we made contact</a> &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named Choo Choo. It was a year I changed my career outlook (yes, again), and found that I&#8217;m not (completely) useless. This was a year of family, for me, and that&#8217;s perhaps the most important aspect.<br />
But despite all that, I hesitate to call it &#8220;a year of change&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2829"></span>Got me as to why, though. Let&#8217;s be honest, there were a lot of changes, not the least of which are the ones noted above. But at no time did I feel like this is a sudden (and possibly unwanted) shift in my life. It actually feels like things are more settled this year, despite the apparent upheaval, than in previous years. Maybe one day I&#8217;ll make some sense of that little quandary.<br />
In the meantime, let&#8217;s review 2010:</p>
<ul>
<li>Began the year with tea at the Banff Springs, seeing my friend Sonny for the first time in about 15 years</li>
<li>Started working with some old friends at a new(er) company, Evans Hunt</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton for a &#8220;surprise&#8221; weekend (mostly for Monkey) and spent a great morning in the waterslides with her</li>
<li>Celebrated my Nana&#8217;s 97th birthday, which would also sadly be her last</li>
<li>Found out that I&#8217;m K+, my kids are K+, and my wife is anti-K</li>
<li>Spent many a sleepless night worrying about Choo Choo before she was born</li>
<li>Though originally disheartened, came to love and be thrilled by the 2010 Winter Olympics in Canada, and felt the massive pride for the successes of our athletes
<ul>
<li>Yes, I Twittered obsessively during the Men&#8217;s Hockey gold medal game</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bought our first flat-screen TV, to go along with our Apple TV</li>
<li>Welcomed my youngest, (code)named Choo Choo to our world</li>
<li>Watched Monkey&#8217;s first Easter egg hunt</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;ve got something called &#8220;narrow angles&#8221; in my eyes, and got laser surgery in both of them</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller, and visited the Royal Tyrell</li>
<li>Guided (albeit not as well as I could have) the technical launch of my first all-Drupal website: VisitCalgary.com</li>
<li>Experienced the abject terror of losing your child in a mall</li>
<li>Said &#8220;thank you&#8221; to my Nana &#8212; I never say &#8220;goodbye&#8221;</li>
<li>Went on my first train chase with Monkey</li>
<li>Went to dim sum a couple of times, but not nearly enough</li>
<li>Introduced Monkey to sushi &#8212; I think she likes it</li>
<li>Went to Heritage Park a couple of times, and even saw Thomas the Tank Engine (hey, I&#8217;m a parent <em>and</em> I like trains, it&#8217;s a win-win)</li>
<li>Went to the Zoo lots (it helps to have a pass)</li>
<li>Saw a few movies, but not enough for my liking (the favourite of the year was Toy Story 3, and no, not just because I&#8217;m a parent)</li>
<li>Went on the first Great Family Roadtrip:
<ul>
<li>Overnighted in Medicine Hat, AB; Whitewood, SK; Moosimin, SK; and Swift Current, SK</li>
<li>Went to Winnipeg</li>
<li>Went to some place east of Camper, out in the middle of nowhere, as part of Alex&#8217;s family reunion</li>
<li>Stopped off in Regina, Moose Jaw, and Portage La Prairie</li>
<li>Drove the whole way and back again, and the kids didn&#8217;t seem to mind at all</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got diagnosed with a hernia (yay, me)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 3rd birthday, her first in Canada (beyond the day she was born, that is)</li>
<li>Finally got right ticked off with Shaw&#8217;s horrid home internet service, and switched over to Telus &#8230; we&#8217;ll see how it all goes</li>
<li>Did some kitchen renovation:
<ul>
<li>Installed a new sink and tap</li>
<li>Tore out the Florida ceiling</li>
<li>Installed new lighting</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had new windows installed in the house</li>
<li>Returned to being a developer, rather than a pure manager (I&#8217;m still adjusting to this one)</li>
<li>Took Monkey out on her first real Hallowe&#8217;en</li>
<li>Grew a moustache for Movember (my first, and last time)</li>
<li>Went to the Currie Barracks location of the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market almost every weekend for a year, until the location finally (and sadly) closed in December</li>
<li>Went on our first family flight out to Abbotsford, to spend Christmas in BC</li>
<li>Visited with some old friends from Radical Entertainment</li>
<li>Went to downtown Vancouver for the first time in about five years, and remembered how much I love it there</li>
<li>Had my first green Christmas in many, many years</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains</li>
</ul>
<p>Whoof. That&#8217;s a lot for one year. Can&#8217;t wait to see what 2011 throws at me. Bring it, New Year &#8212; I&#8217;m ready for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A year in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/a-year-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-year-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/a-year-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 19:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning was cool and wet, something I can say with confidence to be a rarity here in the Central Valley region of Costa Rica. I can say this because today marks my first anniversary in Costa Rica. One year ago today, I moved from my comfort in Canada, tucking my poor cat Asia into &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/a-year-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A year in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This morning was cool and wet, something I can say with confidence to be a rarity here in the Central Valley region of Costa Rica. I can say this because today marks my first anniversary in Costa Rica. One year ago today, I moved from my comfort in Canada, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/">tucking my poor cat Asia</a> into the space under the seat in front of me, and braved the 14-hour trip south (counting the six hours one spends in Houston during the layover).<br />
It&#8217;s been a year of utter chaos, extreme stress (I now look back at what I used to think was stressful, and have realised a tremendous amount of new strength), and unbelievable challenge and testing. It&#8217;s been mixed with wondrous discovery, gorgeous vistas (even though we&#8217;re hours from a beach), many new friends, and a truest definition of experience: skills and memories that can&#8217;t be acquired any other way.<br />
<span id="more-1397"></span>Yes, I can already hear you asking the question: So it&#8217;s been a year in. What do I think after all this?<br />
It&#8217;s been a tough ride, and the ride is far from over. We&#8217;ve had to learn a lot to work down here, we&#8217;ve had to work with a lot of people, and those aforementioned unbelievable challenges have made life interesting down here. That, and until a little while ago, Murphy lived in my broom closet.<br />
I&#8217;ve bitched about a few things that have driven me crazy, and I&#8217;m happy to say that some of them don&#8217;t bug me as much as they did. It&#8217;s a form of acceptance / complacency, I suspect, but some of it is also understanding more about how things work here and not trying to force my way of thinking onto them.<br />
Well, that, and I&#8217;ve got a few people who know shield me from having to deal with some of those things day after day.<br />
I still feel like an outsider, though. Simple reality: I&#8217;m gringo, and I don&#8217;t speak serviceable Spanish. I can get by in simple situations, but I find myself often asking for people to repeat things, and I get stumped easily when trying to give even simple instructions. Reason? Lack of practice. I default to English too easily, so I never get to reinforce my own habits.<br />
It&#8217;s, as the saying goes, all part of the fun. (Though I will say that not everything has been fun. See above note about extreme stress.) It&#8217;s all part of experience, and education, and being someplace that&#8217;s not as familiar as home.<br />
Above all else, it really helps me appreciate how things are in North America. For all the trivial complaints that I hear from my friends (and used to have myself), I now realise how good things really are, and that most North Americans have no idea how good they have it.<br />
Sure, you can go on vacation to far-flung places in the world and see things you&#8217;d never see at home. But you&#8217;re a tourist in all senses of the word. You&#8217;ll never experience what it&#8217;s like because you know, even in the back of your head, that you&#8217;re going home. There&#8217;s escape (most of the time). But when you&#8217;ve moved to a new country, it doesn&#8217;t work the same way.<br />
Do I miss Canada? Well, does a Hoser drink beer? Same answer. Of course I miss my birth country. There&#8217;s so much about nearly every part of Canada that I miss. Being in a tropical country is hard for many reasons, not the least of which is language and temperature (I&#8217;ve been wearing shorts and sandals for a year &#8212; I&#8217;m uncomfortably warm most of the time). But it&#8217;s also the distance from family and our friends.<br />
I don&#8217;t have any friends outside of the ones I work with down here. The internet is there to keep me connected with friends both home and abroad, but the reality is that here I often feel very alone. That&#8217;s a part of the last year I&#8217;ve struggled with nearly every day. When things go horribly wrong, when you&#8217;re stressed beyond reason, when all you want to do is rant about how things are, that&#8217;s when a friend helps most.<br />
Slowly, things change. Things get better. And things will get better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/a-year-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1397</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2008, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2008-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 18:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hasta la vista, 2008! You were a tough year in the life, and while you certainly gave me a good run, I&#8217;m not unhappy to see you go. You&#8217;ve lead me further down the road of fatherhood, brought me back dear old friends, brought me new challenges at work &#8230; and of course moved me &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2008, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hasta la vista, 2008! You were a tough year in the life, and while you certainly gave me a good run, I&#8217;m not unhappy to see you go. You&#8217;ve lead me further down the road of fatherhood, brought me back dear old friends, brought me new challenges at work &#8230; and of course moved me to an entirely different country. But with all of this, you&#8217;ve brought a whole mess of turmoil, instability, and grief.  <br />
Now for those of you who&#8217;ve not been following along &#8212; and what the heck, even for those of you have &#8212; here&#8217;s what I&#8217;m talking about:<span id="more-1212"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Started the year with a big decision: move to Costa Rica and help start up a new business</li>
<li>Marvelled in the wonder of my daughter learning how to speak, and starting her first unaided steps (of course now we need a homing beacon and a volume setting, but that&#8217;s another story)</li>
<li>Came to the heavily sobering reality that I am not my father, and finally agreed that we needed a contractor to finish the redevelopment of our basement</li>
<li>Was extremely happy to see the basement finally complete</li>
<li>Switched briefly to a Mac before switching back to a PC (too many issues with emails and meetings); I now curse the reality that I wish I were on one</li>
<li>Came down with an evil flu, despite getting a flu shot</li>
<li>Saw my first NBA game</li>
<li>Went to Chicago</li>
<li>Went to San Francisco</li>
<li>Went to Santa Cruz (and went for a sailboat trip out on the ocean)</li>
<li>Went to Las Vegas</li>
<li>Went to London</li>
<li>Went to Glasgow</li>
<li>Went to Oban</li>
<li>Went to Iona</li>
<li>Went to Inverness</li>
<li>Went to Edinburgh (albeit briefly)</li>
<li>Went to York</li>
<li>Went to Costa Rica twice in three weeks &#8230; the second time to move there</li>
<li>Haven&#8217;t returned to Canada since mid-July (went to bring my family down)</li>
<li>Went to Panama City twice</li>
<li>Saw the Panama Canal (and a ship travel through the locks)</li>
<li>Went to Toronto</li>
<li>Went to Oakville and Burlington</li>
<li>Went to Punta Leona</li>
<li>Went to Montezuma</li>
<li>Went to Arenal (again)</li>
<li>Went into San José many times</li>
<li>Went to New York City for Christmas</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains (despite going to the UK)</li>
<li>Attended the Web 2.0 conference</li>
<li>Learnt to drive Costa Rican-style</li>
<li>ComenzÃ³ a aprender español</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of my friend Sean</li>
<li>Missed my many friends dearly &#8212; one feels very alone and separated down here</li>
<li>Made more new friends</li>
<li>Bought a new used car (for far more than it should have cost&#8230;)</li>
<li>Got a traffic ticket for pulling a u-turn</li>
<li>Went to a Costa Rican soccer, er futbol game</li>
<li>Tried to encourage my former co-Calgarians to vote Jim Prentice out of office (sadly, it was likely too little, too late)</li>
<li>Experienced considerable grief with our internet connections, both at home and at work</li>
<li>Actually managed to get a decent Thanksgiving meal in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Felt two earthquakes, one of which I almost slept through</li>
<li>Drank my first cup of coffee (current tally: 15)</li>
<li>Got to experience Halloween in a different country</li>
<li>Came to loathe Costa Rican traffic</li>
<li>Had our first Costa Rican office Christmas party</li>
<li>Saw the fireworks for New Year&#8217;s Eve</li>
</ul>
<p>So that brings us into 2009. I wonder what this year will bring us?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2007, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/2007-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2007-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/2007-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2008 15:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/02/2007-a-year-in-review/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just realised &#8212; after I&#8217;d already posted this year&#8217;s review &#8212; that this is the 10th one I&#8217;ve done. Ten years already! Man&#8230; I&#8217;ve been doing this longer than I&#8217;d thought! It&#8217;s that time of the year again &#8212; to look back on the year passed, and reflect on the things I&#8217;ve done. Where &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/2007-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2007, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just realised &#8212; after I&#8217;d already posted this year&#8217;s review &#8212; that <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/year-in-review/">this is the 10th one I&#8217;ve done</a>. Ten years already! Man&#8230; I&#8217;ve been doing this longer than I&#8217;d thought!<br />
It&#8217;s that time of the year again &#8212; to look back on the year passed, and reflect on the things I&#8217;ve done. Where did I go? What did I do? What have I honestly got to show for myself. It&#8217;s been an insanely long year. Sure, it was still 365 (and 1/4) days, but it felt at least three times longer&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-884"></span>Before I dive into the bullets, yes there is one overriding event that outclasses everything else I did in 2007:</p>
<p align="center"><strong>I became a father.</strong></p>
<p align="left">Absolutely nothing else tops it. Not the trip around the world, not the CBC adventure, not getting promoted, not moving to a new city, not even seeing old friends (as truly awesome as that is). Being a dad is an experience I never truly experienced until now. And it&#8217;s an experience that I get to have each and every day, that changes almost daily, for the rest of my life.</p>
<p align="left">No way could that ever be eclipsed.</p>
<p align="left">Anyway, this is the other stuff I got around to last year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Upgraded this blog to run on WordPress, and I&#8217;m never looking back</li>
<li>Also upgraded from storing pictures through the blog to storing pictures on Flickr &#8212; a far better solution</li>
<li>Went to Tamara&#8217;s dad&#8217;s funeral</li>
<li>Had some very good discussions about how Calgary Transit needs to improve</li>
<li>Helped Tamara get another job at Critical Mass</li>
<li>Saw the Rankin Family perform</li>
<li>Guided the launch of the new Rolex.com website (a Herculean effort by my team)</li>
<li>Went to Huntington Beach, CA for a conference</li>
<li>Went to Ruskin (Maple Ridge), BC twice</li>
<li>Went to Beaverton, ON for my friend Kathryn&#8217;s wedding</li>
<li>Went to Huntsville, ON</li>
<li>Went to Oakville, ON for a night</li>
<li>Went to the Big Island of Hawaii
<ul>
<li>Had my bag lost</li>
<li>Went to a sunset luau</li>
<li>Swam with the dolphins (sort of)</li>
<li>Almost got suckered into a timeshare</li>
<li>Saw the Kilauea volcano</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Complained about Air Canada&#8217;s continuing dip in service</li>
<li>Sold our house in Garrison Woods, and bought a house in Westgate. And moved. Again. Ugh.</li>
<li>Started to renovate the basement:
<ul>
<li>Tore out the old basement in its entirety</li>
<li>Build new walls</li>
<li>Had a new heating system installed (I didn&#8217;t do it, though &#8212; I ain&#8217;t <em>that </em>crazy)</li>
<li>Had a new air circulation (and heating for upstairs) system installed</li>
<li>Had plumbing for new appliances and a bathroom installed</li>
<li>Had the electrical panel moved, meter put outside, new service installed, and put in electrical sockets around the basement (myself)</li>
<li>Laid down flooring (rather poorly, it would now seem &#8212; too many damned gaps)</li>
<li>Installed insulation and put up drywall in the largest room</li>
<li>Did most of the flooring and drywalling in one week while Alex and baby were in Ruskin</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had too many friends leave the city</li>
<li>Said farewell to my friend Rich, who passed away in May</li>
<li>Rode the zipline at Canada Olympic Park twice</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;m pretty good at laying sod</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t have nearly enough dim sum</li>
<li>Chased CP 2816 from Calgary to Canmore</li>
<li>Nearly injured myself badly pruning a tree (just don&#8217;t tell Alex!)</li>
<li>Got a new camera lens</li>
<li>Taunted people with fake birth announcement entries on the blog (I&#8217;m such a jerk)</li>
<li>Was a partial recipient (with the rest of my business unit) of a TP&#8217;ing</li>
<li>Really realised just how long I&#8217;ve been in this industry, and how much I&#8217;ve seen</li>
</ul>
<p>And I had a great Christmas break, since most people I work with were taking a MUCH needed vacation, and I got to relax with my now-expanded family. I hope you got time to spend with yours!<br />
As for this year, no resolutions (I follow the belief that if you have to wait until 1 January to set resolutions, you&#8217;re not really looking to change) &#8212; though I do have a big plan in the works. And for now, that&#8217;s all you&#8217;re going to know about it.<br />
No, it&#8217;s not another baby. That&#8217;s coming later. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/2007-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">884</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2006, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/2006-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2006-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/2006-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2007 14:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2007/01/03/2006-a-year-in-review/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wow, what another roller coaster year. Highs, lows, excitement, disappointment, joy, sorrow, laughter, and pain. Things I regret, things I wish I did, things I wish I didn&#8217;t do. Lots of potential, lots of opportunity. And if nothing else, a validation that I do finally seem to understand the job I have and how to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/2006-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2006, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wow, what another roller coaster year. Highs, lows, excitement, disappointment, joy, sorrow, laughter, and pain. Things I regret, things I wish I did, things I wish I didn&#8217;t do. Lots of potential, lots of opportunity. And if nothing else, a validation that I do finally seem to understand the job I have and how to do it. It ain&#8217;t perfect but at least it&#8217;s a start.<br />
<span id="more-596"></span>So on with the recap of 2006:</p>
<ul>
<li>Was disappointed that the Tories came back into power, but so far have been impressed that they haven&#8217;t rolled back the clock 30 years &#8230; yet</li>
<li>Took this website back from a WordPress blog to a hand-coded blog &#8230; then started the switch back when I couldn&#8217;t keep up with the work</li>
<li>Got really pissed off when Starbucks canned the Chantico</li>
<li>Attended my first CMMY (and got an iPod!)</li>
<li>Ranted. A lot.</li>
<li>Picked up our new kitty, Asia, from the SPCA and have had fuzzy therapy every day since</li>
<li>Bade farewell to far too many good friends</li>
<li>Listened to the VP of Marketing for Google Canada, and lamented that the engineers do better presentations</li>
<li>Went to Honolulu, HI</li>
<li>Saw where WWII began in the Pacific</li>
<li>Went to (and all the way around) Kauai, HI</li>
<li>Went on a cruise and saw whales</li>
<li>Experienced my first and second luaus</li>
<li>Went to Maple Ridge, BC several times</li>
<li>Went to Montreal, QC</li>
<li>Experienced Earth Day on an apple farm in southern Quebec</li>
<li>Went to London, UK</li>
<li>Saw Buckingham Palace</li>
<li>Went to York, UK</li>
<li>Visited the National Railway Museum in only 30 minutes (far too quickly!)</li>
<li>Went to Glasgow, UK</li>
<li>Went to Ayr, UK</li>
<li>Went to Edinburgh, UK</li>
<li>Froze on Calton Hill during a festival</li>
<li>Went to Belfast, Northern Ireland</li>
<li>Drove around Northern Ireland in a car too large for most of the roads</li>
<li>Walked the Giant&#8217;s Causeway and Carrick-a-Rede bridge</li>
<li>Went to Castleblaney, Ireland</li>
<li>Went to Newtownards, Northern Ireland</li>
<li>Went to Dublin, Ireland</li>
<li>Drank Guinness from its home town</li>
<li>Visited the Guinness Brewery &#8230; sort of</li>
<li>Stayed at a castle</li>
<li>Drove from the east to west coast of Ireland and back in two days, visiting:
<ul>
<li>Tara Hill</li>
<li>Trim</li>
<li>Clonmacnoise</li>
<li>Shannonbridge</li>
<li>The Burren (and the Poulnabrone Dolmen)</li>
<li>Doolin</li>
<li>Cliffs of Moher</li>
<li>Newmarket-on-Fergus (and the wonderful Kells B&amp;B)</li>
<li>Bunratty Castle</li>
<li>Limerick (well, <em>through</em> Limerick)</li>
<li>Cashel (and the Rock of Cashel)</li>
<li>Carrick on Suir</li>
<li>Ballyhale (and really bad pizza)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Went to Bow Lake and Num-Ti-Jah Lodge</li>
<li>Went to Revelstoke and Three Valley Gap</li>
<li>Went to Paris (on business, but did get to see a fair bit despite exhaustion)</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton, AB (on business)</li>
<li>Went to Banff, AB several times</li>
<li>Went to London, ON</li>
<li>Went to Oakville, ON</li>
<li>Went to St. Thomas, ON</li>
<li>Moved my desk to the best spot in the building (lucky me!)</li>
<li>Saw Stuart McLean twice, though only once in concert (front row at the Banff Centre)</li>
<li>Met my niece for the first time</li>
<li>Ripped the deck out of the backyard and laid down grass</li>
<li>Repaired the hot tub (again) &#8212; what a money pit!</li>
<li>Stopped driving to work and biked</li>
<li>Stopped biking to work (when it got too dark and nearly got creamed by a car) and took the bus</li>
<li>Stopped taking the bus when I realized Calgary Transit sucks and went back to driving</li>
<li>Did an article for the CBC on my experiences on the CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train</li>
<li>Was paid a visit by Chris and Kaz</li>
<li>Had the first game night with the Asian Brother Crew since Chris left</li>
<li>Started using video conferencing extensively, and really marveling at what the technology can do</li>
<li>Saw Cirque du Soliel&#8217;s <em>Delirium</em></li>
<li>Unclogged a sink without losing my pants</li>
<li>Realized I can still tell when a hard drive is about to fail</li>
</ul>
<p>and of course:</p>
<ul>
<li>Worked way too hard for my own good</li>
</ul>
<p>But that&#8217;s to be expected, non? There&#8217;s one other thing that&#8217;s not on this list. But I can&#8217;t let that cat outta the bag just yet&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/2006-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">596</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2005, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/01/2005-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2005-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/01/2005-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2006 04:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/01/02/2005-year-in-review/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, last year was a quiet one for information on me. Many reasons, none of which I&#8217;m going to bother to detail here. (One, you don&#8217;t need to know. Two, I really don&#8217;t feel like having to explain everything.) So, in as much of a nutshell as I can do (given that I&#8217;m likely to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/01/2005-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2005, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, last year was a quiet one for information on me. Many reasons, none of which I&#8217;m going to bother to detail here. (One, you don&#8217;t need to know. Two, I really don&#8217;t feel like having to explain everything.)<br />
<span id="more-419"></span>So, in as much of a nutshell as I can do (given that I&#8217;m likely to miss a few things), here&#8217;s what last year was all about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Got engaged (yeah, that was pretty much the first thing of the year)</li>
<li>Went to Chicago</li>
<li>Went to New York City (for the first time since September, 1998)</li>
<li>Sold my house</li>
<li>Bought a house</li>
<li>Got rid of my 1991 Plymouth Acclaim &#8212; finally!</li>
<li>Went to Radium, BC</li>
<li>Went around the world, including the following places:
<ul>
<li>Seattle</li>
<li>San Francisco</li>
<li>London Heathrow</li>
<li>Paddington Station</li>
<li>Hyde Park</li>
<li>Covent Gardens</li>
<li>Trafalgar Square</li>
<li>Big Ben</li>
<li>St. Petersburg</li>
<li>Hermitage Winter Palace</li>
<li>Tsarkoe Selo</li>
<li>Moscow</li>
<li>Kremlin (the Armoury, to be specific)</li>
<li>Arbat Street</li>
<li>Segijev Posad (formerly Zagorsk)</li>
<li>Kazan</li>
<li>Yekaterinburg (formerly Svedlovsk)</li>
<li>Krasnoyarsk (briefly)</li>
<li>Irkustsk</li>
<li>Listvyanka</li>
<li>Lake Baykal</li>
<li>Ulan Ude</li>
<li>Ivolginsky Datsan</li>
<li>Naushky</li>
<li>Sukbaatar</li>
<li>Ulan Baatar</li>
<li>The middle of the Mongolian Desert (approx.  <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=47%C2%B024%2758.20%22N+103%C2%B039%2725.13%22E&amp;ll=47.416241,103.657036&amp;spn=0.153095,0.336456&amp;t=k">47 °24&#8217;58.20&#8243;N 103 °39&#8217;25.13&#8243;E</a>)</li>
<li>Erdene Zuu</li>
<li>Hustai National Park</li>
<li>Beijing</li>
<li>Tiananmen Square</li>
<li>Tianjin</li>
<li>Muyitanu (Great Wall)</li>
<li>Beijing Summer Palace</li>
<li>Forbidden City</li>
<li>Shanghai</li>
<li>Xi&#8217;an</li>
<li>Terra Cotta Warriors</li>
<li>Guangzhou</li>
<li>Tsim Tsa Tsui</li>
<li>Hong Kong</li>
<li>Stanley Beach</li>
<li>Macau</li>
<li>Kowloon</li>
<li>Shek Lap Kok</li>
<li>Narita</li>
<li>Yotsukaido</li>
<li>Chiba</li>
<li>Tokyo</li>
<li>Nara</li>
<li>Osaka</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got promoted</li>
<li>Got buried under six months&#8217; of heavy work</li>
<li>Went to Sylvan Lake</li>
<li>Moved into the new house</li>
<li>Competed in the 2005 Calgary Dragon Boat festival</li>
<li>Went to Ruskin, BC</li>
<li>Got married (seems like a minor point in all this, doesn&#8217;t it?)</li>
<li>Went to Greenville, SC (client meetings)</li>
<li>Went to Oakville, ON</li>
<li>Bought a lot of new furniture at IKEA</li>
<li>Started working on the new Rolex account</li>
<li>Went to Cranbrook, BC</li>
<li>Got a speeding ticket</li>
<li>Went to Ruskin, BC again (for a funeral)</li>
<li>Celebrated Christmas in the house</li>
<li>Made Christmas dinner for a large group of people (forgot the cranberries!)</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;m missing a few things, but that&#8217;s the bulk of it. It was a rough year, to be sure &#8212; one of the hardest for me in a long time. I made mistakes and poor decisions that will likely haunt me for a long while. But then, that&#8217;s life, isn&#8217;t it? Sadly, few things in this world are perfect, and you must contend with the consequences of your actions (or inactions).<br />
This year? Who knows what will come my way. Hopefully not the same rollercoaster ride again (as much as I love the change, I can only stand so many peaks and valleys before losing my marbles).<br />
Bring it on&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/01/2005-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">419</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2004, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/01/2004-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2004-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/01/2004-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2005 04:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/01/03/2004-year-in-review/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2004 wasn&#8217;t exactly what I&#8217;d call a tumultuous year, but it was certainly marked with some pretty big events for me, not the least of which was meeting Alex. If there was a number one in the list, she would be it. 2005 is already looking to be an interesting year, since there are a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/01/2004-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2004, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2004 wasn&#8217;t exactly what I&#8217;d call a tumultuous year, but it was certainly marked with some pretty big events for me, not the least of which was meeting Alex. If there was a number one in the list, she would be it. 2005 is already looking to be an interesting year, since there are a lot of things that will be happening for me. It&#8217;s not going to be an easy year, but if we always had easy years, we&#8217;d never feel a sense of accomplishment.<br />
<span id="more-402"></span>And on with my little year in review&#8230;</p>
<ul>
<li>Tried my first hand at blackjack &#8230; didn&#8217;t do too well</li>
<li>Watched in awe as Luke paid over $1,000,000 (in funny money) to buy a coffee maker</li>
<li>Saw David Bowie at Calgary (Pengrowth) Saddledome from the eighth row</li>
<li>&#8220;Discovered&#8221; The Polyphonic Spree, and realized that, yes, Macy Gray is a bit of a freak job</li>
<li>Team built with the Mercedes-Benz USA marketing team in a frigid cold downtown Calgary, and got cheated out of a well-deserved win! (No, I&#8217;m not bitter about it, but I can&#8217;t resist noting that fact!)</li>
<li>Was saddened by the departure of my friend and physical health mentor, Arthur, from Critical Mass (and Calgary)</li>
<li>Got very, very drunk at his going away party</li>
<li>Started taking yoga</li>
<li>Realized that changes to my dental plan were downright ugly, and that I was quite literally paying through the mouth for it</li>
<li>Flew to Montreal to visit Therese and Stuart</li>
<li>Remembered French I had thought long since forgotten</li>
<li>Went to Oakville twice</li>
<li>Went to Waterloo</li>
<li>Went to Stettler</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller</li>
<li>Went to Banff (Bamf!) several times</li>
<li>Went to Japan for the second time in a year</li>
<li>Went to Yotsukaido</li>
<li>Went to Tokyo</li>
<li>Went to Toyohashi</li>
<li>Went to Irako</li>
<li>Went to Hiroshima</li>
<li>Went to Miyajima</li>
<li>Went to Kyoto</li>
<li>Went to Osaka</li>
<li>Went to Chiba</li>
<li>Went to Kamakura</li>
<li>Went to Kelowna</li>
<li>Went to Canmore</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton</li>
<li>Went to Fairmont Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Radium Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Invermere</li>
<li>Went to Cranbrook</li>
<li>Went to (or rather, though) Golden</li>
<li>Went to Ruskin (outskirts of Maple Ridge)</li>
<li>Went to Three Valley Gap</li>
<li>Went to Takkakaw Falls</li>
<li>Went to San Jose (California)</li>
<li>Went to Denver &#8230; sorta</li>
<li>Went to San Francisco &#8230; Airport</li>
<li>Took Montreal&#8217;s AMT commuter train for the first time</li>
<li>Visited Gare Windsor</li>
<li>Visited what was the Montreal Forum (home of Les Habitants!)</li>
<li>Roamed around Montreal&#8217;s underground malls</li>
<li>Ate at Schwartz&#8217;s Deli &#8230; I can still taste the corned beef (*droooool*)</li>
<li>Saw more of Montreal than I had seen in several previous visits</li>
<li>Took a VIA train from Montreal to Toronto</li>
<li>Saw VIA #6403 (the CBC locomotive)</li>
<li>Saw my friend Kathryn for the first time since Cathy&#8217;s wedding</li>
<li>Saw my friends (and old roommates) Ed and Brian (Ed, a year and a half; Brian, about four years)</li>
<li>Fixed my mother&#8217;s and sister&#8217;s computers more than a few times</li>
<li>Saw my friend Kim</li>
<li>Realized that the old Terminal 1 no longer exists at Pearson International Airport</li>
<li>Was happy to see that Peter Jackson got appropriate recognition for the &#8220;Lord of the Rings&#8221; trilogy</li>
<li>Took Jen out to Japanese restaurants to get her ready for eating in Japan (hey, it&#8217;s a good reason to try sushi)</li>
<li>Found getting into Japan a lot less stressful than last year (&#8216;course, I was ready for it this time)</li>
<li>Took several shinkansen while in Japan</li>
<li>Met Chris&#8217; friend Tony</li>
<li>Re-met Chris&#8217; friend Shinichiro</li>
<li>Stayed at a hotel overlooking a beautiful bay on coastal Japan</li>
<li>Played in a Japanese bowling alley</li>
<li>Walked down a beach near the hotel</li>
<li>Went to Chris and Kaz&#8217;s wedding (I cried)</li>
<li>Went to five wedding parties for Chris and Kaz (four in Japan, one in Canada)</li>
<li>Saw Chris&#8217; parents</li>
<li>Met Chris&#8217; uncle Garth</li>
<li>Ate a lot of strange things for breakfast</li>
<li>Ate an unbelievable amount of food at Chris&#8217; family reception (the first of the five)</li>
<li>Went to a restaurant barely four hours later for another large meal (reception number two)</li>
<li>Went to an izakaya for the third reception (all of these in a single day!)</li>
<li>Saw the Hiroshima Atomic Bomb dome (and surrounding museums and monuments)</li>
<li>Received blessings for happiness from an elderly woman</li>
<li>Traveled to Miyajima, and found what I can only describe as a slice of heaven on Earth</li>
<li>Caught a cab in Kyoto and worried for a moment that we would forever be lost inside the city</li>
<li>Took the Temple Lane in Kyoto, visiting Teapot Alley</li>
<li>Took several trains to get to Mt. Hiei</li>
<li>Visited Enryaku-ji temple</li>
<li>Visited the Osaka Aquarium</li>
<li>Broke an air hockey table at an adjacent arcade (oops!)</li>
<li>Visited Osaka Castle</li>
<li>Went up Kyoto Tower to take pictures</li>
<li>Went to the Kyoto Imperial Palace grounds, but couldn&#8217;t get into the palace itself (it was a Saturday)</li>
<li>Got to stay at Chris and Kaz&#8217;s new apartment in Yotsukaido</li>
<li>Helped move Chris out of his old apartment into the new one</li>
<li>Tried okonomiyaki for the first time</li>
<li>Saw &#8220;Zatoichi: The Blind Master&#8221;</li>
<li>Experienced my first earthquake that actually moved something</li>
<li>Went to the fourth reception party in Chiba</li>
<li>Did a load of laundry in Japan &#8230; a decidedly different experience</li>
<li>Took Jen around to some of the hot spots of Tokyo</li>
<li>Went to Tsukiji Market (twice, once to see the actual fish auctions)</li>
<li>Wandered through Ginza, seeing both Sony&#8217;s headquarters and the infamous Apple Store</li>
<li>Saw the Great Buddha of Kamakura</li>
<li>Marvelled at all the sakura (cherry blossoms)</li>
<li>Flew from Tokyo to Vancouver to Calgary to Kelowna &#8230; never doing that again</li>
<li>Saw David Bowie (again!) at Prospera Place</li>
<li>Went curling for the first time</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/01/2004-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">402</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
