<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>new york &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/new-york/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.   Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?   So, where to start?   &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.  <br />
Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?  <br />
So, where to start?  <br />
<span id="more-1199"></span>We didn&#8217;t want to stick around the hotel any longer &#8212; the breakfasts here are so darned expensive considering the quality you get. So we opted to head off to a place Alex wanted to see: Alice&#8217;s Teacup, a teahouse up on 64th. Sadly, despite the published opening time at 8:00, the place wasn&#8217;t opening until 10:00. So we adjourned to the French restaurant we spotted along the way.  <br />
By the time we got back to the hotel, Mom was trying to check in. (Such began the longest check-in process I have ever experienced at a hotel.) We gathered together, chatted, and almost immediately put Mi Pequeña Niña to bed. It was nap time, and she was getting a little cranky. She didn&#8217;t wake up again until we stirred her until just after noon, at which point we all headed out for lunch.  <br />
My bright idea? Finding an eatery at Grand Central Terminal.  <br />
Yes, it&#8217;s the train thing. Suck it up. I haven&#8217;t seen a real train in months.  <br />
We found Michael Jordan&#8217;s (I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s related to the basketball player) where we endulged in some seriously tasty edibles. (I think MPN got the best of all of us &#8212; her macaroni and cheese was fantastic). While we were there, we were entertained by a lightshow that was going on in the main concourse, which kept MPN completely fascinated.  <br />
We strolled a bit, but ended up back at the hotel before long, about in time for MPN to crash again. Which was about the time Alex and I started planning our night out. It&#8217;s part of the reason Mom came down &#8212; to keep an eye on MPN while Alex and I tried to paint the town &#8230; well, maybe not red so much as pink.  <br />
We walked to Times Square (again) and started our task at finding a place to see a movie, which was a lot harder than it seems. There are two movie theatres in the area (Regal and AMC), and you have to figure out which movie that you want to see is at which theatre. Which was about when Alex made it clear to me that she needed to eat dinner. That led us to some diner just south of Times Square with the driest chicken I ever ate. (But, admittedly, I&#8217;ve had worse.)<br />
The movie, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was Bedtime Stories. Overall, a well done movie. And I&#8217;m still giggling at Russell Brand&#8217;s rendition of Sleep Panic Disorder. Then we hit the Virgin Megastore for more movies. I had a serious need for a movie fix.  <br />
This morning started a little different, and much more slowly than the previous mornings. We headed off to the Waldorf Astoria (the next block south) for breakfast, and then returned for MPN to have another nap. By the time she awoke, it was time for luch, which was at Au Bon Pain a couple of blocks away. We hopped a cab and about 25 minutes later we were at the Cloisters Museum, a branch of the Met up at the north end of Manhattan island.  <br />
Barely 2 minutes after arriving, Alex realised in a panic that the little backpack that she uses to carry MPN&#8217;s stuff (and her wallet) were in the bag, and the bag was still in the taxi, now departed from the Cloisters. That sent me to a phone to cancel the credit card, and list a missing bag with the Taxi and Limosine Commission. That said, I was also told that it&#8217;ll be a cold day in hell before we get this stuff back, due to the way that the taxis run in this city. Which, I have to admit, is a little odd.  <br />
The Cloisters, for the record, is one of New York City&#8217;s unspoken gems. It&#8217;s out of the way, admittedly, which is why, but it is gorgeous. It was like the churches I saw in England, Scotland, and Ireland (although most of it came from France). Absolutely wonderful! I can see why Mark has said that he wants to hold his wedding there. (Well, when he gets around to getting married, that is.)  <br />
The driver of the hired car we took on the way back really didn&#8217;t listen to me and ended up taking us through Times Square. The hard way. (Believe me, there are easier ways.) He apologised for the mistake, and didn&#8217;t charge us what he should have charged us if he&#8217;d had a meter running.  <br />
Dinner was at a place called Bobby Van&#8217;s, a steakhouse on 54th between Lexington and Park Ave. We were perhaps a bit underdressed, but the meal was fantastic. I&#8217;m going to have such a steak hangover in the morning. And I&#8217;m going to revel in it as much as possible.  <br />
But until then, I&#8217;m exhausted, and looking forward to going home. (That&#8217;s Costa Rica, in case you&#8217;re not sure.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 02:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merry Ho Ho, everyone!   Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Merry Ho Ho, everyone!  <br />
Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For those of you keeping track, I&#8217;m at 12 coffees since I started.)  <br />
Then it was back for present opening. &#8216;Cuz it just ain&#8217;t Christmas without presents.  <br />
<span id="more-1196"></span>Due to our travel plans, Alex and I opted not to actually get each other presents. Instead, we went for the &#8220;Aw, Honey, You Shouldn&#8217;t Have!&#8221; move where we buy what we want for ourselves, and then thank the other for being so thoughtful. (Yes, it borders heavily on the extremely lame, but we neither need or want much, and it&#8217;s just easier to do it this way rather than try to bring it all, or remember what the other wants and try to purchase it when you&#8217;re rarely alone). Alex already did her book run earlier in the week. I might never get a chance to do mine, and I&#8217;m okay with that. Lately, I&#8217;ve been realising that I haven&#8217;t cared as much about me as I have about Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña.  <br />
The scavenger hunt wasn&#8217;t long &#8212; the presents were easy to find for Megan (that&#8217;s the point) and we didn&#8217;t have a chance to wrap anything. There will be wrapped presents back in Costa Rica, but for now she&#8217;ll do without. She found her new books in her stocking, her new shirts, and Yorkie (the name we gave to the stuffed dog). Then came much playing with all of them while we tried to find some sort of Christmas movie on TV. The best we could do was <em>Bad Santa</em>. Not exactly a kid-friendly movie.  <br />
We chatted with Cathy, Craig, and their kids (well, Tori &#8212; Natalee the newborn babe seems to be asleep every time we see her) &#8212; and my mom &#8212; while they were having breakfast, awaiting the time we could call Allen. Sadly, we had problems lining up our time with Allen, so we eventually had to give up and start working on our day. Bundling up, it was time for our Christmas Day excursion to the Central Park Zoo.  <br />
New York City never slows down, never stops. Even Christmas Day, traffic is bustling, people are everywhere, stops (some) are open, and it&#8217;s almost business as usual. It&#8217;s truly my kind of town! (No, I doubt I&#8217;ll ever get a chance to live here.) We walked from our hotel at 51st and Lexington to Central Park, watching all the people and wondering if we bundled up Megan well enough for the brisker-than-it-first-felt weather. In the end she seemed fine, and didn&#8217;t complain about the cold. (She would later complain about missing a nap.)  <br />
The Central Park Zoo isn&#8217;t what I thought it would be. Again, damn you Hollywood!, my vision wasn&#8217;t what it was. No attention-hogging lions, no wise-cracking zebras, no hypochondriatic giraffes, and no pushy hippos. Mind you, I could swear one of the penguins looked like he was up to something. (Mind you, it could have been a &#8220;her&#8221; &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to tell.)  <br />
Don&#8217;t get me wrong, the Central Park Zoo is really a wonderful place on Christmas Day. Not only does the clock chime Christmas Carols, but it&#8217;s not really busy, and easy to get around. It doesn&#8217;t hurt that the place is miniscule &#8212; literally the smallest zoo I&#8217;ve ever been to. (I&#8217;ve been to petting zoos that were larger.) Good use of the space, I should add.  <br />
By the time we were leaving, MPN was rapidly approaching meltdown due to lack of sleep. It was a near-race to get back to the hotel and get her down. Along the way, I ended up having to carry her (it calms her down), and before long I had a little bobble head baby &#8212; she was literally falling asleep and trying to sit in my arms. I leaned her forward into my chest and that was that &#8212; she went deadweight. Alex and I took the opportunity to go into the Oxford Cafe for lunch, putting her back into her stroller to sleep.  <br />
I had turkey. My only turkey of the day, as it would turn out. Alex indulged in perhaps the largest tuna salad bagel I&#8217;ve ever seen. It was far from gourmet, but given the circumstances, I was hardly one to argue.  <br />
Although MPN woke up briefly on the way back to the room, it was a tenuous consciousness, and it wasn&#8217;t long before she was back down and passed out. We tried to figure out where to go for dinner. While New York City truly is a wondrous place for food, Christmas Day is a little more limited. While (almost) every hotel restaurant is open, not all of them are easy to get into, have availability, or even turkey for that matter. We ended up going with San Martin, a nearby Italian restaurant.  <br />
Seafood risotto and fusilli primavera. Not exactly traditional, but then this trip has been anything but &#8212; so why stop with dinner? I wouldn&#8217;t go so far as to recommend the place, however. It&#8217;s okay, but I wouldn&#8217;t call it &#8220;great&#8221;.  <br />
MPN and I tried to check out Rockefeller Center while Alex endulged in a long-overdue bath. I think about half of New York came out for it, and I had the briefest glimpse what Times Square on New Year&#8217;s Eve must be like. It was a roundabout trip before we headed back and got the wee one to bed.  <br />
Speaking of which, it&#8217;s our turn to do the same. Mom arrives tomorrow, and we&#8217;re both in need of some serious ZZZs. I hope you all had a Merry Christmas. (And for those of you back in Canada, enjoy the Boxing Week sales!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 03:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Pequeña Niña if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Pequeña Niña if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking about. (Considering that was her only nap of the day, that&#8217;s not a bad thing, either.)<br />
The way started out as a rough plan to go to the Empire State Building, and check out the view of Manhattan. But our plans here are very flexible. Aside from the fact that I&#8217;ve been to New York City twice before, we&#8217;re travelling with a napping toddler, who is apt to change our plans at a moment&#8217;s notice for any number of reasons. So I try not to go too crazy when plans are forced to change.  <br />
(Emphasis on the word &#8220;try&#8221;.)<br />
<span id="more-1194"></span>Following a decent breakfast, we dressed for our run out to the CitiGroup building, and hop the E train eastwards to the 7th Ave station, where we switched to a northbound B train to 81st St. The stop, for those of you who don&#8217;t know, for the American Museum of Natural History. I&#8217;d seen it once before from the outside, but had really wanted to visit it since seeing &#8220;A Night At the Museum&#8221;.  <br />
A couple of things about the New York Subway system:<br />
  </p>
<ol>
<li>Accessibility. Not everyone has two capable feet. Some people require wheels, from those in wheelchairs to parents who try to get around with strollers. I&#8217;m amazed that not only are many stations on the system not equipped with ramps and elevators, in order to get in or out of the system, you need a station attendant to unlock the &#8220;service&#8221; gates (or trip the alarm on your way out).  </li>
<li>Not every person riding the subway is from the United States of America. So asking for a ZIP code when you want to use a credit card to purchase tickets is really short-sighted. (A note for those of you in our boat: punch in &#8220;99999&#8221;, &#8216;cuz it&#8217;s not posted anywhere.)</li>
<li>Allow people to purchase more than one ticket at a time, or at least suggest how you can use the same Metrocard for more than one person. Take a few lessons from the London Underground, who have this down to an artform.  </li>
<li>There is no better place to find amateur musicians. Why most of these people don&#8217;t have music on iTunes for sale is beyond me.  </li>
</ol>
<p>  <br />
The main entrance to the AMNH is made up of three small revolving doors. Not suitable for all strollers, certainly not ours. I had to go in through the planetarium entrance and work my way back to the main entrance. Which wasn&#8217;t easy due to malfunctioning elevators (and a near total lack of signage for alternatives). I&#8217;m certain that Alex (who went in through the main entrance) was wondering where Mi Pequeña Niña and I were.  <br />
When we did finally meet up in the main entrance hall, I was supremely disappointed. That massive entranceway in &#8220;A Night At The Museum&#8221;? About a third of that size. No statue of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback. No round front desk. There is a dinosaur &#8212; three, actually. But it&#8217;s just not as impressive. (Other things that seemed to be missing: Dioramas of railway builders and Roman legions, Civil war soldiers, and an Egyptian wing with a golden plaque that brings things together at night. But I digress.)<br />
Our first stop was at a temporary exhibit &#8212; a butterfly garden. It is with supreme irony that we flew five hours from Costa Rica to visit a butterfly garden with specimens from Costa Rica. (And in greater numbers than we&#8217;ve experienced before.) MPN was enthralled with all the butterflies, with them fluttering all about. The guides there (all volunteers) were all really well-educated about butterflies, too.  <br />
We moved on from there, moving to the 1st floor, in search of the Spitzer Hall of Human Evolution. (Alex would have a PhD in Anthropology by now if she&#8217;d known about anthropology before going into university.) To get there, we went through the Hall of Biodiversity, the Environment of New York State (featuring exhibits that hadn&#8217;t been dusted in at least 40 years &#8212; and looked about that dated), before passing a café on the south-west side.  <br />
It gave us a chance for a quick bite (I eschewed the $10.50 sandwiches), before we entered the Spitzer Hall. That was about when MPN finally passed out. Alex read every letter of every sign in the hall. I scanned many of them, reading more into the things that interested me more (e.g. the various branches of evolution that led to homo sapiens, and especially those branches that turned out to be dead-ends. (I still want to know where Neanderthals came from, and why they died out.)  <br />
While Alex continued to review evolution, I strayed along, eventually finding my way into another &#8220;hall&#8221; (the Arthur Ross Hall) dedicated wholly to meteorites. In the centre of the room was a particularly large specimen, Ahnighito (so dubbed by the Inuit of Greeland), is effectively a massive chunk of iron clocking in at a serious 34 tons. (That&#8217;s Imperial tons, by the way &#8212; some 68,000+ pounds.) It doesn&#8217;t look like it weighs 34 tons when you first see it. But when you touch it, you suddenly feel the weight of its mass and the distance it&#8217;s travelled.  I also ducked into the hall of minerals next door (at one point, I was a budding geologist) before returning to Alex and we continued our excursion around the museum.  <br />
The Hall of North American Mammals, the Hall of North American Tourists (otherwise known as  the gift shop), and finally the exit back to the subway to return to the hotel.  <br />
This being Christmas Eve, we planned to hit a Christmas service. I suggested St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, a particualrly wonderful example of gothic architecture just across the street from Rockefeller Center. But when we arrived, we found that we weren&#8217;t the only ones with the idea. Most of Manhattan gets this idea. Tickets for the event were apparently sold out by Labor Day.  <br />
Fortunately, there&#8217;s a non-denominational church nearby (though I think its roots are in the Anglican church) called St. Bart&#8217;s. We popped in there to find plenty of seating. The only problem with the service, sadly, was MPN, who would have none of this sitting still crap. Alex and I ended up having to take turns keeping her pinned down (or occupied) as not to disturb the entire church. Murdo&#8217;s talk of hearing MPN&#8217;s &#8220;music&#8221; was not echoed here.  <br />
When we left, it was raining. Yes, raining. It&#8217;s Christmas in New York, and it&#8217;s raining. The chill we first felt at landing is now gone, and I find the weather much warmer. Why didn&#8217;t we stay at home in Costa Rica?, you&#8217;re asking, I&#8217;m sure.  <br />
Alex made a desperate last-dash to a nearby CVS (drugstore) for some Christmasy things, such as a string of lights (very important), some decorations (right out of the classic &#8220;Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer&#8221; TV special), and the only tradition that we&#8217;ve had every year thus far &#8212; Turtles (the chocolate kind).  <br />
And on that note, it&#8217;s now time for us to go to bed. So to all of you, Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1194</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 1 &#8230; Part 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 03:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alex found Barnes and Noble without difficulty. Choosing what to buy? Now that&#8217;s difficult.   Upon her return, Mi Pequeña Niña and I suited up for our little excursion &#8212; the &#8220;other&#8221; major toy store in Manhattan. I speak, of course, of none other than the new Apple Store.   I jest. (Slightly.) It was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 1 &#8230; Part 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex found Barnes and Noble without difficulty. Choosing what to buy? Now that&#8217;s difficult.  <br />
Upon her return, Mi Pequeña Niña and I suited up for our little excursion &#8212; the &#8220;other&#8221; major toy store in Manhattan. I speak, of course, of none other than the new Apple Store.  <br />
I jest. (Slightly.)<br />
<span id="more-1192"></span>It was FAO Schwartz. The toy store. The place that kids dream of going to, of going completely bonker inside with the sheer pletora of toys. (Parents tend to go bonkers for the same reason, if not necessarily the same cause.)  <br />
MPN went almost insane the moment we rolled in the doors: she saw piles of stuffed animals. She immediately began blirping (my name for the noise she makes that&#8217;s half-bark, half chirp, and is always accompanied with an outstretched arm pointing (gnerally) at the thing she wants) constantly, indicating she wanted most of the store.  <br />
This wasn&#8217;t gonna be pretty.  <br />
I learned, the hard way, the first tenant of being a parent: Never take your kid into a toystore alone. Especially if you have to keep track of the stroller. Yes, sis, I know understand. MPN had half the store bundled up in her arms in mere moments. When forced to return these things to their respective piles, she merely ran off to get more of them. It was a losing battle. The only way to &#8220;win&#8221; it was to put her back in the stroller, which she rather reluctantly gave into. But that didn&#8217;t stop the roaming hands trying to grab anything and everything.  <br />
In the end, I acquired a Christmas present for her &#8212; one of the FAO Schwartz puppies, that&#8217;s about 3/4 her size. (Alex sort of scolded me for getting something so large, but even Alex fell in love with it when she saw it.) It saved me from also going into the Lego section, and plunking down some serious cash on a Lego Millennium Falcon or a Lego Death Star. That would be &#8230; painful. And not to the pocketbook, let me tell you&#8230;  <br />
Dinner was at a nearby TGI Fridays. Not for any real reason than it was the nearest thing we knew of, and it was already passing MPN&#8217;s bedtime. Sadly, we haven&#8217;t gotten ourselves into a good rhythm here yet. Not due to jet lag, I assure you &#8212; just because it&#8217;s New York City, and sleeping just seems to be such a tragedy.  <br />
I went out after dinner to get some night photos, but I&#8217;m not sure how they&#8217;re going to turn out. My autofocus is still broken, and I don&#8217;t know how it&#8217;s going to work out for me until I can get it fixed. But at least the long-exposure shots should turn out well.  <br />
Reasonably well.  <br />
Well, at least you&#8217;ll see a blurry something that resembles what I was trying to take a picture of.  <br />
And on that note, it&#8217;s bed time. Tomorrow, with luck, the Empire State Building. And apparently, I have to do some shopping on my own. [Insert manical laughter here.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1192</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary is big enough for better transit</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 14:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/16/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I&#8217;ve said before, I&#8217;m no expert. I haven&#8217;t been everywhere or done everything. But one thing I have done is paid attention to public transit systems, especially the ones I&#8217;ve had to deal with on a daily basis. Such as the one in Calgary. You already know [[Calgary Transit Sucks&#124;how I feel about our &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary is big enough for better transit"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I&#8217;ve said before, I&#8217;m no expert. I haven&#8217;t been everywhere or done everything. But one thing I have done is paid attention to public transit systems, especially the ones I&#8217;ve had to deal with on a daily basis.<br />
Such as the one in Calgary. You already know [[Calgary Transit Sucks|how I feel about our beloved transit system]]. And we&#8217;re long overdue to consider how much bigger it should be.<br />
<span id="more-861"></span>In fact, some replies to posts I did on [[Calgary Transit Sucks]] and [[Improving Calgary Transit in the city core]], and a half-argument I got into with someone waiting for the 301 led me to think: How does Calgary compare to other cities in terms of transit, anyway?<br />
Some cities I do have direct experience with:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Toronto, Canada</strong><br />
Canada&#8217;s largest city. Hundreds of thousands of people need to enter and leave the city daily. It&#8217;s messy. <a href="http://www.gotransit.com">GO Transit</a> funnels people into the downtown core. <a href="http://www.toronto.ca/ttc/">TTC</a> (subway, buses, streetcars) whisk people about town. The subway is nowhere near as extensive as it needs to be, having only started in the early 1950s  (when the city was less than a million people) and never having received the attention it needs. If it weren&#8217;t for a well-planned surface system, the city would be screwed.</li>
<li><strong>Montreal, Canada</strong><br />
Once Canada&#8217;s largest city (now #2), Montreal has perhaps one of Canada&#8217;s <a href="http://www.stm.info/">best public transportation systems</a>. This all stems from a signficant investment made in the mid-1960s in preparation for for <a href="http://expo67.ncf.ca/">Expo 67</a> &#8212; a large-scale subway system was installed. Combined with ages-old railway (Montreal was the headquarters of both <a href="http://www.cpr.ca">Canadian Pacific</a> and <a href="http://www.cn.ca">Canadian National Railways</a>, so was strewn with large train stations), and well-planned bus routes, Montreal is a public transit dream. Sadly, not one that seems to show up in a lot of case studies.</li>
<li><strong>Ottawa, Canada</strong><br />
Despite a reputation for the surliest bus drivers in Canada (my friend Chris took serious issue with a few of them during his habitation in our Nation&#8217;s Capital for not listening to passengers, yelling at passengers, driving like a maniacs, etc.), Ottawa has a pretty decent system. Notably because someone saw fit to have <a href="http://www.octranspo.com/">OC Transpo</a> buy roads and make them dedicated transit ways. It&#8217;s helped keep the million-plus area flowing well. And the addition of the O-Train should help keep major corridors flowing even better. Problem: I&#8217;m sure this plan never accounted for the Ottawa area extending over the border into Hull.</li>
<li><strong>Vancouver, Canada</strong><br />
Vancouver has a lot of trouble due to its physical and geopolitical limitations (mountains to the north, ocean to the west, USA to the south), which add up to some interesting problems for the population. Namely, they tend to live in a 20-kilometre wide swath from the Georgia Strait out to Hope. To get people around is <a href="http://www.translink.bc.ca/">an excellent bus system</a> (including rapid service buses on major routes), an ever-expanding light rail system (despite the NIMBYism in Point Grey), and the <a href="http://www.westcoastexpress.com/">West Coast Express</a> along the CP line (although the trains need to run all day, instead of just a few in the morning and a few in the evening &#8230; and run them until 23:00, would ya?).</li>
<li><strong>Kitchener/Waterloo/Cambridge, Canada</strong><br />
The tri-city area was once just Kitchener Transit. KW (as it was known when I went to university) were two cities that functioned as one. The <a href="http://www.grt.ca">Grand River Transit</a> system (as it&#8217;s now known) grew from a single small city system to cover three cities. And a lot more effectively than Calgary Transit seems to cover its measly self.</li>
<li><strong>New York City, USA</strong><br />
New York City is a true prototype of how to build a city: vertically. People live in skyscrapers, and travel quickly underground. The Big Apple&#8217;s first subway rolled along in the mid 1860s &#8212; a full century before Montreal got its Metro. <a href="http://www.mta.info/">New York&#8217;s system</a> covers five cities (now boroughs) and started when the population meter was barely at 830,000! And NYC is wholly dependent on the system &#8212; if the subways stop, the city goes into traffic gridlock. You can get anywhere in NYC by subway, and it&#8217;s simple for any visitor to pick up the system quickly. Trains and buses bring people in and out of the city, but inside, it&#8217;s the subway bringing the city to life.</li>
<li><strong>San Francisco, USA</strong><br />
Although San Francisco was late in getting its light rail (BART), San Francisco had already mastered ferries, trains, streetcars (the famous cable cars). Buses came later. And with San Francisco being on a peninsula, there was a lot of need to make it work well. Yes, SF was big when light rail finally came in (the SF area was huge) but this was to augment <a href="http://transit.511.org/">the transit system</a> already in place.</li>
<li><strong>London, England</strong><br />
London was the first to get an Underground in the mid-1860s. The city was already 1.6 million, though, and the Underground was to alleviate the trouble of travelling on the surface. All the trains, all the horse-drawn vehicles (and automobiles were fast-coming), and all the people were making movement nearly impossible. (Calgary &#8212; does this at all sound familiar? Well, maybe on with the horses during Stampede.) <a href="http://www.tfl.gov.uk/">London now is a paradise for public transit</a>, with outstanding subway systems, excellent rail services (for those of you who would beg to differ, I offer Canada as an example of how bad it can get), and well-marked bus services (you don&#8217;t need a map to know where you&#8217;re going).</li>
<li><strong>Paris, France</strong><br />
Given, Paris was about two million when the Metro arrived. Paris had similar problems to London &#8230; just with more people in a smaller space. The Metro saved Paris&#8217; population from having to survive travelling on roads and quickly get around. Today, <a href="http://www.ratp.fr/">Paris&#8217; Metro is fast, cheap, and effective</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Moscow, Russia</strong><br />
One of the largest in the world in terms of volume, the <a href="http://www.metro.ru/">Moscow Metro</a> has only been around since the 1930s. A bit more on the state-enforced development end, the Metro is something most Moscovites depend on, much in the way New Yorkers depend on the subway. No Metro, no Moscow.</li>
<li><strong>Shanghai, China</strong><br />
In addition to a great subway system (connected with China&#8217;s extensive rail system), Shanghai also has the world&#8217;s <a href="http://www.smtdc.com/en">first commercial magnetic levitation train</a>. It runs at high speed (over 400 km/h) to the airport. Sadly, it doesn&#8217;t do this from downtown Shanghai (which would make it truly exceptional), so it&#8217;s almost more kvitchy. I doubt Calgary would benefit from maglev, but such a train from Calgary to Edmonton would cover the distance in less than an hour.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong SAR, China</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.hkpt.com/">Buses</a>: super-comfortable and air-conditioned. <a href="http://www.mtr.com.hk/prehome/index.html">Subway</a>: not very extensive, but at least runs out to the airport. Trains: not many, but they do run into China. <a href="http://www.hktramways.com/">Tramways</a>: Handy and cheap, when you&#8217;re in the Central/Admiralty areas of Hong Kong. Mind you, much of that area is small enough that you can walk on foot.</li>
<li><strong>Tokyo, Japan</strong><br />
Tokyo and trains go hand-in-hand. <a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp/e/">No trains, no Tokyo.</a> Japan it heavily dependent on public transit because its made owning a car prohibitive. This is a lesson most of the rest of the world should learn: cars shouldn&#8217;t be considered necessities, except in some circumstances (e.g. ambulances). There is little that can&#8217;t be accomplished on your own two feet, with buses, trains, and subways covering the rest.</li>
</ul>
<p>Calgary should be learning from cities such as these &#8212; especially its cousins in Canada &#8212; and learning what could be done to make things better. It should also look at its own history. Calgary used to have an interurban system that covered a lot of the city. Gone, and pretty much forgotten. But more extensive (by a wide margin) than the current C-Train.<br />
It&#8217;s not about planning for more roads. It&#8217;s not about ensuring there&#8217;s parking downtown. It&#8217;s about making better (that includes regularly-staffed, regularly-timed, and appropriately-equipped) bus routes, dedicated lanes during rush hours to funnel people in and out of downtown, [[Improving Calgary Transit in the city core|buried transit lines downtown]], more C-Train lines, and maybe (just maybe) trains to/from <a href="http://http://www.banffrailco.com/commuter.htm">High River, Canmore, Strathmore, and Airdrie</a>.<br />
It&#8217;s not like it hasn&#8217;t been done before.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">861</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
