<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>blogging &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/blogging/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 19:52:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Story Is Key</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/01/the-story-is-key/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-story-is-key</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/01/the-story-is-key/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3679</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Years ago, I started blogging because I had moved away from home and wanted those I knew and loved to know what I was up to, things I&#8217;d done, and that I was, in fact, okay. (The grand irony in that belief is that I wasn&#8217;t, in fact, okay, and that this blog made that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/01/the-story-is-key/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Story Is Key"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Years ago, I started blogging because I had moved away from home and wanted those I knew and loved to know what I was up to, things I&#8217;d done, and that I was, in fact, okay. (The grand irony in that belief is that I <em>wasn&#8217;t</em>, in fact, okay, and that this blog made that pretty clear to everyone but me.)</p>



<p>In the years that followed, these stories started to give way to my &#8220;professional&#8221; life, and the need to publicize my own wisdom and knowledge and bla bla bla. Yeah, I soapboxed a lot. Most of it, when I read it now, makes me feel ill. Because that&#8217;s not what I really wanted to do &#8212; I did it because I felt I had to. </p>



<p>It&#8217;s high time to get back to story-telling. </p>



<span id="more-3679"></span>



<p>The blog was moved from the original http://www.sowrey.org to https://geoff.sowrey.org partly as a branding exercise (ick!) and partly as an experiment in moving sites and seeing if Google would keep my site&#8217;s value in the process. (In short: it was a dumb idea in the first place, and no, Google didn&#8217;t partly because I botched the redirects.) </p>



<p>Anyway, the site at <a href="https://www.sowrey.org">https://www.sowrey.org</a> was left unused and it just sat there, begging me to do something with it. Frankly, I&#8217;m amazed it took as long as it did. </p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been writing (or trying to write) stories for years. Some of them are for me: short stories (most unfinished) and a couple of novels (none published, as most are also unfinished), but some are for my kids: bedtime stories that I wrote down because I liked how they sounded. These are the things I liked writing about, not about whether the web industry is going in a particular direction and how my umpteen years of experience will get you the best </p>



<p>[<em>throws up</em>]</p>



<p>[<em>cleans up mess</em>] </p>



<p>Sorry about that. I can&#8217;t stomach that pedantic garbage anymore. </p>



<p>So, stories. That&#8217;s where you&#8217;ll find most of my writing now, over at <a href="https://www.sowrey.org/">https://www.sowrey.org/</a>. Come have a read. And if you have an idea for a story, send it to me. Can&#8217;t say I&#8217;ll make you famous, but you&#8217;ll definitely get credit. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/01/the-story-is-key/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3679</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things I learned by leaving social media</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 04:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3553</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[On 8 November 2016, Americans elected their new president, whom I hope to never have to publicly acknowledge. That night, I came to a rather painful conclusion: I needed to abandon social media for a while. In this particular election, the media had (unwittingly, foolishly, stupidly, or all of the above) enabled a level of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Things I learned by leaving social media"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On 8 November 2016, Americans elected their new president, whom I hope to never have to publicly acknowledge. That night, I came to a rather painful conclusion: I needed to abandon social media for a while.<br />
In this particular election, the media had (unwittingly, foolishly, stupidly, or all of the above) enabled a level of insipid, unchecked banter that intelligence and logic were utterly cast aside in favour of whomever had the best catchphrase. Basically, a Hollywood political satire come to life. Very real, very <em>painful</em> life.<br />
It hurt so bad that I had to turn it off.<br />
<span id="more-3553"></span><br />
So I left Twitter and Facebook behind. (I already mostly ignore LinkedIn, except for reference checks when hiring people. I don&#8217;t use any other tool for sheer sanity.) I even stopped listening to CBC Radio, for the same reasons. I just needed to ignore The Stupid for a while and worry about myself, and my family.<br />
I returned on 1 January. I&#8217;d just had <a href="http://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/16/disney-world-2016-the-kids-find-out/">a wonderful vacation</a>, I&#8217;d been away from the nonsense long enough, and to be honest &#8230; I was missing my friends. It seemed like a good time to go back online. (Whether that&#8217;s still the case remains to be seen&#8230;)<br />
It&#8217;s at this point that we need to acknowledge some lessons learned. And no, this isn&#8217;t one of those articles that suggests <em>everyone </em>should abandon social media. For some, it makes total sense. For me, however, it&#8217;s just not an option.</p>
<h2>More pressure, than less pressure</h2>
<p>The biggest problem is expectation. It doesn&#8217;t matter that you leave a great big sign that says &#8220;Gone Fishin'&#8221;, people expect you to be there. And yes, I do mean people, as in actual humans.<br />
Whether anyone readily acknowledges it or not, when you engage with someone on social media, it&#8217;s not just text &#8212; there&#8217;s a real human behind that text: a family member, a friend, or a colleague. Someone with real emotions who might start to wonder what&#8217;s up. And your &#8220;out of office&#8221; notice doesn&#8217;t say anything useful.<br />
That started to weigh on me pretty hard. I am proud to say that I have a lot of friends. And in my daily life, I get to see about ten of them &#8230; because they work next to me. The other thousand or so? Some I get to see once in a while, after some careful planning, for a few short hours. Others live out of the city, and as much as technology enables real-time video conversations, the reality is that I see them almost never. One of my favourite recent pictures is when I saw a whole bunch of them all at once last summer.<br />
Email? Honestly, how many people write personal emails these days? We cram so many things into our daily lives that we don&#8217;t have the time to write. Believe me, I know &#8212; I&#8217;ve used that excuse for close to four years as a reason for not blogging. Personal emails? &#8220;Close to never&#8221; is the best definition for me.<br />
I use social media. Whether it&#8217;s a chance to vent for a moment, or get input, or share something I find really interesting, all of it matters. And <em>not</em> being able to do that really started to wear on me.</p>
<h2>Wait, you did what?!</h2>
<p>The other major problem with getting off social media is completely losing track of your friends. I thought I was doing myself a service. Since then, I&#8217;ve learned of deaths in families, a good friend is undergoing cancer treatment (again!), and another one is nearly in the midst of a career crisis.<br />
My friends need friends, too, and I&#8217;d abandoned them in the process of trying to save myself. There&#8217;s a certain amount of &#8220;me&#8221; that I need to deal with, yes, but there&#8217;s no nobility in turning one&#8217;s back &#8212; unintentionally or not &#8212; against your friends.<br />
My friends are important to me. Because I&#8217;ve learned what it&#8217;s like to not have them, and I can&#8217;t afford to lose the ones I have.</p>
<h2>Oh that&#8217;d make a great tweet!</h2>
<p>Two times a day, <em>minimum</em>, I thought of great tweets. (Well, &#8220;great&#8221; to me, anyway.) Several times I caught myself reaching for my phone, ready to blurt it out to the world.<br />
I&#8217;m vocal. (Yeah, I know: <em>duh</em>.) Even if nearly no-one is listening, that&#8217;s okay. I still need to talk. And if I&#8217;m just talking to myself &#8230; well, I&#8217;ve been to those doctors. I&#8217;d rather just talk to my friends.</p>
<h2>Filter or die</h2>
<p>Here&#8217;s my lesson to you, dear reader. Out of all of this, the greatest lesson I&#8217;ve learned is the need to filter: follow only those you need to follow, ditch the ones who don&#8217;t help.<br />
Yes, you can easily argue that you should engage people on social media, especially those who need a different point of view. I&#8217;ve tried. I&#8217;ve seen others try. The sad truth is, you can&#8217;t.<br />
Social media doesn&#8217;t change minds, it just helps people find like minds to reinforce their beliefs.<br />
I used to have a policy of following people even if I disagreed with them, because there was a learning opportunity. But all I learned was that people are easily angered, often seen as ignorant (regardless of factual basis), and arguments can go on for days without any resolution.<br />
I&#8217;ve dropped those people. I&#8217;ve shrunk my circle to the ones who matter, the ones who can truly influence me, the ones who have thoughts that I feel matter. Those who want to promote different agendas aren&#8217;t of interest to me, nor do I have the patience to sit through rhetoric I don&#8217;t agree with.<br />
I know many people who aren&#8217;t me, and are quite happy to do what I can&#8217;t. (I know a few who likely crack a bottle of wine, sit down at their keyboards, and see how many people they can rile in an evening.) Me? I want to know how you&#8217;re doing, what new things are going on, hopefully help out in some way. And I hope that maybe you&#8217;d return the favour down the road to me.</p>
<h2>Staying &#8230; for now</h2>
<p>I&#8217;m back to my old ways, and hopefully even the oldest one, blogging. Whether I stay here remains to be seen. The year(s) to come will be hard. The right wing of the world is flapping hard, stirring up fear and hatred in an effort to seize control. There may yet come a point when I delete my accounts. (And possibly move to a remote island&#8230;)<br />
For now, I&#8217;m happy to engage. Just so long as everyone else is happy, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>True story</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=true-story</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2158</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As you know, I&#8217;m going to be moving back to Calgary in December. The exact timing for that is still being determined, but let&#8217;s just go with the broad stroke: we have a lot of stuff that needs to be done as part of moving back. One of those things &#8212; rather obvious to anyone &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "True story"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you know, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/09/o-canada-my-home-and-native-land/">I&#8217;m going to be moving back to Calgary in December</a>. The exact timing for that is still being determined, but let&#8217;s just go with the broad stroke: we have a lot of stuff that needs to be done as part of moving back.<br />
One of those things &#8212; rather obvious to anyone who&#8217;s ever been responsible for their own utilities &#8212; is making sure that the electricity, gas, and water are put back in our names. And there&#8217;s no time like the present to do the research about services, plans, companies, and so forth.<br />
<span id="more-2158"></span>One obvious choice, at least in Calgary, is <a href="http://www.enmax.com/">Enmax</a>. It&#8217;s a city-owned utility that provides electricity (its original function), water, and has a license to also distribute gas (we&#8217;ll ignore, for the moment, that the &#8220;distribution&#8221; is exceedingly virtualised). I&#8217;ve used Enmax for every house I&#8217;ve lived in (at least within Calgary), and having everything on one bill is a big plus.<br />
Add to that the desire to have green energy, I also wanted to look into their <a href="http://www.enmax.com/greenmax">Greenmax</a> programme, as it&#8217;s something I&#8217;d like to support (at least until I can afford my own solar panels). As I started hunting around in the site, I came across something that made me genuinely laugh:</p>
<blockquote><p>If your mailing address is outside of North America, please contact us at 310-2010 (toll free in Alberta) to verify details.</p></blockquote>
<p>If you&#8217;re wondering why I&#8217;m laughing, it&#8217;s because of the &#8220;310&#8221; number. It doesn&#8217;t work outside of Alberta (at least so far as I know). It&#8217;s also a real misnomer because it doesn&#8217;t include an area code, either. Certainly, there&#8217;s an assumption that you somehow know that Calgary&#8217;s area code is &#8220;403&#8221;, but too much assumption becomes presumption.<br />
At any rate, <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/statuses/3809821233">I found this so humourous, I tweeted it</a>. Go on, follow the link. I&#8217;ll wait.<br />
Now you might be wondering what the heck the &#8220;#&#8221; is in that content. If you&#8217;re not familiar with <a href="http://twitter.com/">Twitter</a>, you&#8217;ve probably never seen a hashtag. That&#8217;s what the &#8220;#&#8221; is. <a href="http://hashtags.org/">Hashtags enable someone to search</a> for tweets (a post in Twitter), so they can follow an event, for example. In the case of companies, it&#8217;s handy to flag them specifically.<br />
The &#8220;#fail&#8221;? Well, that&#8217;s a note that something is wrong. Possibly horribly wrong. It&#8217;s half-Twitterese, and half-internet geekery.<br />
Now, I&#8217;d posted that tweet figuring that I&#8217;d never hear anything of it. It&#8217;s one of those things with Twitter &#8212; you expect, if anything, for your friends to make smarmy comments about the things you say and do. (Yes, <a href="http://twitter.com/humantorch">@humantorch</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/jthale">@jthale</a>, and <a href="http://twitter.com/froosh_ca">@froosh_ca</a>, I&#8217;m looking at you. Jerks.)<br />
Well, apparently, Enmax is much further into this internet thing than I was giving them credit for. Someone was watching the <a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23enmax">#enmax hashtag</a>. Someone saw it. And they showed it to their marketing consultant. The marketing consultant&#8230; well&#8230;<br />
He doubled over laughing.<br />
Why?<br />
Because <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dan-evans/2/81/593">Dan</a> knows me &#8230; very well. (Dan used to be the President of <a href="http://www.criticalmass.com/">Critical Mass</a> &#8212; he&#8217;s now a principal of <a href="http://www.evanshunt.com/">The Evans Hunt Group</a> &#8212;  and was even my direct boss for a while.)<br />
Dan dropped me a line with the correct 877 number. And I suspect that he had some influence on the copy in Enmax&#8217;s website, because I can&#8217;t find the original quote anymore (it used to be on <a href="https://www.enmax.com/Energy/Res/Moving/Open+new+account.htm">Enmax&#8217;s Sign Up page</a>).<br />
[Insert singing dolls here.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>20 years of blogging (and Post #1,000)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/20-years-of-blogging/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=20-years-of-blogging</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/20-years-of-blogging/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 20:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[milestones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soviet union]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1429</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, okay, not so much &#8220;blogging&#8221; as journaling, but most of them are now online for everyone to ignore. Twenty years ago, I got to do something that (comparatively) very few westerners got to do, and will never get to do again: I went behind the Iron Curtain. I visited the (former) Soviet Union. Believe &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/20-years-of-blogging/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "20 years of blogging (and Post #1,000)"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, okay, not so much &#8220;blogging&#8221; as journaling, but most of them are now online for everyone to ignore.<br />
Twenty years ago, I got to do something that (comparatively) very few westerners got to do, and will never get to do again: <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/1989/07/behind-iron-curtain-moscow-flight/">I went behind the Iron Curtain</a>. I visited the (former) Soviet Union. Believe it or not, the journey was a field trip, organised by one of the teachers in my school board. We had to do prerequisite classwork and had to write two length reports, all of which added up to academic credits.<br />
And we had to write a journal.<br />
<span id="more-1429"></span>My journal, as originally written, was short. I didn&#8217;t go for depth of content. (Yes, you can all insert &#8220;unbelievable shock&#8221; here.) I wasn&#8217;t a writer &#8230; yet. I was a kid in a foreign country (my first foray outside of North America) experiencing a part of the world few people had any desire to see at all, and was largely misunderstood except for what mainstream media portrayed.<br />
At the time I wrote it, there wasn&#8217;t a lot of understanding about what the journal was for, except maybe as source material for our reports that we would write afterwards. Little did we know that when we got back, we had to hand in our journals for grading.<br />
If you&#8217;ve ever seen my handwriting, you know this is a Bad Thing.<br />
So I did what any smart kid (who wanted a really good grade) would do: I typed it all out. Except the more I typed, the more I inserted because I remembered other things. Before long, my 10 or so pages of journal entries had turned into over 100 pages. Single spaced. (I got an A+, by the way.)<br />
That was the moment I started to become a writer. I look back at that journal now and &#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say I&#8217;ve had many years to improve my writing ability. But that was the start.<br />
Twenty years is a long time to be writing. I&#8217;m having real trouble believing it&#8217;s been that long. Come January 2010, it&#8217;ll have been 10 years since I started writing internet-based journals (that eventually became the blogging we all know and love).<br />
And with this post, at least according to my WordPress post count, is number 1,000. (That includes a couple of drafts that are coming shortly, and posts you can&#8217;t see.) That might not seem like a lot, but when each post is over 1,000 words &#8230; well, you do the math.<br />
So, in a way, this is an anniversary: the birth of The Observer, my (former) self-assigned moniker for my journaling habits. A birthday.<br />
Happy birthday, Me!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/20-years-of-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1429</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A few of my favourite tweets</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/a-few-of-my-favourite-tweets/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-few-of-my-favourite-tweets</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/a-few-of-my-favourite-tweets/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2009 20:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1246</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wordle.net/gallery/wrdl/528000/%40sowrey%27s_Twitters" title="Wordle: @sowrey&#039;s Twitters"><img src="http://www.wordle.net/thumb/wrdl/528000/%40sowrey%27s_Twitters" alt="Wordle: @sowrey&#039;s Twitters" style="padding:4px;border:1px solid #ddd" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/a-few-of-my-favourite-tweets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1246</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blog or Die</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/blog-or-die/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=blog-or-die</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/blog-or-die/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 22:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2611</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s been a lot of talk lately about people saying you shouldn&#8217;t blog anymore. The arguments seem to break into two categories: Don&#8217;t blog because you probably have nothing interesting to say and no-one will read it Don&#8217;t blog because it&#8217;s passé and there&#8217;s better places to go The problem with these arguments is that they&#8217;re missing the big &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/blog-or-die/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Blog or Die"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s been a lot of talk lately about people saying <strong>you shouldn&#8217;t blog</strong> anymore. The arguments seem to break into two categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Don&#8217;t blog because <a href="http://adage.com/digitalnext/article?article_id=131126">you probably have nothing interesting to say and no-one will read it</a></li>
<li>Don&#8217;t blog because <a href="http://www.wired.com/entertainment/theweb/magazine/16-11/st_essay">it&#8217;s passé and there&#8217;s better places</a> to go</li>
</ul>
<p>The problem with these arguments is that they&#8217;re <strong>missing the big picture</strong>, and that&#8217;s presence. Namely, your presence (either your company or yourself) on the internet.<br />
<span id="more-2611"></span><br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2008/10/blog-or-die/blog-or-die-2/' title='Blog or die'><img width="300" height="273" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Blog-or-die-300x273.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignleft wp-image-3255" alt="Blog or die" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2965574914/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The internet is a noisy place. It&#8217;s filled with every type of company and personality, all trying to make themselves heard all at the same time. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marshall_McLuhan">Marshall McLuhan</a> would have exploded from joy if he&#8217;d lived to see today&#8217;s internet). Like standing in the middle of a loud party, it&#8217;s hard to be heard. That&#8217;s why <strong>presence is so important</strong> &#8212; people will pay attention to those they perceive as important. You need to be staking claims in a variety of places, and investing time and effort in key areas to ensure the <strong>quality and intensity of your signal</strong> can rise to the top.<br />
You need <strong>multiple approaches</strong> in various forms all leading to the same message (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_medium_is_the_message">love you, Marshall</a>, really!). And on the internet, it&#8217;s definitely a plural thing &#8212; not just one thing. A single channel would be a blog or a MySpace page. One thing. Multiple (full) channels would be like maintaining a big website, constantly engaging people in forums, and Twittering constantly. That&#8217;s expensive.<br />
So think of things in a smaller sense: <strong>microchannels</strong> (and no, I refer not to the ill-fated <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Channel_Architecture">Micro Channel</a> of yore).<br />
There are countless ways of approaching other people, from social networking to one-off media downloads. To give you an idea, this is what I personally engage in:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/">Experience Matters</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/">My personal blog site</a> (home of many a rant)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/">Flickr</a></li>
<li>Numerous forums</li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="http://brightkite.com/people/sowrey">Britekite</a> (I also had a Fire Eagle setup but let it expire)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.last.fm/user/gsowrey">Last.fm</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/sowrey">LinkedIn</a></li>
<li><a href="http://delicious.com/gsowrey">Delicious</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/sonworf">YouTube</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=803520530">Facebook</a> (even though I don&#8217;t really do anything)</li>
<li>and some other ones that I&#8217;m missing because I&#8217;ve got <strong>too many to keep track of</strong>&#8230;</li>
</ul>
<p>And just to illustrate the point, here&#8217;s a series of services I don&#8217;t use (for no particular reason) that friends of mine use:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://twitpic.com">TwitPic</a></li>
<li><a href="http://furl.com">Furl</a></li>
<li><a href="http://tumblr.com">Tumblr</a></li>
<li><a href="http://twine.com">Twine</a></li>
<li><a href="http://digg.com">Digg</a></li>
<li><a href="http://reddit.com">Reddit</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pownce.com">Pownce</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a></li>
<li><a href="http://slideshare.com">SlideShare</a></li>
<li><a href="http://upcoming.yahoo.com">Upcoming</a></li>
<li><a href="http://43things.com">43Things</a></li>
</ul>
<p>As you can see, there&#8217;s a lot of them. But most of them can <strong>provide only limited value</strong> due to specific focus (e.g. bookmarking, or current location) or limitation on the content (e.g. 140 characters for Twitter). This creates the <strong>nature of the microchannel</strong> &#8212; limited, specific content.<br />
Hopefully, you&#8217;ve already noticed the problem here. Microchannels &#8212; as cool and enticing as they are &#8212; are <strong>tricky to coordinate</strong> into a cohesive message. It&#8217;s sort of like trying to pull together lines from a dozen different books so you can read &#8220;Dick and Jane.&#8221; It also requires work for the reader (e.g. reading multiple Twitters or looking through Flickr pictures). And that (drum roll, please) <em>makes it really hard to easily provide your point of view</em>.<br />
(I wonder where he&#8217;s going with this. <a href="http://snltranscripts.jt.org/87/87fchurchchat.phtml">What could he be talking about?</a> Could it be &#8230; BLOGS?)<br />
Yes, blogs. I don&#8217;t care if people think they&#8217;re old and boring &#8212; anyone who doesn&#8217;t think blogs provide value has not directly experienced what a blog can do. Well-crafted <strong>messages on blogs provide value</strong>, insight, and can impart actual personality of an otherwise faceless company (heck, even a half-assed blog entry can be very useful). As part of a microchannel effort, you can direct readers (and links) to blog entries that are specifically tuned to the <strong>points you wish to discuss</strong>. Anyone reading the blog could then be directed to a website to enquire about products or services.<br />
That said, don&#8217;t just think you can only blog and that&#8217;ll be enough. You need to <strong>engage people where they&#8217;re spending their time</strong>, which means going into the microchannels, too. But it&#8217;s not too much effort to lead them back to a blog entry. And if you provide a good RSS feed, some of these things are automatic (my blog automatically posts announcements to Twitter, for example).<br />
Now comes the other question: <strong>Should you blog?</strong><br />
With <strong>only a couple of exceptions</strong> (notably anyone in the financial industry), it&#8217;s a resounding &#8220;<strong>yes</strong>&#8220; in my book. The reasoning behind not having anything interesting to say (or have the chops to write it down) is weak at best &#8212; just because one person might not find it interesting doesn&#8217;t mean no one will (believe me, if you&#8217;ve seen any of the posts on my blog, you might think mine is a total waste of time &#8212; but I get a lot of traffic). At worst, the only thing your blog will do is <strong>increase traffic to your website</strong>. At best, it might <strong>make you rich</strong>.<br />
But what happens if you <strong>choose not to blog?</strong><br />
Well, if you stick to what others suggest, and do only the most trendy things, you&#8217;ll <strong>miss a lot of potential audience</strong>. You&#8217;ll have to spend more effort to get across complex ideas because the microchannels don&#8217;t always offer enough space, and spend more time linking everything together. And you&#8217;ll have to <strong>wave goodbye to a lot of potential search traffic</strong> because Google (and Yahoo! and Microsoft and Baidu) can&#8217;t search Facebook, parse your audio/video for keywords, won&#8217;t tie together all your Twitter entries, or understand that all your tagged articles mean something as a whole.<br />
So I say &#8220;blog.&#8221; Or die the <strong>death of the unseen</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/blog-or-die/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2611</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web Analytics Porn</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-analytics-porn</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=994</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[So this morning, I&#8217;m scanning through my Twitter feeds on Twhirl, and I came across a rather interesting note by Dave Fleet, which said: @cspenn planning to install it tonight. Waiting for the confirmation email. Long-winded installation process! Things like that tend to pique my curiousity. I&#8217;m a curious person. So I decided to see &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web Analytics Porn"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning, I&#8217;m scanning through my <a href="http://twitter.com/">Twitter</a> feeds on <a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl</a>, and I came across a rather interesting note by Dave Fleet, which said:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://twitter.com/davefleet/statuses/826847428">@cspenn planning to install it tonight. Waiting for the confirmation email. Long-winded installation process!</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Things like that tend to pique my curiousity. I&#8217;m a curious person. So I decided to see what Christopher Penn had wrote about it. I quote:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://twitter.com/cspenn/statuses/826843267">OMFG. Just installed Woopra and it really is web analytics porn.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>That just sooooo necessitated a look-see.<br />
<span id="more-994"></span><a href="http://www.woopra.com/">Woopra</a>, as it turns out, is free. I like free. Free is always good for evaluation, and if the evaluation goes well, I&#8217;m rarely objected to purchase. But that&#8217;s just me. The sign up process was a little slow, as I had to wait for an approval code first (it&#8217;s still in beta), but once it was set up, away I went.<br />
I&#8217;ve been using <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> for a long time (though I only realised this morning that I&#8217;d accidentally forgotten to put my new code in with the <a href="http://www.onehertz.com/portfolio/wordpress/mandigo/">Mandigo theme</a>, so I&#8217;m out of stats for the last month or two), and I&#8217;ve also relied heavily on <a href="http://www.feedburner.com/">Feedburner</a>&#8216;s stats to get an idea of how my site&#8217;s been performing. Overall, I&#8217;ve had little to complain about, but I missed having something real-time.<br />
A few years ago, <a href="http://www.schillmania.com/">Scott Schiller</a> turned me onto a tool that provided real-time stats. It was pretty cool to see the numbers come by, see where people were visiting from, and so forth. Compiled stats aren&#8217;t as interesting &#8212; it&#8217;s like reading the newspaper. It&#8217;s yesterday&#8217;s news. I want something that can tell me what&#8217;s happening right now. Not because I have a business need, but because I&#8217;m a nosey little bastard.<br />
Woopra is stats porn. Wow.<br />
Installation is simple: a snippet of JavaScript code not unlike putting in Google Analytics. You can then use Woopra&#8217;s site to see what&#8217;s going on, or you can download the (also in beta) desktop app. This is where you go hardcore.<br />
[flickr]photo:2550756431(medium)[/flickr]<br />
Not only is there a crawl at the bottom of the window (think stock ticker), you can see real-time where people are coming from and what they&#8217;re doing. The tools allow some pretty deep-diving for information, too.<br />
Does this hold up against other tools like Google Analytics? Yep. Some features aren&#8217;t the same, but it&#8217;s still in beta so there&#8217;s a lot of things they can yet change. Does it stand up to things like Omniture? Hell, no. Not yet, anyway, but taking on the 8,000 lb gorilla of web analytics is just not a wise idea, anyway.<br />
Woopra, if you&#8217;re listening, can I suggest a couple of changes?</p>
<ol>
<li>Allow me to exclude my own IP from the stats. I can&#8217;t see anything in the interface for this.</li>
<li>Let me set how long items stay in the live feed. I don&#8217;t have the most active site, and I&#8217;m a curious S.O.B.</li>
<li>Let me copy and paste items, like referrers. Just &#8216;cuz.</li>
<li>Put a sort into the search results &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of neat stuff that can be seen merely by sorting, before filtering.</li>
</ol>
<p>For an average schmuck like me, this is just plain fun. Now if you&#8217;ll excuse me, I&#8217;ve got website stats to watch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ScribbleLive: Live Blogging Done Right!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/scribblelive-live-blogging-done-right/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=scribblelive-live-blogging-done-right</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/scribblelive-live-blogging-done-right/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 16:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=972</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Late last month, I had the chance to go to the Web 2.0 Expo in San Francisco. On behalf of my co-workers, I blogged notes from the event to make sure that they had the benefit of getting the information in as much detail as could be effectively provided. (Of course, Scott Schiller out-did me &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/scribblelive-live-blogging-done-right/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "ScribbleLive: Live Blogging Done Right!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late last month, I had the chance to go to the <a href="http://en.oreilly.com/webexsf2008/public/content/home">Web 2.0 Expo in San Francisco</a>. On behalf of my co-workers,<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/web-20-expo/"> I blogged notes from the event</a> to make sure that they had the benefit of getting the information in as much detail as could be effectively provided. (Of course, Scott Schiller out-did me on the day he was there, and recorded the audio on his MiniDisc system. But I digress.)<br />
My major issue was the blogging. It&#8217;s tough to write down the notes, and ensure that they all get posted properly. WordPress lost connection at one point and I lost my notes. I was peeved, to say the least. Ideally, it would be blog each point as it came up. But that looks dumb in <a href="http://www.wordpress.org/">WordPress</a>. And I knew of no other tool that did it well.<br />
Until now&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-972"></span>Thanks to the <a href="http://twitter.com/">TwitterSphere</a> (believe it or not), I found out about a tool called <a href="http://www.scribblelive.com/">ScribbleLive</a>. I got a chance to play around with it a bit this morning, and found it not only lightweight, but now I&#8217;m just ITCHING for a chance to put it to good use.<br />
Then &#8212; skin me alive and call me &#8220;luggage&#8221; &#8212; I found out that I know one of the guys who developed it. <a href="http://www.keebler.net/">Jonathan Keebler</a> and co-worker Michael De Monte with CTV (former with MUCH Interactive before the much-wept purchase of CHUM) banged it together in their spare time. And in true Web 2.0 form, it&#8217;s lightweight, simple, easy-to-use, and makes good use of other services such as OpenID to manage logins.<br />
<a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/05/22/scribblelive-two-guys-in-canada-launch-sweet-liveblogging-platform/">TechCrunch found out about them</a>, too. Not a bad way to start a new business model. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />
Well done, guys!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/scribblelive-live-blogging-done-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">972</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web 2.0 Expo: Ontologies for the Internet</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-ontologies-for-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-20-expo-ontologies-for-the-internet</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-ontologies-for-the-internet/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=941</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Definitely not my strong point. But I wanted to go to this given all the working in tagging as of late. Presenter: Duane Nickull folksonomies became powerful quickly because people got tired of waiting for the so-called AI problem with folksonomies is that they&#8217;re language and context dependent (e.g. car vs. voiture) also reusing a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-ontologies-for-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web 2.0 Expo: Ontologies for the Internet"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Definitely not my strong point. But I wanted to go to this given all the working in tagging as of late.<br />
<span id="more-941"></span>Presenter: Duane Nickull</p>
<ul>
<li>folksonomies became powerful quickly because people got tired of waiting for the so-called AI</li>
<li>problem with folksonomies is that they&#8217;re language and context dependent (e.g. car vs. voiture)</li>
<li>also reusing a term for different meanings</li>
<li>need a shared conceptualisation of a domain</li>
<li>one of the major problems with social networking is having to redefine connections on each new system</li>
<li>could use a system to connect folksonomy tag clouds to relate to objects to acquire meaning (will not happen overnight)</li>
<li>Three methods of formal logic:
<ul>
<li>Deduction (Every bird flies. Tweey is a bird. Infer: Tweety flies.)</li>
<li>Induction (Tweety, Polly, Hooty are birds. They fly. Infer: All birds fly.)</li>
<li>Abduction (Every bird flies. Tweety flies. Infer: Tweety is a bird.)</li>
<li>Analogy (uses a combination of the previous three)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>ontology would be to allow a folksonomy to relate to taxonomy terms, and engage a user to disambiguate</li>
<li>Hook tags through Crowd Find</li>
<li>Google and Yahoo have not released their onotologies, which are very in-depth and accurate</li>
<li>Question: What about the semantic web?
<ul>
<li>There&#8217;s a lot of work going on, but they (like us) need this solved before it&#8217;ll truly work. There&#8217;s not enough concrete work for it to work. We&#8217;re actually further ahead with folksonomies in Web 2.0 than the semantic web efforts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Folksonomies tend to be more generalised. Ontologies need more specificity. How will this be resolved?
<ul>
<li>At this point, don&#8217;t know. Too hard to tell, but it is a low-hanging fruit problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>[flickr]tag:web20expo+ontologiesoftheweb@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-ontologies-for-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">941</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
