<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>edmonton &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/edmonton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 15:04:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Red Eye Greyhound</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=red-eye-greyhound</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 15:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So when you last left me, dear reader, I was sitting in the Denny&#8217;s in Red Deer (the only place I could find that was open sufficiently late), biding my time before heading down to the Greyhound station to find my 3:00 (am) bus for Edmonton. I honestly wish I could spin a yarn of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Red Eye Greyhound"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So when you last left me, dear reader, I was sitting in the Denny&#8217;s in Red Deer (the only place I could find that was open sufficiently late), biding my time before heading down to the Greyhound station to find my 3:00 (am) bus for Edmonton.<br />
I honestly wish I could spin a yarn of difficulty, with a late, packed bus, screaming kids, barfing drunk people, a tired and beligerent driver, getting lost in who-knows-where Alberta before the engine gives out and stranding us in -15 C weather. I wish I could tell you that, because it would be a lot more interesting than what happened.<br />
I got on the bus at 3:07 (the bus was a wee bit late), and I got off just after 6:00 (I didn&#8217;t look at the clock). I had two seats to myself. No-one made a sound save for the driver, who was very nice about announcing arrivals, and drove very well (so far as I could tell, anyway &#8212; I was trying to get some sleep, which I think I managed). I arrived with my head attached.<br />
The worst part of this segment of the trip has been trying to find a decent place in Edmonton for breakfast. Your run-of-the-mill diner is hard to come by, though that&#8217;s likely due to the fact that it&#8217;s the downtown core, and not the funkier parts of town.<br />
But I sit here, in the Three Bananas Cafe (eating a breakfast sandwich), looking out on the Edmonton City Centre building in his purplish glow, watching the signs at the top of the CN building tracing out the company&#8217;s logo over and over.<br />
Yeah. Boring.<br />
Sorry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3228</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2010-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Man, it feels like a year ago since I last wrote one of these &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;) 2010 was the year we made contact &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2010, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, it feels like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/">a year ago since I last wrote one of these</a> &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;)<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_(film)">2010 was the year we made contact</a> &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named Choo Choo. It was a year I changed my career outlook (yes, again), and found that I&#8217;m not (completely) useless. This was a year of family, for me, and that&#8217;s perhaps the most important aspect.<br />
But despite all that, I hesitate to call it &#8220;a year of change&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2829"></span>Got me as to why, though. Let&#8217;s be honest, there were a lot of changes, not the least of which are the ones noted above. But at no time did I feel like this is a sudden (and possibly unwanted) shift in my life. It actually feels like things are more settled this year, despite the apparent upheaval, than in previous years. Maybe one day I&#8217;ll make some sense of that little quandary.<br />
In the meantime, let&#8217;s review 2010:</p>
<ul>
<li>Began the year with tea at the Banff Springs, seeing my friend Sonny for the first time in about 15 years</li>
<li>Started working with some old friends at a new(er) company, Evans Hunt</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton for a &#8220;surprise&#8221; weekend (mostly for Monkey) and spent a great morning in the waterslides with her</li>
<li>Celebrated my Nana&#8217;s 97th birthday, which would also sadly be her last</li>
<li>Found out that I&#8217;m K+, my kids are K+, and my wife is anti-K</li>
<li>Spent many a sleepless night worrying about Choo Choo before she was born</li>
<li>Though originally disheartened, came to love and be thrilled by the 2010 Winter Olympics in Canada, and felt the massive pride for the successes of our athletes
<ul>
<li>Yes, I Twittered obsessively during the Men&#8217;s Hockey gold medal game</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bought our first flat-screen TV, to go along with our Apple TV</li>
<li>Welcomed my youngest, (code)named Choo Choo to our world</li>
<li>Watched Monkey&#8217;s first Easter egg hunt</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;ve got something called &#8220;narrow angles&#8221; in my eyes, and got laser surgery in both of them</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller, and visited the Royal Tyrell</li>
<li>Guided (albeit not as well as I could have) the technical launch of my first all-Drupal website: VisitCalgary.com</li>
<li>Experienced the abject terror of losing your child in a mall</li>
<li>Said &#8220;thank you&#8221; to my Nana &#8212; I never say &#8220;goodbye&#8221;</li>
<li>Went on my first train chase with Monkey</li>
<li>Went to dim sum a couple of times, but not nearly enough</li>
<li>Introduced Monkey to sushi &#8212; I think she likes it</li>
<li>Went to Heritage Park a couple of times, and even saw Thomas the Tank Engine (hey, I&#8217;m a parent <em>and</em> I like trains, it&#8217;s a win-win)</li>
<li>Went to the Zoo lots (it helps to have a pass)</li>
<li>Saw a few movies, but not enough for my liking (the favourite of the year was Toy Story 3, and no, not just because I&#8217;m a parent)</li>
<li>Went on the first Great Family Roadtrip:
<ul>
<li>Overnighted in Medicine Hat, AB; Whitewood, SK; Moosimin, SK; and Swift Current, SK</li>
<li>Went to Winnipeg</li>
<li>Went to some place east of Camper, out in the middle of nowhere, as part of Alex&#8217;s family reunion</li>
<li>Stopped off in Regina, Moose Jaw, and Portage La Prairie</li>
<li>Drove the whole way and back again, and the kids didn&#8217;t seem to mind at all</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got diagnosed with a hernia (yay, me)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 3rd birthday, her first in Canada (beyond the day she was born, that is)</li>
<li>Finally got right ticked off with Shaw&#8217;s horrid home internet service, and switched over to Telus &#8230; we&#8217;ll see how it all goes</li>
<li>Did some kitchen renovation:
<ul>
<li>Installed a new sink and tap</li>
<li>Tore out the Florida ceiling</li>
<li>Installed new lighting</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had new windows installed in the house</li>
<li>Returned to being a developer, rather than a pure manager (I&#8217;m still adjusting to this one)</li>
<li>Took Monkey out on her first real Hallowe&#8217;en</li>
<li>Grew a moustache for Movember (my first, and last time)</li>
<li>Went to the Currie Barracks location of the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market almost every weekend for a year, until the location finally (and sadly) closed in December</li>
<li>Went on our first family flight out to Abbotsford, to spend Christmas in BC</li>
<li>Visited with some old friends from Radical Entertainment</li>
<li>Went to downtown Vancouver for the first time in about five years, and remembered how much I love it there</li>
<li>Had my first green Christmas in many, many years</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains</li>
</ul>
<p>Whoof. That&#8217;s a lot for one year. Can&#8217;t wait to see what 2011 throws at me. Bring it, New Year &#8212; I&#8217;m ready for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A bullet train in Calgary?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-bullet-train-in-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 22:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/09/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train from here to Fort McMurray. Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks. Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A bullet train in Calgary?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/calgary/story/2008/01/09/10year-plan.html">Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train</a> from here to Fort McMurray.<br />
Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks.<br />
<span id="more-887"></span>Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train in Alberta is insane. Completely. Why, you ask?</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is going to pay the $3-4 billion to build a dedicated grade-separated, high-speed rail network? Don&#8217;t look to either <a href="http://www.cp.ca/">CP</a> or <a href="http://www.cn.ca">CN</a>.</li>
<li>Similarly, who runs it? If it&#8217;s VIA, expect the service to have constant problems, since budgets to run high-speed are much higher than regular trains, and <a href="http://www.viarail.ca">VIA</a>&#8216;s got enough budgetary problems as it is.</li>
<li>Do we honestly think there would be enough use of the trains to make them even remotely cost-effective? <a href="http://www.westjet.com">WestJet</a> is pretty darn cheap, y&#8217;know&#8230;</li>
<li>The provincial government was looking to shore up the existing lines up north to help move heavy equipment by train. CN passed on the work (they own the lines) after realising the cost to build up the service wasn&#8217;t worth the revenue. Take that as a subtle hint for new lines.</li>
<li>It hits -40 in many places, with a lot of snow. I don&#8217;t know of many (read: any) high-speed lines that regularly go through such conditions. Hokkaido in Japan is the nearest, and even that&#8217;s not as severe.</li>
</ul>
<p>Politically, it strikes me as odd that anyone would stand up behind this as a good idea, since it&#8217;ll likely be a government that owns it, and it would probably become a white elephant. Very cool, and I&#8217;d ride it just for the sake of riding it &#8212; but governments have been voted out of office for stuff like this.<br />
All of that said, it&#8217;s totally the green option. Run the train often enough, and you have less cars (less automobile pollution) and less planes (less aviation pollution). It&#8217;s also a nicer way to travel long distances. And Canada&#8217;s full of that distance thing.<br />
Mind you, the bullet train wasn&#8217;t the only &#8220;odd&#8221; thing in that report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Building a ring road in Calgary. Um&#8230; <a href="http://content.calgary.ca/CCA/City+Hall/Office+of+the+Mayor/Press+Room/Archive/2006/February+2006/NE+Ring+Road.htm">aren&#8217;t we doing that already</a>?</li>
<li>Where is the mention of expanding Calgary Transit? For the love of Pete, people &#8212; why are you trying to link together cities when [[Calgary Transit Sucks|we can&#8217;t even sort ourselves out]]?</li>
<li>A covered skywalk or monorail between the Telus Convention Centre and the Stampede facilities. What, the C-Train isn&#8217;t good enough for you already? (See previous note about public transit.)</li>
<li>An international aerospace hub. If there was a way to eloquently describe my blank stare at this one, I would. But I&#8217;m simply not that good a writer.</li>
</ul>
<p>I offer one thought to the people who came up with this: Let&#8217;s blueprint something for success, please? Around my office, we ask people to set SMART goals. It&#8217;s an acronym, with the &#8220;R&#8221; standing for &#8220;realistic&#8221;. Which these blueprints really seem to be missing.<br />
If you want success, you needn&#8217;t look further than our own front door. We have three overloaded hospitals, our transit system is not keeping pace with the need, ambulances are running short on availability regularly, and if you haven&#8217;t thought about our water supply availability, you might want to consider that soon, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend in Edmonton</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-edmonton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2004 04:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/08/22/surprise-weekend-edmonton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend in Edmonton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away.<br />
It was a bit of a special one, but for no other reason than we&#8217;d barely seen each other in almost three weeks. I was away in San Jose for a conference (see [[Search Engine Strategies Conference 2004 San Jose, Calgary to San Jose]]), followed immediately by the Calgary Dragon Boat Festival (see [[2004 Calgary Dragon Boat Festival]]), and then Alex was off in Ontario for a week and a half. So I had to plan this weekend&#8217;s getaway so we&#8217;d have some time to ourselves.<br />
<span id="more-378"></span>That&#8217;s the tricky part, actually. I had a devil of a time finding something quasi-romantic, yet equitable, and that wouldn&#8217;t put a major dent in my wallet. Easier said than done when you consider that it&#8217;s high season out here for tourism. So I decided to go some place somewhere unconventional for tourism. The sort of place that doesn&#8217;t immediately come to your mind as a destination. (It is, at least at this end of Alberta, even considered a punishment by some.)<br />
Edmonton.<br />
It&#8217;s a large city, with interesting things, comfortable hotels, and a wee bit of shopping. (Yes, that&#8217;s a joke.) I&#8217;d only ever been there three times before (once on my Trans-Canada tour in 1997, again with the Rocky Mountain Rail Society in October 2001, and then with the CBC almost a year later). In those three times, I&#8217;d barely seen anything of Edmonton, so this was a chance to see &#8230; well, more than I had. Now all I had to do was keep Alex in the dark as to where she was going.<br />
That&#8217;s a lot harder than it sounds. Alex wanted to know &#8212; who doesn&#8217;t want to know what a surprise is? Be damned if she didn&#8217;t really dig for it, too. In fact, Thursday night, she kept at me for nearly two straight hours of questioning. She was persistent, and sometimes really sneaky when composing her questions. I was quite proud of myself for not supplying the answer, while not lying about the destination.<br />
But everyone has their Achilles heel. Mine is Miao-Yin.<br />
Alex took a turn of what was supposed to be silly questioning, where she asked if the cat would like where we were going. Would the cat enjoy the view? Would she like to drive? What about if she wanted to stop and get out for a while? Hey, maybe she could take us out for dinner one night! It was supposed to be in fun, but I got stuck on the more serious side: namely, the cat wouldn&#8217;t survive the trip down the block without me going insane from her yowling, let alone the three hour drive to Edmonton&#8230;<br />
Insert a long string of emphatic expletives here. Because that&#8217;s what spewed out of my mouth immediately after &#8212; letting the cat out of the bag &#8212; I said where we were going.<br />
So that piece of the surprise was divulged the night before. Doh. But Alex didn&#8217;t know where we were staying, or why she had to bring a nice outfit. And those I kept quite tightly under wraps.<br />
Despite leaving Calgary a little later than I&#8217;d planned Friday evening, we arrived in Red Deer before 19:30. Hunting for a restaurant downtown (and turning up empty), we ended up at the White Spot. (Not my first choice of places for dinner, but it holds a particular place in Alex&#8217;s heart from when she was younger.) It took everything I had not to mock our waiter, obviously a student from Red Deer College, either trying to be an actor or a radio personality, and failing miserably. His schmaltzy shtick dripped of goofiness, despite an obvious desire to be taken seriously. I know more than a few people who would have talked back to him in the same manner.<br />
I&#8217;d never arrived in Edmonton from the south before. Fortunately, signs weren&#8217;t too hard to follow to downtown, and the road was actually familiar from the time the CBC crew had taken a shuttle bus to the train station &#8212; surprisingly, I still remembered it. The hard part was then finding the hotel. Despite having the address, the grid system actually confused me rather than helped. Alex was rhyming off building names or companies, starting at the names of hotels before slipping into ones like banks, insurance companies, restaurants, and the YMCA. Finally, I found the Westin, and we pulled in.<br />
Why the Westin? One reason: The Heavenly Bed. I spent a weekend in one during a prison term in Cincinnati (see [[Live from Cincinnati, Surviving Memorial Day]]) and haven&#8217;t forgotten it. Given how much Alex and I hadn&#8217;t seen each other, and Alex&#8217;s less-than-stellar trip to Ontario, I felt that perhaps a really comfortable stay would help. It certainly couldn&#8217;t hurt&#8230;<br />
We checked in on a very auspicious weekend. In addition to the Fringe Festival (an annual event in Edmonton), there was also the Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival (Topmade sent the Dragoneers, and Sang and Colette were also paddling for Crew Yahoo of the Calgary Dragon Boat Club), the Jazz Festival (I think), the 100th Anniversary of Edmonton, and the coup de grace, being held at the Westin, the National Bodybuilding Championship.<br />
Be still my beating heart.<br />
After waking up quite late the following morning (we were both quite content to stay in the Heavenly Bed), we went in search of breakfast. A flip through the phonebook was a bit frustrating due to the lack of options. Eventually, we decided on the Denny&#8217;s, about 12 blocks from the Westin. It would have been a nice walk, had it not been cold, windy, with a spattering of rain mixed in for flavour. We cut through the mall downtown to save ourselves from the chill.<br />
The Denny&#8217;s was packed. But it was also one of the only eateries that we could find in the area that serves breakfast, at least from judging by the line-up inside. It took nearly a half hour to get a seat for two. It would take about the same amount of time to actually get our breakfast once ordered.<br />
While we waited, we babbled nearly incoherently about whatever kept coming to mind. (Hey, we had almost three weeks of events and trivial crap to catch up on.) While we chatted, a semi-familiar silhouette passed through my peripheral vision, heading into the washroom.<br />
Me: &#8220;I think that&#8217;s Mo!&#8221;<br />
Alex: &#8220;Mo? Topmade Mo?&#8221;<br />
Me: &#8220;Yeah&#8230; it *is* Mo! And there&#8217;s Byron, and Arnold!&#8221;<br />
The Topmade Dragoneers were in town (the aforementioned Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival), and some of the team had apparently decided to grab a meal at Denny&#8217;s in between the races. (The Edmonton Festival, unlike it&#8217;s Cowtown counterpart, is planned very well. It also had the sense to judge teams by the times they logged racing, not by some idiotic point system &#8212; Calgary Festival organizers, take note!)<br />
Arnold was surprised by our appearance:<br />
&#8220;You&#8217;re the last two I expected to see here!&#8221;<br />
Yeah, I know, what the heck does that mean? I was wondering that, slightly miffed. It wasn&#8217;t like we didn&#8217;t enjoy ourselves paddling. I&#8217;m rather looking forward to it next year. Actually, if anything, I&#8217;m miffed that I&#8217;m not getting the club updates (they were looking for volunteers this weekend; not that I&#8217;d have been able to go even if I had got the notice). We promised to drop by later on.<br />
We trudged out into the rain following our meal, and decided to take a shortcut through Grant McEwan Community College, just across the street. (Partly because it&#8217;s an interesting-looking building, but also because it was warm and dry.) The college campus is situated on the old Canadian National rail yard that used to run through downtown Edmonton (well, what is now downtown Edmonton &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t downtown when the yard was built). With the yard relocated to the north end of the city, the lands were freed up for other uses. The $16 million parcel of land was donated to the College, which then built its main campus.<br />
The College&#8217;s namesake, Grant McEwan, is a man of considerable distinction. Alex and I didn&#8217;t really know who the man was. Thanks to an exhibit in the main lobby, we found out that the Honourable Mr. McEwan was a Professor and the Director of the School of Agriculture at the University of Saskatchewan, a magazine editor (and prolific author), a Calgary alderman and a three-year Mayor of our fair city, became an MLA for Calgary and was elected the Liberal Party leader, became the Lieutenant Governor of Alberta for eight and a half years before going into semi-retirement. He never slowed down, however, and continued humanitarian work until his death in 2000 (at the age of almost 98).<br />
There are times when you simply can&#8217;t avoid feeling humbled.<br />
We ended up having to dive back into the rain, thoroughly unable to avoid it. We trudged through the Farmer&#8217;s Market before finally finding our way back to the mall we&#8217;d cut through earlier in the morning. We did some window shopping (I ended buying a new fleece jacket, mostly because I hadn&#8217;t come properly prepared for the weather) before returning to the hotel. We napped. It was great.<br />
Dinner was a surprise I managed to keep on tap, though Alex guessed the destination by some of the clues I had let out (but by then, I didn&#8217;t mind) &#8212; Fairmont&#8217;s Hotel MacDonald, about a block from the Westin. Specifically, the Harvest Room. I was told this was one of the best restaurants in town, and I wanted to take Alex there. I even wore a suit and tie for the affair.<br />
Oh, one thing I need to point out. While we were preparing for dinner (mainly me ironing my clothes), we listened to the radio. Much to our surprise (and near shock), we came across 92.5, known as Joe FM. Now this might sound a little weird &#8212; why would I identify a radio station, you might ask? It&#8217;s a sister station of 96.9 Jack FM. Same commercials, same commercial voice dude, but it just didn&#8217;t sound right. Even the slogan was different: Playing &#8230; Anything! (In Calgary, it&#8217;s &#8220;Playing &#8230; what we want!&#8221;) Yet another reason why Edmonton and Calgary don&#8217;t get along.<br />
I have to say that I was mildly disappointed with the experience. The hotel itself is nice, but the Harvest Room lacked the old-world quality you often find in the older Fairmont hotels (most notably the Banff Springs). The food was well done, but I felt I&#8217;d had better meals here in Calgary, and much &#8220;lower-end&#8221; restaurants. I also felt the service wasn&#8217;t quite to the level I&#8217;d expect for Fairmont. (Or more importantly, a Canadian Pacific Hotel.) Such as it is, the meal was wonderful, as was the company. Next time, though, I think we&#8217;ll go somewhere else.<br />
By the time the meal was done, it was nearly 20:00, so we opted for a dip in our hotel&#8217;s hot tub (it was a little chilly outside). After a cold beverage in the bar, we headed for bed. Despite really doing nothing, we were both quite tired.<br />
Awaking late again the next morning, we rose, showered and packed, while watching the Olympics. I haven&#8217;t watched much of it this year (partly due to the time change), but what little I have seen kind of annoys me. And it&#8217;s not he performances, it&#8217;s all the media.<br />
C&#8217;mon folks, it ain&#8217;t about the medals. So what if Canada isn&#8217;t getting that many this year? Big deal! Our athletes are out there, competing, and doing a pretty good job, all things considered. Are they gonna bring home the bacon? Maybe, but will the world end if they don&#8217;t? Probably not. Just let them compete without all the additional pressure &#8212; they went there to represent Canada, not be bad-mouthed by us.<br />
Checking out, we drove (as it was raining even harder Sunday morning) for Denny&#8217;s. No-one from Topmade was there that time, so we ate in relative anonymity. We headed back to our hotel&#8217;s parking lot, though, to go down to the festival area to see our friends and team-mates.<br />
We arrived just in time for the Sistership tribute. This is something they do almost every festival (they didn&#8217;t do it in Calgary, for some reason). It&#8217;s in tribute to those lost to breast cancer. Sistership is a club whose members are all cancer patients, past and present.<br />
Passing by the boards, we found the scores of the previous day. Topmade Dragoneers had done quite well, and were ranked up with EDBC and Jetstart (from Toronto). One of the others under the tent commented that the first race was going to be a good one. Alex and I would not wait to see it, as we were cold and wet, and really not wanting to stick around in the weather.<br />
Finding Topmade&#8217;s tent, we found Sang and Collette inside. We chatted for a while before following them down as they went to get something to eat. We left them at the food vendors and returned to the car. We were off&#8230;<br />
&#8230;to West Edmonton Mall. The largest mall in the world. The megalopolis of merchandising.<br />
It&#8217;s a weird place, if you&#8217;ve never been. Parts of it make sense. But then you run into Galaxyland (formerly known as Fantasyland), which is the midway there. Rides that you would normally see at the Calgary Stampede, PNE, or CNE are permanent showcases there. Even the infamous rollercoaster on which people died a number of years ago. It&#8217;s loud. It&#8217;s hard to believe you&#8217;re in a shopping mall.<br />
And then there&#8217;s the ice rink, the water park, the indoor golf course, the submarines, and the model of the Santa Maria.<br />
Oh, and lest we forget the over two decade-old design? That place is in *serious* need of a facelift. (It also didn&#8217;t help that the glass roof leaks, probably due to that nasty hailstorm and flooding of a couple months ago.)<br />
Considering its size, the mall wasn&#8217;t that bad for crowds &#8212; we had little or no trouble getting around. Well, except for size &#8212; the mall is huge, after all. I was disappointed to see that Sega Playdium had closed down. Considering the other attractions in the mall, however, I could understand.<br />
After about four hours, we&#8217;d had enough, and it was time to head home. Alex tried to cross-stitch as we headed out of town, but eventually switched over to reading for a while (reading to *me*, I might add) to take a break.<br />
We stopped again in Red Deer for dinner, this time going to Boston Pizza for, well, pizza. Nothing outlandish, we split a small (10&#8243;) between us, which was just perfect. Then it was back on the highway in the rain, drizzle, and fog, before arriving back at Alex&#8217;s shortly after 21:00.<br />
The weekend was good, despite the weather. Edmonton isn&#8217;t exactly the vacation destination I had thought it might be, but then we didn&#8217;t see much of it either. Next time, we&#8217;ll have to go somewhere else, though. Someplace less urban.<br />
And if you&#8217;re looking for hints here, Alex, you&#8217;ll have to try harder than that!<br />
[flickr]tag:edmonton+august+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">378</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
