<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>critical mass &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/critical-mass/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 06:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Goodbye, Critical Mass</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/goodbye-critical-mass/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=goodbye-critical-mass</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/goodbye-critical-mass/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 06:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey Critical Mass! I&#8217;m sorry I didn&#8217;t say &#8220;goodbye&#8221; properly. You know, the traditional email that goes around to cmassother, usually followed with the &#8220;we&#8217;ll be in the Ship starting at 5 o&#8217;clock&#8221;. I never got a chance to fire one out, such as things are, so really my best avenue to say hasta la &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/goodbye-critical-mass/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Goodbye, Critical Mass"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey Critical Mass! I&#8217;m sorry I didn&#8217;t say &#8220;goodbye&#8221; properly. You know, the traditional email that goes around to cmassother, usually followed with the &#8220;we&#8217;ll be in the Ship starting at 5 o&#8217;clock&#8221;. I never got a chance to fire one out, such as things are, so really my best avenue to say hasta la vista is here. Hopefully a few of you get to see it.<br />
Truth be told, I had been planning my &#8220;goodbye&#8221; message for years. (As my dad used to say, if you&#8217;re going to do something, do it right.) If nothing else, it would have been fun to make: a video that would cover my time at CM, complete with a snazzy soundtrack, and some bogus story about going to teach at an all-girls school. But planning means nothing without execution, and I never got around to it. I&#8217;m sure I will come to regret that.<br />
Some of you won&#8217;t have a clue about who the fark I am. Some of you know me all-too-well. No matter where you sit in the spectrum, do yourself a favour and look around at all the people sitting near you. They, and you, are the people who make up Critical Mass.<br />
As many have said before me, it&#8217;s the people I will miss most.<br />
<span id="more-2503"></span>It&#8217;s been said &#8212; often by the spouses of CMers &#8212; that Critical Mass is a cult. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s really true anymore (I can&#8217;t honestly say &#8212; don&#8217;t forget I&#8217;ve been in Costa Rica for a year and a half), but it was certainly fact in my earlier years. We worked together, we ate together, we drank together, we played together, and in more than a few cases, we married and had kids together. You make your own decision on the definition.<br />
In those years, I met (and drank with) a lot of amazing people. And if you&#8217;re reading this, you&#8217;re one of them. No matter what you think of me now, or what you believe I might think of you, here&#8217;s a little unvarnished truth: I admire you. I do, really. I admire you for any number of reasons, not the least of which would include your creativity, your logic, your passion, your leadership, your wisdom, your calmness, your insight, your humour, your kindness, your tolerance. This list could go on quite a lot longer, but hopefully you see where I&#8217;m coming from.<br />
Yes, I like you. And I <em>will</em> miss you. All of you. I will miss seeing you daily (or at least weekly). I will miss the banter. I will miss the feeling of inclusion. I will miss the challenges, the victories, the discussions, and especially the arguments. I will miss the Bistro. I will miss the frontline of the front desk.<br />
I miss it all already.<br />
But change is inevitable in life. You can&#8217;t avoid it, you can&#8217;t cheat it. When change comes, the only thing you can do is embrace it and move with the beat &#8212; fighting change just incurs injury. My time to change coincided with my return to Canada, for better or for worse. Change is also chaotic, which is why I haven&#8217;t really had a chance to say anything. Better late than never, right?<br />
So this is my chance to tell you, the best of luck in <em>your</em> future endeavours.<br />
I also have to say &#8220;thank you&#8221;. When I started in April 2000, I was pretty green. I&#8217;d had some experience in my own projects, but I quickly learned that I had a lot to learn. And you were always willing to teach me, from every department, from every level. You gave me access to the best minds, and the opportunities to test those learnings and prove my own worth. You allowed me to take more responsibility, and allowed me to guide others as others had guided me.<br />
I hope that whatever legacy I&#8217;ve left behind either helps, or is duly forgotten (there&#8217;s nothing like a roadblock to mess up your day). I hope that the friends I made over the years don&#8217;t mind me popping in every now and then to visit. And I hope I can make off with the mulligatawny soup recipe &#8212; that one is worth killing for.<br />
And yes, I&#8217;ll still be watching. I want to see how my friends are doing, and see their successes. There&#8217;s no point in an award if there&#8217;s no-one to congratulate you on it, right?<br />
Until when next we meet&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/goodbye-critical-mass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2503</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 years &#8230; and counting</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/9-years-and-counting/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=9-years-and-counting</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/9-years-and-counting/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hangar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today marks yet another notch on the belt of my career. Today, I&#8217;ve been at Critical Mass (or within the Critical Mass family, anyway) for nine years.   It&#8217;s weird. Very weird. I&#8217;m actually having trouble comprehending this fact. Nine years of my life (1/10th, depending on how long you think I might live) has &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/9-years-and-counting/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "9 years &#8230; and counting"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today marks yet another notch on the belt of my career. Today, I&#8217;ve been at Critical Mass (or within the Critical Mass family, anyway) for nine years.  <br />
It&#8217;s weird. Very weird. I&#8217;m actually having trouble comprehending this fact. Nine years of my life (1/10th, depending on how long you think I might live) has been with one company. In my father&#8217;s generation, that would be considered &#8220;getting started&#8221;. In my generation, it&#8217;s considered &#8220;insane&#8221; &#8212; the turnaround is often two years or less.  <br />
But here I am. Nine years, and counting. If you&#8217;d asked me at the end of my first year if I&#8217;d still be around eight years later, I&#8217;d have said that you were crazy. It&#8217;s been a hell of a ride, and at the same time seems almost short, now. But there&#8217;s a lot of memories in those years, too.  <br />
Okay, enough reminiscing&#8230; I got work to do&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/9-years-and-counting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2008, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2008-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 18:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hasta la vista, 2008! You were a tough year in the life, and while you certainly gave me a good run, I&#8217;m not unhappy to see you go. You&#8217;ve lead me further down the road of fatherhood, brought me back dear old friends, brought me new challenges at work &#8230; and of course moved me &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2008, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hasta la vista, 2008! You were a tough year in the life, and while you certainly gave me a good run, I&#8217;m not unhappy to see you go. You&#8217;ve lead me further down the road of fatherhood, brought me back dear old friends, brought me new challenges at work &#8230; and of course moved me to an entirely different country. But with all of this, you&#8217;ve brought a whole mess of turmoil, instability, and grief.  <br />
Now for those of you who&#8217;ve not been following along &#8212; and what the heck, even for those of you have &#8212; here&#8217;s what I&#8217;m talking about:<span id="more-1212"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Started the year with a big decision: move to Costa Rica and help start up a new business</li>
<li>Marvelled in the wonder of my daughter learning how to speak, and starting her first unaided steps (of course now we need a homing beacon and a volume setting, but that&#8217;s another story)</li>
<li>Came to the heavily sobering reality that I am not my father, and finally agreed that we needed a contractor to finish the redevelopment of our basement</li>
<li>Was extremely happy to see the basement finally complete</li>
<li>Switched briefly to a Mac before switching back to a PC (too many issues with emails and meetings); I now curse the reality that I wish I were on one</li>
<li>Came down with an evil flu, despite getting a flu shot</li>
<li>Saw my first NBA game</li>
<li>Went to Chicago</li>
<li>Went to San Francisco</li>
<li>Went to Santa Cruz (and went for a sailboat trip out on the ocean)</li>
<li>Went to Las Vegas</li>
<li>Went to London</li>
<li>Went to Glasgow</li>
<li>Went to Oban</li>
<li>Went to Iona</li>
<li>Went to Inverness</li>
<li>Went to Edinburgh (albeit briefly)</li>
<li>Went to York</li>
<li>Went to Costa Rica twice in three weeks &#8230; the second time to move there</li>
<li>Haven&#8217;t returned to Canada since mid-July (went to bring my family down)</li>
<li>Went to Panama City twice</li>
<li>Saw the Panama Canal (and a ship travel through the locks)</li>
<li>Went to Toronto</li>
<li>Went to Oakville and Burlington</li>
<li>Went to Punta Leona</li>
<li>Went to Montezuma</li>
<li>Went to Arenal (again)</li>
<li>Went into San José many times</li>
<li>Went to New York City for Christmas</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains (despite going to the UK)</li>
<li>Attended the Web 2.0 conference</li>
<li>Learnt to drive Costa Rican-style</li>
<li>ComenzÃ³ a aprender español</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of my friend Sean</li>
<li>Missed my many friends dearly &#8212; one feels very alone and separated down here</li>
<li>Made more new friends</li>
<li>Bought a new used car (for far more than it should have cost&#8230;)</li>
<li>Got a traffic ticket for pulling a u-turn</li>
<li>Went to a Costa Rican soccer, er futbol game</li>
<li>Tried to encourage my former co-Calgarians to vote Jim Prentice out of office (sadly, it was likely too little, too late)</li>
<li>Experienced considerable grief with our internet connections, both at home and at work</li>
<li>Actually managed to get a decent Thanksgiving meal in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Felt two earthquakes, one of which I almost slept through</li>
<li>Drank my first cup of coffee (current tally: 15)</li>
<li>Got to experience Halloween in a different country</li>
<li>Came to loathe Costa Rican traffic</li>
<li>Had our first Costa Rican office Christmas party</li>
<li>Saw the fireworks for New Year&#8217;s Eve</li>
</ul>
<p>So that brings us into 2009. I wonder what this year will bring us?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/2008-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finally got my box!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/finally-got-my-box/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=finally-got-my-box</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/finally-got-my-box/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 17:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hangar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Way back in June &#8212; the 13th, to be specific (I guess that should have been a first sign, eh?) &#8212; I packed up a whack of things on my desk to bring down to Costa Rica. TeamMG (Mary and Morgan) arranged for this to be shipped down here by FedEx, a company I had &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/finally-got-my-box/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finally got my box!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Way back in June &#8212; the 13th, to be specific (I guess that should have been a first sign, eh?) &#8212; I packed up a whack of things on my desk to bring down to Costa Rica. TeamMG (Mary and Morgan) arranged for this to be shipped down here by FedEx, a company I had used many, many times to get things from Point A to Point B quickly.<br />
Problem: When a company doesn&#8217;t have a complete representation in Point B, you&#8217;re not going to get your box as fast as you thought.<br />
Today is 24 July. I only got the box today.<br />
<span id="more-1024"></span>The box I used was a photocopier paper box. They&#8217;re fairly strong, put up well with abuse. I packed it carefully, because I figured even with a &#8220;good&#8221; shipper like FedEx (more on that in a moment) that it might get jostled a bit. The box as received was battered, torn, well-deformed, and heavily-taped. This was definitely not the condition I expected to receive it in.<br />
[flickr]photo:2699145382(small)[/flickr]<br />
Only one thing was damaged &#8212; my Hawaiian Tiki doll (the God of Money). Something must&#8217;ve shifted and broke the legs off. The way I&#8217;d packed it, there&#8217;s no chance of that happening, but things were also moved around in there, so someone really did a piss-poor job of repacking. Should I claim the damages? I suppose so, but somehow the $3,500 dollars to fly back out to the Big Island to get a new one probably won&#8217;t come through. I think some crazy glue will do.<br />
[flickr]photo:2699164180(small)[/flickr]<br />
The process to get the box was insane. And it still is for Mark &#8212; his boxes are still in customs, and they want $200 to clear them. Each. All because Mark tossed in some running shoes in lieu of bringing them himself. What the hell! Apparently, Jason&#8217;s in a similar boat, and he&#8217;s got stuff that&#8217;s not even worth $50.<br />
FedEx washed their hands of the affair, too. Apparently, once it&#8217;s inside Costa Rica, it&#8217;s not their problem. Well, FedEx, it&#8217;s definitely no longer your problem, as we&#8217;re no longer going to use you. Your competitor, DHL, seems far more competent and willing to help. Jerks.<br />
Now all I need is some tea and some hot water&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/finally-got-my-box/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1024</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RIP: Sean Lineham</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=rip-sean-lineham</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 02:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rolex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I arrived back in Costa Rica with my family in tow. Little did I know that my &#8220;other&#8221; family &#8212; my friends and colleagues back in Calgary, were facing quite the tragedy. I found out no sooner than I turned on my computer to send a quick note to my partners here in Costa &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "RIP: Sean Lineham"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I arrived back in Costa Rica with my family in tow. Little did I know that my &#8220;other&#8221; family &#8212; my friends and colleagues back in Calgary, were facing quite the tragedy. I found out no sooner than I turned on my computer to send a quick note to my partners here in Costa Rica (remember, I have no phone with which to call them), and I got an IM request from Dave. All he said was: &#8220;Call me. Urgent.&#8221;<br />
It would appear that my friend, colleague, and fellow watch geek (though I could never ascribe to the level he attained) Sean Lineham passed away last night.<br />
<span id="more-1023"></span>Needless to say, I was shocked. It&#8217;s never easy to hear that a friend has died. It&#8217;s even harder when there seemed to be no warning. No chance to say anything, no opportunity to change the outcome.<br />
I can&#8217;t imagine how hard it must be for my old team back up in Calgary. Sean was a core part of the Rolex team, and was the heart of knowing all there was to know about watches. And since his switch to I&amp;P, he was the guy we bugged to figure out our next directions with technology. His enthusiasm and joy about the things we did were tangible at every moment. It is a terribly sad loss to lose that kind of energy.<br />
Farewell, Sean. May you find peace, and with luck our paths may cross again in this strange little universe.<br />
Here&#8217;s to you Sean!<br />
[flickr]photo:2299900469(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where I&#039;ve been for the last few days</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/where-ive-been-for-the-last-few-days/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=where-ive-been-for-the-last-few-days</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/where-ive-been-for-the-last-few-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 03:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panama canal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1012</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m in Panama. Been here since Tuesday afternoon. Been really, really busy. So far, the biggest problem I&#8217;ve had here (aside from the aforementioned busy-ness and subsequent inability to talk to my family), is that I&#8217;ve had Van Halen&#8217;s Panama stuck in my head pretty much since we left San Jose. Damn you, David Lee &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/where-ive-been-for-the-last-few-days/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Where I&#039;ve been for the last few days"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in Panama. Been here since Tuesday afternoon. Been really, really busy. So far, the biggest problem I&#8217;ve had here (aside from the aforementioned busy-ness and subsequent inability to talk to my family), is that I&#8217;ve had Van Halen&#8217;s <em>Panama</em> stuck in my head pretty much since we left San Jose.<br />
Damn you, David Lee Roth. Damn you!<br />
So far, it&#8217;s a great place to visit (a post coming on this soon). But we&#8217;ve been steadily on the move.<br />
Oy.<br />
<span id="more-1012"></span> Lemme recap the last couple of days as best I can.<br />
Tuesday:<br />
8:00 leave apartment, catch taxi to airport.<br />
8:30(ish) arrive at airport<br />
9:05 finally get through check-in<br />
9:15 through security<br />
10:05 board the plane<br />
10:55 finally depart for Panama<br />
13:15 touchdown in Panama (+1 hour time change)<br />
14:45 arrive at hotel<br />
13:15 Javier takes Mark, Jason, and I for a &#8220;little walk&#8221; in the area around the hotel. Javier&#8217;s a shopper. Hits about every second store along the Via España.<br />
16:30 Gabriel (our contact here) picks us up at an Indian shop near the hotel and takes us to the Old Quarter for a tour<br />
16:30 &#8211; 20:30 &#8220;tour&#8221; of the Old Quarter and Miraflores lock of Panama canal. Gabriel (who lives here) gets lost (I think).<br />
20:30 &#8211; 23:00 dinner<br />
23:30 finally get into my room (didn&#8217;t actually get the key until then). Pass out.<br />
[flickr]photo:2630358701(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631180750(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631181706(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2630361231(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631182548(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631184642(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631187954(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2630367431(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2630371793(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631194890(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2631197298(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2630384071(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2630389311(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Wednesday<br />
6:15 up and out to the gym for a workout<br />
7:15 in room and showering.<br />
8:00 breakfast with the team + Dave (who arrived the evening before). Strategy discussion over huevos reveltos.<br />
8:45 &#8211; 18:00 meetings in various places. Convinced I&#8217;m going to get a freaking disease from the DEEP FREEZE Panamanians seem to maintain their air conditioning at. Freaking INSANELY cold. We go outside into the oppressive heat and humidity because it&#8217;s more comfortable.<br />
18:00 &#8211; 19:00 try to answer emails. Emphasis on &#8220;try&#8221;. Internet works, but unable to connect to much. Not sure why. Highly annoying.<br />
19:00 &#8211; 20:00 waiting in the lobby for people to appear. Total lack of communication and no-one knows where everyone else is. Namely Dave, who decides that running in a strange, possibly dangerous city (after dark) is a good idea.<br />
20:00 &#8211; 21:30 Gabriel picks us up again in his Yaris. Yes, Yaris. <em>Four</em> large white men and two not-so-small Ticans. In a YARIS. Jason (probably the tallest of the bunch) and I literally share the front seat, him resting his ass half on the console, the other half on me, and hoping to sweet mercy that the gear shift don&#8217;t end up where the sun don&#8217;t shine. We get lost. Twice. In 10 minutes. In some very sketchy parts of town.<br />
21:30 &#8211; 23:30 finally get to the restaurant (on a peninsula out in the ocean, no less). Panamanians eat late, it seems. Dinner. Chat. Try to not fall asleep in my fish.<br />
00:00 get back to my room. Catch up on a day&#8217;s worth of email. Pass out.<br />
Today<br />
6:15 alarm goes off.<br />
6:25 alarm goes off.<br />
6:35 alarm goes off. Finally drag my arse out of bed. Go have shower.<br />
7:10 breakfast with the team.<br />
7:45 leave for the client&#8217;s office.<br />
8:00 &#8211; 15:30 meetings. Long, tiring day.<br />
15:30 &#8211; 16:00 got to meet Ruben Blades, internationally-renowned singer and actor, who is also the Minister of Tourism. Very freaking cool guy. No, I don&#8217;t have a picture because it&#8217;s highly inappropriate to POIDH while in a business meeting.<br />
16:30 leave the client office for the hotel<br />
17:00 as a result of things from the meetings, we decide to grab a cab and &#8220;drive around&#8221; a bit to get a better feel for Panama. End up in the Old Quarter (again), but get a bit of a guided tour, which is cool.<br />
19:30 dinner. Earliest one yet. Good, but picked a WAY too pricey restaurant. Cheap by our standards, but three times the price of other places we&#8217;ve been.<br />
21:34 I get to post this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/where-ive-been-for-the-last-few-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1012</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lastday. Gemini 13s. Year of the Company 2008. Carousel begins.</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/lastday-gemini-13s-year-of-the-company-2008-carousel-begins/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=lastday-gemini-13s-year-of-the-company-2008-carousel-begins</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/lastday-gemini-13s-year-of-the-company-2008-carousel-begins/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 15:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been with Critical Mass (Canada) for 8 years. Eight years, two months, and 9 days. Today is my last day. Sorta. On Sunday, I leave for Costa Rica. Although I am working for another company, I&#8217;m still technically tied / linked / married / owned / have-tattoo-emblazoned-on-my-arse by Critical Mass. It works out somehow, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/lastday-gemini-13s-year-of-the-company-2008-carousel-begins/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lastday. Gemini 13s. Year of the Company 2008. Carousel begins."</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been with Critical Mass (Canada) for 8 years. Eight years, two months, and 9 days.<br />
Today is my last day.<br />
Sorta.<br />
<span id="more-1001"></span>On Sunday, I leave for Costa Rica. Although I am working for another company, I&#8217;m still technically tied / linked / married / owned / have-tattoo-emblazoned-on-my-arse by Critical Mass. It works out somehow, and I&#8217;m not going to question it. Just in case I ask something that effectively negates something I&#8217;m relying on right now, and it causes more trouble than it&#8217;s worth.<br />
Yes, ignorance is bliss.<br />
It&#8217;s not easy to leave. I have a lot of friends here. Well, actually, most of my friends in Calgary work here, to be honest. I&#8217;m going where I don&#8217;t really know anyone, save for 3-4 people that I&#8217;m working with. That&#8217;s it. I just hope I can get to be friends with them. I leave behind the best team that I&#8217;ve worked with since I started here. That&#8217;s hard for me.<br />
I&#8217;ve had countless people ask me if I&#8217;m excited to go. I&#8217;ll be honest: I&#8217;m terrified.<br />
Not of Costa Rica, or of the uncertainty, or of any of the million or so things that could go wrong. I&#8217;m terrified of being alone. Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña won&#8217;t be coming until mid-July. I have a hard enough time being away from them for a few days, let alone a month. I&#8217;m going to be burning up the internet between Santa Ana and Calgary through Skype. I&#8217;ll likely have my video running most of the day so I can see my daughter. I&#8217;m terrified that she might forget her father. I&#8217;m terrified that I&#8217;m going to miss her first steps.<br />
Yes, I&#8217;m going to a tropical country. Yes, I&#8217;m living in a complex that actually has a swim-up bar. But this is not a vacation, folks. This is a new start-up. This is a lot of work. I&#8217;ve been there before, so I have no illusions about what I&#8217;m getting into. Key things: I have a place to live, I have a place to work. Beyond that, all bets are off.<br />
Ask me again in August if I&#8217;m excited. With luck, I&#8217;ll have a better answer for you by then.<br />
But this is a chapter ending for me. It&#8217;s my last day (and it&#8217;s not). Somehow, I always thought there&#8217;d be more fanfare (on my end, not the company&#8217;s) with this day. At least I thought there&#8217;d be more beer&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/lastday-gemini-13s-year-of-the-company-2008-carousel-begins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1001</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One last lunch with the team</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/one-last-lunch-with-the-team/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=one-last-lunch-with-the-team</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/one-last-lunch-with-the-team/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 19:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rolex]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For all intents and purposes, I&#8217;m off the Rolex team. I&#8217;m still on their resource sheet, but the reality is that I haven&#8217;t done sqwat with the Rolex account for over a couple of weeks now. It&#8217;s all been transferred to Torin, who&#8217;s the new Tech Lead. I went into self-imposed exile at the fringes &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/one-last-lunch-with-the-team/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "One last lunch with the team"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For all intents and purposes, I&#8217;m off the Rolex team. I&#8217;m still on their resource sheet, but the reality is that I haven&#8217;t done sqwat with the Rolex account for over a couple of weeks now. It&#8217;s all been transferred to Torin, who&#8217;s the new Tech Lead. I went into self-imposed exile at the fringes of the team&#8217;s seating space, soon to be a long-distant memory.<br />
But before I left, I had a debt to settle. Many months ago now, I had to institute what we called the &#8220;Jugo Juice Rule&#8221;. It was an effort to get everyone to calm down a bit (we were all under a lot of pressure, and mistakes were becoming more frequent) and concentrate on what they were doing. Short version: If you made a mistake, you owed the entire team Juge Juice (a fruit smoothie).<br />
<span id="more-999"></span>It was pretty simple. Until Tim called me out:</p>
<blockquote><p>If we don&#8217;t make any mistakes, do you owe us Jugo Juice?</p></blockquote>
<p>Well, hell, why not? If I&#8217;m willing to institute a penalty, I&#8217;d better damn well be ready to ante up with a reward, right? It&#8217;s only fair, and incentive is always a good thing.<br />
We came close &#8212; once &#8212; to having the rule violated. In the end, however, no more mistakes were made (peace was restored to the valley) and we moved on. Except that I owed the team Jugo Juices. I even got their orders. But I could never get myself organised well enough to get them purchased and brought in. Add to that the logistical issue of the smoothies all melting before I got them to the office &#8230; and well the idea needed a bit of reevaluation.<br />
(Maybe in the future I&#8217;ll suggest they go for a Froster rule, since there&#8217;s a Macs about four blocks down, which is a perfect distance for the team to go on a break.)<br />
I refuse to leave this team with an unpaid debt. Instead of Jugo Juice, I offered lunch at the nearby Vietnamese place (although I had to buy Phil lunch in the Bistro due to food allergies; still, thanks for coming out anyway, Phil!). Not exactly on-par with cost, but I figured I owed them interest on the unpaid debt, and this was my last chance to have lunch with my old team. The next time I have lunch with a team, it&#8217;ll be over tamales, I think.<br />
It&#8217;s been a blast working with you folks. Try not to forget me too quickly, okay?<br />
[flickr]photo:2570516215(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/one-last-lunch-with-the-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#039;s the end of the world as we know it&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 16:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8230;and I feel, well, okay. Maybe not necessarily &#8220;fine&#8221;. Critical Mass has done a bit of a reorganisation. I emphasise &#8220;a bit&#8221;. Mostly because this is not the radical shifts we&#8217;ve seen in the past. I think this is my third or fourth reorganisation since starting with Critical Mass back in 2000 (admittedly, I&#8217;m losing &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s the end of the world as we know it&#8230;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;and I feel, well, okay. Maybe not necessarily &#8220;fine&#8221;.<br />
Critical Mass has done a bit of a reorganisation. I emphasise &#8220;a bit&#8221;. Mostly because this is not the radical shifts we&#8217;ve seen in the past. I think this is my third or fourth reorganisation since starting with Critical Mass back in 2000 (admittedly, I&#8217;m losing track), and this is the most minor change we&#8217;ve had.<br />
At least when you look at the big picture.<br />
<span id="more-971"></span>In short, no promotions, no demotions. Just changes in role and responsibility. Which, when you think about it, is the real purpose of a reorganisation: shuffle the existing chart to align with your needs. And our needs are global. We have production offices in Calgary, Chicago, Toronto, and London. Costa Rica starts up in 30 days.<br />
In our old system, it was becoming hard to handle all that. We had department VPs who had to spread their influence across many offices. Control was all centralised at Calgary, which while we thought it was good for ensuring standards and practises, tended to impose controls on the other offices, which was detrimental to their operation.<br />
So now we&#8217;ve got independent offices. Each have General Managers, four lead people from each of the former departments (Creative, Technology, Planning, and Operations), and their own controls. They still report to Critical Mass Global Operations (aka Head Office aka Calgary), but the influence of old is greatly lessened.<br />
We&#8217;ve effectively given them all much more rope, and more room for success. We&#8217;ve also likely created more competition. I just hope it remains the healthy kind.<br />
The trick out of all of this is that we don&#8217;t have our over-arching leadership at the department level. It&#8217;s going to be up to the office leads to ensure that communication remains. The last thing we need is to turn into our competition where the individual offices have no clue what the others are doing. It&#8217;s a lousy way to learn when you can&#8217;t/don&#8217;t talk to each other.<br />
There is one part in all of this I don&#8217;t like. Allard Losier, my 8-year leader, mentor, devil&#8217;s advocate, prank target, talk show host, Defender of the Right and Just, and friend is leaving. I can&#8217;t even begin to rhyme off the things I&#8217;ve learned from him over the years, and there&#8217;s no way to calculate the huge effect he&#8217;s had on my career development. An era officially comes to and end with his departure. To the few of us multi-year veterans still left in the (now former) Technology department, this is a hard loss. It also puts the onus on us to ensure that we live up to the expectations, to the things we still believe are right.<br />
We&#8217;re going to miss you Allard. Just so you know.<br />
It&#8217;s (a bit of) a new world. I&#8217;m going to be a part of it, even if at a distance. But I can say that if this goes the way I&#8217;m told it will go, we should see some new and exciting things come from Critical Mass in the coming months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">971</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
