<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>flooring &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/flooring/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 05:20:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The kitchen reno moves along</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-kitchen-reno-moves-along</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 05:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bathroom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitchen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, since I last wrote, much has happened in the house. In our previous installment, the floors were starting to come up. Since then, a lot as happened, and we&#8217;ve had the prerequisite miscommunications, strange discoveries, and mild panic attacks (from us, the client &#8212; our contractor is likely annoyed as hell with us at &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The kitchen reno moves along"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, since I last wrote, much has happened in the house. In our previous installment, the floors were starting to come up. Since then, a lot as happened, and we&#8217;ve had the prerequisite miscommunications, strange discoveries, and mild panic attacks (from us, the client &#8212; our contractor is likely annoyed as hell with us at this point).<br />
But if there&#8217;s one thing I can say, we have progress. Lots of it.<br />
<span id="more-3011"></span>Since we last chatted, the floors have completely come up in the kitchen. However, the subfloor isn&#8217;t perfectly level. The contractor said the addition on our kitchen was a &#8220;handyman special&#8221;, which I gather is a term for &#8220;put together very quickly, and not enough attention was paid to the right things&#8221;. I wasn&#8217;t the least bit surprised.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/the-now-missing-wall-next-to-the-entrance/' title='The (now missing) wall next to the entrance'><img width="238" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/The-now-missing-wall-next-to-the-entrance-238x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3310" alt="The (now missing) wall next to the entrance" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/7003351119/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The wall near our front door is gone, as well, which exposed another issue with the house. In the original construction, there&#8217;s a 2&#215;6 beam that runs from the wall perpendicular to the front entrance over to the main load-bearing member, which runs longitudinally down the house. One 2&#215;6. Just one. 16 feet long. And it supports the weight of the gable over the living room.<br />
Those of you in the know are nodding, perhaps gravely. For the rest of you, this is the same as having a four-legged chair with one leg made out of spaghetti. You can sit on the chair if you&#8217;re careful enough, but &#8230; well, don&#8217;t be surprised if it cracks and breaks. Which is sort of what&#8217;s happening now. There&#8217;s a crack just under the joist, and the entire ceiling is bowed. (Incidentally, it&#8217;s not likely a result of the reno per se &#8212; it looks like it&#8217;s been there a long time, only we couldn&#8217;t see it until we were eye-level with the ceiling.) A second joist will be added to strengthen the ceiling and prevent potential collapse.<br />
The wall between the kitchen and living room is gone; that&#8217;s now a beam tucked into the ceiling to support the weight. The kitchen ceiling has come down (along with the paltry excuse for the insulation in our attic &#8212; something that will also be addressed) along with a fair amount of drywall in the kitchen.<br />
The electricians have come and (almost) gone, having run in the wiring for the new stove outlet, the light fixtures, and the wall sockets. The plumber will be along shortly to deal with the new fittings for the island, the new main bathroom vanity, and tweaks to our ensuite lines so we can hide them behind a pedestal sink (repurposed from our downstairs bathroom).<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/clear-view-now-without-fireplace/' title='Clear view, now without fireplace!'><img width="300" height="176" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Clear-view-now-without-fireplace--300x176.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3311" alt="Clear view, now without fireplace!" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/6861453868/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The fireplace is gone. We&#8217;d discussed at length about refinishing it, then changing it to a gas insert and moving it down the wall, but in the end the sheer cost of the job combined with the reality that we don&#8217;t use a fireplace that much anyway pretty much killed the idea entirely. While I do love fireplaces &#8230; I&#8217;m not heartbroken over it. I&#8217;d rather have the space.<br />
The cabinets arrive tomorrow. (Keep in mind, folks, the first bit of destruction was only on Monday of THIS week!) That&#8217;s assuming, of course, that I can get my arse down to the cabinet builder first-thing tomorrow and half off a cheque for the remainder of the price. Our contractor is none-too-pleased about that arrangement, either. We&#8217;re only supposed to be dealing with him, but things went wonky. My guess is that the dealings with the cabinet builder&#8217;s founder had slowly changed over the last little while as the builder hired new people to help deal with the workload, and they don&#8217;t follow the contractor&#8217;s verbal agreement, single point of contact approach. (The builder&#8217;s accountant doesn&#8217;t seem to much like our contractor, as he doesn&#8217;t follow the &#8220;rules&#8221;.)<br />
For the record, I side with our contractor. Why? Because I&#8217;m a contractor. I know that world works: you do what needs to get done, and worry about the aftermath afterwards. When you&#8217;re on a schedule &#8212; which we are &#8212; any slow down like that&#8217;ll kill you. Frankly, I want my house back, so I&#8217;m quite alright to drop a cheque off and make sure this happens &#8230; fast.<br />
Anyway, the electrical walk-through is tomorrow morning, followed (I think) by city approval. Plumbing will likely occur a bit before the cabinets actually get installed, which also gets an approval. Then the walls and ceiling are seald up, cabinets go in, the countertop goes on, the floor goes in, and in theory, we have a kitchen back. (Alex will do the painting later.)<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/what-all-that-wiring-is-for/' title='What all that wiring is for'><img width="300" height="200" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/What-all-that-wiring-is-for-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3312" alt="What all that wiring is for" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/6861482214/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Total elapsed time? Hard to say, but possibly as little as two and a half weeks. Were it me? Two and a half YEARS. Maybe decades at the rate I&#8217;m going&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-kitchen-reno-moves-along/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The floors start to disappear</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-floors-start-to-disappear/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-floors-start-to-disappear</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-floors-start-to-disappear/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 03:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitchen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Funny thing. Yesterday, when we&#8217;d thought the renovations were due to start on Tuesday (that&#8217;d be tomorrow), we weren&#8217;t exactly in a pressing need to finish getting certain appliances and a massive table out of the kitchen. Instead, we did what we could before passing out, exhausted, in bed. (Which, of course, didn&#8217;t last all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-floors-start-to-disappear/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The floors start to disappear"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Funny thing. Yesterday, when we&#8217;d thought the renovations were due to start on Tuesday (that&#8217;d be tomorrow), we weren&#8217;t exactly in a pressing need to finish getting certain appliances and a massive table out of the kitchen. Instead, we did what we could before passing out, exhausted, in bed. (Which, of course, didn&#8217;t last all night, as Choo Choo woke up crying because she wasn&#8217;t in her crib and was completely in the dark.)<br />
It&#8217;s funny, because at just after 13:00 today, I got a series of text messages from Alex saying the floor was coming out of the kitchen. The same floor that wasn&#8217;t supposed to be coming out until tomorrow. This, of course, soon turned into bits of frustration, as I was already struggling with my project at work, and suddenly my home was under attack.<br />
It&#8217;s very safe to say that I&#8217;ve had better/easier days.<br />
<span id="more-3007"></span>I&#8217;ll dispense with the work-related items, since most people wouldn&#8217;t have a freaking clue what I&#8217;m talking about, anyway. So instead, let me regale you with our home situation.<br />
As you may recall, we&#8217;re having considerable work done in the kitchen, much of which starts with floors being torn up and walls coming out. The floors started disappearing today. Two things we learned, in a short period of time: first, most of the wood flooring upstairs is very thin &#8212; only 3/8&#8243; thick (most hardwood flooring is thicker). Second, the flooring in the kitchen (more recent) was apparently done by an &#8220;amateur&#8221;, since the maple hardwood (5/8&#8243; thick) was put overtop the old linoleum (a swirlly limey-green), which was itself asphalted to the subfloor &#8212; all of which needs to be torn out.<br />
The term, ladies and gentlemen, is &#8220;painful&#8221;. All that flooring is heavily screwed, glued, and nailed. I can&#8217;t imagine how long it&#8217;ll take to come out.<br />
Anyway, I had to make a dash home after work today to get the stove, &#8220;new&#8221; microwave, dishwasher, and our kid-strength (&#8220;industrial&#8221; is far too weak for our needs) dining table out of the kitchen. That got me in a discussion with &#8220;Curly&#8221;, our contractor&#8217;s newest hire, who was engaged in the floor removal. He&#8217;s a chatty one, that.<br />
Tomorrow, I gather, the wall comes out. (And likely the fireplace, given where it sits.) Should be interesting, given the piping and wiring present within. If nothing else, it&#8217;ll be more progress.<br />
Pictures to come soon!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/the-floors-start-to-disappear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3007</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renovations nearing completion!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=renovations-nearing-completion</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 15:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a long, hard slog since all this began a year ago. Demolition, plumbing, heating, framing, electrical, gas, contractor nightmares, self-realisation, and now the end of the tunnel is fully lit. This weekend, barring disaster, the basement will be done. Just in time for us to leave the house and let someone else enjoy &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Renovations nearing completion!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long, hard slog since all this began a year ago. Demolition, plumbing, heating, framing, electrical, gas, contractor nightmares, self-realisation, and now the end of the tunnel is fully lit. This weekend, barring disaster, the basement will be done.<br />
Just in time for us to leave the house and let someone else enjoy it. I&#8217;ve still not really come to grips with that part.<br />
<span id="more-993"></span>But as you can see, the basement is looking pretty good. At this point, the outstanding issues are installation of the floor; getting the toilet, sink, and bathroom hardware in place; hanging the doors; putting covers on the rest of the holes left in the ceiling (e.g. vents); a second coat of paint on two walls (looks a bit thin); and fixing the cable in one bedroom (which is mysteriously non-functional).<br />
[flickr]photo:2549991526(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549167077(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549994298(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549169117(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549996906(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549171725(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2551302668(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2550481817(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2551303876(thumbnail)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Laminate flooring sucks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/laminate-flooring-sucks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=laminate-flooring-sucks</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/laminate-flooring-sucks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 03:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/27/laminate-flooring-sucks/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I state this now: I will never use laminate flooring again. Ever. I don&#8217;t care how inexpensive and near-indestructable it is &#8212; the stuff simply is not well-designed and is far too cumbersome for one person to install alone. The need for a second person is ridiculous and if nothing else points out the usability &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/laminate-flooring-sucks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Laminate flooring sucks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I state this now: I will never use laminate flooring again. Ever. I don&#8217;t care how inexpensive and near-indestructable it is &#8212; the stuff simply is not well-designed and is far too cumbersome for one person to install alone. The need for a second person is ridiculous and if nothing else points out the usability of the product.<br />
I&#8217;m ranting because I&#8217;m on night #2 trying to get this stuff into the basement while Alex and the wee one are out of town. I&#8217;m pulling long nights, spending virtually every moment downstairs wrestling with a Tarkett laminate we purchased a couple of weekends ago.<br />
<span id="more-865"></span>I&#8217;m trying to do this mostly as a surprise for Alex &#8212; finish off as much of the basement as I can, so that when she comes home the upstairs is fully liveable, and the main room of the downstairs is finally useable. It won&#8217;t be complete, but it&#8217;ll at least be a start. And we can start to live in this house, rather than merely exist.<br />
The instructions printed on the insert with each box make it sound simple. This stuff is the &#8220;clickable&#8221; type, which means there are special hooked grooves that interlock. The idea is that once the stuff is down, it doesn&#8217;t separate and you don&#8217;t get the gaps common with ordinary tongue-and-groove types.<br />
It&#8217;s a complete and utter myth. This stuff is actually worse than tongue-and-groove. Especially if you&#8217;re one person. When you lay down the first row, it&#8217;s easy &#8212; lay end-to-end, and they magically interlock. Done. The problems begin with the second row. According to instructions, you lay down the row end-to-end, and then slide the entire row into the previous one, completing the effect. In principle, it makes sense.<br />
But it never works. Once you get one section of the row in place, another part pops back out. The interlock is tenuous. And you can&#8217;t tap it into place with a hammer. Although the floor is durable, the grooves are flimsy as hell, and are prone to breakage. I&#8217;ve got gaps everywhere. They&#8217;re not just unsightly, they&#8217;re highly annoying. I can already foresee cuts forming.<br />
And no, I don&#8217;t have any friends I can call on. I&#8217;m doing this installation until well into the morning, and I can&#8217;t ask friends to stay up that late to help me. It&#8217;s simply just not acceptable.<br />
That&#8217;s my rant. Next time, I&#8217;ll use engineered hardwood. Or the real thing. But I&#8217;m sure as hell never using laminate again. I wish the floor had been regular concrete&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/laminate-flooring-sucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expensive floors are a problem</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/expensive-floors-are-a-problem/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=expensive-floors-are-a-problem</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/expensive-floors-are-a-problem/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 14:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/09/24/expensive-floors-are-a-problem/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s two ways to install a floor: the cheap way and the expensive way. This isn&#8217;t about right and wrong &#8212; though important, for once this hasn&#8217;t been the sole guiding factor. And when the difference between them is orders of magnitude &#8230; well, &#8220;right and wrong&#8221; and &#8220;cheap and expensive&#8221; aren&#8217;t really that different &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/expensive-floors-are-a-problem/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Expensive floors are a problem"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s two ways to install a floor: the cheap way and the expensive way. This isn&#8217;t about right and wrong &#8212; though important, for once this hasn&#8217;t been the sole guiding factor. And when the difference between them is orders of magnitude &#8230; well, &#8220;right and wrong&#8221; and &#8220;cheap and expensive&#8221; aren&#8217;t really that different for comparison.<br />
The biggest question is: what will be the deciding factor?<br />
<span id="more-824"></span>Initially, we set no budget, preferring to get the &#8220;right&#8221; answer first. So we went to Kensington One, one of the best flooring companies in town. They sent out an estimator, and we were quoted for 630 sq. ft. of engineered hardwood (for the rec room and office) and 250 sq. ft. of tile for the laundry and bathroom. We&#8217;re leaving the bedroom unfinished for now, until we&#8217;re ready to finish it off properly.<br />
I expected a high quote. This is what you expect from one of the best companies in town, using quality materials. This is normal.<br />
But about $13,000 is enough for you to pause for a moment, swallow the bile that unexpectedly ran into your mouth, and wonder if you&#8217;re actually doing the right thing.<br />
I&#8217;m not suggesting in any way that Kensington One is wrong, or attempting to gouge us. The reality is that we hadn&#8217;t figured on that high a cost for what is effectively a simple floor. And let&#8217;s also make one thing understood &#8212; the floor itself isn&#8217;t that expensive. It&#8217;s all the labour that goes along with it.<br />
So I took a trip to Home Depot on the weekend to see if there were any alternatives to blowing through the equivalent of our heating system budget on  a new floor. Home Depot is the home of the DIY. In theory, yes, I could have also gone to Rona, but the nearest one to me is seriously lacking in options because it&#8217;s so darned small.<br />
Kensington One&#8217;s prices came out to over $14/sq. ft. At Home Depot, I could get a rather nice-looking engineered floor for about $4/sq. ft. If I went really cheap, I could get a laminate floor (&#8220;a picture of wood&#8221;) for less than a buck. Basically, put in my rec floor for about $630. That&#8217;s versus the about $8,000 I was quoted.<br />
When does &#8220;right&#8221; mean &#8220;cheap&#8221;? I dunno, but at less than 1/10th the cost, it&#8217;s not a stretch.<br />
So we&#8217;re in debate mode. As much as Alex really wants someone to come in and do the job right, I&#8217;m keen on keeping the budget in check &#8212; and $13,000 is way out of check. Sadly, even if we go to a cheaper material, the cost will only go down maybe a couple thousand at most &#8212; it&#8217;s the labour, and that don&#8217;t come cheaply.<br />
The other pressure is to get any floor down at this point, so we can move stuff around upstairs. We&#8217;ve got no space, and after a fairly serious baby shower, we&#8217;re left with a lot less room than we had before. And we&#8217;re getting hand-offs from Cathy. Soon we&#8217;ll need mountaineering equipment just to get around.<br />
Space is at a premium, and we need that basement back in order, quickly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/expensive-floors-are-a-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">824</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
