<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sports &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/sports/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 05:08:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Bronze is still a medal</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/bronze-is-still-a-medal/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bronze-is-still-a-medal</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/bronze-is-still-a-medal/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 05:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had a debate with my neighbour the other day over the Olympics, and notably how Canadians are approaching our successes at the Games. I love having debates with my neighbour &#8212; he&#8217;s well-educated, open-minded, (loves beer), and is a pragmatist when it comes to opposing views (he explores ideas, rather than shooting them down). &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/bronze-is-still-a-medal/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Bronze is still a medal"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a debate with my neighbour the other day over the Olympics, and notably how Canadians are approaching our successes at the Games. I love having debates with my neighbour &#8212; he&#8217;s well-educated, open-minded, (loves beer), and is a pragmatist when it comes to opposing views (he explores ideas, rather than shooting them down).<br />
He was perplexed that Canadians &#8212; media, especially, but also actual people &#8212; were jumping for joy at winning medals other than gold. The idea of not winning, but getting second or third, seemed utterly bizarre, let alone the jumping for joy we exhibit when we get a medal.<br />
That was my point, though: it&#8217;s a medal. And yes, it&#8217;s worth celebrating.<br />
<span id="more-3132"></span>Let&#8217;s be honest, gold is &#8230; well, the standard. It&#8217;s been that way for millennia, so yes, gold should be the most valuable award. And yes, it&#8217;s quite a drop from gold to silver, in terms of value, and I&#8217;m sure (on some mathematical scale) it&#8217;s an equal drop from silver to bronze. Bronze, really, is just copper and tin, so it&#8217;s not even precious, and not really valuable.<br />
But we&#8217;re not really talking metals, here. We&#8217;re talking achievement. We&#8217;re talking about how one person has strived, over the course of many, many years, to aim for an inexorably high level of standard, beyond that of mere mortal humans. They come to define a level of physical perfection, of intense mental focus, of rigourous and highly-skilled training.<br />
I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to be an Olympic-level athlete, but I do have an idea of what it&#8217;s like to be competitive in sports. In my youth, I learned to sail, using the same basic routes and plans (even boats) that are used at the Olympics. I&#8217;ve swam at many competitions, and felt the crushing defeat of missing something by mere tenths of a second (it was high school in the late 80s, people &#8212; we didn&#8217;t have these new-fangled accurate gizmos).<br />
Lemme tell ya something: I knew, even then, that those were low-key events. I made it to the regionals on the swim team, which was fantastic (and insanely stressful), but &#8230; well, I challenge you to find <em>any</em> record of me having done that. Yes, that&#8217;s because it&#8217;s minor, insignificant.<br />
Now let&#8217;s amp that up, oh, a <em>few million times</em>. Those folks you see on-screen, putting themselves out on the line (and I don&#8217;t care what sport)? They&#8217;ve been through hell to get there, and <em>still</em> going through hell being put in front of <em>the entire world</em>. And they have to push themselves to beat personal bests, and keep up with dozens of other athletes who are all beating themselves senseless to do the same thing.<br />
And <em>every single one of them</em> is doing this at a level that 99.999% of will, and never could achieve. They&#8217;re the hardcore of the hardcore. And most of them are going to fail.<br />
There are, and have always been, three placements in the Olympics: First, Second, and Third. The top 3. Sometimes, separated by mere hundredths of seconds, or by single digit points, tiny slivers of difference that space gold from bronze, and sometimes first from last.<br />
Is a bronze less than a gold? Of course it is. Is it more than the others? <em>Of course it is.</em> Would I tell an Olympian who won bronze: &#8220;Gee, that&#8217;s too bad&#8230;&#8221;? I might as well discount those people who only matched 5 of the 7 numbers in the 6/49, or ignore the rest of the people in Parliament not in the majority or official opposition. It might not be gold, but in no way would I ever consider silver or bronze to be any less of an achievement.<br />
Sadly, part of the problem is how Canadian media has been reacting to medals, and praising them on equal level as gold, which is not really fair. Gold medals are the pinnacle (even if some of the sports are stacked heavily in one country&#8217;s favour <em>cough</em>BASKETBALL<em>cough)</em>, and should be recognised that way.<br />
But there are some countries, such as Canada, where gold (notably in Summer Games) is simply not a reality. We&#8217;re not a &#8220;summer&#8221; country. We have snow for 11 months of the year. We like things when they&#8217;re frozen. Normally, when we go swimming, we use a chainsaw to get down to the water that hasn&#8217;t frozen yet. So, yeah, we take achievements when we get them, and are proud of them for what they are. Heck, Canada&#8217;s identity largely includes knowing damn well that we&#8217;re not the top of the heap, and we&#8217;re okay with that.<br />
Well&#8230; <em>mostly</em> okay with that. Oh, let&#8217;s be honest, there&#8217;s also that neighbour to the south of us. You know them: the ones with the money and the flashy cars, the nice clothes, the immaculate lawn. When they go to the Olympics, it&#8217;s almost like they&#8217;ve gone to the jewelry shop and pre-ordered the ones they want to win. If it&#8217;s not gold, they&#8217;re not interested, so they go all out. There&#8217;s lots of money spent on US athletes, which is why they&#8217;re so good. They&#8217;ve got more corporate sponsorship, and more Government assistance. Canada is a tenth of the US in population &#8212; we simply don&#8217;t have the cash. So, yeah, we take achievements where we get them.<br />
And, ultimately, I guess we also have to find some way to justify Own The Podium, that odourous little program started up to make Canada more visible in the Games (winter and summer), though the mere thought that Canada &#8212; keep in mind the identity I mentioned previously! &#8212; should ever attempt to dominate something like this makes many of us sick to our stomachs. That&#8217;s not Canadian pride, no sir. Furthermore, this goofy little program only benefits the top athletes &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t really help the ones who need it most, keeping the financial burdens and the barriers to entry prohibitively high.<br />
I am proud of the athletes who went to London this year. I&#8217;m proud not so much for the medals won, but for the fact that they competed. They did what they&#8217;d dreamed most of their lives, and fought hard for what they wanted most. For those who achieved? Of course, the heartiest of congratulations. For those who &#8230; came short? Don&#8217;t think you won&#8217;t still get a hearty round of applause. You did what most of us could never do, so even if you return with nothing more than what you went there with, you&#8217;re no less an Olympian.<br />
I&#8217;ll tell you this: if I ever manage to go to a Games, and see someone I know win bronze, from my cheer alone they&#8217;d think they&#8217;d won gold.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/bronze-is-still-a-medal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Believe</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-believe</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Canada, I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I Believe"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Canada,<br />
I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter Olympics (having lived there a couple of years, I know how finicky the weather can be).<br />
And I wasn&#8217;t alone. Thanks to media mainstays, such as The Guardian and the Denver Post, and CTV&#8217;s frequently slipshod and amateurish approach, there was little reason for me to think otherwise.<br />
I find myself, now at the end, relieved to be wrong, and fiercely proud to be a repatriated Canadian.<br />
<span id="more-2626"></span>The <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/">Own The Podium</a> program had me enraged. It was meant to increase the chances of medal wins &#8212; to the point where we had the most medals. Not only was it arrogance beyond our Canadian norm, I found that the program sponsored only those who were in medal contention &#8212; and abandoned the rest. Considering we&#8217;re a socialist country, it seems a very un-Canadian setup. (And can someone tell me, please, why on earth the <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/Funding/detailsw.aspx?id=8">Men&#8217;s Hockey team received Own The Podium funding</a>? It just seems odd to support millionaires who already have significant amounts of training and coaching resources.)<br />
Then came the the death of Georgian luger Nodar Kumaritashvili mere hours before the cauldron was lit.  (And no, Tom Clark, CTV <em>did not need</em> to show footage of the fatal run to &#8220;tell the full story&#8221;. That was utter <em>pandering</em> to sensationalist news coverage. You want to be better than CBC? You&#8217;d better <em>act</em> like you are, first.) The pall cast over the opening felt almost suffocating.<br />
The opening ceremonies themselves were filled with a host of flubs: lip syncing (seriously, we are unable to trust our biggest performers to perform in public?), slight delays (starting even with the snowboarder not coming down on cue), and mechanical failures (erectile dysfunction, anyone?). Problems seemed to continue past the hutzpah, with broken ice resurfacing machines, and an ill-timed rampage by ill-tempted and extremely short-sighted rioters. The press ate us alive.<br />
Our lauded best, held on pedestals for months, were put to the test. But the gold we were promised didn&#8217;t come. Our speedskaters failed to place, and our former moguls world champion could only garner a silver. And admit it, Canada, for a little while, you doubted, too. Had we put too much pressure on our athletes? Did we expect too much? Maybe where I failed was not to recognise it as a beginning of something bigger.<br />
The next day &#8212; less than 24 hours after our first disappointment &#8212; things started to change. Someone I&#8217;d never heard of, suddenly appeared on top. After almost 34 years of waiting, Alexandre Bilodeau had won Canada&#8217;s first gold medal at home. For a moment, the country stood and cheered! We would walk away with something, at least. We would feel like we&#8217;ve achieved. Maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; it was enough to take away our collective dread. Or at least mine.<br />
But the medals were still slow to come. It was two days before another gold from Maelle Ricker. Five days into the games, we had a mere five medals. Our hubris was an embarrassment. Our medals, though appreciated, would stand more as an example of an effort not carried to fruition.<br />
And then something happened that we didn&#8217;t expect. It caught me by surprise, as I know it caught many others. A word that is rarely used in Canada, because of the imagery of our neighbours to the south that it usually invokes: Patriotism. Not a fevered adherence to dogma, but a feeling of national pride the likes of which have not been since I was barely two months old. We all suddenly noticed that you can&#8217;t spell &#8220;Canada&#8221; without &#8220;can&#8221;. And we did.<br />
For me, it was the evening of the men&#8217;s skeleton finals, 19 February. Canada had already won another gold in speed skating, but it was Jon Montgomery&#8217;s victory that seemed to spark something in me. He is not your typical Canadian &#8212; he is brasher, bolder, more outspoken, and not afraid to do things in public that the rest of us would feel the urge to poo-poo as &#8220;not proper&#8221;. His primal scream of victory was the first cry, followed shortly after by a tremendous leap to the top of the podium at the sliding centre; he carried the entire nation with him in that moment. This time, I didn&#8217;t look back down. I &#8212; like you, Canada &#8212; looked forward.<br />
I started to believe.<br />
(And yes, I even started to like that &#8220;<em>I Believe</em>&#8221; song. Probably because after watching enough coverage, you don&#8217;t really have much choice.)<br />
We started the second week with seven medals. Forecasts still placed us well into the 20s. Even with all of our victories in preliminary curling and hockey, it just didn&#8217;t seem possible. But funny thing about believing &#8212; you worry less about failing, and you don&#8217;t want to get left behind.<br />
Our games started with difficult stories:  the disappointment of silver, the struggle in speed skating, and seemingly random disqualifications. The stories had changed. The commentators seemed to take on the energy not just of the crowds, but of the athletes themselves. The stories covered the brotherly dedication, the triumphant (and periodically beer-fuelled) victory marches, impromptu parades, double medals, first wins in new sports, and the sweetheart skaters who not only stole the gold but also the hearts of millions.<br />
But no story could exceed that of Joannie Rochette.<br />
I&#8217;m no figure skater &#8212; I can&#8217;t even skate, really. Growing up, though, I watched a lot of figure skating as a result of watching TV with my mom, a former skater herself, and still an adamant lover of the sport. So, in some small way, I am periodically attracted to it. It was with great fortune that I caught her performance, only days after learning her mother had suddenly died.<br />
I couldn&#8217;t tell you how well she actually skated &#8212; I&#8217;m no judge &#8212; but I can tell you that on that night, Joannie embodied the strength and courage of an Olympian, producing her best possible performance, allowing herself tears only after she was done, to the sound of a thunderous standing ovation. Her medal may have only been a bronze, but as a local paper emblazoned on its headline: it was as good as gold to us.<br />
Most of us Canadians never made it to the games, though I know more than a few who were there, who witnessed gold first-hand. The closest I ever got was my home in southwest Calgary, where I subjected my family to my growing obsession, cheering on my country in its quest for gold, to the point where Alex and I taught the Monkey to chant: &#8220;CA-NA-DA!&#8221; as loudly as she could. We all watched, we all cheered, we all hoped, and we all cried.<br />
And we achieved. We achieved records the likes of which exceeded our expectations. Even with Own The Podium&#8217;s lofty goals, most of us never expected to set a record for the most number of gold medals won in a Winter Olympics. We might not have owned the entire podium, but we took the step that mattered the most to us: the top.<br />
The top was capped with our national games: curling and hockey. Men&#8217;s curling gold, a three-time victory for the women&#8217;s hockey team, and a rematch against our oldest nemesis, the United States. It was joked many times by many people that the men&#8217;s hockey final would effectively close the entire country for the three hours the game would be played. I suspect the joke was not far off. The game would prove to be something special, especially to those born after the early 1970s &#8212; it would become my generation&#8217;s Summit Series, the game that we watched with extreme anticipation, desperately wanting that gold back in our hands.<br />
Vancouver did something to Canada that few would have predicted, even with our previous experience with Calgary and Montreal. For a few weeks,  Vancouver brought together our country &#8212; six timezones and a hugely diverse culture (yes, Canada, we are not just one group; we thrive in our multiculturalism, even if we can&#8217;t always recognise it). Not just in representation, but in anticipation and celebration.  We broke out of our Canadian mould &#8212; we stopped thinking we&#8217;d stop short, that we&#8217;d choke right at the key moments &#8212; and we started to live the dream.<br />
The media has suggested that maybe we&#8217;ll break out from our mould permanently, and be more like our cousins to the south. But we won&#8217;t. That&#8217;s not us. That&#8217;s not <em>Canadian</em>. These games are over, and we&#8217;ll return to our Canadian ways. But we won&#8217;t shrink away, we won&#8217;t forget what happened. We&#8217;ve gotten stronger; we&#8217;ve learned. We&#8217;ve learned how to perform, that success isn&#8217;t just a dream &#8212; it&#8217;s a reality. That we can compete head-to-head with the best the world has to show us, and not be just &#8220;that nice country&#8221;. We&#8217;re now <em>that</em> country: a tough competitor, a fierce opponent. The ones everyone else has to beat.<br />
And it would be nice if we could get our legends back. Mr. Orser, are there not Canadians you can train? Can our curling coaches consider teaching our up-and-comers, rather than guide our competitors? And can we please treat all our athletes with some form of equality? If nothing else, these games proved that underdogs can achieve what no-one expects.<br />
We&#8217;ll freely admit we had things that didn&#8217;t go perfectly. Massive events aren&#8217;t perfect &#8212; the best you can hope for is to mitigate the troubles. So, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14414668">yes Mr. Kiszla, we had a few problems</a> &#8212; I assure you that your lauded Denver games will have their own headaches that will made you cringe. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2010/feb/15/vancouver-winter-olympics-2010">And Mr. Donegan? I&#8217;ve heard better whining</a> from my two-year old when her cereal ends up a bit soggy. Rather than suggesting you return to the golf courses you seem to understand so much better, I suggest you join London&#8217;s Olympic Committee and become personally responsible for London&#8217;s success. Because we&#8217;ll be watching. Closely.<br />
Oh, and one more thing, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14398658">Mr. Kiszla, about the trash talk</a>? After listening to American bragging for so long, you have no idea how wonderful it is to say: <a href="http://media3.hockeycanada.ca/digital_asset/7/1/6/6/3/image_17ee18aea2c8fd14b8ba92026a8b7525.jpg?cache=305395">It&#8217;s still our game</a>. I believe it will remain that way for a long time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ole Ole Ole Ole Ticos Ticos</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/ole-ole-ole-ole-ticos-ticos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=ole-ole-ole-ole-ticos-ticos</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/ole-ole-ole-ole-ticos-ticos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 18:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night, we were originally to be in Panama, having completed meetings with our client, discussing the next steps and planning out strategies. Over bottles of Panama Lager, of course. But as is well-known in the industry, plans change. And when the client needs to alter their schedule, you end up doing things a little &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/ole-ole-ole-ole-ticos-ticos/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Ole Ole Ole Ole Ticos Ticos"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, we were originally to be in Panama, having completed meetings with our client, discussing the next steps and planning out strategies. Over bottles of <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2631206572/">Panama Lager</a>, of course. But as is well-known in the industry, plans change. And when the client needs to alter their schedule, you end up doing things a little differently.<br />
So we&#8217;re still in Costa Rica. (The meeting is now tomorrow, but I&#8217;m not going. Why I&#8217;m not going will be plainly obvious tomorrow.)<br />
Instead of hanging around the hotel&#8217;s swim-up bar, we decided to take in something different: A football game. What North Americans know as &#8220;soccer&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-1037"></span>After work yesterday Mark, Ingrid, and I packed into the back of Jason and Jen&#8217;s Pathfinder to head out to the national stadium in north San Jose &#8212; an area called Tibas. Ingrid navigated, since she seems to know every freaking corner in Costa Rica, and without her, we&#8217;d probably have had some difficulty getting there (considering the traffic we were trying to avoid). As it stands, the location isn&#8217;t really that hard to get it, but weaving around so many blocks last night, it took us a while to realise where we were.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t hard to know when we were getting close to the stadium &#8212; the glow of the lights was clearly visible at a distance. We parked on the road a couple of blocks away (Ingrid knew a great place) for 5,000 colones (about $10). This is cheap, considering that if you don&#8217;t pay them, you might never see your car again.<br />
You think I&#8217;m kidding, don&#8217;t you?<br />
The road leading to the stadium was pretty much packed &#8212; wall-to-wall fans, all dressed in red (the team&#8217;s primary colour). Hooting and hollering were expected. Vendors sold new jerseys on the sides, putting their wares on tarps over the broken sidewalks and potholed streets, hanging them from the battered rusty fences. Several vendors offered meat-on-a-stick (not sure what the exact term is for that), and the smell of cooking meats was hard to avoid.<br />
Given that we hadn&#8217;t eaten dinner yet, it was very tempting. But refrain is a well-learned art.<br />
Suddenly the crowd slowed as we arrived at the first of several checkpoints. Here, we had to show our tickets to prove we had the right to be there. Riots aren&#8217;t exactly common here (the police make sure of that), but they do a lot to make sure that only the people with tickets get to be in the area. Ingrid&#8217;s husband Mauricio was waiting just on the other side of the checkpoint, and handed our tickets to us as we got to the front.<br />
Once inside, you couldn&#8217;t miss the cops. They were scattered about, watching, keeping an eye out for misbehaviour. Although a large throng of loud people, no-one was acting particularly poorly. We stopped at a bar that was roughly kiddie-corner from the stadium itself (already very loud, and we weren&#8217;t even in it) to get a beer before going in. We were told that they were already sold out.<br />
Turns out that they were <em>almost </em>sold out. But inside, it was clear that they&#8217;d been virtually cleaned out. There was nothing left in the fridges. The beer was cold, even if it was in a plastic cup. It tasted like Imperial or Pilsen, but I&#8217;m not sure which it was (I couldn&#8217;t see the bottle from which it was poured).<br />
The tickets were checked about a half-dozen more times as we went in through the gates and headed towards our seats. The stadium is not like any I&#8217;ve been in before. I&#8217;ve been to baseball games, football games, basketball games, and hockey games in North America. Most of those stadiums are practically half malls, with large brightly-lit areas for food, drink, and of course, souvenirs. Like almost everything in Costa Rica, this stadium was open-air. There were hardly any lights, and only one concession stand that I could see.<br />
As we entered into the stadium, the roar got substantially louder. And the crowd wasn&#8217;t even cheering. That&#8217;s just the background noise. The stadium has four sets of bleachers &#8212; one on each side, with the corners completely devoid of any structure. The ones on the long sides have a lower reserved-seating, a middle &#8220;executive&#8221; style seating, and the ever-present nosebleed seats on top. The ones at either end are just a single set of bleachers, about 30 rows at one end, and 20 at the other. The taller one seems to be the rowdy section.<br />
We were at the back of the lower section, just to the right of the centre line. A really great view of the field, really. The seats, incidentally, were 12,000 colones (about $24), or about 1/5 the price of equivalent seats at any other game in North America.<br />
Of the seats I could see (I couldn&#8217;t see the nosebleeds above us), roughly 90% were wearing red, 7-8% were wearing blue, and about 2-3% (including we gringos) were wearing something other than those colours. Red, as I already mentioned, is the colour of the Costa Rican National team. Blue is the colour of the El Salvador National team.<br />
This was no ordinary game. This is one of the FIFA 2010 World Cup qualifying games. You gotta win here to even get a shot at the World Cup. And El Salvador is not a trivial team to beat. Given, we&#8217;re not talking about the Mexicos of the world (we won&#8217;t even mention Brazil), but they weren&#8217;t about to simply give the game up, either.<br />
The jeering was already well underway, with anyone supporting El Salvador (usually very proudly) getting a lot of whistling and a serious amount of name-calling. People here are very vocal. And things can get ugly, so there are police scattered all over, just to be safe.<br />
Incidentally, I have no pictures of all this, because you&#8217;re not allowed to bring in cameras. Not because of reasons like TicketMaster (no unauthorised pictures of performers) but for safety and security. The past has been pock-marked with things being thrown onto the field &#8212; notably at players &#8212; and withing the crowds, causing injuries and sometimes leading to larger-scale incidents. As such, certain things are banned. The list has been turned into marketing, and is repeated constantly throughout the game on the video screen (you see it more than you do anything of the game itself):</p>
<ul>
<li>No violence (kind of a &#8220;well, duh!&#8221; statement, I know)</li>
<li>No cameras</li>
<li>No coins</li>
<li>No radios</li>
<li>No batteries</li>
<li>No lipstick (or makeup, presumably)</li>
</ul>
<p>[flickr]photo:2784024095(small)[/flickr]<br />
That said, cell phones are apparently still permitted. But I don&#8217;t have a cell phone with a camera. Ergo, I&#8217;ve got no pictures. (Though Mauricio will be sending pictures my way, so hopefully you&#8217;ll see something in the next day or two.) I could have probably snuck my camera in, but it&#8217;s also highly likely it would have been confiscated if seen.<br />
When the teams the field, the crowd started to go wild. There wasn&#8217;t the totally-buzzed up introduction for the home team &#8212; both entered the field at once. Frankly, a far more reasonable approach to having the visiting team have to put up with the potential abuse. That was followed by the singing of the national anthems, which was very respectful (given the rivalry, you could have expected Ticos to drown out the Salvadoreans, but they didn&#8217;t), and very loud (Americans have nothing on Ticos for singing proudly).<br />
As soon as the teams started to take to the field, everyone started buzzing with anticipation (and you could regularly hear the chant that has become the title of this post), the drink and food vendors started getting more active, and the riot police donned their helmets.<br />
Again, you probably think I&#8217;m kidding.<br />
The details of the game are rather unimportant (Costa Rica won, thanks to a goal in the first half as a result of a penalty kick), it&#8217;s more about the experience. I&#8217;d never been to a soccer/football game before, and certainly not in a country where football/soccer fields are clearly marked on virtually every map. They come in almost any size, and I think each baby is handed a ball when they&#8217;re born.<br />
People take football  (futbol) here seriously and passionately. Take Ingrid, for example. At the office, which is where (until last night) was mostly where I knew her, she&#8217;s a wonderful person. Helpful, smart, and eloquently-spoken. Get her in a red shirt and put her in a soccer game, and she makes sailors blush. While I couldn&#8217;t understand most of it, I&#8217;ve never heard &#8220;puta&#8221; (a particularly nasty Spanish curse that effectively means &#8220;whore&#8221;) so much in my life.<br />
I kid, of course. Ingrid wasn&#8217;t the only one shouting that at the top of their lungs.<br />
It was particularly bad when El Salvador won a penalty kick against Costa Rica. The two sections of El Salvador fans (a small one in the south bleachers, and what sounded like a massive section above us in the nosebleeds) started cheering. The rest of the stadium then started whistling (the loud kind of whistle), cat-calling, yelling &#8220;puta&#8221;, and waving middle fingers.<br />
I&#8217;m sure this is all in good nature, of course.<br />
With the game over, we retreated to the streets to find our way back to the cars. The road at the north end of the stadium (next to the rowdy bleachers, and where the locker rooms are for the teams) was blocked by 10 policemen in riot gear on horseback. They make sure everyone continued on their way north back to their cars, and home.<br />
The route back wasn&#8217;t nearly as complicated as the route in, and we were soon in what I consider to be familiar territory. (I do have a decent sense of direction, but it&#8217;s always good to see landmarks you recognise.) We were soon speeding down the pista (Spanish for &#8220;highway&#8221;) into Escazu to get something to eat. It was almost 23:00, and none of us had eaten anything since lunch (except Jen, who had the good sense to inhale a &#8220;ghetto pizza&#8221; before leaving).<br />
Harry&#8217;s, the first place we tried, was packed. You couldn&#8217;t even get into the parking lot. We blitzed right past it down the old road, going over the mountain to the Santa Ana side, finally stopping at an old favourite: <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/">Yakky&#8217;s</a>. Even at 23:30, a plate of arroz con pollo tastes pretty darn good.<br />
Well, that an a couple beers, of course.<br />
Having covered pretty much all of the &#8220;big&#8221; stadium sports (hockey, baseball, basketball, American football, football/soccer), I have to say football/soccer is one of my more favoured ones. Still, it&#8217;s hard to watch two hours of a game without something to eat and/or drink (that&#8217;s what makes baseball bearable). If I&#8217;m lucky, I&#8217;ll get to see another game.<br />
I just have to work on my cursing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/ole-ole-ole-ole-ticos-ticos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1037</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The IOC is living in a dream world</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 19:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I was skipping through my various feeds this morning, I came across the following quote from Jacques Rogge, President of the IOC: Jacques Rogge, the president of the International Olympic Committee, said the Games would &#8220;help the world to understand China, and it will also help China to understand the world.&#8221; I think we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The IOC is living in a dream world"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was skipping through my various feeds this morning, <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/sport/othersports/olympics/2518676/Beijing-Olympics-George-Bush-calls-on-China-to-improve-human-rights-record.html">I came across the following quote</a> from Jacques Rogge, President of the IOC:</p>
<blockquote><p>Jacques Rogge, the president of the International Olympic Committee, said the Games would &#8220;help the world to understand China, and it will also help China to understand the world.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>I think we need to send a team into the IOC&#8217;s fantasy world and extract them, because they&#8217;ve clearly (and totally) misunderstood the situation.<br />
<span id="more-1029"></span>I have two fundamental issues with that quote:</p>
<ol>
<li>The world will not understand China</li>
<li>China has no interest in understanding the world</li>
</ol>
<p>Why won&#8217;t the world understand China? Because the world doesn&#8217;t want to. China is the world&#8217;s   (current) longest-standing culture. Over 5,000 years of history &#8230; a lot of it engaged in conflicts. Not so much war with others, but mostly with themselves. That&#8217;s 5,000 years of political instability, dictatorships (the Emperors weren&#8217;t exactly the nicest of people), insurrections, and various foreign invasions (Mongols, British, and Japanese, to name but a few).<br />
In a country with 1.3 billion people (70% of whom are rural farmers) and a very long history of political upheaval, you can&#8217;t really blame the so-called Communist Party (by textbook definition, China isn&#8217;t communist, nor has there ever been a truly communist government) for being so strong-armed. It could be even viewed (on an optimistic level) that this is more about ensuring the stability of China as a nation than it is about political power.<br />
If you were being optimistic. I could go pessimistic, but that&#8217;s another post&#8230;<br />
Here&#8217;s the problem, though: The world wishes to impose its political views on China. The world wants China to be democratic. The world wants China to end its human rights abuses. <em>The world wants China to change.</em> This isn&#8217;t an act of understanding. This is the world pointing it&#8217;s finger at China.<br />
China, on the other hand, is sort of like a bull. It&#8217;s a big, heavy animal that pretty much does what it wants, when it wants. Everyone needs that bull for various things (bulls are handy things to have on the global ranch), but if you ask that bull to do something it doesn&#8217;t want to do, it&#8217;s not going to do it. It doesn&#8217;t need to, and it&#8217;s quite content to stay the way it is.<br />
More importantly, China doesn&#8217;t want to take direction from outsiders. It has its own view of what it needs to survive, and the views of the rest of the world don&#8217;t really matter. Why? Because even with everything &#8220;bad&#8221; that China does, everyone still buys &#8220;Made In China&#8221; because it&#8217;s cheaper than buying it elsewhere. The money keeps coming, so China has no need to change. (Ain&#8217;t greed grand?)<br />
Hence, there is no need for China to understand the world. Ergo, it won&#8217;t.<br />
So, a note to the IOC: I dunno where the heck you people have been for the last decade, but you really shouldn&#8217;t be surprised with the situation you&#8217;re walking into. China is effectively third-world in terms of its industrialisation, political system, environmental controls, and judicial process. Their economy makes them damn near the most powerful country on Earth (they own a seriously large chunk of the United States&#8217; debt). Hence all the pollution, lack of access to free information, and all their reasons to crack down on perceived freedoms.<br />
Expect protests and expect problems. The Olympics in Beijing have only just started, but you should expect that you&#8217;ll be hearing about these for years to come.<br />
(Incidentally, if my blog isn&#8217;t already blocked in China, this should pretty much prevent it from ever being seen there. Oh well.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech Summit, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-summit-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 05:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/12/tech-summit-day-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Tech Summit, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know how they affect me, and I know how to handle them.<br />
This thing &#8212; whatever it was &#8212; knocked me flat on my back and sent me back to bed for the rest of the morning. Fortunately, I didn&#8217;t feel like I missed too much.<br />
<span id="more-902"></span>The day was spent completing the tasks from yesterday, and working to our department strategy. That meant debate. And a lot of it. But when you&#8217;re changing the way you work, you&#8217;re more concerned with change, rather than status quo. Still, it does raise blood pressure in a few.<br />
At the end of the day, we started to try define the qualities and responsibilities of Technology Directors. It&#8217;s harder than it sounds. Especially since those of us who are Technology Directors have found that we don&#8217;t always see things the same way. It&#8217;s why Cory and I proposed the exercise in the first place.<br />
Afterwards was the Technology Lead event: we got to go see Da Bulls. (That would be the Chicago Bulls NBA franchise, in case you completely missed the late 1980s of Saturday Night Live.)<br />
I&#8217;d never been to a basketball game before. I wasn&#8217;t sure what to expect, and honestly believed that I wouldn&#8217;t really like it. I&#8217;m not a sports nut. I like hockey, and I used to love baseball, but I don&#8217;t really follow sports in any appreciable way. My last stint at a football game was underwhelming (I left the game early), and wondered how bored I&#8217;d be at this one.<br />
Turns out that you don&#8217;t get the option. The game is &#8212; likely due to television contracts &#8212; very ADD-oriented. Every so often (likely about the time of a commercial break), they game stops and there&#8217;s dancing (the cheerleaders went through three costume changes), games (Benny the Bull &#8212; the Bulls&#8217; mascot &#8212; had his birthday and several of the other NBA mascots came out to celebrate), random t-shirt throwings, and these weird little CG &#8220;races&#8221; on the JumboTron.<br />
All at the same time.<br />
No, I&#8217;m not kidding.<br />
It was hard to figure out what you should be looking at. It was almost confusing.<br />
But &#8212; I&#8217;ll give it this &#8212; it was entertaining. The Bulls lost, but it was easy to miss that fact.<br />
Afterwards, we had to figure out how to get from the United Center back to our hotel. Easier said than done. Couldn&#8217;t find a taxi. Anywhere. And when we did, they were all taken.<br />
The 11 of us traipsed down West Madison, Bill nearly freezing a jacket not made for the cold weather (he had literally flown in from Costa Rica and had not planned on such frigid temperatures) and all of us sliding around in the slush and snow (Chicagoans appear to not want to shovel walkways or sidewalks).<br />
Aside from a 1.5 hour stop at the Third Rail bar to &#8220;warm up&#8221;, we walked most of the way back. Scott, Allard, Sep, and Joe were the first to bail out when we finally saw a cab. Bill, Torin, Johnathan, and Cory took the second cab a couple of blocks later. Dave took a cab (he had a long way to drive home). Only Reid and I walked the entire way back (his apartment is barely a block from the hotel).<br />
And now, to bed. It&#8217;s been another long day. Looking forward to going home. I have a pair of babies at home that I miss dearly.<br />
[flickr]tag:chicago+february+&#8221;12&#8243;+2008@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Football and music</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/football-and-music/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=football-and-music</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/football-and-music/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2005 08:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[st. petersburg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/06/football-and-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Turns out that our excursion to Tinkoff to discuss politics turned into a football lesson. (That&#8217;s &#8220;football&#8221; as in how the rest of the world defines &#8220;soccer&#8221; for us North Americans.) Kat and Nick are huge fans. So large, as a matter of fact, that Kat is delaying her departure to Khazakstan so she can &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/football-and-music/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Football and music"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turns out that our excursion to Tinkoff to discuss politics turned into a football lesson. (That&#8217;s &#8220;football&#8221; as in how the rest of the world defines &#8220;soccer&#8221; for us North Americans.) Kat and Nick are huge fans. So large, as a matter of fact, that Kat is delaying her departure to Khazakstan so she can catch the cup game her favourite team will be playing.<br />
<span id="more-527"></span>I tried to have Kat explain to me the whole cup/league thing for &#8220;final&#8221; games, and to her credit, she tried. It didn&#8217;t sink in.<br />
Tinkoff was also broadcasting games between St. Petersburg and Moscow, and between Russia and Italy. A group of fairly drunk Russians in the back kept trying to sing the &#8220;Ole, ole, ole, ole&#8221; chant often heard in football games, but were either so drunk they couldn&#8217;t sing or were utterly tone deaf.<br />
Then it was on to music. Nick&#8217;s a music fiend. He has a lot of exposure to music of many types, which led to a few interesting arguments about who was good and who wasn&#8217;t. The different perspectives are definitely interesting to hear.<br />
I was accused of starting some of these conversations because I had something to day. I suppose that&#8217;s true, and anyone who knows me knows that I do usually need to open my big yapper. But it was unintentional &#8212; I like to see where conversation goes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/football-and-music/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">527</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
