<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>calgary &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/calgary/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 06:06:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>10 Years in Canada</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2019/12/10-years-in-canada/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=10-years-in-canada</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2019/12/10-years-in-canada/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was born in what was once the small town of Oakville, west of Toronto. I lived there until I was 18, when I went to university, and split my time between Waterloo, Oakville, Ottawa, and Toronto, until January 1998, when I moved away, apparently forever. I moved to Vancouver, where I spent two bipolar &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2019/12/10-years-in-canada/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "10 Years in Canada"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I was born in what was once the small town of Oakville, west of Toronto. I lived there until I was 18, when I went to university, and split my time between Waterloo, Oakville, Ottawa, and Toronto, until January 1998, when I moved away, apparently forever.</p>



<p>I moved to Vancouver, where I spent two bipolar years of amazing experiences and painful relationships. I came to Calgary in March 2000, got married, had a kid. In 2008, my family made the epic decision to move to a completely different part of the world for nearly 18 months of &#8230; well, painful experiences and amazing relationships. </p>



<p>Ten years to the minute of this post, we came home. </p>



<span id="more-3676"></span>



<p>A decade has passed since we walked into the hotel, found a new parka for Monkey, got the cat out of her bag (totally not a joke or innuendo), and breathed that sigh of &#8220;what the hell happened&#8221;. We were <em>home</em>. Calgary, Canada. A place we&#8217;d not seen in 18 months. We&#8217;d only talked with people here, we felt utterly out of place and out of touch. </p>



<p>If that seems odd to you &#8212; the idea of feeling out of place when you&#8217;re back home again &#8212; you need to travel more. And I don&#8217;t mean to different places, I mean to a different <em>place</em> for a long time, more than you would normally. Force yourself to live as the locals do: eat where they eat, buy food and cook yourself, learn the habits, understand the culture as more than fancy dress or dance. Once you start to feel comfortable, come back home and see how strange it feels. </p>



<p>That was us a decade ago, sitting into a hotel room at the Calgary Airport, exhausted and bewildered. Well, Alex and I, anyway. Monkey just went to sleep. The cat peed. We didn&#8217;t know what would happen next. We had no idea. Our lives in the city had effectively ended 18 months earlier. And I don&#8217;t mean &#8220;paused&#8221;, I mean brought to a close. We had some aspects of our lives still intact: we still owned a house, we still had a bank account, we still had family and friends. </p>



<p>But we had no jobs. My promised position would disappear two days later; Alex had been forced to resign to go on this adventure, and she was already 30-some weeks pregnant with our second child, Choo Choo. We had no car. Things would be &#8230; awkward. Even talking with family was a bit weird at first: Canadian English was so easy compared with the Spanish-toned English &#8212; or the extra effort of trying to converse with our limited Spanish &#8212;  that we found ourselves tripping on words. </p>



<p>The day we walked back into our home was even more awkard. We had rented it out, and the agency who had managed the rentals had done a bitterly poor job of maintaining the place. We spent hours cleaning before we could unpack. It felt a mess for weeks afterwards. But slowly, we settled again. We started to live in Calgary, again. </p>



<p>A new job was soon followed by a new child. We met neighbours, fixed up the house, visited with family, travelled when we could. Monkey went to preschool, in Spanish, no less. The kids grew older, and the fabled First Day of school arrived, with Monkey proudly walking into kindergarten. Three years later, Choo Choo would do the same. Alex returned to work, though in a different schedule than preferred, but it was what was reasonable &#8212; and we began the days of Mommy being at work while Daddy was at home. The last year has been a different schedule, with Alex at work during the day, but the old schedule is potentially coming back in a few months. </p>



<p>We became the dutiful parents: taking kids to school, picking them up, going to the Parent Council, and volunteering in classes. We helped with the community centre, helped our neighbours, helped our family and our friends. We grew a few more wrinkles than we&#8217;d like, gained a few extra pounds we could do without. We took the kids to Costa Rica a couple of years ago, just to see if any of the magic was still there.</p>



<p>I worry sometimes that time is passing far faster than it should, that I&#8217;m aging so quickly that things will turn into a blur, and suddenly I&#8217;ll be an old man, devasted by the loss of youth and the cold hand of oblivion. But then I have these moments &#8212; the milestones, as it were &#8212; and I look at the spans of my life and realize that things are worth living. That we sit in moments of pure, absolute horror as time passes and nothing seems to happen, only to realize later that it&#8217;s those very moments that challenge us to realize the value of the small events, not the big ones. There will always be big events to pockmark a calendar, but the little events fill it up. </p>



<p>Ten years. It&#8217;s been an interesting ride, a proper rollercoaster in every sense and experience. May the next ten be just as tumultous and riveting.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2019/12/10-years-in-canada/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3676</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to fix the Calgary Board of Education</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 15:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been wrestling with the Calgary Board of Education for a couple of years, now. And it&#8217;s not for anything complicated. To be honest, all I have is a simple hope: to have my children go to a school where they don&#8217;t have to worry about if they&#8217;re staying in the school, or if there &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to fix the Calgary Board of Education"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I&#8217;ve been wrestling with the Calgary Board of Education</strong> for a couple of years, now. And it&#8217;s not for anything complicated. To be honest, all I have is a simple hope: to have my children go to a school where they don&#8217;t have to worry about if they&#8217;re staying in the school, or if there will be a school at all. Note that this is a &#8220;hope&#8221;, not anything more concrete&#8230;<br />
Over the last couple of years, I&#8217;ve come to realize a few nasty things about <strong>how the public education system works in this city</strong>. The internals of the <strong>CBE are highly secretive</strong> (finding out who is actually in charge of certain things is about as easy as learning the inner workings of CSIS), and so intensely political that decisions appear to be made utterly at random, against student interests. None of this seems to go through check-and-balance because &#8230; well, <strong>there&#8217;s no accountability to anyone</strong>, nor does anyone take responsibility.<br />
As a result <strong>the CBE, as a whole, is failing</strong>. And that needs to change.<br />
<span id="more-3432"></span>The system is split into <strong>three basic parts</strong>: <strong>the teachers</strong> (who generally do an exemplary job, given limited resources), the <strong>board administration</strong> (at this point, pretty much the polar opposite of the teachers), and the <strong>Board of Trustees</strong> (elected, but ineffectual).<br />
The teachers are, at the heart of the CBE, the gears that allow the machine to move forward. (I&#8217;m sure the board administration would say it&#8217;s them. It&#8217;s not.) So <strong>we&#8217;re not going to worry too much about the teachers</strong>. Yes, we can delve into the problems of tenure and people past their prime, but those folks have a limited impact.<br />
And while I would love to (figuratively and literally)<strong> throw the administration under a bus</strong>, that&#8217;s a tough challenge. While I see <strong>utterly inept planning</strong> (bordering on outright lying, which I&#8217;ve had happen to my face), <strong>impenetrable organization</strong>, <strong>unavailable communication</strong>, and <strong>top-down decision-making</strong> that gets dictated without input from the bottom, these are not things that we cannot change without pressure from someone else with authority.<br />
And authority, at least with the CBE, seems to necessarily involve the one holding the purse strings.<br />
Every year, the <strong><a href="http://www.cbe.ab.ca/about-us/budget-and-finance/Documents/Budget-Briefing-April-6-2015.pdf" target="_blank">CBE receives about $1.25 <em>billion</em> a year</a></strong> for operating the schools in Calgary. That translates into over $9,000 per student (CBE&#8217;s own numbers). Obviously, each student doesn&#8217;t see that funding, that&#8217;s just an average. Those dollars are broken down into how the CBE operates.<br />
However, <strong>there is considerable concern</strong> (largely from parents) that the Resource Allocation Method (an algorithm that apparently is subject to privacy laws, so parents can&#8217;t actually see it) is funnelling away funds from schools back into the CBE &#8230; for <em>something</em>.<br />
It&#8217;s the vagueness that&#8217;s driving a lot of concerned parents (and yes, I am one) a bit off the edge. <strong>The CBE is protecting their own information for unknown purposes.</strong> They won&#8217;t even disclose the reasons why. It&#8217;s like asking your child why they broke your favourite lamp, and with pieces of said broken lamp in their hands, they respond: &#8220;I didn&#8217;t do it&#8221;.<br />
<strong>The CBE is not transparent</strong> when it comes to funding. Not even close. They&#8217;re quick to pull the &#8220;privacy&#8221; card and not discuss the details. Details that, ultimately, concern the very they&#8217;re supposedly protecting. (I do have to ask exactly <em>how</em> my child&#8217;s name has been directly attached to operating budgets. That seems a bit <em>wrong</em> to me.)<br />
This all happens for one simple reason: <strong>no-one is telling the CBE they&#8217;re doing it wrong</strong>. Or to be more specific, no-one with <em>authority</em>.<br />
Supposedly, that&#8217;s what the <a href="http://globalnews.ca/news/872020/what-does-a-school-board-trustee-actually-do/" target="_blank">CBE&#8217;s Board of Trustees</a> is supposed to do. That&#8217;s why we elect them. Except that over many years,<strong> it&#8217;s become exceptionally hard to actually <em>trust</em> our trustees</strong>. There&#8217;s issues of transparency, <a href="http://metronews.ca/news/calgary/963030/accusations-fly-during-impromptu-calgary-board-of-education-trustee-call-to-metro-reporter/" target="_blank">being belligerent to the media</a>, ignoring parents (this one I&#8217;ve experienced myself), and <a href="https://www.google.ca/webhp?q=cbe+board+trustees+%22closed+door%22+-cbe.ab.ca" target="_blank">controversial &#8220;closed door&#8221; matters</a>. It also doesn&#8217;t help that the Board of Trustees apparently voted out their own authority, putting into the hands of the CBE&#8217;s Chief Superintendent. You know, the head of the very group the Board of Trustees is supposed to monitor?<br />
I think there&#8217;s a better approach: put the very people who have the most vested interest in the CBE&#8217;s operations as oversight. <strong>We, the parents.</strong><br />
Every year, in every single CBE school across the city, we elect a Parent Council. Every Parent Council follows a set of operating rules, which includes the election of a <strong>Chair of the Parent Council</strong>.<br />
<strong>I propose that these Chairs then form a CBE Parent Chair Council</strong>, a group that meets month (or as needed, if matters dictate) to deal with larger issues. They are the ones tasked with broadcasting information from the CBE operations down to the parents of their respective schools. They also help communicate the specific issues from their schools back to the Council.<br />
The Parent Chair Council, in turn, elects from themselves a Board of Governors. The Board of Governors are the replacement for the current Board of Trustees. But this is not a one-for-one swap, as that achieves only a little. In addition to the <strong>establishment of a parent-run Board of Governors</strong>, we bestow upon them the <em>authority</em> to demand information from the CBE, to which the CBE must comply. (This is something the province needs to enact, as the CBE itself will not change without outside influence.)<br />
Already I can hear the complaints: <strong>How is this any different than the mess we currently have?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Parents with children <em>currently </em>in the CBE are in control.</strong> Once children have left the CBE, parents become (necessarily) disengaged.</li>
<li>The election of the Board of Governors is an extension of the election of the Chair of a given school&#8217;s Parent Council: <strong>parents putting trust in one of <em>their own</em></strong> to represent them.</li>
<li><strong>Any member of the Board of Governors can be ousted at any time</strong> by the <em>current</em> rules that elect a Chair of Parent Council: someone who loses the trust in their school&#8217;s parents would be voted out at the school level, thereby removing that Chair from both the Parent Chair Council and the Board of Governors.</li>
<li><strong>Real authority would be given</strong> (again, requiring provincial mandate) that would allow the Board of Governors to truly <em>govern</em> the CBE (see, there&#8217;s a reason for the name!). I know this is a sticky part, but I do not see it as unrealistic.</li>
</ol>
<p>Okay, one major point I know some will raise: <strong>where would people find the time to do all of this?</strong> I mean, being on the Board of Governors is a lot of work, right?<br />
Yes, it is. Two counters to that point, however:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Board of Trustees already invest a fair bit of time</strong> with the existing situation. So it&#8217;s not unrealistic.</li>
<li><strong>There are parents in this city who are more than willing to invest that time</strong> because they <em>believe</em>. Every school has a few of these people, and interestingly, they&#8217;re often ones who put themselves up for election as the Chair of their Parent Council.</li>
</ul>
<p>The other obvious elephant is <strong>the teeth the province needs to bestow upon the Board of Governors</strong>. This is not a trivial aspect, but it is something that can be readily defined. It&#8217;s not like we don&#8217;t see similar constructs for other &#8220;watchdog&#8221; agencies who ultimately can deliver painful judgements against governments and/or industries.<br />
It is time for the <strong>parents to take back their schools</strong>, and require more of an organization that demands more and more, while delivering less and less. Parents get engaged very quickly, and can do a far better job as a collective interest than <strong>long-standing obstacles who march only to their political aspirations</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3432</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Canadian politicians have forgotten</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.] Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every three years, on average). And in Alberta, a province &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What Canadian politicians have forgotten"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><em>[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.]</em></p>
<p class="p1">Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every <i>three years</i>, on average). And in <strong>Alberta, a province of wealth and entitlement</strong>, that means the old guard fending off competitors who dare lay siege to the castle, <strong>replete with feces-slinging</strong> (we’re well past mere mud), ethically-laden promises, and scare tactics, from all sides.</p>
<p class="p1">Canada is also heading down the road to a <strong>federal election</strong>, which by schedule we will see this fall. We will likely see <strong>the same slinging and fearmongering</strong>, not only because the same mentalities are at play, but because we’ve been witnessing the preamble for several months, now.</p>
<p class="p1">And all of it has shown one thing: that <strong>our politicians have forgotten about Canadians</strong>.</p>
<p class="p1"><span id="more-3428"></span>The squabbling alone is like <strong>listening to the group of neighbourhood kids fight over a favoured toy</strong>. The younger ones are petulant, the older ones use their physical strength and bully to get their way. Some of the other kids in between ages argue logically, but receive neither support nor a sympathetic ear. All I hear, as the parent who wishes them to sort anything out, is crying, fighting, and threats of tattling to parents.</p>
<p class="p1">The same thing happens in our political landscape, just without the benefit of (somewhat) impartial parents to sort out the mess and restore order. The parents we should have — <strong>the Canadian people</strong>, acting through an election — <strong>have become disillusioned, disaffected, and apathetic</strong>. As a whole, we have stopped caring. And as much as I, and others, have tried to blame this on the Canadian people, the reality is that we cannot blame the people. Individual persons, perhaps, but as a collective, the Canadian people have lost faith in government.</p>
<p class="p1">For a person to care, they <strong>need to feel attachment</strong> to something. To get that attachment, we need three things, in order:</p>
<h2 class="p1">Vision</h2>
<p class="p1">Most important of any politician’s toolbelt should be a concept of what they want to achieve, something that they know their constituents need. Sadly, most politicians fall short into short-term or simple goals: lower taxes (which politicians never lower), more jobs (which politicians don’t control), better education (which politicians take neither accountability nor responsibility), and so forth. <strong>We’ve all heard these promises, every single election.</strong></p>
<p class="p1">These are not visions, <strong>these are <em>tactics</em></strong>. Real vision comes from things that are far more intangible, such as understanding the division between the wealthy and the poor, looking to the health and welfare not of today’s children but those who will come in two generations, looking at how we are truly perceived on a global stage and knowing we could be better, preparing for a world with an ever-expanding population with less space.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Our governments do not offer vision. They offer fear.</strong> Ruling parties tell us we are in danger, so take away the freedoms of the many to benefit the extremely few; they tell us we cannot have sustainable incomes from a consistent tax base, to placate business, they tell us that the present is failing and sacrifice our future. Our opposing parties are no better, instead choosing to define themselves only by how they will reverse ruling party’s efforts, or how they will do things different.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Such actions offer no inspiration, no dreams, no hope.</strong> They serve only to oppress and defeat, leaving Canadians with nothing more than apathy. Without vision, we fall into mere name-calling, and petty arguments. We don’t have anything new to believe in, so we fall back on what we already believe, regardless of how flawed it may be. And we’ll fight to the death to protect those beliefs, because <strong>we’re human, and we loathe others telling us what to believe</strong> in the absence of new thought.</p>
<h2 class="p1">Charisma</h2>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Part of the problem of vision, even when it is available, is an inability to connect with Canadians. While making public appearances, they certainly glad-hand everyone they can find with big, wide smiles … but this is not a connection. After such events, <strong>Canadians will no more relate to a politician as they will to the politician in a sound bite on TV</strong>. We relate better to actors in trashy B-movies than we do the people we’re supposed to trust with our future. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The leader of our nation, Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper, has the <strong>personality of a cardboard cutout</strong>. Hon. Thomas Mulcair, the leader of the official opposition, is <strong>identifiable more by his beard</strong> than anything he has said or done. And our supposed saviour, Hon. Justin Trudeau, scion of Canadian political legend, has somehow managed to turn himself into a bizarre punchline, where lately his <strong>only defining attribute is reverse-parroting</strong> nearly everything the Prime Minister says. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Nevermind our provincial woes: a recently-elected Premier who, starting off with supposedly open eyes, has turned a deaf ear; the official opposition imploded; and <strong>the polls show the province tearing itself down the middle</strong>, with divisions widening daily. There is not a single person who has stepped up within the province to show a new way to think, nothing beyond promises of old that have been broken time and time again. <strong>Not a single party who defines hope</strong>, not a single hope for the change we so desperately need. </span></p>
<p class="p1">Sadly, <strong>our politicians appear to have started to ignore us</strong>. They only truly care when elections are in the wind, for obvious reasons. Otherwise, they&#8217;re more preoccupied with each other, with in-fighting, name-calling, petty one-up-manship, and throwing people under busses (figuratively speaking that is; if that ever turns literal, we&#8217;ll have bigger problems to solve). The net result isn&#8217;t even entertainment, anymore. It&#8217;s irritation.</p>
<p class="p1">Worse still, we <strong>Canadians still end up dividing on ideological lines</strong>, blindly painting ourselves Blue, Red, and Orange because &#8230; well, because that party is how I&#8217;d <em>like</em> to think. But that paint is a two-way street, and <strong>the actions and words of the politicians flows down to the people</strong>, tarnishing the ideal of what that paint was supposed to be, and the Painted People argue about what&#8217;s ideal, despite the reality.</p>
<p class="p1">It’s not like Canada has not seen charismatic, even idiosyncratic politicians before. I&#8217;ll sidestep an obvious one, largely because my province has a ridiculously long memory and a terribly short sight.</p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Instead, I&#8217;ll look to the late <strong>Hon. Jack Layton, who set a benchmark in Canada</strong> for the very things that Canadians were longing for: helping Canadians, not scaring them. He ignored personal attacks, choosing instead to inspire. He made fun of himself on <i>This Hour Has 22 Minutes</i>, engaged Quebecois in their language, and despite a strange police run-in (an unproven but suspected smear campaign), his trustworthiness amongst those polled topped out at 97%. In the following election, the NDP — the “left wing” party, formerly the butt of many political jokes — became the official opposition for the first time in federal politics. When Layton died in August 2011, the nation mourned the loss of <strong>our last great statesman</strong>.</span></p>
<h2 class="p1">Leadership</h2>
<p class="p1">This leads me to the last major problem with our politicians: their inability to lead. They are defined as leaders of their respective parties certainly — they are elected from within the party for that very purpose. That does not, however, necessarily define them as leaders of Canadians.</p>
<p class="p1">Imagine, if you will, a crowd in a large field. A single person steps from the crowd, raises their hand, and promptly marches off in a direction. Some of the crowd will undoubtedly follow, either because they know the person or because they have a like mind. The rest may follow over time, some due to not wishing to remain in the field, some due to the pressure of others leaving. Some will remain, and possibly follow someone else who marches off in a different direction.</p>
<p class="p1">Now imagine that same crowd in a dark tunnel. There are two ways to go, and almost no-one knows the right way. One person, armed with a flashlight, walks ahead to look for dangers: open holes, tripping rocks, unstable walls, and so forth. Nearly all will follow, if just not to be left in the dark.</p>
<p class="p1">These are the <strong>two leadership patterns we see in Canada: follow by choice, or follow by fear</strong>. Both are problematic, though most people, when asked, would prefer the choice. It doesn’t matter whether or not your choice may lead you off a cliff, you just wish to know that you feel right about something. In both cases, <strong>the key missing element is education</strong>. With fear, you’re offering only the downside: follow me, or else. With choice, you’re selling only the benefits: follow me, for I have cookies!</p>
<p class="p1">So what’s best? <strong>Follow by understanding.</strong> Yes, we have cookies, and they are delicious, but some have raisins, and we know they’re not for everyone. Allow people to know what you stand for, why that matters, why you think you’ll make mistakes, where you will draw lines, and how much you’re willing to risk to bring your vision. <strong>A rare politician is one who does not worry immediately about the next election</strong>, but more about the people they represent.</p>
<h2 class="p1">But Where’s the Proof?</h2>
<p class="p1">It took me a long time to realize that we had an example of how it <i>could</i> be done. And, somewhat ironically, it exists in a place we don&#8217;t expect to see greatness: in municipal government. I can look at my own city and see the proof. Calgary is a microcosm of Canada: a right-leaning, multi-cultural, fast-growing city that has, historically, had a lacklustre governing body.</p>
<p class="p1">Until 2012, the general impression of City Council was anything but transparent, ruled largely by old guard red tape, with but a few who fought for real change. Then in 2012, the change happened: a man with a vision of what Calgary could be, that flew in the face of some of that old guard, asked <strong>people to believe not necessarily <em>in</em> him, but <em>with</em> him</strong>. And people could, because he had a personality that was infectious, one that made you <em>want</em> to believe. He followed through, showing people how things could really be done.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Mayor Naheed Nenshi proved to a right-leaning city that had stopped caring, that you <i>could</i> do different.</strong> For his first term, Calgary became a very different place. It felt more energetic, more interesting and vibrant, more passionate. He did so well, that he got reelected. He continues to express his opinions, his vision, his desire for change, and his will to put himself out for public approval.</p>
<p class="p1">Is Mayor Nenshi popular with everyone? Of course he isn’t — he rubs some people badly, and they would love to see him unseated. And, to some degree, Mayor Nenshi doesn’t seem to care. <strong>Opposition is seen as a healthy thing, to foster debate, to find middle grounds, to develop long-lasting solutions.</strong> And despite perceptions of some city councillors working more for corporate interests than their constituents, the City of Calgary functions more like the Canada I knew as a child: with mutual respect, honest debate, and a desire to do Calgarians proud.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>This is what our politicians are missing: pride.</strong> They’ve forgotten how to inspire through vision, engage through charisma, and gain a following through leadership. This Alberta election is a farce, and our next federal election will be like watching poo-flinging monkeys.</p>
<p class="p1">Our only hope is that someone recognizes this, and brings change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling the awful to the angry</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=selling-the-awful-to-the-angry</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 05:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Selling the awful to the angry"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE Area IV director, as well as the Planning &amp; Transportation folks.<br />
I emphasize the word &#8220;supposed&#8221; &#8212; that was the CBE&#8217;s perspective. They thought they would get a lot of interest, and a lot of people who were genuinely happy that a solution had been found for the accommodation woes at Westgate School, which is at over 90% of its rated capacity.<br />
But, funny thing, there weren&#8217;t many happy people.<br />
<span id="more-3405"></span><br />
When we received the official notice that Eugene Coste was the &#8220;solution&#8221; to the problem, there&#8217;s been almost the equivalent of an angry mob. (I know &#8212; I&#8217;m one of them.) And that angry mob has been inundating the CBE with emails, phone calls, petitions, and even an appeal rally in the lobby of their headquarters last Friday. It would be awfully hard for anyone at the CBE to be able to not notice that there are a lot of unhappy people.<br />
Yet, despite all the warning, the CBE continued with its open house at Eugene Coste. I would like to refer to it as &#8220;Eugene Coste School&#8221; at this point, but in truth, it&#8217;s only a building with some rooms &#8212; everything that could make it a school, like desks, chairs, art on the walls, books in the library, and so forth, are utterly <em>absent</em>. The building was little more than a shell.<br />
When we entered the building, we were effectively directed to what I think was previously the library, to see some information, and talk to the directors. Except there wasn&#8217;t much talking &#8212; it was largely listening to the angry parents question the directors, and listen to the directors attempt to explain their position. Amongst all of this were kids running about, having to be corralled by parents who were trying to speak their minds. There were a lot of angry parents. Amazingly, so I heard later, the CBE was surprised that so many people were unhappy about the affair.<br />
Now this, dear reader, is where I give myself the facepalm. You know this expression, yes?<br />
<img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://forums.riftgame.com/attachments/general-discussion/9358-open-challenge-daglar-picard-facepalm.jpg" width="750" height="600" /><br />
I say this because I&#8217;m utterly unable to see how the CBE thought that asking a large number of unhappy parents to drive through rush hour traffic to a school to which they&#8217;re largely opposed with their tired and hungry kids in tow (without a single distraction available to occupy them), not run a single tour of the facility to sell its virtues, and corral everyone in one room to &#8220;talk&#8221; with the people most of the angry parents are blaming in the first place, was <em>ever</em> a good idea.<br />
Exactly <em>how</em> was this supposed to be successful?<br />
I work in marketing. You know, the industry that exists to sell you the things you don&#8217;t really want to buy? (Okay, slightly cynical. I admit that perhaps I&#8217;ve been doing this job too long&#8230;) You can look at <em>Mad Men</em> and snicker, but the basis of the show isn&#8217;t far from reality: we make you want something.<br />
The CBE didn&#8217;t even <em>try</em> to make us want to send our kids to Eugene Coste. Let&#8217;s ignore the hour-long bus rides and massive disruption to families&#8217; lives &#8212; the school building was devoid of any life whatsoever, and we didn&#8217;t even really get a chance to see much of it. And having our fears glossed over by &#8220;best case&#8221; scenarios of bus routes and timing? A little more than moderately insulting. Basically, they failed at selling the idea.<br />
This is the point at which an agency is asked to leave the pitch process and not return. Or, worse, the agency&#8217;s account is brought up for review and they have to validate their existence against dozens of competitors who want the account.<br />
This is something the CBE needs to figure out: how to sell awful situations to angry people. The entire city is under school space crunches, and there aren&#8217;t a lot of options for anyone. The releases we receive are emotionless, lacking sufficient information, and unable to address the fears that arise &#8212; the very things that any good marketing job should address.<br />
No competition for the CBE, you say? You&#8217;d be surprised how many people are readily willing to consider the separate school system, or even the extra cost of charter schools. And we&#8217;ve got a lot of charter schools in Calgary, so this is definitely not a hypothetical scenario. The CBE just ends up with more angry customers, who won&#8217;t be willing to put up with the problem much longer.<br />
So a suggestion to the CBE: you want people to like you? Get someone else to tell your story, &#8216;cuz you&#8217;re doing a lousy job of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary Board of Education: we need a decision on Westgate Elementary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi, CBE? I&#8217;m a concerned parent. Yeah, I know you&#8217;ve heard from a lot of us in the last year regarding what you want to do with Westgate Elementary. You&#8217;ve heard so much, you&#8217;re not listening to us anymore, which I can understand &#8212; there&#8217;s only so much you can hear before you&#8217;ve heard enough. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary Board of Education: we need a decision on Westgate Elementary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, CBE? I&#8217;m a concerned parent. Yeah, I know you&#8217;ve heard from a lot of us in the last year regarding what you want to do with <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b140/">Westgate Elementary</a>. You&#8217;ve heard so much, you&#8217;re not listening to us anymore, which I can understand &#8212; there&#8217;s only so much you can hear before you&#8217;ve heard enough.<br />
But we &#8212; that&#8217;s you as the Board, and us as parents &#8212; have a problem: there&#8217;s no decision. The school is still over-populated, and despite having pulled another grade out, there&#8217;s going to be too many students for next year.<br />
So &#8230; what&#8217;s going on? We need an answer. And preferably now, and not at the end of this school year.<br />
<span id="more-3392"></span><br />
You&#8217;ve pulled Grade 5 and sent them abroad. (Those students, by the way, are having trouble trying to function in a much bigger school. Big trouble. Ask their parents.) But that&#8217;s not enough. You need to decide the future of French and Spanish at the school. We&#8217;ve already heard that Spanish is likely to be the one to depart. It&#8217;s the youngest of the two programs, after all. (It&#8217;s terrible reasoning, incidentally &#8212; both programs are equally used, according to the Principal.) It needs to live, separately, at a different school.<br />
My problem is that my child is enrolled in Grade 1 Spanish. She quite likes it. I quite like that the school is less than five minutes <em>by foot</em> from our home in Westgate. It&#8217;s effectively our community school, even though it&#8217;s really not, since it&#8217;s a language school first. So if Spanish leaves &#8230; where does my child go?<br />
Did I mention she&#8217;s in Grade 1? I&#8217;m not a big fan of bussing her somewhere, even less considering driving her. Yes, I know <em>kindergarten</em> students are currently bussed &#8212; I don&#8217;t agree with that, either. Maybe I&#8217;m old school (pardon the pun), but I believe schools should be walked to, not driven.<br />
Okay, rant aside, we still have to contend with <em>where</em>. In all the discussions that have been had to date, the schools mentioned are quite a way beyond Westgate. One of them, <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b103/">Jennie Elliott Elementary School</a>, is in Lakeview, a minimum 7.7 kilometre drive. I know that doesn&#8217;t sound like much to you, but for someone who has been a mere 350 <em>metres</em> away, it&#8217;s a significant change.<br />
Admittedly, that&#8217;s just us. We know that we&#8217;re in the minority &#8212; most kids are shipped into Westgate everyday, and in the end, the percentage of bussed/driven students vs. walking distance would probably remain somewhat similar.<br />
What won&#8217;t remain the same is the effort and time taken to get students somewhere. Let&#8217;s go back to that change in distance: about 8 kilometres between the two schools. Why is this significant? Because bus routes will have to change, and parents driving their kids will have to change. Going in and out of Lakeview isn&#8217;t particularly easy during rush hour (Westgate, we know, is bad enough). You&#8217;re diverting people even further (we know a large proportion comes from &#8220;up the hill&#8221; to the west of Sarcee), and incurring more time.<br />
How about we suggest something different? There&#8217;s a highly unused school barely a kilometre away that could easily accommodate the change: <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b133/">Rosscarrock Elementary</a>. It&#8217;s very underpopulated. So much so that a large portion of that school is used by Chinook Learning Services, presumably to fill the otherwise unused space. (We know this because our youngest child attends a preschool there, presumably also in unused space.) And at barely a kilometre difference from Westgate Elementary, you&#8217;re not asking for huge changes in how people move around &#8212; it&#8217;s only an extra couple of minutes to drive there, and access to Rosscarrock is marginally better.<br />
So, can I suggest you consider Rosscarrock for the new home for Spanish? For the parents at large, and for the kids who have to travel by bus, this is a far more sane option than asking them to trek further into Lakeview. And if, as your plans last year suggested, that Spanish kids would eventually flow to A.E. Cross, Rosscarrock is a closer school, again reducing the distance delta.<br />
No matter what your final decision, we would like to know <em>soon</em>. We&#8217;ve been waiting a long time for a decision, because &#8212; believe it or not &#8212; it does affect how we plan our lives. We know planning things like this is hard, and that no matter what you do, you&#8217;ll be heavily criticized for it. That&#8217;s just the nature of providing a service like this. But make the decision, and allow us to start adapting soon. Because if it doesn&#8217;t go in our favour, adapting could take quite a long time.<br />
Thank you for your consideration,<br />
A loving and concerned parent</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3392</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monkey&#039;s First Stampede</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=monkeys-first-stampede</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 04:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amusement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Perhaps the title&#8217;s a bit misleading, Monkey, but I suspect this will be the first Stampede you actually remember. And you have reason to remember it, too. You&#8217;ve listened to marching bands, eaten pancakes, ridden rollercoasters, and even seen a future King. Not bad for only a little over 48 hours, eh? It started Friday &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monkey&#039;s First Stampede"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the title&#8217;s a bit misleading, Monkey, but I suspect this will be the first Stampede you actually remember. And you have reason to remember it, too. You&#8217;ve listened to marching bands, eaten pancakes, ridden rollercoasters, and even seen a future King.<br />
Not bad for only a little over 48 hours, eh?<br />
<span id="more-2950"></span>It started Friday morning, which was Stampede Parade Day. The Calgary Stampede Parade is one of the largest in the world (I&#8217;ve heard it&#8217;s second, but have yet to hear what&#8217;s first, or the conditions under which that define its size), and has been a tradition in Calgary for close to a century. Now that you&#8217;re nearly four, it seemed like a good idea to take you to the parade so you could see it yourself, and not drive me insane by having a total loss of focus.<br />
There&#8217;s only one catch with seeing the parade: you have to either have bench seating (acquired in advance, usually with paid tickets), or you get there early to get anywhere near a decent place to sit. Rather foolishly, I thought we had plenty of time leaving at 6:35am.<br />
The lines had formed much earlier that morning (the people we sat next to &#8212; you remember them, right? They had the little white dog named &#8220;Cookie&#8221;? &#8212; arrived at 6:30 that morning and said all the front-line seats were long gone), and we were met with a sea of people as we crossed under the bridge into downtown.<br />
My other grandiose plan was to stop at McDonald&#8217;s for breakfast, since we hadn&#8217;t the time to eat before we left the house. That line was equally as bad, and it meant that we either ate, or suffered through poor seating. Given the time we&#8217;d have to wait, I felt the the latter was more important. We had at least brought you some snacks, Monkey, so you wouldn&#8217;t be starving. I would have to go without&#8230;<br />
We found a place, next to a wooden fence at the edge of the massive Impark lots on the south side of 9th Ave., that offered a fairly decent view of the route, and was not totally blocked by the scads of folding chairs that everyone else had (next time, I&#8217;ll remember to bring <em>real</em> chairs). And there we sat down and waited for something &#8212; well, <em>anything</em> &#8212; to happen.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/its-going-to-be-a-long-wait-to-see-anything/' title='It&#039;s going to be a long wait to see anything'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/It-s-going-to-be-a-long-wait-to-see-anything-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3291" alt="It&#039;s going to be a long wait to see anything" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924247238/">Geoff S.</a><br />
It dawned on me rather suddenly that I had been sitting in almost the same place some 10 years earlier with Auntie Cathy and Uncle Craig (before they got married) to watch my first Stampede parade. I wouldn&#8217;t have imagined that 10 years later I&#8217;d be watching the Parade with my own daughter on my knee.<br />
William and Kate, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge &#8212; the future king of the United Kingdom and his wife (I&#8217;m not sure if she&#8217;ll be a &#8220;Queen&#8221; or a &#8220;Princess Consort&#8221; at that point) had been in Canada for the last couple of weeks on a whirlwind tour of the country (supposedly a &#8220;honeymoon&#8221; &#8212; Mommy and I have had some pretty whirlwind-type trips, but nothing that hectic), and were going to see the Stampede Parade, too. And before the Parade started, they would do a pass through the Parade route, themselves &#8230; in reverse. [Insert joke about driving on the wrong side of the road here.]<br />
By 8:40, we were already fairly tired of waiting (and my ass already bruised from the hard ground and stones I had to sit on &#8212; you sat on me, I should add), but we were rewarded by the Royal Drive By (albeit far faster than anyone would have desired, and it was difficult to actually see the Royals &#8212; Kate was on our side of the car). Pretty much everyone clapped and cheered.<br />
We didn&#8217;t really see much for another hour. Given our place on the route, that wasn&#8217;t entirely surprising, but it did seem a bit much, all things considered. Marching bands, clowns, and lots and lots and lots of horses. And a guy riding a bull (memories of Mel Brooks&#8217; <em>Blazing Saddles</em>, indeed!). Our Mayor, Naheed Nenshi, rode a horse, too and seemed quite happy to do so. We saw Rick Hanson, who was the Parade Marshall for 2011 &#8212; he drove himself (hey, he drove himself around the world &#8212; a paltry couple of kilometres is nothing for him, right?). The biggest cheers were for the Canadian Armed Forces, notably the Army &#8212; almost everyone stood and cheered loudly for them. (One day, I&#8217;ll explain why, Monkey. That&#8217;s a very long topic, and pretty much entirely another blog post.) The quietest moments were when our faithful Ministers of Parliament drove past &#8212; the &#8220;Honourable&#8221; Rob Anders was met with embarrassed silence (guess what, Calgary, you aren&#8217;t allowed to be embarrassed &#8212; you <em>voted</em> for him, remember?).<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/calgary-stampede-band/' title='Calgary Stampede Band'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Calgary-Stampede-Band-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3292" alt="Calgary Stampede Band" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923718161/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/calgary-mayor-naheed-nenshi/' title='Calgary Mayor Naheed Nenshi'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Calgary-Mayor-Naheed-Nenshi-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3293" alt="Calgary Mayor Naheed Nenshi" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924322318/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/canadian-armed-forces-tank/' title='Canadian Armed Forces tank'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Canadian-Armed-Forces-tank-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3294" alt="Canadian Armed Forces tank" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923786989/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/wes/' title='&amp;quot ;Wes &amp;quot ;'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/quot-Wes-quot--300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3295" alt="&amp;quot ;Wes &amp;quot ;" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924377722/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Mommy met us at the Safeway downtown where we ran into two friends of mine: Evelyn, who I worked with for many years; and a childhood friend of mine, Neil, who also lives in Calgary. You then went home, and I went to work.<br />
Yesterday, we went for our first (and possibly only) free pancake breakfast. The pancake breakfast is a tradition that has existed in Calgary for almost as long as the Stampede itself. It&#8217;s so rooted in tradition that when someone actually charges for a breakfast (and the money doesn&#8217;t go directly to charity), they get the stinkeye from just about everyone. People take their free breakfasts around here pretty seriously.<br />
The Stampede Caravan runs a very efficient and very tight ship when it comes to pancakes. You, Choo Choo, and I walked up to the Sunterra, where the Caravan had set up their event. (We had gone last year, too, but I&#8217;m not sure if you remember that at all.) By the time we arrived, the parking lot was packed with people waiting for pancakes &#8212; they hadn&#8217;t yet started flipping them.) You declared you wanted to see the animals first, which seemed like a good idea, since we had to wait anyway.<br />
Butterfield Acres was also there, just like last year, with pony rides and their portable petting zoo. Chicks, bunnies, goats, and lambs. You shrieked in eagerness, then raced in to give out hay to the goats, pet the bunnies, and be reminded several times not to pick up the chicks. (Choo Choo, you petted the lambs, which you loved, and the goats. You couldn&#8217;t really reach the bunnies, and we weren&#8217;t allowed to pick them up.)<br />
Despite the several-hundred person-long line, it took a mere 15 minutes to get our pancakes. (Like I said, the Stampede Caravan runs a <em>very</em> efficient operation. They set the standard for how it should be done.) Your pancake, thanks to one very nice cook, was shaped like Mickey Mouse. We got our pancakes, found a curb to sit down, and dug in. Even Choo Choo inhaled her pancakes.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/pancakes/' title='Pancakes !'><img width="224" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Pancakes--224x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignright wp-image-3296" alt="Pancakes !" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924387592/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Afterwards, we went over to the pony ride, which I had promised. Just as you got into line to get on a pony, Erin and her friend arrived (which I had known about, but forgotten about). You love riding ponies, I&#8217;ve noticed &#8212; a far cry from the day we tried to get you on a pony in La Sabana Park in San José, when you cried in terror at the idea. It&#8217;s just a shame that you couldn&#8217;t go around more than once, though, and had to come out.<br />
We went shopping for dinner afterwards, and &#8220;helped&#8221; by picking out chocolate milk, and deciding that we needed to take a pie as well (which you summarily dropped on the floor, forcing my hand to purchase it). Although you wrecked the pie (actually, a 9&#8243; creme brulée), the Sunterra manager very kindly swapped it with a new one, reinforcing the reason why I prefer to shop there.<br />
This morning, we were all going to go to the Stampede itself. It was Family Day at the Stampede, meaning there was free entrance to the park before 9:00, and a pancake breakfast for the first 20,000 people. You would think we could do that&#8230;<br />
Choo Choo was against us, however, and woke up several times last night without going back to sleep. Eventually Mommy decided to stay up with her, letting you and I get a little more sleep. But I woke later than I&#8217;d wanted to, and Mommy was too tired to go (she has to work until midnight tonight), so it ended up being just you and me, and we didn&#8217;t get to the park until just after 8:00 &#8230; and about 1 minute after they ran out of tickets for the pancakes. Once again, Daddy was going hungry.<br />
It also appeared that the Stampede hadn&#8217;t really opened yet, either. Most of the exhibits didn&#8217;t open until 9:00, with a number not opening until 10:00. That left us with &#8230; well, not to much to do. Thankfully, Mommy had the foresight to have me bring you something good to eat (although the Stampede has lots of food, most of it is &#8230; well, not exactly healthy). Down went an apple sauce, banana, and a heck of a lot of grapes. And you were still hungry.<br />
We wandered through the BMO Centre and the Corral looking for the kids midway &#8212; something I thought would be a little easier for you to handle. Immediately, I felt nostalgic for the days when I was about your age, and my parents took me to the Canadian National Exhibition (&#8220;The EX&#8221; or the &#8220;CNE&#8221;) in Toronto. It was always the last hurrah of the summer, and the clown-faced logo of Conklin Shows is something I&#8217;ll not likely ever forget &#8212; something you&#8217;ll likely never know, either, since Conklin sold out to North American Midway Entertainment. It&#8217;s really not quite the same thing.<br />
We picked up 12 tickets, which I figured would be good for three rides. I didn&#8217;t know what you&#8217;d like yet, and felt buying too much was a bad idea. First stop? The carousel. I know you love carousels &#8212; you&#8217;ve been on several, now &#8212; and you asked quickly for the &#8220;horsie ride&#8221;. Although not nearly as nice as the one in Heritage Park (a vintage machine that is infinitely more attractive, at least during the day) or the one at the zoo (zoo animals being a major plus), you loved being on it just the same.<br />
Then, to my surprise, you asked to go on the &#8220;boat ride&#8221;. The &#8220;Rockin&#8217; Tug&#8221; is a kid-friendly version of the classic Swinging (Pirate) Ship ride, except it sits on rails rather than being suspended from a massive hinge. And, unlike its larger sibling, the tug actually spins around.<br />
I thought you&#8217;d chicken out. Really. Maybe I had a lower expectation, Monkey, given some of the things you&#8217;d said you wanted to do and changed your mind at the last second; or maybe I was even extending some of my fears from when I was your age. But you not only eager climbed up, you virtually stunned me by cheering and screaming &#8220;wheeeee!&#8221; the entire time. You&#8217;re hooked.<br />
After that, we tried to get into SuperDogs. I emphasize &#8220;tried&#8221;, because the line to buy tickets (I wasn&#8217;t even aware that SuperDogs even needed tickets &#8212; my memory had always been that of a walk-in event) was almost as long as the line for pancakes.<br />
So we had some of Those Little Donuts instead. Infinitely yummier, if you ask me.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/mmmm-donuts/' title='Mmmm... donuts...'><img width="224" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Mmmm-donuts--224x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignright wp-image-3297" alt="Mmmm... donuts..." /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923831923/">Geoff S.</a><br />
We tried to find a petting zoo in the agricultural area. You&#8217;d think for an agricultural-based event, there&#8217;d be more kid-friendly things. But there was no petting area that we could see, no pig races, nothing even remotely fun for the kids. Just an endless stream of horses (even you got tired of them all), a few cows (surprisingly few for an agricultural-based event), and a bunch of miniature donkeys.  We went back for rides, and got sidetracked by kettle corn (and for good reason).<br />
We went back for another round on the carousel, and again went to the Rockin&#8217; Tug. By this point, my lack of coffee/lack of real food/subjection to the extremely loud and annoying squeaky horns that every little kid seemed to have/lack of coffee (hey, trust me, it&#8217;s that serious) had finally caused a near epic-level headache to form. I couldn&#8217;t wear my hat, and having you on my shoulders was causing intense throbbing. I wasn&#8217;t sure we&#8217;d even survive a trip on the Wacky Worm without me losing what little not-really-lunch I had.   But you loved it &#8212; I remember being totally terrified of my first rollercoaster &#8212; and I got off with my dignity intact.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/the-kiddie-midway-at-the-calgary-stampede/' title='The Kiddie Midway at the Calgary Stampede'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/The-Kiddie-Midway-at-the-Calgary-Stampede-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3298" alt="The Kiddie Midway at the Calgary Stampede" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923833753/">Geoff S.</a><br />
And then we had to go home. My head was threatening to explode. As it stands, I had to take two strong pills and crawl into bed for about 45 minutes before I could function again. &#8220;Next time&#8221;, I say now, knowing that I&#8217;m probably deluding myself.<br />
I hope you had fun, kiddo. And Choo Choo, next year you&#8217;ll get a chance to go and have fun, too. But maybe during the week &#8212; this going on &#8220;Family Day&#8221; just equates to a little too much torture, methinks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2950</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back at the (new) Calgary Farmer&#039;s Market</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/back-at-the-new-calgary-farmers-market/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-at-the-new-calgary-farmers-market</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/back-at-the-new-calgary-farmers-market/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 03:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, a few months behind schedule, the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market finally re-opened its doors at their new location near the corner of Blackfoot Trail and Heritage Drive in Southeast Calgary. It&#8217;s been long-planned and long-awaited by many &#8212; especially the Monkey, who wanted to go back to the &#8220;jumping castle&#8221;. But if you&#8217;ve read &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/back-at-the-new-calgary-farmers-market/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back at the (new) Calgary Farmer&#039;s Market"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Thursday, a few months behind schedule, the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market finally re-opened its doors at their new location near the corner of Blackfoot Trail and Heritage Drive in Southeast Calgary. It&#8217;s been long-planned and long-awaited by many &#8212; especially the Monkey, who wanted to go back to the &#8220;jumping castle&#8221;.<br />
But if you&#8217;ve read by blog, you know that <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market/">the jumping castle is no more, and Mike the Balloon Tycoon is no longer a figure at the market</a>. Many things have changed, actually, all of them affecting the market we once knew and loved. It&#8217;s definitely not the same market anymore, and rings more of <a href="http://www.theforks.com/">The Forks in Winnipeg</a>, or <a href="http://www.granvilleisland.com/public-market">Granville Island in Vancouver</a>.<br />
I can&#8217;t yet say if it&#8217;s a step up or down, but it&#8217;s definitely a step forward.<br />
<span id="more-2924"></span>Unlike <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=calgary&amp;aq=&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=34.999041,78.925781&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=Calgary,+Division+No.+6,+Alberta,+Canada&amp;ll=51.01471,-114.12021&amp;spn=0.001698,0.004817&amp;t=h&amp;z=18">the old site</a>, which was a 1940&#8217;s military warehouse, <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=calgary&amp;aq=&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=34.999041,78.925781&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=Calgary,+Division+No.+6,+Alberta,+Canada&amp;ll=50.985028,-114.050751&amp;spn=0.001699,0.004817&amp;t=h&amp;z=18">the new market</a> is an expanded end of an industrial complex, conveniently placed next to a shooting range. We&#8217;d seen the plans for the new market many times as the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market executive advertised the new space in hopes of bringing over as many existing clients as possible. It was likely a necessary thing, since the old market was the only decent market on the west side of town, and the West side folk have to be encouraged to drive into the East beyond visiting IKEA (which, conveniently, isn&#8217;t too far away from the new market).<br />
Normally, we went to the market on Saturdays to have breakfast, and do a little shopping (and let Monkey burn off steam in the no-longer-present jumping castle). But today being Good Friday, it was a convenient chance for us to visit on a weekday. Apparently, along with half of the rest of the city&#8230;<br />
When we got to the light at 71st Ave SE at 8:45 this morning, all we saw were cars. First thought: they didn&#8217;t allow for nearly enough parking. That was something the old site had in spades, thanks to the massive gravel parking lots that were likely leftover from previous warehouses. The new market has only side streets, and a limited lot. I will not be surprised to hear this is the single biggest complaint of the new market&#8217;s location.<br />
The cars worried us for two reasons: 1) it meant that, in previous experience, getting in and getting a table so we could get breakfast would be hard, even if 2) we could find a place to park.<br />
Thankfully (in a matter of speaking), we soon realised that a significant proportion of the cars were actually going to The Shooting Zone, the shooting range right next door to the market. (Monkey would later ask what the &#8220;bangs&#8221; were. She has yet to comprehend the concept of a gun.) There was a sale, and the double-whammy effect was a bit more than I think either organisation had expected.<br />
The market was just opening, and not many people had arrived yet. First impressions being the important ones, we were immediately impressed with the appearance. The ceilings were lower (but not claustrophobic), the stalls spaced well enough to get around easily (especially with strollers), and it looked much more polished than the old market (hence my allusions to both The Forks and Granville Island).<br />
We did a slow clockwise circuit, eventually arriving at the Fratello Analog Cafe stand. The lineup was already formed, and since we knew the Colombians (who ran the excellent Tutti Frutti booth at the old market) had opted not to go to the new market, we needed to find a new favourite coffee place. The Fratello stand is massive and exceedingly well-equipped with well-trained staff.<br />
Well, &#8220;well-trained&#8221; is a bit subjective, and something I have to apply to nearly every booth at the new market. Simple reality, it was the opening week (as I mentioned, the market actually opened yesterday), and everyone was still learning the ropes. Today was the first official &#8220;flood&#8221; day, and it was readily apparent that the all-important &#8220;flow&#8221; was still being learned (and re-learned, in some cases). Every booth we visited had the same problem, and it amazed me the level of  indignance  some people showed at the slower-than-preferred (by everyone, especially the staff) service. Sometimes, I think pissy people need to be ejected to the back of the line every time until they learn some respect and patience.<br />
Anyway, Fratello want to be to coffee what auteurs are to film. There is nothing but stylistic perfection, right down to even wanting a simple drip coffee. The Colombians, I felt, served a fantastic cup of coffee that was dispensed from a large thermos (frequently seen in many otherwise-fine coffee shops). Fratello thinks this is not an ideal way to get a fresh cup, so each &#8220;drip&#8221; cup is poured with hot water through freshly-ground coffee directly into the cup. (For the record, this is similar to how I make my coffee, but I steep mine before filtering through a Costa Rican coffee-sock.) For showmanship, it&#8217;s very nice. For expediency, it&#8217;s extremely slow. One guy next to me was nothing but contained rage about the time to get his coffee, and marched off without even getting a lid. One suggestion to Fratello &#8212; recognise that people want coffee, and not necessarily artisan coffee. Buy a thermos or two. You&#8217;ll sell more, if only by getting returning regulars. Respect the regulars, and you&#8217;ll increase business.<br />
The Food Court area is now more segregated from the rest of the market, and tucked into the corner is where Mike would have gone had he stayed. Instead, they&#8217;ve erected a jungle gym for the kids to play around it. It&#8217;s not very large, so kid collisions rise almost geometrically to the number of minutes the market&#8217;s been open that day. The number of screams seemed to double every ten minutes. But it was empty enough when we got there for Monkey to have a run-around and blow off a bit of steam.<br />
A Ladybug Pastries also opted to not make the transition, which surprised me. Given that they had a three-stall layout in the old market (and most certainly one of the nicest), I fully expected them to move over as well. But our favourite crepes, regardless of the high cost, were not to be found. We instead tried a new(er) place run by the same people who operate L&#8217;Epicerie on Macleod Trail just south of downtown. Whereas the folks who run A Ladybug are from Belgium, the proprietors of L&#8217;Epicerie are from Brittany. The crepes are decidedly more French. Alex was not a big fan, although I do like the ham and cheese and egg.<br />
The food court area has easily twice as many tables, and many of them are more family-sized, eschewing the massive eight-person round tables that made getting a seat at the old market so difficult. (Note to the Market executive: parents would like to see booster seats. Could you not have brought those over from the old market?) The ceiling is high, there&#8217;s a massive glass wall at the south end, and even a double gas fireplace in the centre for those really chilly winter days. It&#8217;s more mall-like, yes, but not so finished that it looks totally recumbent.<br />
Many of the old favourites did carry over to the market, and have continued with their work as before. I was happy to see Simply Good Eats, Shef&#8217;s Fiery Kitchen, Shanghai Fine Food, Margarita&#8217;s and 2 Greek Gals continue to sell breakfast. The Cherry Pit, Innisfail Grower&#8217;s Co-op, the various colonies, Wayne&#8217;s Bagels, Gull Valley, and Saskatoon Berry Farm also came. TotaliTea and the awesome <a href="http://www.silkroadspices.ca">Silk Road Spices</a> also have continued to be present. You&#8217;d have to be blind to miss Simple Simon. Mysteriously absent is the old market&#8217;s summertime anchor, Walker&#8217;s (they held no less than four stalls and were <em>the</em> place to get fruits and vegetables), and I&#8217;m personally miffed to see that Sunworks seemingly has vanished &#8212; where the heck am I gonna get my Thanksgiving turkeys, now?<br />
By the time we left, the market was jammed, making it very difficult to get around. I am able to pass this off as opening-day curiousity, and it will eventually slide into regulars. Outside, people were having extreme difficulty finding a place to park, and I imagine The Shooting Zone is going to have more than a little trouble with market-goers using up their valuable members-only parking stalls.<br />
It&#8217;s good to the see the market open again. It&#8217;s clear that some effort has been placed on making sure there&#8217;s a good mix of vendors, and attention has been paid to retain at least some of the old anchors to keep things familiar. I&#8217;m curious as to the loss of some of the old vendors, especially the ones I liked and frequented, and I imagine the inclusion of some vendors led to the departure (or non-signing) of others (Hoven Farms out, Silver Sage in; Walker&#8217;s gone, replaced with Soutu Farms).<br />
Will it succeed? Of course it will &#8212; for the same reasons the old market succeeded: it offered a higher quality of selection and service without the kvitch common to other markets like Crossroads (sorry, Crossroads, but you know what I mean). Will it be a &#8220;farmer&#8217;s&#8221; market? Therein lies the question &#8212; that aspect may have permanently changed, now with more emphasis on ready-made items, and less on the raw materials that farmer&#8217;s markets have historically been associated with. But it will be appealing to a significant proportion of Calgarians.<br />
As for my family, we will see. In terms of family-friendliness, the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market is likely to remain high in our books. The tripling of the distance to get to it is a downside, but even the old market was well beyond walking distance. After things settle, we&#8217;ll see how they go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/back-at-the-new-calgary-farmers-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2924</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An argument for wired city council</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-argument-for-wired-city-council</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 03:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As little as a hundred years ago, North Americans lived (generally) in towns and (much smaller) cities, where it was possible to know your elected representatives personally, meet with them, and have a person-to-person chat. In the years following, our representatives have been accused more and more of being &#8220;disconnected&#8221; and &#8220;out of touch&#8221; from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "An argument for wired city council"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As little as a hundred years ago, North Americans lived (generally) in towns and (much smaller) cities, where it was possible to know your elected representatives personally, meet with them, and have a person-to-person chat. In the years following, our representatives have been accused more and more of being &#8220;disconnected&#8221; and &#8220;out of touch&#8221; from their constituents, as the towns and cities grow, and the number of people in a given district rise well past the point of &#8220;manageable&#8221; by a single person.<br />
The biggest problem is not really the number of people &#8212; it&#8217;s the time councillors need to connect with them all, while still doing the job for which they were elected. In a physical sense, it&#8217;s nearly impossible. Some have turned to the internet to help bridge the gap, using technology to connect.<br />
Allow me to show you an example, which I experienced today&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2905"></span>While waiting for one of my software commits to complete, I took a few minutes to read my news feeds. One article, which caught me more than a little off-guard, was a note about <a href="http://enenews.com/recent-radioactivy-testing-vancouver-canada-shows-iodine-131-rainwater-almost-100-times-above-drinking-water-limit">radioactive particles from the Japanese Fukushima reactor appearing in Vancouver&#8217;s water supply</a>. It was surprising as no-one had really expected that to happen, and moreso because the levels were a lot higher than I would have imagined.<br />
My first thought was how that would affect the water supply in Vancouver, especially towards children (it&#8217;s already an issue in parts of Japan, and BC has already had a scare that led to a run on iodine tablets). My second thought was: the rain on this side of the Rocky Mountains often comes in from the Vancouver area.<br />
Now I &#8212; as a regular, ordinary citizen of Canada&#8217;s fourth largest city &#8212; would likely have to spend quite some time to find out where to start to see if that problem had arrived here. But I&#8217;m not &#8220;regular&#8221; &#8212; I&#8217;m highly connected. And not in the &#8220;I know people way&#8221;, I mean by the internet. And I follow my ward&#8217;s alderman, <a href="http://twitter.com/aldjohnmar">John Mar</a>, on Twitter. Who better to find out if Calgary&#8217;s at risk than one of Calgary&#8217;s tooth-and-nail fighters?<br />
I started with the simple question:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-I-know-you_re-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2906" title="Twitter _ Geoff Sowrey_ @aldjohnmar I know you_re ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-I-know-you_re-....jpg" alt="" width="617" height="334" /></a><br />
Knowing that John&#8217;s a busy guy (he regularly tweets his activities; which I gotta say, it&#8217;s a very handy way of knowing what your elected representative is up to without having to call them on a regular basis), I didn&#8217;t expect an immediate response. Heck, I&#8217;d have been happy with a simple &#8220;yes/no&#8221; answer. I got John&#8217;s response just a few minutes later:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-I-don_t-know-but-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2909" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey I don_t know, but ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-I-don_t-know-but-....jpg" alt="" width="617" height="268" /></a><br />
Okay, first off, in any service-based organisation &#8212; public or private &#8212; immediate (or at least near-immediate) response &#8212; even if it&#8217;s &#8220;we&#8217;ll get back to you&#8221; &#8212; is necessary to instill confidence. Lack of response breeds doubt, and especially with government, makes people think things are being done behind closed doors. In an era where we demand transparency, acknowledgement of a request is <em>the</em> killer app.<br />
It took a little while &#8212; still less time than it would have taken me, I&#8217;m sure &#8212; but I got my answer:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Pleased-to-Report-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2911" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey Pleased to Report, ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Pleased-to-Report-....jpg" alt="" width="613" height="303" /></a><br />
There you go &#8212; we were safe. And you feel a lot more secure with an answer from a public figure than you do from a city bureaucrat. But John&#8217;s answer got me to thinking: a) Iodine 131 is probably not regularly tested for in water supplies (why would it be?), and b) that&#8217;s a fairly recent test. Which led me to wonder if it might be an ongoing test for the foreseeable future:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-That_s-a-relie-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2907" title="Twitter _ Geoff Sowrey_ @aldjohnmar That_s a relie ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-That_s-a-relie-....jpg" alt="" width="615" height="266" /></a><br />
John&#8217;s response, interestingly enough, I mostly expected:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-As-I-understand-it-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2908" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey As I understand it ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-As-I-understand-it-....jpg" alt="" width="611" height="266" /></a><br />
Now, it&#8217;s very easy to dismiss that as &#8220;well, that&#8217;s not answer&#8221; &#8230; and you&#8217;d be right, especially if you&#8217;re concerned about this sort of thing (which I am). But, where John does not fail, he followed up (unprompted) with this:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Just-heard-back-fr-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2910" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey Just heard back fr ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Just-heard-back-fr-....jpg" alt="" width="610" height="299" /></a><br />
So, net result, at least so far as Calgary&#8217;s water is concerned: we&#8217;re okay. But that&#8217;s actually the lesser part of the story. The more important, I think, is that I got an answer to a pressing question over Twitter (not waiting on phones), and directly from my elected official.<br />
As an interesting aside, <a href="http://twitter.com/aldjohnmar/status/11837858318913536">John actually left Twitter early last December</a>, after he received a fair amount of abuse from people who didn&#8217;t think he was tweeting enough. It was a loss for us who followed, since he had been a valuable source of information on the regular goings-on in city council.  Thankfully, John returned to Twitter about two months later.<br />
It&#8217;s a tough gig, being a public figure on Twitter. There are a lot of demands from the informed and uninformed alike, and people&#8217;s patience online is about a tenth of what it is in person (and politeness can sink to a hundredth or less). Somehow, people seem to forget that Twitter is an outlet, not a full-time job. John, so far, has done an admirable job of balancing the act, and remains (in my view) the best of Calgary&#8217;s city council in using Twitter is a communications tool.<br />
So go on, ask me if I feel my councillor is out of touch. I dare ya.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2905</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our last day at the Calgary Farmer&#039;s Market</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 04:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On 23 December, the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market will close its doors in the old CFB Calgary lands forever. It&#8217;s a dark day for the Sowrey family, as the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market has been a fairly significant part of our lives for the last few years (Costa Rica notwithstanding). Shortly before Alex and I were married, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Our last day at the Calgary Farmer&#039;s Market"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On 23 December, the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market will close its doors in the old CFB Calgary lands forever. It&#8217;s a dark day for the Sowrey family, as the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market has been a fairly significant part of our lives for the last few years (Costa Rica notwithstanding).<br />
Shortly before Alex and I were married, we moved to a house a mere 10 minute walk from the Market, so we visited frequently. After our return from Costa Rica, going to the Market became a weekly event, to the point where we got to know some of the Market vendors fairly well.<br />
Because we fly out to Abbotsford tomorrow, today was our last day. We just about cried.<br />
<span id="more-2812"></span>Seriously! No, I&#8217;m not taking this lightly! The Market, as it stood, was (at least in my humble view) the best example of a farmer&#8217;s market in Calgary, and was the only thing that served the west side of the city, or offered any reasonable option to a large portion of the north part of the city, too.<br />
The Market isn&#8217;t disappearing from Calgary, but relocating to another venue off of Blackfoot Trail. Not all the vendors are going. Some are hanging their hats, deciding that it&#8217;s time to move on, and it appears the once-lauded children&#8217;s space is likely to wither to a mere echo of a whisper of its former grandeur. Mike, the Balloon Tycoon, is one who will not be seen at the new location.<br />
The distance away likely means we will not be visiting regularly, and without a children&#8217;s space for Monkey and Choo Choo, it means there is less of a reason for us to go. For that distance, we might as well go just the little bit further and go to IKEA instead.<br />
But this is how life goes, right? Change? Things not remaining the same?<br />
Thank you, CFM, for the years you were the way you were. Those are memories that I am already thankful for, and I can only hope they&#8217;ll be ones that my kids might remember, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-last-day-at-the-calgary-farmers-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2812</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You can never go home again</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/you-can-never-go-home-again/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=you-can-never-go-home-again</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/you-can-never-go-home-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 03:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was a kid, I heard the phrase &#8220;you can never go home again&#8221;, but never understood it. I mean, I went home every day after school, so what was wrong with that? It wasn&#8217;t until I went to university that I started to appreciate it &#8212; I was regularly amazed at how much &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/you-can-never-go-home-again/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "You can never go home again"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was a kid, I heard the phrase &#8220;you can never go home again&#8221;, but never understood it. I mean, I went home every day after school, so what was wrong with that? It wasn&#8217;t until I went to university that I started to appreciate it &#8212; I was regularly amazed at how much my hometown seemed to change whenever I was away at school.<br />
When my father died in 2002, the term gained a whole new meaning for me. Suddenly, I couldn&#8217;t even go home. My home was where my family lived, which was now only in the past. When my mother moved away, my home became a sightseeing stop.<br />
Then I moved home from Costa Rica, to a house we own. Man, talk about change of perspective.<br />
<span id="more-2253"></span>Okay, let&#8217;s get the obvious one out of the way: It&#8217;s farking cold. In Santa Ana, the temperature stayed between 15 C and 27 C. Every day. Every single solitary day. All year long. That&#8217;s a level of consistency that Canadians find as hard to understand as &#8230; well, as hard as it is for Costa Ricans to understand the idea of -40 degrees. It&#8217;s not easy to from shorts and sandals and lush green, to thick heavy coats and gloves and a foot of snow.<br />
I was rather amazed that I found the house. I hadn&#8217;t driven to the house for a year and a half, and there was a moment when I thought I might get lost. But it was still there, the lawn covered in pink flamingos (a &#8220;welcome home&#8221; present from my sister, Cathy). Inside, the house looked &#8212; at first &#8212; almost exactly the way we&#8217;d left it.<br />
But there were a few issues. Therein lies the problem with tenants &#8212; they never really treat the place the way you want them to. The downstairs heating had been out for a year &#8212; a YEAR. It&#8217;s a heated floor (heat was supplied via forced air, which does the upstairs), controlled by battery-powered thermostats. The batteries were dead. For some reason, no-one had bothered to THINK about replacing them. Heat was running again after a few hours (the system had to bleed air out of the lines again).<br />
Then there was the handrail into the basement, just about entirely dislocated from the wall. Gashes in a couple of places. And the reality that despite a clear instruction to not allow smoking in the house, someone had smoked. I couldn&#8217;t smell it, but Alex could. Allen and Alex made a variety of repairs in those first few days.<br />
I&#8217;m actually having problems believing we&#8217;re in our house. And I don&#8217;t have to be a renter anymore.<br />
The city&#8217;s changed. Downtown is bigger. There&#8217;s more traffic lights in a few places. A line of houses, stores, and a church are gone from 17th Avenue, where the West LRT will be built in the next couple of years. Stores we went to are gone, and new ones have appeared. (Interesting, the lane reversals on Memorial are still in testing.) It&#8217;s almost like walking into an alternate universe version of our home.<br />
Our stuff arrived moved into the house the same day we did. We&#8217;ve got a zillion boxes, some of which we haven&#8217;t seen since before we moved out of our house in Garrison Woods back in 2007! We&#8217;ve got things we&#8217;re pulling out of boxes, wondering where we got it &#8230; and in a couple of cases, what the heck it is.<br />
For the last year and a half, we lived minimally. We rented a furnished apartment. We had next to no kitchen gadgets (although we did have an espresso machine), very few clothes (you have only one season: warm), not a lot of books, and a single flat panel television. We&#8217;ve now got several times that unfolding into the house, and it&#8217;s not easy to figure out where it&#8217;s all going. At least we have full access to the basement, now.<br />
We bought a car. Calgary&#8217;s not a pedestrian-friendly city, unfortunately. Although Calgary Transit does cover a lot of ground, things are far too spread out to use a bus effectively, especially when a toddler is involved. Besides, we want to go out to the mountains without having to book charter tickets. There&#8217;s a certain amount of flexibility that is required.<br />
We started looking before we left Costa Rica. Our goal was fairly simple: small, and fuel-efficient. Alex found a black Jetta TDI at Shaganappi Motors, now the only GM dealership in town. It was a used 2006 model year, with about 75,000 clicks on it, but it was a diesel, and in good shape. We put down a deposit, just to make sure it was still around when we got there. The car was purchased in a single day, from the actual test drive all the way through registration, plating, insurance, and financial.<br />
It&#8217;s our fifth car in two years. Hopefully it&#8217;ll last us a long time to come.<br />
The one thing that has been most consistent for us are the people we know: our family and friends. Even though we haven&#8217;t seen some of them in a year and a half, it&#8217;s almost like we haven&#8217;t left. Like putting on your favourite pants.<br />
Be it ever so different, there&#8217;s no place like home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/you-can-never-go-home-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2253</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
