<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>parks &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/parks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A walk in the (amusement) park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-walk-in-the-amusement-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amusement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kids, we missed the Calgary Stampede this year. That was partly intentional, to be honest. Yes, it was the 100th anniversary, and Choo Choo was old enough to actually do some of the things there, but &#8230; well, it was kind of crazy this year, and maybe the 101th anniversary won&#8217;t be quite so crazy. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A walk in the (amusement) park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kids, we missed the Calgary Stampede this year. That was partly intentional, to be honest. Yes, it was the 100th anniversary, and Choo Choo was old enough to actually <em>do</em> some of the things there, but &#8230; well, it was kind of crazy this year, and maybe the 101th anniversary won&#8217;t be quite so crazy. And you&#8217;ll be older, and slightly more &#8230; how can I put this? &#8230; <em>controllable</em>.<br />
That said, you both like rides, Monkey especially. (<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/">We found that out last year.</a>) So denying you two a trip to an amusement park, especially during what&#8217;s turning out to be Calgary&#8217;s best summer in a long time, is just plain criminal. So with Mommy&#8217;s acquired coupons, we packed you up, dragged out Grandpa, and all headed to Calaway Park.<br />
In a word? &#8220;WHEEEEEEEE!&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-3128"></span>We were a tad late leaving, because &#8212; completely stunning everyone &#8212; we all slept in. Well, most of us. Choo Choo, you were up, but you (in an extremely rare move) didn&#8217;t tell anyone you were up. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever made pancakes so quickly before.<br />
The park wasn&#8217;t busy when we arrived, though our arrival was a bit elongated as we tried to all find one another. But it wasn&#8217;t long before we were off into the park to wreak appropriate havoc.<br />
First up were bumper boats. I was mildly surprised that they had any water-based rides, but one of my favourites seemed to not be an issue. As I commented to Grandpa, they&#8217;re not the ones I grew up with. Those were using <em>real</em> outboard motors, and we had to wear life jackets (we were also on Lake Ontario). Calaway&#8217;s are electric, with built-in squirt guns (that really need to have the ability to aim up/down &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to hit the guy in front of you). Sadly, Choo Choo was too small, and Mommy wasn&#8217;t &#8220;suitably dressed&#8221; for water play, so they went off while Monkey, Grandpa, and I tried to soak each other.<br />
We found our way to a ride called the Samba Swing, which was a real definition of &#8220;spinny ride&#8221;. Not only did it go around in a circle, it raised on an angle like a tilted ferris wheel, but each of the pods could spin around on its own. Mommy and Choo Choo went in one, while Monkey and I went in the other. Sadly, the pods tended to spin, even if you didn&#8217;t try, as the centripetal force caused the heavier person to swing to the outside. Monkey, you giggled pretty much the entire time; Choo Choo, you didn&#8217;t dig it so much.<br />
Thankfully, merry-go-rounds are easier, and both of you seemed okay with that. We marched off in search of a train ride, which was preempted by a kids-sized rollercoaster (you&#8217;re still a bit too small for the big rollercoaster, Monkey, though you REALLY wanted to go on it). Mommy spotted a game called &#8220;Stinky Feet&#8221;, which we played. I won, and the game attendant let me get two (smaller) prizes for the two of you.<br />
The train ride was &#8230; well, slow. But at least fun. And not rainy, like the previous one we&#8217;d been on.<br />
After lunch, we went in search of more rides. We found the Berry Go Round, which was another spinny ride (but not as spinny as Samba). Monkey wouldn&#8217;t let us spin at all, though I have no idea why. That&#8217;s not to say that I didn&#8217;t try to get us to spin &#8212; even just a little. Then Monkey and Grandpa went on an airplane ride while Choo Choo went and played in a tugboat playset.<br />
We tried to find ice cream. You&#8217;d think this should be about, oh, ever metre in an amusement park in the summer? It&#8217;s not, which I found particularly odd. Our search took us over towards Shoot the Chutes, which is (so Mommy tells me) an original ride, which doesn&#8217;t appear to have changed much since Mommy was a kid. Monkey, Grandpa, and I got in line while Mommy and Choo Choo went off in search of ice cream &#8212; sadly, Choo Choo, you&#8217;re just a bit too small for my liking.<br />
It took nearly 45 minutes to get through the line, which went slower than it should have because they weren&#8217;t loading the boats completely full. When we finally got to the end, they had started maxing the capacity. As it stands, we ended up with a five-person boat; the three of us, plus a father and daughter.<br />
The first hill caused a spat of maniacal laughter in Monkey. I&#8217;ve never heard her laugh so wildly, declaring the ride was awesome.<br />
Well, that was the <em>first</em> hill. Which is about <em>half</em> the height of the full thing.<br />
When we go to the top of the second hill &#8212; the big one &#8212; Monkey wanted off. Now. Please.<br />
There&#8217;s a picture that gets taken when you go down the big hill. What you see is a look of abject terror on Monkey&#8217;s face, the sheer excitement of the kid behind her (that would be Monkey&#8217;s father, of course), and Grandpa looking like he was nearly asleep from boredom (Grandpa should play poker, really).<br />
At the bottom, our boat kicked up a huge wall of water, which fell right on top of Monkey. That elicited some tears, which is understandable. Thankfully, Mommy had thought to bring a zip-up fleece, which replaced Monkey&#8217;s soaked t-shirt. Then we were off &#8212; FINALLY &#8212; for ice cream.<br />
A clown found the both of you as the last of the ice cream went down, which you both loved (especially for the bubbles).<br />
Exhaustion having set in fully with Choo Choo, we headed for home; Choo Choo was asleep five minutes later.<br />
But worry not, we&#8217;re going back! Hopefully it&#8217;ll be as much fun as yesterday!<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3128</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monkey&#039;s First Stampede</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=monkeys-first-stampede</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 04:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amusement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Perhaps the title&#8217;s a bit misleading, Monkey, but I suspect this will be the first Stampede you actually remember. And you have reason to remember it, too. You&#8217;ve listened to marching bands, eaten pancakes, ridden rollercoasters, and even seen a future King. Not bad for only a little over 48 hours, eh? It started Friday &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Monkey&#039;s First Stampede"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the title&#8217;s a bit misleading, Monkey, but I suspect this will be the first Stampede you actually remember. And you have reason to remember it, too. You&#8217;ve listened to marching bands, eaten pancakes, ridden rollercoasters, and even seen a future King.<br />
Not bad for only a little over 48 hours, eh?<br />
<span id="more-2950"></span>It started Friday morning, which was Stampede Parade Day. The Calgary Stampede Parade is one of the largest in the world (I&#8217;ve heard it&#8217;s second, but have yet to hear what&#8217;s first, or the conditions under which that define its size), and has been a tradition in Calgary for close to a century. Now that you&#8217;re nearly four, it seemed like a good idea to take you to the parade so you could see it yourself, and not drive me insane by having a total loss of focus.<br />
There&#8217;s only one catch with seeing the parade: you have to either have bench seating (acquired in advance, usually with paid tickets), or you get there early to get anywhere near a decent place to sit. Rather foolishly, I thought we had plenty of time leaving at 6:35am.<br />
The lines had formed much earlier that morning (the people we sat next to &#8212; you remember them, right? They had the little white dog named &#8220;Cookie&#8221;? &#8212; arrived at 6:30 that morning and said all the front-line seats were long gone), and we were met with a sea of people as we crossed under the bridge into downtown.<br />
My other grandiose plan was to stop at McDonald&#8217;s for breakfast, since we hadn&#8217;t the time to eat before we left the house. That line was equally as bad, and it meant that we either ate, or suffered through poor seating. Given the time we&#8217;d have to wait, I felt the the latter was more important. We had at least brought you some snacks, Monkey, so you wouldn&#8217;t be starving. I would have to go without&#8230;<br />
We found a place, next to a wooden fence at the edge of the massive Impark lots on the south side of 9th Ave., that offered a fairly decent view of the route, and was not totally blocked by the scads of folding chairs that everyone else had (next time, I&#8217;ll remember to bring <em>real</em> chairs). And there we sat down and waited for something &#8212; well, <em>anything</em> &#8212; to happen.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/its-going-to-be-a-long-wait-to-see-anything/' title='It&#039;s going to be a long wait to see anything'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/It-s-going-to-be-a-long-wait-to-see-anything-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3291" alt="It&#039;s going to be a long wait to see anything" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924247238/">Geoff S.</a><br />
It dawned on me rather suddenly that I had been sitting in almost the same place some 10 years earlier with Auntie Cathy and Uncle Craig (before they got married) to watch my first Stampede parade. I wouldn&#8217;t have imagined that 10 years later I&#8217;d be watching the Parade with my own daughter on my knee.<br />
William and Kate, the Duke and Duchess of Cambridge &#8212; the future king of the United Kingdom and his wife (I&#8217;m not sure if she&#8217;ll be a &#8220;Queen&#8221; or a &#8220;Princess Consort&#8221; at that point) had been in Canada for the last couple of weeks on a whirlwind tour of the country (supposedly a &#8220;honeymoon&#8221; &#8212; Mommy and I have had some pretty whirlwind-type trips, but nothing that hectic), and were going to see the Stampede Parade, too. And before the Parade started, they would do a pass through the Parade route, themselves &#8230; in reverse. [Insert joke about driving on the wrong side of the road here.]<br />
By 8:40, we were already fairly tired of waiting (and my ass already bruised from the hard ground and stones I had to sit on &#8212; you sat on me, I should add), but we were rewarded by the Royal Drive By (albeit far faster than anyone would have desired, and it was difficult to actually see the Royals &#8212; Kate was on our side of the car). Pretty much everyone clapped and cheered.<br />
We didn&#8217;t really see much for another hour. Given our place on the route, that wasn&#8217;t entirely surprising, but it did seem a bit much, all things considered. Marching bands, clowns, and lots and lots and lots of horses. And a guy riding a bull (memories of Mel Brooks&#8217; <em>Blazing Saddles</em>, indeed!). Our Mayor, Naheed Nenshi, rode a horse, too and seemed quite happy to do so. We saw Rick Hanson, who was the Parade Marshall for 2011 &#8212; he drove himself (hey, he drove himself around the world &#8212; a paltry couple of kilometres is nothing for him, right?). The biggest cheers were for the Canadian Armed Forces, notably the Army &#8212; almost everyone stood and cheered loudly for them. (One day, I&#8217;ll explain why, Monkey. That&#8217;s a very long topic, and pretty much entirely another blog post.) The quietest moments were when our faithful Ministers of Parliament drove past &#8212; the &#8220;Honourable&#8221; Rob Anders was met with embarrassed silence (guess what, Calgary, you aren&#8217;t allowed to be embarrassed &#8212; you <em>voted</em> for him, remember?).<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/calgary-stampede-band/' title='Calgary Stampede Band'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Calgary-Stampede-Band-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3292" alt="Calgary Stampede Band" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923718161/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/calgary-mayor-naheed-nenshi/' title='Calgary Mayor Naheed Nenshi'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Calgary-Mayor-Naheed-Nenshi-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3293" alt="Calgary Mayor Naheed Nenshi" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924322318/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/canadian-armed-forces-tank/' title='Canadian Armed Forces tank'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Canadian-Armed-Forces-tank-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3294" alt="Canadian Armed Forces tank" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923786989/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/wes/' title='&amp;quot ;Wes &amp;quot ;'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/quot-Wes-quot--300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3295" alt="&amp;quot ;Wes &amp;quot ;" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924377722/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Mommy met us at the Safeway downtown where we ran into two friends of mine: Evelyn, who I worked with for many years; and a childhood friend of mine, Neil, who also lives in Calgary. You then went home, and I went to work.<br />
Yesterday, we went for our first (and possibly only) free pancake breakfast. The pancake breakfast is a tradition that has existed in Calgary for almost as long as the Stampede itself. It&#8217;s so rooted in tradition that when someone actually charges for a breakfast (and the money doesn&#8217;t go directly to charity), they get the stinkeye from just about everyone. People take their free breakfasts around here pretty seriously.<br />
The Stampede Caravan runs a very efficient and very tight ship when it comes to pancakes. You, Choo Choo, and I walked up to the Sunterra, where the Caravan had set up their event. (We had gone last year, too, but I&#8217;m not sure if you remember that at all.) By the time we arrived, the parking lot was packed with people waiting for pancakes &#8212; they hadn&#8217;t yet started flipping them.) You declared you wanted to see the animals first, which seemed like a good idea, since we had to wait anyway.<br />
Butterfield Acres was also there, just like last year, with pony rides and their portable petting zoo. Chicks, bunnies, goats, and lambs. You shrieked in eagerness, then raced in to give out hay to the goats, pet the bunnies, and be reminded several times not to pick up the chicks. (Choo Choo, you petted the lambs, which you loved, and the goats. You couldn&#8217;t really reach the bunnies, and we weren&#8217;t allowed to pick them up.)<br />
Despite the several-hundred person-long line, it took a mere 15 minutes to get our pancakes. (Like I said, the Stampede Caravan runs a <em>very</em> efficient operation. They set the standard for how it should be done.) Your pancake, thanks to one very nice cook, was shaped like Mickey Mouse. We got our pancakes, found a curb to sit down, and dug in. Even Choo Choo inhaled her pancakes.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/pancakes/' title='Pancakes !'><img width="224" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Pancakes--224x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignright wp-image-3296" alt="Pancakes !" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5924387592/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Afterwards, we went over to the pony ride, which I had promised. Just as you got into line to get on a pony, Erin and her friend arrived (which I had known about, but forgotten about). You love riding ponies, I&#8217;ve noticed &#8212; a far cry from the day we tried to get you on a pony in La Sabana Park in San José, when you cried in terror at the idea. It&#8217;s just a shame that you couldn&#8217;t go around more than once, though, and had to come out.<br />
We went shopping for dinner afterwards, and &#8220;helped&#8221; by picking out chocolate milk, and deciding that we needed to take a pie as well (which you summarily dropped on the floor, forcing my hand to purchase it). Although you wrecked the pie (actually, a 9&#8243; creme brulée), the Sunterra manager very kindly swapped it with a new one, reinforcing the reason why I prefer to shop there.<br />
This morning, we were all going to go to the Stampede itself. It was Family Day at the Stampede, meaning there was free entrance to the park before 9:00, and a pancake breakfast for the first 20,000 people. You would think we could do that&#8230;<br />
Choo Choo was against us, however, and woke up several times last night without going back to sleep. Eventually Mommy decided to stay up with her, letting you and I get a little more sleep. But I woke later than I&#8217;d wanted to, and Mommy was too tired to go (she has to work until midnight tonight), so it ended up being just you and me, and we didn&#8217;t get to the park until just after 8:00 &#8230; and about 1 minute after they ran out of tickets for the pancakes. Once again, Daddy was going hungry.<br />
It also appeared that the Stampede hadn&#8217;t really opened yet, either. Most of the exhibits didn&#8217;t open until 9:00, with a number not opening until 10:00. That left us with &#8230; well, not to much to do. Thankfully, Mommy had the foresight to have me bring you something good to eat (although the Stampede has lots of food, most of it is &#8230; well, not exactly healthy). Down went an apple sauce, banana, and a heck of a lot of grapes. And you were still hungry.<br />
We wandered through the BMO Centre and the Corral looking for the kids midway &#8212; something I thought would be a little easier for you to handle. Immediately, I felt nostalgic for the days when I was about your age, and my parents took me to the Canadian National Exhibition (&#8220;The EX&#8221; or the &#8220;CNE&#8221;) in Toronto. It was always the last hurrah of the summer, and the clown-faced logo of Conklin Shows is something I&#8217;ll not likely ever forget &#8212; something you&#8217;ll likely never know, either, since Conklin sold out to North American Midway Entertainment. It&#8217;s really not quite the same thing.<br />
We picked up 12 tickets, which I figured would be good for three rides. I didn&#8217;t know what you&#8217;d like yet, and felt buying too much was a bad idea. First stop? The carousel. I know you love carousels &#8212; you&#8217;ve been on several, now &#8212; and you asked quickly for the &#8220;horsie ride&#8221;. Although not nearly as nice as the one in Heritage Park (a vintage machine that is infinitely more attractive, at least during the day) or the one at the zoo (zoo animals being a major plus), you loved being on it just the same.<br />
Then, to my surprise, you asked to go on the &#8220;boat ride&#8221;. The &#8220;Rockin&#8217; Tug&#8221; is a kid-friendly version of the classic Swinging (Pirate) Ship ride, except it sits on rails rather than being suspended from a massive hinge. And, unlike its larger sibling, the tug actually spins around.<br />
I thought you&#8217;d chicken out. Really. Maybe I had a lower expectation, Monkey, given some of the things you&#8217;d said you wanted to do and changed your mind at the last second; or maybe I was even extending some of my fears from when I was your age. But you not only eager climbed up, you virtually stunned me by cheering and screaming &#8220;wheeeee!&#8221; the entire time. You&#8217;re hooked.<br />
After that, we tried to get into SuperDogs. I emphasize &#8220;tried&#8221;, because the line to buy tickets (I wasn&#8217;t even aware that SuperDogs even needed tickets &#8212; my memory had always been that of a walk-in event) was almost as long as the line for pancakes.<br />
So we had some of Those Little Donuts instead. Infinitely yummier, if you ask me.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/mmmm-donuts/' title='Mmmm... donuts...'><img width="224" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Mmmm-donuts--224x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignright wp-image-3297" alt="Mmmm... donuts..." /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923831923/">Geoff S.</a><br />
We tried to find a petting zoo in the agricultural area. You&#8217;d think for an agricultural-based event, there&#8217;d be more kid-friendly things. But there was no petting area that we could see, no pig races, nothing even remotely fun for the kids. Just an endless stream of horses (even you got tired of them all), a few cows (surprisingly few for an agricultural-based event), and a bunch of miniature donkeys.  We went back for rides, and got sidetracked by kettle corn (and for good reason).<br />
We went back for another round on the carousel, and again went to the Rockin&#8217; Tug. By this point, my lack of coffee/lack of real food/subjection to the extremely loud and annoying squeaky horns that every little kid seemed to have/lack of coffee (hey, trust me, it&#8217;s that serious) had finally caused a near epic-level headache to form. I couldn&#8217;t wear my hat, and having you on my shoulders was causing intense throbbing. I wasn&#8217;t sure we&#8217;d even survive a trip on the Wacky Worm without me losing what little not-really-lunch I had.   But you loved it &#8212; I remember being totally terrified of my first rollercoaster &#8212; and I got off with my dignity intact.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/the-kiddie-midway-at-the-calgary-stampede/' title='The Kiddie Midway at the Calgary Stampede'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/The-Kiddie-Midway-at-the-Calgary-Stampede-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3298" alt="The Kiddie Midway at the Calgary Stampede" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5923833753/">Geoff S.</a><br />
And then we had to go home. My head was threatening to explode. As it stands, I had to take two strong pills and crawl into bed for about 45 minutes before I could function again. &#8220;Next time&#8221;, I say now, knowing that I&#8217;m probably deluding myself.<br />
I hope you had fun, kiddo. And Choo Choo, next year you&#8217;ll get a chance to go and have fun, too. But maybe during the week &#8212; this going on &#8220;Family Day&#8221; just equates to a little too much torture, methinks.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2950</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diversions at Parque Diversiones</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/diversions-at-parque-diversiones/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=diversions-at-parque-diversiones</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/diversions-at-parque-diversiones/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 04:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amusement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Kiddo, today was a really fun day! Plans don&#8217;t always go according to plan, but there are those times when one plan ends up giving who new plans that are possibly even more fun than the original ones. I&#8217;d like to think today was like that, largely because we got to go somewhere fun, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/diversions-at-parque-diversiones/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Diversions at Parque Diversiones"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Kiddo, today was a really fun day!<br />
Plans don&#8217;t always go according to plan, but there are those times when one plan ends up giving who new plans that are possibly even more fun than the original ones. I&#8217;d like to think today was like that, largely because we got to go somewhere fun, and I got to spend nearly the whole day with you! (Except for, y&#8217;know, when you were sleeping.)<br />
<span id="more-1458"></span>The big plan of the day was to attend Marisa&#8217;s birthday. You know her, she&#8217;s your friend &#8212; that&#8217;s Meranda&#8217;s daughter! So after getting ourselves all dolled up, we headed out for &#8230; breakfast. It&#8217;s Saturday, we always go out for breakfast. Today, it was the Marriott again for their buffet. It&#8217;s a tasty place, and it&#8217;s near the highway. One of the waitresses there tried to get you to say &#8220;agua&#8221; instead of &#8220;water&#8221;.<br />
If only she knew you only say &#8220;agua&#8221; and not &#8220;water&#8221;.<br />
After breakfast, we hopped on the highway and drove to <a href="http://www.parquediversiones.com/">Parque de Diversiones</a>, an amusement park just west of San José. We&#8217;d heard of the place before, and had hoped to go there before, but never had. (In fact, I had thought it to be little more than a park, and wasn&#8217;t aware what we were about to run into.) It wasn&#8217;t until we arrived in front of the parking lot that the light began to shine on what we were getting into.<br />
We parked and waited for Meranda to arrive so the party could begin. You were sound asleep at the time, so didn&#8217;t really notice the passage of time. You were asleep maybe 30 minutes in total, maybe about 20 of which we waited in the car amidst some spitting of rain.<br />
When we finally went in, it was just the three of us. The entrance confused and frustrated me, as even with our reasonably-okay read-Spanish, we couldn&#8217;t figure out what the heck we were supposed to pay to get in. As it turns out the park is a very interesting set-up &#8212; entrance is actually free. You pay only to go to on rides &#8230; and buy food, souvenirs, etc. So we sauntered right in.<br />
That&#8217;s when we found out that the party had effectively been cancelled. (Mommy called Meranda.) So our original plans became just for us. And on we wandered&#8230;<br />
We spent most of our time in an area known as the Pueblo Antiguo (&#8220;Old Town&#8221;), which is a representation of what San José was like back at the turn of the previous century. Most of it is reconstruction and doesn&#8217;t seem to feature original buildings (unlike Calgary&#8217;s Heritage Park), but it was still fun to wander around. There&#8217;s even a farm with chickens and cows and horses and turkeys and even a little train.<br />
Afterwards, we had a light snack while you played with the spouting frogs at the fountain.   You got mostly soaked. You also ate most of my sno-cone, and wouldn&#8217;t even touch the cotton candy! I mean, what kid doesn&#8217;t like cotton candy?!<br />
Sadly, we didn&#8217;t ride anything. We&#8217;d understood we could purchase more tickets inside, so had kept an eye out so we could ride the merry-go-round, or even the train. In all cases, we couldn&#8217;t find anything. But that was okay for us, we just enjoyed the walking around. It wasn&#8217;t insanely busy, either.<br />
The park isn&#8217;t huge, and it has a range of different rides. You&#8217;re way too small for most of these, though. It&#8217;s a little like Calaway Park back in Calgary, or an in-between to Centre Island and Canada&#8217;s Wonderland back in Ontario. One day, I hope you&#8217;ll see all of these. For now, this will have to do.<br />
We toured the park for about two and a half hours before it was clear that you were running out of steam (you tend to get hyper and distracted when you&#8217;re tired), so we opted to head back for home. It took longer for you to fall asleep than I&#8217;d thought &#8212; you didn&#8217;t actually pass out until we were in EscazÃº (and given the detour I took us on to get there, that was a good 20 minutes).<br />
Mommy and I ate a light lunch while you slept in the car. We parked right in front of the table (which was outside at Grau), so it was very easy to see you. You didn&#8217;t wake up until we left, but were asleep again moments later.<br />
Needless to say, we&#8217;ll be going back to Parque de Diversiones, and next time we&#8217;ll be definitely going on a few rides.<br />
[flickr]set:72157621314774600(square)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/diversions-at-parque-diversiones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DÃ­a del Padre en Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/dia-del-padre-en-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=dia-del-padre-en-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/dia-del-padre-en-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 03:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kiddo, Today was Father&#8217;s Day. Not just here in Costa Rica, but in many other places around the world. Today was a special day in many ways, notably in that you and I got to spend a lot of time together (sadly, something we don&#8217;t get most days), and that you gave me a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/dia-del-padre-en-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "DÃ­a del Padre en Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kiddo,<br />
Today was Father&#8217;s Day. Not just here in Costa Rica, but in many other places around the world. Today was a special day in many ways, notably in that you and I got to spend a lot of time together (sadly, something we don&#8217;t get most days), and that you gave me a wonderful present: a photo of you, and a nicely-coloured picture of your favourite Sesame Street character &#8212; Elmo! (Even if Mommy had to help you. A lot.)<br />
You also gave me another wonderful gift: sleep. You let us sleep in a bit instead of getting us all up for 6:00 (or earlier).<br />
<span id="more-1405"></span>Mommy treated us to her special pancakes, made with cocoa powder. The were really yummy. You had three of them. (Along with a lot of papaya and pineapple.) After breakfast, Mommy and I showered while you played with our clock radio. I&#8217;m quite certain I&#8217;ll be getting up at 3:28 tomorrow morning to some strange radio station &#8230; though more likely the buzzer, with the volume cranked all the way up.<br />
Ready for the day, we all hopped in the car and drove into San José to spend some time in La Sabana park. The park is the largest urban park in Costa Rica (I think), and is very popular with people who live here. We&#8217;ve driven by it many times over the last year, but we&#8217;ve never actually gone into it before. That&#8217;s a real shame, as it is a really nice place.<br />
The Dos Piños company (the ones who make your favourite milk &#8212; the one that comes in the red Tetrapak container?) had a booth selling ice cream, and a bouncy castle. Mommy tried to get you to go inside, but you decided that the bigger kids in there were too much and (rather wisely) left before you got hurt.<br />
[flickr]photo:3648451450[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3648443988[/flickr]<br />
We walked along the lake, and saw some little horses go past. They were taking children for rides. You pointed at them and said &#8220;horse&#8221; (I believe it was actually &#8220;caballo&#8221; or something equivalent, anyway), and couldn&#8217;t stop staring at them. A foal (the baby horse) came right near us. You were rather mesmerised.<br />
[flickr]photo:3647641915[/flickr]<br />
One note I&#8217;m going to toss out here: your vocabulary is increasing daily. You&#8217;re getting very good at repeating things others say to you, including words in Spanish. In fact, you tend to say &#8220;yo&#8221; instead of &#8220;me&#8221; (you still won&#8217;t say your name), are quick to utter &#8220;si&#8221; instead of &#8220;yes&#8221;,  &#8220;vamos&#8221; in lieu of &#8220;let&#8217;s go&#8221; (though you do say &#8220;come&#8221;), and &#8220;agua&#8221; instead of &#8220;water&#8221;. You say both &#8220;jugo&#8221; and &#8220;juice&#8221;, but you&#8217;re still signing &#8220;milk&#8221; instead of saying them. But I digress&#8230;<br />
The horse rides were a mere six hundred colones (barely over a dollar), and we couldn&#8217;t help pass up the chance for you to go for a ride. Sadly, you would have nothing to do with the horse and all attempts were met with screaming. Maybe next time we should have you touch the horse first before we try to put you on one.<br />
[flickr]photo:3648451450[/flickr]<br />
Plopping you on my shoulders, we walked around the lake watching everyone spend their lazy Sunday enjoying the sun and the warmth. Some kids played in a spring that fed the lake, others fished for perch (I think they&#8217;re perch). Many others were playing football (what you&#8217;ll come to know as &#8220;soccer&#8221;) in one of the many fields that dot the park.<br />
[flickr]photo:3647651377[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3648462260[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3647663361[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3647669241[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3647676829[/flickr]<br />
In the shade of trees, we shared ice creams and you ate a small dish of Cheerios (one of your favourite snacks). That&#8217;s when we saw people actually zip-lining through the park. We&#8217;d seen the wires, but hadn&#8217;t thought them to be in use. It was almost comical to see them drift overhead.<br />
[flickr]photo:3649270124[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3648583884[/flickr]<br />
We headed home shortly afterwards. We ate the last of our pizza, and then you went for a nap. So did I, after I made the mistake of laying down &#8212; I had a long, hard week and it really took the wind out of me.<br />
Denise woke me up, thankfully, when she came to our door looking for help with her email password. We woke you up a little bit later, when Grandpa called. We had a problem with our connection with him, so he hung up &#8212; just as Nana called! We chatted with Nana for about 20 minutes before hanging up and calling Grandpa back.   You spent most of that time running around with your cart, my iPod, and your milk, all the time without wearing a diaper. We&#8217;re trying to potty train you now, and you&#8217;re slowly taking to the potty. But you prefer to run around without anything on.<br />
We went to Tandoori Palace for dinner, which had a surprising number of people there given that the three times I&#8217;ve gone to get dinner, there&#8217;s been hardly anyone there. At first we had the place to ourselves, but a family of eight arrived, then two more couples. But we had a fantastic dinner, and you tried a few new things like pakoras, lhassi, and jafrazzi.<br />
And watched a lot of the Bollywood movie clips they show on the TVs.<br />
You&#8217;re in bed now, after we played a bit more after getting home. You didn&#8217;t really want to go to bed at first, but you didn&#8217;t put up a single fuss. You almost never do.<br />
Thank you for today, my sweet darling. You make it feel like every day is Father&#8217;s Day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/dia-del-padre-en-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend at Bow Lake</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/07/10/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go. We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend at Bow Lake"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go.<br />
We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different.<br />
<span id="more-440"></span>This weekend was grossly delayed, though. This year has been quite busy with a multitude of things to do and see. As such, we&#8217;re several months behind schedule on surprises. To make sure I don&#8217;t follow too far behind, I felt something particularly nice was important. That&#8217;s how we came to Bow Lake in Banff National Park and Simpson&#8217;s Num-Ti-Jah Lodge.<br />
We went up on Saturday, the first weekend of the Calgary Stampede. In fact, because it&#8217;s Stampede time again, it gave us the opportunity to have a hearty Stampede breakfast in our neighbourhood. I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s a homeowner&#8217;s group specifically, but someone definitely has their act together. We came across the same breakfast a year or two ago (admittedly I can&#8217;t remember which) and thought that it would be neat to attend. Little did we know that we&#8217;d be living there. The group puts on a mean breakfast.<br />
We then started the long drive out to Bow Lake. Only I knew where we were going, so it did raise the constant question: &#8220;Where are we going?&#8221; That was usually tied with: &#8220;When will we get there?&#8221; The gaps in between were punctuated with &#8220;How far are we going?&#8221;, &#8220;Are we going to [insert place name here]?&#8221;, and &#8220;Would Asia like going to [insert place name here]?&#8221; (That last one is a nod to a previous spoiled Surprise Weekend where I was caught off-guard with the [[Surprise weekend in Edmonton|mention of my oft-misbehaved cat]].)<br />
Thankfully, I&#8217;m very good at not answering questions like this. In order, the answers might sound like this: &#8220;Somewhere&#8221;, &#8220;Before we go to bed&#8221;, &#8220;As far as we need to&#8221;, &#8220;We might be going there&#8221;, and &#8220;Possibly, but I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;d enjoy being caged in the car for more than five minutes&#8221;. (Asia hates going to the vet, which only takes 10 minutes.)<br />
Our first stop was Banff. Not for any real reason other than we had to eat lunch. Our favourite place, the Old Spaghetti Factory, has finally lost its charm. A couple of years ago, they changed their recipe for the bread. It&#8217;s not bread anymore, it&#8217;s some conglomeration of bread-like powder. And the Italian salad dressing is &#8230; I don&#8217;t know how to describe it, but it ain&#8217;t the same. The quality has slumped overall, which is probably to recoup some of the costs on their otherwise reasonably-priced meals. It will likely be the last time I eat there. Considering we&#8217;ve already written off Starbucks, who knows how many more places will end up on the banned list&#8230;<br />
We did a little shopping (I can&#8217;t say for what, though) and I searched for sandals. As of yet, I&#8217;ve found nothing. But then I&#8217;m a picky sandal person, so it&#8217;ll probably take a while. Hopefully not too long, though &#8212; I need a second pair, and soon.<br />
Returning to the car, we headed back to the Trans Canada and continued west. This brought a return of questions regarding our destination, and a wad of non-commital responses. About 40 minutes later, we turned up Highway 93 (the Icefields Parkway part of it, of course). This brought about a specific direction of questions. It&#8217;s about three hours to Jasper, and there isn&#8217;t much in between. Alex wasn&#8217;t too keen on being in the car that long. While not giving away anything truly important, I swore that we wouldn&#8217;t be long until we got there. Well, except for one thing:<br />
I&#8217;d totally forgotten the name of the place we were going.<br />
Thankfully, when the sign came into view, it wasn&#8217;t too hard to realize that we&#8217;d arrived. The cat, as it were, was finally out of the bag.<br />
Room 24 overlooks Bow Lake, facing roughly south. The view is spectacular. They key is big and old, tied to a horseshoe so you don&#8217;t lose it. No fancy electronics here. When we entered the room, we had our Romantic Package waiting for us. In all honesty, I&#8217;d totally forgotten about it. A bottle of champagne and chocolate-covered strawberries all served on a flat rock. Decadent, most certainly.<br />
Being late in the afternoon, we wandered around looking at the natural splendour of the area before going to dinner. One downside were all the bugs. Not mosquitoes, but flies of somekind. Mildly annoying. That and the American tourists who wanted to know about Calgary, yet seemed to &#8220;know&#8221; all the answers. Can&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn &#8217;em&#8230;<br />
Num-Ti-Jah is known for an amazing kitchen. The reputation is well-deserved. The food there is outstanding, if a tad over-priced. (I will freely admit that the Lodge as a whole is expensive. This is not your average stay at a Holiday Inn &#8212; this is on the order of a Fairmont, but at a log-cabin appearance. In all honesty, it&#8217;s worth it. Especially if you&#8217;re there for the nature. If you just want a room, you can go many places that are a lot cheaper. But if you want to hit the trails right after an excellent sleep and a killer breakfast, there isn&#8217;t much better.<br />
Which is pretty much what we did the following morning. Following breakfast, we checked out and packed the car. Tying my car keys to a loop in my pants, we headed off on the 4.5 km trail to Bow Glacier Falls. (As a point of note, bear bells or jingling keys do very little. Bears apparently have no better sense of hearing than humans. So if you think you can hear a bear bell past a couple of hundred metres on a flat plain &#8212; let alone in the forest &#8212; you can imagine how easily you&#8217;d run into a bear. The recommendation is to make a lot of noise. Apparently, that&#8217;s what helps most.<br />
The hike took us about an hour, depositing us at a glacial valley. It&#8217;s bleak, cold, wet, and utterly gorgeous. There&#8217;s just something inspiring about the sheer rawness of an area that has barely any vegetation, where snow probably fills the area metres deep during the winter. Where few humans tread (indeed, we saw only two couples in the area) there is much to be seen.<br />
Returning to the car, we found that a storm was brewing at the south end of the Bow Valley. It seemed that there was a massive storm going over the mountains, probably heading right for Calgary. Indeed, a fair amount of rain and golf ball-sized hail wreaked havoc in the north of Calgary (the south seemed to be spared) later that day.<br />
We ate a bag lunch (courtesy of Num-Ti-Jah) before taking a leisurely drive back to Calgary, managing to avoid getting the Mini hailed on a second time.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603434328282[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Mongolia</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=adventures-in-mongolia</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2005 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mongolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulaan baatar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/25/adventures-in-mongolia/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.) Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Adventures in Mongolia"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.)<br />
Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up that somehow manages to sway us (which I doubt will happen), then Mongolia will be <em>the</em> thing on the trip. Also without question, we would heartily recommend coming to Mongolia (and soon, before the rest of the world discovers how cool this country is) and signing up with Nomadic Journeys. They take far too good care of you.<br />
<span id="more-550"></span>Our campsite was about 300 km west of Ulaan Baatar &#8212; a trip that takes six hours. Most of the roads in Mongolia were built back in the 1950s by the Russians and Chinese &#8230; and haven&#8217;t really received any major attention since then. Needless to say, if you&#8217;re not driving something well-built, you don&#8217;t be driving it too long &#8212; the roads will turn them to pulp. We drove in a small Russian-built jeep without seatbelts. Our driver, Lasaa (assuming I&#8217;m spelling his name correctly) is an expert driver, and avoided the majority of the disasters of the road. That meant driving all over the road, including the shoulders.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03595.JPG" alt="The scenery as you drive in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
It&#8217;s an interesting commentary when the dirt roads that sometimes parallel the highway are better than the highway.<br />
When we arrived at our camp (which appeared rather suddenly), we found three gers, tents used by the Mongolian nomadic people. They&#8217;re wood-framed, built in a circle with a sloped conical roof. The entire frame is covered with felt and canvas. They&#8217;re ridiculously comfy, even in the heat we experienced. Amy and I were the only tourists there &#8212; we&#8217;re the first of the season at that location. There were two nomadic families across the valley.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03596.JPG" alt="Our ger camp" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03597.JPG" alt="Just to prove I was there" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03598.JPG" alt="The all-important toilet; which, thankfully, did not stink" width="300" /></a><br />
The first day there was a laid-back one: hiking up the adjacent mountain (Amy to half-way; I couldn&#8217;t resist the surge to the top). Meals were in the middle ger. The second day took us on a hike north through the valley, passing a family of domesticated camels, and through a mountain pass to a small Buddhist temple on the other side (Lasa met us there to drive us back). The temple has but a single nun (not even a monk, so far as we could tell) and a museum curator, who showed us around. There&#8217;s ruins there from a previous building destroyed when the Soviets ran amok through Mongolia in an attempt to stamp out all religion.<br />
To give you an idea of how unspoiled this place is, when we wandered around the ruins, we found fragments of Buddha statues and artwork still in the dirt. That&#8217;s how few tourists have been here. (Even though there is a &#8220;card shop&#8221;.)<br />
After lunch, we visited a small lake featuring kites, ducks (that sounded like frogs), and horses. Beautiful scenery, too. Then it was a visit over to one of the nomadic families to see how they live. Truth be known, they live pretty well. The gers are so comfortable, most nomadic families choose to live in them instead of permanent shelters. It&#8217;s also necessary as many families have to move (up to four times a year) to keep their herds of animals fed and watered. We petted baby sheep and goats. One tried to milk me by banging it head repeatedly into my groin. I mean, honestly, do I look like a goat?? After dinner, Amy and I dragged Ganaa (our guide/translator) up the side of a sand dune to watch a sunset. We were treated to a rather strange spectacle when we returned as the nomadic family tried to get their herd into a small corral for milking time.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03599.JPG" alt="Down by the bay (but no watermelons grow)" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03601.JPG" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03602.JPG" alt="Inside a nomadic ger" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03603.JPG" alt="Sunset on top of a sand dune" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03606.JPG" alt="Our driver, Lasa, with a baby goat" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03607.JPG" alt="Not nearly as noisy as you think it should have been" width="300" /></a><br />
Our third day marked a trip to Kharakorum and Erdene Zuu, the former being the ancient capital of Mongolia, and the latter being the monastery that still operates there. Three hours on bumpy roads. Beatiful buildings, though. Amazing part of it was that we were among the first tourists there that day &#8212; most of those in attendance were there for the ceremony marking the first 15 days of summer, which was the monks chanting the entire day. The fact we could walk around the museum temples unimpeded by a single tourist was &#8230; very zen.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03608.JPG" alt="The temples of Erdene Zuu" width="300" /></a><br />
The weather on the morning of our fourth day was unbelievable. The wind that had started the night before had given rise to rain, blowing sand (you couldn&#8217;t see the dunes &#8212; a mere kilometre away &#8212; for the clouds erupting from them), and eventually snow as we rolled to Hustai National Park, 95 km from Ulaan Baatar.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03610.JPG" alt="Crappy weather on the road" width="300" /></a><br />
Hustai is a preserve that hosts the only wild population of tahki &#8212; the Mongolian wild horse. It was reintroduced here in the early 1990s, and has grown to over 200 horses in 14 small herds. (That, and an insane number of marmots.) It was freezing as we got our glances at a distance, but they were neat to see. We stayed in Ger #7 at the Hustai Tourist &#8220;Resort&#8221;. (About 20 gers, a couple of permanent buildings, and a &#8220;restaurant&#8221; serving food so lacking in flavour, I&#8217;d describe it as a gastronomic vacuum.)<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03611.JPG" alt="The ger camp at Hustai National Park in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
I woke up about 3:00 this morning in a big shivering ball. Our fire had gone out and the temperatures had plunged. Needless to say, I&#8217;m a little tired as a result. Even once I was more bundled up (and I was beginning to think that long underwear wasn&#8217;t a good idea to bring!), my brain ran crazy with ways of trying to rekindle our dead fire. Note to self: always bring matches in the future when going to places that need fires.<br />
We returned to UB today and made a beeline for the Gobi Factory Store. Gobi is the major manufacturer of cashmere goods, at least in Mongolia. I knew of them before coming, but hadn&#8217;t really thought that this was the place. It really was a factory store, too &#8212; the store was attached to the Gobi factory. Prices were decent, although the place was mobbed by some very unruly and rude French tourists.<br />
The real prize, however, was not the completed fabrics. It was cashmere yarn, which Gobi does <strong>not</strong> sell in their stores. And Amy could not leave Mongolia without it. To get it, Ganaa went through the most amazing display of digging that I&#8217;ve ever seen. It took 90 minutes, including walking deep into the Gobi factory to find the yarn storage room to select the spools, but we walked away with 2.3 kilos of it. Amy&#8217;s happy, to say the least. But I&#8217;ll leave that portion of the story to her. It&#8217;s a doozy.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03614.JPG" alt="Cashmere yarn at the Gobi Factory in Ulaan Baatar" width="300" /></a><br />
After that, we visited the Bogd Khaan&#8217;s Summer Palace in the south part of the city. It&#8217;s nice, but poorly maintained. Some of the treasures inside are wonderful, but it wasn&#8217;t worth the 5500T it cost for me to take pictures (even though that&#8217;s only about US$5). After Erdene Zuu, it was hard to look at the Summer Palace and think it was wonderful.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03615.JPG" alt="The gates of the Bogd Khan's Summer Palace" width="300" /></a><br />
And so we leave Mongolia for China. Our plans have changed a bit, there. We&#8217;re hitting only Beijing, Xi&#8217;an, and Guangzhou (only because it&#8217;s right next to Hong Kong, and after the train from Xi&#8217;an, we won&#8217;t be up to crossing the border right away). Then it&#8217;s into the Hong Kong area, first with Macau, then HK proper. Why the cutting back? Too much running in and out of places has made us weary, and after hearing a few too many horror stories, we&#8217;re not sure that we&#8217;re even going to like China that much. But we shall see&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">550</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs and Kootenay National Park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2004 04:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/02/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s nothing quite like waking up to the sound of lawnmowers. Rousing, yet entirely annoying. We started the day off with a mom saver. This is generally a breakfast meal, though I suppose you could just as easily use a version of one for any meal of the day. The breakfast one we had consists &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs and Kootenay National Park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s nothing quite like waking up to the sound of lawnmowers. Rousing, yet entirely annoying.<br />
We started the day off with a mom saver. This is generally a breakfast meal, though I suppose you could just as easily use a version of one for any meal of the day. The breakfast one we had consists of eggs, cubed bread, cream cheese (cubed, or something similar), some spices, and thrown in the oven to cook for 45 minutes. Throw on some maple syrup on top, and it&#8217;s pretty tasty. There&#8217;s also a ham and cheese version that I&#8217;m dying to try some time.<br />
<span id="more-380"></span>Showered and ready for the day, we decided that we weren&#8217;t heading off anywhere in particular until after lunch. This was a bit of a surprise to me, since we didn&#8217;t finish breakfast until almost 10:00. To wait only a mere two hours before lunch seemed awfully short. But then, Alex seems to have an insane metabolism &#8212; one I can&#8217;t even begin to hope to keep up with.<br />
So instead of heading off to Kootenay National Park for our hike, Alex and I decided to go for a little walk. The Mountain Villas of Fairmont Hot Springs (where Alex&#8217;s parents have a timeshare) are built around the Fairmont Creek, which is the outflow of the hot springs. The creek has been modified a bit over the years, mostly to accommodate the resort, but still flows into the Columbia River.<br />
We hiked over to the creek, not far from the condo, and started to walk up its shore. But the inviting burbling of the creek soon drew us to its side, and in Alex&#8217;s case, into the creek itself. (Had I been walking with my flip-flops, I would have followed Alex in. As I was wearing my hiking shoes, that wasn&#8217;t bloody likely.) We went up the river (and in the river) until I was driven out due to lack of dry walking space. Naturally, this was when Alex lost one of her flip-flops (which she later recovered).<br />
The creek bed isn&#8217;t like a regular creek &#8212; pebbly, with small stones, algae, and fairly free-flowing. This creek had a beige &#8220;liner&#8221; that the water coursed over and around, the result of years of mineral deposits. (It looks like someone poured concrete all along the creek bed to smooth out the bottom.) The minerals caked on tightly to anything and everything. Trees and branches that had fallen into the water were blended in with the creek&#8217;s bed, making it hard to tell where the tree ended and the creek bed began. Rocks in the creek created little pools of water. Being so warm, the pools were very tempting to sit in.<br />
About three-quarters of the way up the creek from where we started, we came to a waterfall. The mineral deposits up above created a chute, causing the water to fall further out into a large pool before cascading down terraces into the creek itself. It was a great place to sit and relax.<br />
Eventually, we found ourselves at the hot springs pool. We stayed only long enough to check out the price and the times before heading back.<br />
We arrived in time for lunch &#8212; leftover macaroni and cheese, with a Greek salad. I find Greek salads to be an interesting anachronism for me: while I love the taste, I can&#8217;t stand either olives or the raw tomatoes found in them. I am very good at eating around things I don&#8217;t like.<br />
Naturally, this preciptated a rather interesting conversation about picky eating habits. I hate olives, raw tomatoes (though I can eat about anything made with cooked tomatoes), sour cream (I&#8217;m sorry, but it&#8217;s *sour* &#8212; that just seems wrong to me), yogourt (I can&#8217;t anything with a &#8216;y&#8217; and a &#8216;g&#8217; in its name, but freeze it and I&#8217;m a happy camper), and I&#8217;m not fond of mushrooms (although as a kid, I used to eat cream of mushroom soup as if my life depended on it). We&#8217;ll forego with the more obvious stuff, like liver&#8230;<br />
Until the beginning of this year, Alex says she was far worse.<br />
Following lunch, Alex, her father, and I all headed out for Kootenay National Park, and the Juniper Trail. This is a fairly short (three kilometre) hike that runs from Highway 93 (just inside the south edge of the park), down into the valley, up the other side, and around over to Radium Hot Springs. You have to hike back to the start of the trail on the highway.<br />
The weather was cool and overcast, with the odd spot of rain. But nothing too serious. It didn&#8217;t take long for Alex to shed her sweatshirt, with Alex&#8217;s dad not far behind. I rolled up my sleeves and unzipped my fleece, but never took it off. I&#8217;m a big fan of regulating temperature, rather than having to rapidly adapt to it.<br />
Along the way, we saw part of a waterfall, mountain goats, a few other brave souls on the trip, the valley seen from the top of the trail (which must be gorgeous on a sunny day), and lots and lots and lots of trees and rocks &#8230; and water.<br />
We headed into Invermere to make a stop at the used bookstore (Alex really needed to see what she could find), and to get food for dinner. I had offered to cook. On the menu tonight was apple walnut-stuff pork loin, garlic mashed potatoes, and grilled asparagus. The loin split part-way through cooking, I didn&#8217;t have beer for the potatoes, and I didn&#8217;t cook all the asparagus. But otherwise, the meal wasn&#8217;t half bad.<br />
I do feel like I&#8217;m trying to show my worth, and this was part of it. Let&#8217;s be honest &#8212; these are Alex&#8217;s parents. I need to prove that I&#8217;m not some yutz. To be honest, I think I&#8217;ve done that, or at least am well on the way, and the meal seems to have been a cap.<br />
Before it was too late, Alex and I made use of the hot springs. The facility is huge, many times larger than Banff&#8217;s springs. It&#8217;s the size of an Olympic swimming pool, divided into three parts. A little over half of it is a general swimming pool, with some lanes so people can can do laps. That section is about 32 degrees (Celcius, of course). There&#8217;s another section with two diving boards, also 32 degrees. Then there&#8217;s the hot section, which varies from about 36 degrees to over 40 degrees, depending on where you sit in the pool.<br />
We arrived at about 21:15, about 45 minutes before the pool closed for the night. It was quite full of patrons, most likely taking advantage of the lowered rate in the last hour of operation. It wasn&#8217;t so full that we couldn&#8217;t get around. We lounged, I even took a dive (although I was very tempted to do a cannonball). We were out of the pool in about half an hour, having had enough heat for one night.<br />
[flickr]tag:fairmonthotsprings+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kootenay+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">380</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
