<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>canada &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/canada/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:30:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>What Canadian politicians have forgotten</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.] Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every three years, on average). And in Alberta, a province &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What Canadian politicians have forgotten"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><em>[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.]</em></p>
<p class="p1">Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every <i>three years</i>, on average). And in <strong>Alberta, a province of wealth and entitlement</strong>, that means the old guard fending off competitors who dare lay siege to the castle, <strong>replete with feces-slinging</strong> (we’re well past mere mud), ethically-laden promises, and scare tactics, from all sides.</p>
<p class="p1">Canada is also heading down the road to a <strong>federal election</strong>, which by schedule we will see this fall. We will likely see <strong>the same slinging and fearmongering</strong>, not only because the same mentalities are at play, but because we’ve been witnessing the preamble for several months, now.</p>
<p class="p1">And all of it has shown one thing: that <strong>our politicians have forgotten about Canadians</strong>.</p>
<p class="p1"><span id="more-3428"></span>The squabbling alone is like <strong>listening to the group of neighbourhood kids fight over a favoured toy</strong>. The younger ones are petulant, the older ones use their physical strength and bully to get their way. Some of the other kids in between ages argue logically, but receive neither support nor a sympathetic ear. All I hear, as the parent who wishes them to sort anything out, is crying, fighting, and threats of tattling to parents.</p>
<p class="p1">The same thing happens in our political landscape, just without the benefit of (somewhat) impartial parents to sort out the mess and restore order. The parents we should have — <strong>the Canadian people</strong>, acting through an election — <strong>have become disillusioned, disaffected, and apathetic</strong>. As a whole, we have stopped caring. And as much as I, and others, have tried to blame this on the Canadian people, the reality is that we cannot blame the people. Individual persons, perhaps, but as a collective, the Canadian people have lost faith in government.</p>
<p class="p1">For a person to care, they <strong>need to feel attachment</strong> to something. To get that attachment, we need three things, in order:</p>
<h2 class="p1">Vision</h2>
<p class="p1">Most important of any politician’s toolbelt should be a concept of what they want to achieve, something that they know their constituents need. Sadly, most politicians fall short into short-term or simple goals: lower taxes (which politicians never lower), more jobs (which politicians don’t control), better education (which politicians take neither accountability nor responsibility), and so forth. <strong>We’ve all heard these promises, every single election.</strong></p>
<p class="p1">These are not visions, <strong>these are <em>tactics</em></strong>. Real vision comes from things that are far more intangible, such as understanding the division between the wealthy and the poor, looking to the health and welfare not of today’s children but those who will come in two generations, looking at how we are truly perceived on a global stage and knowing we could be better, preparing for a world with an ever-expanding population with less space.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Our governments do not offer vision. They offer fear.</strong> Ruling parties tell us we are in danger, so take away the freedoms of the many to benefit the extremely few; they tell us we cannot have sustainable incomes from a consistent tax base, to placate business, they tell us that the present is failing and sacrifice our future. Our opposing parties are no better, instead choosing to define themselves only by how they will reverse ruling party’s efforts, or how they will do things different.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Such actions offer no inspiration, no dreams, no hope.</strong> They serve only to oppress and defeat, leaving Canadians with nothing more than apathy. Without vision, we fall into mere name-calling, and petty arguments. We don’t have anything new to believe in, so we fall back on what we already believe, regardless of how flawed it may be. And we’ll fight to the death to protect those beliefs, because <strong>we’re human, and we loathe others telling us what to believe</strong> in the absence of new thought.</p>
<h2 class="p1">Charisma</h2>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Part of the problem of vision, even when it is available, is an inability to connect with Canadians. While making public appearances, they certainly glad-hand everyone they can find with big, wide smiles … but this is not a connection. After such events, <strong>Canadians will no more relate to a politician as they will to the politician in a sound bite on TV</strong>. We relate better to actors in trashy B-movies than we do the people we’re supposed to trust with our future. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The leader of our nation, Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper, has the <strong>personality of a cardboard cutout</strong>. Hon. Thomas Mulcair, the leader of the official opposition, is <strong>identifiable more by his beard</strong> than anything he has said or done. And our supposed saviour, Hon. Justin Trudeau, scion of Canadian political legend, has somehow managed to turn himself into a bizarre punchline, where lately his <strong>only defining attribute is reverse-parroting</strong> nearly everything the Prime Minister says. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Nevermind our provincial woes: a recently-elected Premier who, starting off with supposedly open eyes, has turned a deaf ear; the official opposition imploded; and <strong>the polls show the province tearing itself down the middle</strong>, with divisions widening daily. There is not a single person who has stepped up within the province to show a new way to think, nothing beyond promises of old that have been broken time and time again. <strong>Not a single party who defines hope</strong>, not a single hope for the change we so desperately need. </span></p>
<p class="p1">Sadly, <strong>our politicians appear to have started to ignore us</strong>. They only truly care when elections are in the wind, for obvious reasons. Otherwise, they&#8217;re more preoccupied with each other, with in-fighting, name-calling, petty one-up-manship, and throwing people under busses (figuratively speaking that is; if that ever turns literal, we&#8217;ll have bigger problems to solve). The net result isn&#8217;t even entertainment, anymore. It&#8217;s irritation.</p>
<p class="p1">Worse still, we <strong>Canadians still end up dividing on ideological lines</strong>, blindly painting ourselves Blue, Red, and Orange because &#8230; well, because that party is how I&#8217;d <em>like</em> to think. But that paint is a two-way street, and <strong>the actions and words of the politicians flows down to the people</strong>, tarnishing the ideal of what that paint was supposed to be, and the Painted People argue about what&#8217;s ideal, despite the reality.</p>
<p class="p1">It’s not like Canada has not seen charismatic, even idiosyncratic politicians before. I&#8217;ll sidestep an obvious one, largely because my province has a ridiculously long memory and a terribly short sight.</p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Instead, I&#8217;ll look to the late <strong>Hon. Jack Layton, who set a benchmark in Canada</strong> for the very things that Canadians were longing for: helping Canadians, not scaring them. He ignored personal attacks, choosing instead to inspire. He made fun of himself on <i>This Hour Has 22 Minutes</i>, engaged Quebecois in their language, and despite a strange police run-in (an unproven but suspected smear campaign), his trustworthiness amongst those polled topped out at 97%. In the following election, the NDP — the “left wing” party, formerly the butt of many political jokes — became the official opposition for the first time in federal politics. When Layton died in August 2011, the nation mourned the loss of <strong>our last great statesman</strong>.</span></p>
<h2 class="p1">Leadership</h2>
<p class="p1">This leads me to the last major problem with our politicians: their inability to lead. They are defined as leaders of their respective parties certainly — they are elected from within the party for that very purpose. That does not, however, necessarily define them as leaders of Canadians.</p>
<p class="p1">Imagine, if you will, a crowd in a large field. A single person steps from the crowd, raises their hand, and promptly marches off in a direction. Some of the crowd will undoubtedly follow, either because they know the person or because they have a like mind. The rest may follow over time, some due to not wishing to remain in the field, some due to the pressure of others leaving. Some will remain, and possibly follow someone else who marches off in a different direction.</p>
<p class="p1">Now imagine that same crowd in a dark tunnel. There are two ways to go, and almost no-one knows the right way. One person, armed with a flashlight, walks ahead to look for dangers: open holes, tripping rocks, unstable walls, and so forth. Nearly all will follow, if just not to be left in the dark.</p>
<p class="p1">These are the <strong>two leadership patterns we see in Canada: follow by choice, or follow by fear</strong>. Both are problematic, though most people, when asked, would prefer the choice. It doesn’t matter whether or not your choice may lead you off a cliff, you just wish to know that you feel right about something. In both cases, <strong>the key missing element is education</strong>. With fear, you’re offering only the downside: follow me, or else. With choice, you’re selling only the benefits: follow me, for I have cookies!</p>
<p class="p1">So what’s best? <strong>Follow by understanding.</strong> Yes, we have cookies, and they are delicious, but some have raisins, and we know they’re not for everyone. Allow people to know what you stand for, why that matters, why you think you’ll make mistakes, where you will draw lines, and how much you’re willing to risk to bring your vision. <strong>A rare politician is one who does not worry immediately about the next election</strong>, but more about the people they represent.</p>
<h2 class="p1">But Where’s the Proof?</h2>
<p class="p1">It took me a long time to realize that we had an example of how it <i>could</i> be done. And, somewhat ironically, it exists in a place we don&#8217;t expect to see greatness: in municipal government. I can look at my own city and see the proof. Calgary is a microcosm of Canada: a right-leaning, multi-cultural, fast-growing city that has, historically, had a lacklustre governing body.</p>
<p class="p1">Until 2012, the general impression of City Council was anything but transparent, ruled largely by old guard red tape, with but a few who fought for real change. Then in 2012, the change happened: a man with a vision of what Calgary could be, that flew in the face of some of that old guard, asked <strong>people to believe not necessarily <em>in</em> him, but <em>with</em> him</strong>. And people could, because he had a personality that was infectious, one that made you <em>want</em> to believe. He followed through, showing people how things could really be done.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Mayor Naheed Nenshi proved to a right-leaning city that had stopped caring, that you <i>could</i> do different.</strong> For his first term, Calgary became a very different place. It felt more energetic, more interesting and vibrant, more passionate. He did so well, that he got reelected. He continues to express his opinions, his vision, his desire for change, and his will to put himself out for public approval.</p>
<p class="p1">Is Mayor Nenshi popular with everyone? Of course he isn’t — he rubs some people badly, and they would love to see him unseated. And, to some degree, Mayor Nenshi doesn’t seem to care. <strong>Opposition is seen as a healthy thing, to foster debate, to find middle grounds, to develop long-lasting solutions.</strong> And despite perceptions of some city councillors working more for corporate interests than their constituents, the City of Calgary functions more like the Canada I knew as a child: with mutual respect, honest debate, and a desire to do Calgarians proud.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>This is what our politicians are missing: pride.</strong> They’ve forgotten how to inspire through vision, engage through charisma, and gain a following through leadership. This Alberta election is a farce, and our next federal election will be like watching poo-flinging monkeys.</p>
<p class="p1">Our only hope is that someone recognizes this, and brings change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Votes don&#039;t split, Justin Trudeau</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 20:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2012/11/votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Trudeau, First off, thank you for putting yourself on the line for leadership of the Liberal Party of Canada. Names notwithstanding, the act is one that is necessarily of self-sacrifice, since the job of leading is often thankless, rarely appreciated for what it delivers, and may very well likely make you age before &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Votes don&#039;t split, Justin Trudeau"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Mr. Trudeau,<br />
First off, thank you for putting yourself on the line for leadership of the Liberal Party of Canada. Names notwithstanding, <strong>the act is one that is necessarily of self-sacrifice</strong>, since the job of leading is often thankless, rarely appreciated for what it delivers, and may very well likely make you age before your time. It is the call of duty that is more admirable, that you would take on a responsibility that <strong>most Canadians would prefer to avoid</strong>. It will be refreshing to have a younger perspective on what has become a party bogged down in its past mistakes, real and perceived, and how that party could be transformed into something more relevant.<br />
It is that relevance of which I am concerned. I am currently sitting in <strong>Calgary Centre, awaiting the outcome of a by-election</strong>. It&#8217;s been an interesting contest, and to some degree, has become even a microcosm of what we&#8217;ve seen across Canada. <strong>The same messages, the same tactics, and the same mistakes.</strong> It will be a turning point, of that I have little doubt, even if (regrettably) the &#8220;status quo&#8221; is maintained &#8212; there are lessons to be learned, here, Mr. Trudeau. And a very important one to which you need to pay very close attention:<br />
<strong>Votes do not &#8220;split&#8221;.</strong><br />
<span id="more-3190"></span><br />
This has been heard for decades in Canada &#8212; I remember this from when you and I were children (we are of the same era): people worried that <strong>unless there was some form of unity</strong>, people would split votes in the wrong place, and <strong>the &#8220;wrong&#8221; side would win an election</strong>. Indeed, with the way our electoral system works, association to a &#8220;right&#8221; or &#8220;left&#8221; tends to lead to a &#8220;right&#8221; victory, merely due to lack of options; the &#8220;left&#8221; necessarily loses due to dilution.<br />
And here we arrive at the abhorrent use of &#8220;splitting votes&#8221;, which I&#8217;ve heard far too many times over the last few weeks. And nearly every single one of these utterances seemed to come from the Liberal candidate. He has been using <strong>fear as his tactic</strong>, to convince potential voters in Calgary Centre that if they didn&#8217;t vote for him, that the Converative would win (effectively) by default. <strong>If this is the sign of the Liberal strategy</strong> to come, Mr. Trudeau, then do yourself a favour and <strong>please step down</strong>. The Trudeau name has stood for far greater things than that, and it does not need to be sullied by pedantic schoolyard wailing.<br />
<em>Votes do not split</em>, Mr. Trudeau. You know this to be true. If you fear a split vote, what you are really fearing is that <strong>no-one comprehends your political platform</strong>, that your message is not understood or not liked, and that you are failing to inspire people to listen. The only outcome of such lack of clarity and focus is a lack of support. <strong>Unity does not come from saying that other options are worse</strong> than your own mess of a statement.<br />
Far too often, journalists and politicians alike shoehorn Canadians into either the &#8220;left&#8221; or the &#8220;right&#8221; sides when it comes to politics, to the detriment of reason. Reason &#8212; and history &#8212; state that we <strong>Canadians believe in people and ideas</strong>, that given a strong leader, we will gladly follow. This has happened since the days of Confederation, and has happened ever since. It is when <strong>we <em>lack</em> a strong leader</strong> that we founder, and allow fear to make our decisions for us.<br />
<strong>You remember Mr. Layton.</strong> He may very well be remembered for more than a generation for a single election, a singular point in Canadian political history when he side-stepped fear, and instead did something that no other political has dared attempt in a very long time: <strong>he made us dream</strong>. He made us smile at the thought of hope. And then he made us want it so badly that <em>tens of thousands</em> of Canadians &#8212; myself included &#8212; voted differently than we had before. He went beyond the name-calling and past the mudslinging, and went directly to the people and asked them to think of a Canada that we&#8217;ve <em>all</em> been longing to see again, one we&#8217;ve thought lost. <strong>Losing Mr. Layton has turned out to be a tremendous tragedy for Canada</strong>, for we lost our path to that future, and are again struggling in the dark.<br />
So what say you, Mr. Trudeau? Will you follow the same steps, dancing to the same tune? Or <strong>will you dare to sing of higher standards</strong>? Will you take your party into the future by making Canadians want to believe? Will you inspire them to feel civic duty again, get out of their homes and vote? Will you <strong>restore a belief in our nation</strong> that is not challenged by Federal draconianism, where Canadians come before corporations, and we do not fear for our children&#8217;s future?<br />
So why you? <strong>Why not say this openly to all of our political leaders?</strong> To all the candidates of the Liberal leadership? If they choose to listen, we will all be better for it, but it&#8217;s been clear that few would. <strong>They continue to use fear to isolate</strong>, not encourage. This is why Mr. Layton&#8217;s message was so well-received &#8212; <strong>we&#8217;re tired of the isolation</strong>, and we want to live together as a nation.<br />
I&#8217;ve chosen you because of your background, not just as the son of a former Prime Minister, but one who has experienced the youth programmes, the political and ideological differences (let alone lingua franca), has lived the life of a politician for a few years and still retains <strong>the burning fire to do better</strong>. That&#8217;s the same burning desire we all need to feel. You have presence in parliament, Canadian politics, and &#8212; especially &#8212; of mind. Someone who is recognized by many, and <strong>a voice that can be heard in the dark</strong>.<br />
The Liberal party stands as perhaps the only party than can effectively bridge the &#8220;left&#8221; and &#8220;right&#8221; sides of our country, <strong>avoiding the extremism that comes from both sides</strong>. Conservative elements distrustful of perceived rampant social spending, Progressives terrified of living in a gestapo nation. A message of hope from the centre will succeed, but <strong>the centre needs to have hope</strong>. And all we see right now is the fear of division.<br />
<strong>Hope eradicates fear.</strong> It gives us reason to rise in the morning, helps us look beyond our troubling present to see future solutions, allows us to believe in something that goes beyond ourselves. We need to hope that there is something better, something more meaningful.<br />
You stepped to the podium, Mr. Trudeau. <strong>I hope you have something worth hearing.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/votes-dont-split-justin-trudeau/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3190</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada&#039;s Two Political Parties: Conservative, and Other</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 20:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Federal election time here in Canada. Which means it&#8217;s a fast-and-furious stream of incoherent messaging all tantamount to white noise as the various political figures attempt to sway Canadian passions (which are, at best, as politically frigid as Winnipeg in February). Adding to all of this are, new to this run, a number of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada&#039;s Two Political Parties: Conservative, and Other"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Federal election time here in Canada. Which means it&#8217;s a fast-and-furious stream of incoherent messaging all tantamount to white noise as the various political figures attempt to sway Canadian passions (which are, at best, as politically frigid as Winnipeg in February).<br />
Adding to all of this are, new to this run, a number of social media-style services all helping to add &#8220;information&#8221; (and likely being more like more noise to the signal) to help people align themselves with the political party of choice. I came across one, recently, and suddenly realised that despite the fact we have five major political parties vying for seats, they&#8217;re really only divided two ways.<br />
Which means you either vote Conservative, or you don&#8217;t.<br />
<span id="more-2925"></span>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not advocating voting Conservative. Frankly, I have serious misgivings of how they&#8217;ve been running things the last few years, and I would very much like them deposed from the throne. The reason I say you either vote one way or the other really boils down to a graphic presented by the <a href="http://csdc-cecd.mcgill.ca/">Centre for the Study of Democratic Citizenship at McGill University</a>, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canadavotes">CBC</a>/<a href="http://elections.radio-canada.ca/">Radio Canada</a>, and the <a href="http://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/~socsci/">Department of Social Sciences at the University of Toronto</a>.<br />
It&#8217;s part of a service they created called <a href="http://federal.votecompass.ca/">Vote Compass</a>, and it strives to help people understand our political parties. It&#8217;s important, because some of the parties are awfully darn hard to differentiate in a meaningful way. With some of the issues, it&#8217;s quite easy to see which party you should look towards. But with others, it&#8217;s more like splitting hairs. That&#8217;s why the service ends up providing 35 questions (30 general ones, 3 regarding the parties&#8217; leaders, and 2 about the parties themselves), which ultimately determine what your best political party would be.<br />
And that&#8217;s really the key thing &#8212; your local candidate, regardless of how awesome they are, ultimately contributes a seat to the overall picture, allowing a party to rule. Your individual candidate, unless they become a Cabinet Minister, is little more than a hand raised during votes and can only hope to offer changes via private member&#8217;s bills. Remember, your party has already chosen its leader, and the one leading the winning party automatically becomes prime minister. (On a cynical note, I also strongly believe that anyone voting Conservative is therefore directly a supporter of Stephen Harper.)<br />
At the end of your questions, Vote Compass produces &#8230; well, a compass, showing you which way you lean, politically-speaking. Mine (currently) looks like this:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Vote-Compass.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2928" title="Vote-Compass" src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Vote-Compass.jpg" alt="" width="471" height="471" /></a><br />
(The checkmark is me, incidentally. Yes, I&#8217;m socialist. I believe very strongly in Canada&#8217;s history of helping others, including ourselves.)<br />
See the split? See how the Conservatives are in one corner, and the other four parties are up in the other? (Given, the Liberals are much more centre, but still&#8230;) This is what I mean by &#8220;you&#8217;re either voting Conservative, or you&#8217;re not&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;But,&#8221; you say, &#8220;that&#8217;s not true! I vote for my non-Conservative party! What&#8217;s wrong with that?&#8221;<br />
Allow me to rephrase my point slightly, then. You either cast a vote for the Conservatives, or you cast your vote against them into a <em>diluted</em> pool.<br />
This has also been my primary gripe with the &#8220;ABC&#8221; campaign (&#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anything_But_Conservative">Anyone/Anything But Conservative</a>&#8220;) that has been popular in parts of Canada since the 2008 federal election. Sure, don&#8217;t vote Conservative &#8230; but now you&#8217;re spreading out a vote amongst (up to) four other parties, reducing the potential power of those votes so much that&#8230;<br />
&#8230;drum roll, please&#8230;<br />
&#8230;you end up with <strong>minority governments</strong>. Two of them so far, as a matter of fact, and from what I&#8217;ve seen, we&#8217;re likely looking at a third. Which means another call for a coalition government, which will likely be nearly as useless with all the in-fighting.<br />
This is one of those few times when I look to the American two-party system and admire its simplicity. You go one way or the other. (&#8216;Course, really, they&#8217;re all the same, just one tends to more open and honest about liking guns than the other.)<br />
What I would like is for one of the other four parties to stand out from the others, and really make themselves out to be a strong contender to the Conservatives. Although the NDP seems to be gaining some serious ground this time out, they&#8217;ll have to do something about the Prairies if they hope to make a serious run. Which, really, leaves the Liberals who don&#8217;t look to have recovered from Chrétien&#8217;s era (nor show any signs of such).<br />
Or better still, have organisations/movements like ABC pick a party. Just one. Please. The message should be &#8220;don&#8217;t vote Conservative, vote for &#8230;&#8221; so long as it&#8217;s focused. Lack of focus equals lack of success. That&#8217;s about as simple a rule as it gets, however it gets applied: in school, in business, how my kids clean up their toys. Focus, please.<br />
T minus 9 days. I actually fear for my country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2925</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suggestions to our political &#034;leaders&#034;</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=suggestions-to-our-political-leaders</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 04:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re barely a week into the 2011 Canadian Federal election, and it already feels like a month. I suppose if there&#8217;s one good thing about elections up here, it&#8217;s that they&#8217;re short &#8212; none of this near-two year campaigning that goes on south of the border. Already, the various political parties are &#8230; well, failing. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Suggestions to our political &#34;leaders&#34;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re barely a week into the 2011 Canadian Federal election, and it already feels like a month. I suppose if there&#8217;s one good thing about elections up here, it&#8217;s that they&#8217;re short &#8212; none of this near-two year campaigning that goes on south of the border.<br />
Already, the various political parties are &#8230; well, failing. I&#8217;m rather stunned how fast that happened, actually. You&#8217;d think they&#8217;d actually try to get out a message first, but they stooped to mud-slinging pretty much out of the gate. Yeah, real positive way to foster respect and attract voters, folks&#8230;<br />
So I feel that, as a Canadian with some significant sense of civic duty (and certainly more than enough know-it-all-ism), I need to offer up some suggestions to our so-called &#8220;leaders&#8221; (read: I choose not to lay insults as they are neither interesting nor constructive) if they have any hope of inspiring Canadians to vote for them &#8230; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/">if at all</a>.<br />
<span id="more-2897"></span>Let&#8217;s start with the <a href="http://www.ndp.ca/">New Democratic Party</a>&#8230;<br />
So far, to be honest, I haven&#8217;t heard much out of you. Not here in the west, anyway. Yes, you need to acknowledge that we exist. Hate to break it to you, but if you have any hope of beating out either the Conservatives or the Liberals for a seat, you need to be <em>seen</em>. Guess whose ads I&#8217;ve yet to see plastered all over TV? I had to Google them, Jack. That required action: a <em>vested interest</em>. You want an audience? You&#8217;ll need to go <em>to</em> them. Maybe all the pick-up trucks scare you off? I don&#8217;t know. But I do know this: First basic rule of marketing &#8212; unless you&#8217;re highly visible, you won&#8217;t be remembered.<br />
Checking out your website is kind of informational, but you&#8217;re stooping to attacking your opponents right away. Your message? A little hard to see past the oh-so-thinly veiled attack on Ignatieff. (Look, if you want to question something he may or may not have done, get some facts. Nothing kills off a campaign run like a damn good scandal. A mere question will go unanswered, and will not sway <em>anyone</em>.)<br />
And the bit about more doctors and nurses? Hey, great, that&#8217;s awesome! What about the people who support the doctors and nurses? What about the hospitals for them to work in? And can you provide the details on how you&#8217;re going to prevent new grads from going elsewhere (like the States)? A few details will help prove that these are more than words. Remember, most Canadians will not shlep down to the local candidate to have a discussion. The internet will help, but only if your message is complete enough to convince someone beyond a simple belief.<br />
And for the love of pete, can someone in your IT group make sure that your website works for both &#8220;ndp.ca&#8221; and &#8220;www.ndp.ca&#8221;? That&#8217;s a pretty low bar, and you&#8217;re tripping over it&#8230;<br />
Next up, the <a href="http://www.liberal.ca/">Liberals</a>.<br />
Iggy, can you actually go a day without saying the word &#8220;Harper&#8221;?  I don&#8217;t think you can. I&#8217;m actually beginning to fear that you have no actual message at all, other than to oppose the Conservatives. I&#8217;m not kidding &#8212; <a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=site%3Awww.liberal.ca+harper">on your website alone, there are over 6,400 mentions of &#8220;Harper&#8221;</a>! Exactly <em>whose</em> side are you on?<br />
You talk about Accountability on your website. How about some examples? Goodness knows that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Harper">your BFF</a> has offered you countless examples upon which you can found your statements. But despite being the only party willing to post your policy points &#8212; you skimp over the details like a cheap restaurant that uses watered down tomato sauce and passes it off as pasta al fresco.<br />
Or how about your digital policy? You offer up a mere <em>three paragraphs</em>, and nothing else? Have you not paid a single shred of attention to all the C-32 and UBB nonsense? Might I remind the lauded Liberals that there are many Canadians who have a <strong>very vested interest</strong> in what plans you say you have, and would likely keenly vote if they made sense. <em>Cough, cough.</em> You might also want to <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Hicock2010/cprs-part-2-nenshi-campaign">chat with Mr. Nenshi&#8230;</a><br />
Here&#8217;s a free I&#8217;ll throw you: &#8220;a Liberal government will not allow corporations and/or regulatory agencies to restrict Canadians access to critical resources through uninformed and/or falsified statements regarding resource use, either as a result of profit or security&#8221; as a broad statement, backed up by a list of proposed bills you intend to introduce to Parliament in your first 100 days. Just saying.<br />
Oh, and Iggy, if your party is going to hold up Laurier, Pearson, and Trudeau as the models for Liberal leadership, you might want to consider <em>finding your own identity</em> so we can pick you out of the noise.<br />
As for the <a href="http://www.conservative.ca/">Conservatives</a>&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve seen <a href="http://www.conservative.ca/multimedia/our_tv_ads/">your ads</a>. They&#8217;re wonderful, truly. They&#8217;re masterful of propagating the fear that right-leaning political groups love to instill in the populace. There&#8217;s nothing quite like creating an identity of evil for you to gain trust. (Hey, it worked in the church &#8212; nothing like the Devil to steer you straight, right?)<br />
Here&#8217;s a thought: you&#8217;ve gone two elections without winning a majority. (With me so far? Good.) See a problem? Here&#8217;s a hint: it&#8217;s not that you didn&#8217;t win a majority. Let me spell it out: your tactics haven&#8217;t changed &#8212; it&#8217;s still about fear. The way I see it, you&#8217;re not going to get much further, as you&#8217;ve scared all you can. It might have worked a couple of years ago when the economy was going through the grinder, but since we&#8217;re on the recovery and things are generally looking decent &#8230; well, you haven&#8217;t really got much, do you? Another problem: highly-educated people tend not to frighten easily. You want the rest of us to vote for you? You&#8217;d better come up with <strong>something more <em>intelligent</em></strong> than mere propaganda.<br />
Speaking of which, I went to your website to look for what you&#8217;re bringing to the table. The only thing under &#8220;Policy&#8221;? The 2011 Budget. That&#8217;s your policy? Nothing about Aboriginal rights? Nothing about the Environment? Not even Corporation support (which, we know, you do so very, very well)? You&#8217;re not really offering much, here. Your tax cuts aren&#8217;t offering much, either, since they don&#8217;t really fit the bill of Canadians&#8217; needs. Yes, we do need more doctors &#8230; but we don&#8217;t need billion-dollar warplanes. <em>Subtle hint.</em><br />
Yes, I know I&#8217;m missing out on the other parties out there: The Bloc Québécois (hint: give a crap about just one person not from Quebec), The Green Party (you need to distance yourself a bit more from the granola crowd), and a retinue of other parties &#8212; all of whom have a ways yet to go. All have a similar problem: appealing to the masses. Canadians, as a whole, are generally accepting, but historically-speaking, generally only vote for Conservative (right) or Liberal (centre). You don&#8217;t fit into those mentalities, you&#8217;re effectively fringe, at least at the federal level.<br />
So, to those who are leading the charge into our electoral fray, can we please dispense with the bull? Can we drop the mud, please, and actually have a real dialogue? It would be nice to know that there is more to our political system than mere bitching.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2897</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Believe</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-believe</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Canada, I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I Believe"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Canada,<br />
I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter Olympics (having lived there a couple of years, I know how finicky the weather can be).<br />
And I wasn&#8217;t alone. Thanks to media mainstays, such as The Guardian and the Denver Post, and CTV&#8217;s frequently slipshod and amateurish approach, there was little reason for me to think otherwise.<br />
I find myself, now at the end, relieved to be wrong, and fiercely proud to be a repatriated Canadian.<br />
<span id="more-2626"></span>The <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/">Own The Podium</a> program had me enraged. It was meant to increase the chances of medal wins &#8212; to the point where we had the most medals. Not only was it arrogance beyond our Canadian norm, I found that the program sponsored only those who were in medal contention &#8212; and abandoned the rest. Considering we&#8217;re a socialist country, it seems a very un-Canadian setup. (And can someone tell me, please, why on earth the <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/Funding/detailsw.aspx?id=8">Men&#8217;s Hockey team received Own The Podium funding</a>? It just seems odd to support millionaires who already have significant amounts of training and coaching resources.)<br />
Then came the the death of Georgian luger Nodar Kumaritashvili mere hours before the cauldron was lit.  (And no, Tom Clark, CTV <em>did not need</em> to show footage of the fatal run to &#8220;tell the full story&#8221;. That was utter <em>pandering</em> to sensationalist news coverage. You want to be better than CBC? You&#8217;d better <em>act</em> like you are, first.) The pall cast over the opening felt almost suffocating.<br />
The opening ceremonies themselves were filled with a host of flubs: lip syncing (seriously, we are unable to trust our biggest performers to perform in public?), slight delays (starting even with the snowboarder not coming down on cue), and mechanical failures (erectile dysfunction, anyone?). Problems seemed to continue past the hutzpah, with broken ice resurfacing machines, and an ill-timed rampage by ill-tempted and extremely short-sighted rioters. The press ate us alive.<br />
Our lauded best, held on pedestals for months, were put to the test. But the gold we were promised didn&#8217;t come. Our speedskaters failed to place, and our former moguls world champion could only garner a silver. And admit it, Canada, for a little while, you doubted, too. Had we put too much pressure on our athletes? Did we expect too much? Maybe where I failed was not to recognise it as a beginning of something bigger.<br />
The next day &#8212; less than 24 hours after our first disappointment &#8212; things started to change. Someone I&#8217;d never heard of, suddenly appeared on top. After almost 34 years of waiting, Alexandre Bilodeau had won Canada&#8217;s first gold medal at home. For a moment, the country stood and cheered! We would walk away with something, at least. We would feel like we&#8217;ve achieved. Maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; it was enough to take away our collective dread. Or at least mine.<br />
But the medals were still slow to come. It was two days before another gold from Maelle Ricker. Five days into the games, we had a mere five medals. Our hubris was an embarrassment. Our medals, though appreciated, would stand more as an example of an effort not carried to fruition.<br />
And then something happened that we didn&#8217;t expect. It caught me by surprise, as I know it caught many others. A word that is rarely used in Canada, because of the imagery of our neighbours to the south that it usually invokes: Patriotism. Not a fevered adherence to dogma, but a feeling of national pride the likes of which have not been since I was barely two months old. We all suddenly noticed that you can&#8217;t spell &#8220;Canada&#8221; without &#8220;can&#8221;. And we did.<br />
For me, it was the evening of the men&#8217;s skeleton finals, 19 February. Canada had already won another gold in speed skating, but it was Jon Montgomery&#8217;s victory that seemed to spark something in me. He is not your typical Canadian &#8212; he is brasher, bolder, more outspoken, and not afraid to do things in public that the rest of us would feel the urge to poo-poo as &#8220;not proper&#8221;. His primal scream of victory was the first cry, followed shortly after by a tremendous leap to the top of the podium at the sliding centre; he carried the entire nation with him in that moment. This time, I didn&#8217;t look back down. I &#8212; like you, Canada &#8212; looked forward.<br />
I started to believe.<br />
(And yes, I even started to like that &#8220;<em>I Believe</em>&#8221; song. Probably because after watching enough coverage, you don&#8217;t really have much choice.)<br />
We started the second week with seven medals. Forecasts still placed us well into the 20s. Even with all of our victories in preliminary curling and hockey, it just didn&#8217;t seem possible. But funny thing about believing &#8212; you worry less about failing, and you don&#8217;t want to get left behind.<br />
Our games started with difficult stories:  the disappointment of silver, the struggle in speed skating, and seemingly random disqualifications. The stories had changed. The commentators seemed to take on the energy not just of the crowds, but of the athletes themselves. The stories covered the brotherly dedication, the triumphant (and periodically beer-fuelled) victory marches, impromptu parades, double medals, first wins in new sports, and the sweetheart skaters who not only stole the gold but also the hearts of millions.<br />
But no story could exceed that of Joannie Rochette.<br />
I&#8217;m no figure skater &#8212; I can&#8217;t even skate, really. Growing up, though, I watched a lot of figure skating as a result of watching TV with my mom, a former skater herself, and still an adamant lover of the sport. So, in some small way, I am periodically attracted to it. It was with great fortune that I caught her performance, only days after learning her mother had suddenly died.<br />
I couldn&#8217;t tell you how well she actually skated &#8212; I&#8217;m no judge &#8212; but I can tell you that on that night, Joannie embodied the strength and courage of an Olympian, producing her best possible performance, allowing herself tears only after she was done, to the sound of a thunderous standing ovation. Her medal may have only been a bronze, but as a local paper emblazoned on its headline: it was as good as gold to us.<br />
Most of us Canadians never made it to the games, though I know more than a few who were there, who witnessed gold first-hand. The closest I ever got was my home in southwest Calgary, where I subjected my family to my growing obsession, cheering on my country in its quest for gold, to the point where Alex and I taught the Monkey to chant: &#8220;CA-NA-DA!&#8221; as loudly as she could. We all watched, we all cheered, we all hoped, and we all cried.<br />
And we achieved. We achieved records the likes of which exceeded our expectations. Even with Own The Podium&#8217;s lofty goals, most of us never expected to set a record for the most number of gold medals won in a Winter Olympics. We might not have owned the entire podium, but we took the step that mattered the most to us: the top.<br />
The top was capped with our national games: curling and hockey. Men&#8217;s curling gold, a three-time victory for the women&#8217;s hockey team, and a rematch against our oldest nemesis, the United States. It was joked many times by many people that the men&#8217;s hockey final would effectively close the entire country for the three hours the game would be played. I suspect the joke was not far off. The game would prove to be something special, especially to those born after the early 1970s &#8212; it would become my generation&#8217;s Summit Series, the game that we watched with extreme anticipation, desperately wanting that gold back in our hands.<br />
Vancouver did something to Canada that few would have predicted, even with our previous experience with Calgary and Montreal. For a few weeks,  Vancouver brought together our country &#8212; six timezones and a hugely diverse culture (yes, Canada, we are not just one group; we thrive in our multiculturalism, even if we can&#8217;t always recognise it). Not just in representation, but in anticipation and celebration.  We broke out of our Canadian mould &#8212; we stopped thinking we&#8217;d stop short, that we&#8217;d choke right at the key moments &#8212; and we started to live the dream.<br />
The media has suggested that maybe we&#8217;ll break out from our mould permanently, and be more like our cousins to the south. But we won&#8217;t. That&#8217;s not us. That&#8217;s not <em>Canadian</em>. These games are over, and we&#8217;ll return to our Canadian ways. But we won&#8217;t shrink away, we won&#8217;t forget what happened. We&#8217;ve gotten stronger; we&#8217;ve learned. We&#8217;ve learned how to perform, that success isn&#8217;t just a dream &#8212; it&#8217;s a reality. That we can compete head-to-head with the best the world has to show us, and not be just &#8220;that nice country&#8221;. We&#8217;re now <em>that</em> country: a tough competitor, a fierce opponent. The ones everyone else has to beat.<br />
And it would be nice if we could get our legends back. Mr. Orser, are there not Canadians you can train? Can our curling coaches consider teaching our up-and-comers, rather than guide our competitors? And can we please treat all our athletes with some form of equality? If nothing else, these games proved that underdogs can achieve what no-one expects.<br />
We&#8217;ll freely admit we had things that didn&#8217;t go perfectly. Massive events aren&#8217;t perfect &#8212; the best you can hope for is to mitigate the troubles. So, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14414668">yes Mr. Kiszla, we had a few problems</a> &#8212; I assure you that your lauded Denver games will have their own headaches that will made you cringe. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2010/feb/15/vancouver-winter-olympics-2010">And Mr. Donegan? I&#8217;ve heard better whining</a> from my two-year old when her cereal ends up a bit soggy. Rather than suggesting you return to the golf courses you seem to understand so much better, I suggest you join London&#8217;s Olympic Committee and become personally responsible for London&#8217;s success. Because we&#8217;ll be watching. Closely.<br />
Oh, and one more thing, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14398658">Mr. Kiszla, about the trash talk</a>? After listening to American bragging for so long, you have no idea how wonderful it is to say: <a href="http://media3.hockeycanada.ca/digital_asset/7/1/6/6/3/image_17ee18aea2c8fd14b8ba92026a8b7525.jpg?cache=305395">It&#8217;s still our game</a>. I believe it will remain that way for a long time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking a pet from Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 20:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It figures, just when we thought we&#8217;d started to have everything figured out, we hit another snag. (There&#8217;s always another snag.) This time, it&#8217;s with Asia, our cat. Our problem is not with Canada &#8212; all they need is a valid rabies vaccination, which we have. Our problem is not our airline (Continental) &#8212; we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Taking a pet from Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It figures, just when we thought we&#8217;d started to have everything figured out, we hit another snag. (There&#8217;s always another snag.) This time, it&#8217;s with Asia, our cat.<br />
Our problem is not with Canada &#8212; all they need is a valid rabies vaccination, which we have. Our problem is not our airline (Continental) &#8212; we already have a reservation that allows us to take our cat. Our problem is with Costa Rica.<br />
I&#8217;m so not surprised.<br />
<span id="more-2243"></span>It hit us about a week or so ago that merely leaving the country with Asia wasn&#8217;t just a matter of having the airline say a pet was okay. There was the matter if we had documentation saying that she was okay. Wendy, our super-awesome travel agent, managed to find out that Continental needed a letter from a vet saying that Asia was fit to fly. No biggie.<br />
So Alex trucked over to the veterinarian (conveniently located at the front of our condo complex) to get that sorted out. That&#8217;s when the complications came in. It wasn&#8217;t just as simple as a letter from the vet. Oh, no, that would be too easy. How quickly we forgot how much Costa Rica loves its bureaucracy!  (Keep in mind that it took us over a year to get our temporary residency.)<br />
No, to leave Costa Rica means that we need to have an export permit to take Asia. Export. Like she&#8217;s a Costa Rican product or something. This isn&#8217;t quite as bad as the fact that we also had to get a similar legal document so we could leave with our two year-old daughter! (That one has me at a level of disbelief that I can&#8217;t even fathom.)<br />
[Insert rising panic here.]<br />
This is not something you want to discover with a mere 11 days (now 10) remaining until you leave. Down here, things never happen quickly, and the word &#8220;urgent&#8221; (as spoken by a North American) never translates well.<br />
Alex got the vet started on getting us a certificate, which could take &#8212; and I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; a week. This could get uuuuugly. We don&#8217;t have the luxury of delaying even a single day going home. We have too many things lined up to start the morning after we arrive, and the balls are already well in motion. I&#8217;m not saying we&#8217;re going to abandon Asia here (we&#8217;re not, just to make that abundantly clear), but it&#8217;s not going to make me in any way happy if things don&#8217;t go according to plan.<br />
We even went through calling 10 different hotels before we could find one that would allow pets of any kind. That&#8217;s enough of an annoying snag. This current one is borderline catastrophic. (CATastrophic. Cat. Get it? Ha!)<br />
I hate moving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadian citizenship questions are kinda funny</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/canadian-citizenship-questions-are-kinda-funny/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canadian-citizenship-questions-are-kinda-funny</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/canadian-citizenship-questions-are-kinda-funny/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 22:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My friend Julia is getting ready to have her Canadian Citizenship test, as she&#8217;s tired of being merely a Permanent Resident, and now apparently wants to have more say in these taxes she&#8217;s been paying. To that end, she&#8217;s received and is now reviewing the requisite materials for the test. (I offer you the list &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/canadian-citizenship-questions-are-kinda-funny/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canadian citizenship questions are kinda funny"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My friend Julia is getting ready to have her Canadian Citizenship test, as she&#8217;s tired of being merely a Permanent Resident, and now apparently wants to have more say in these taxes she&#8217;s been paying.<br />
To that end, she&#8217;s received and is now reviewing the requisite materials for the test. (I offer you <a href="http://docs.google.com/Doc?docid=0AdMNaHmNLgy9ZGRwYnBocTNfMzBjN3pmdmJjYw&amp;hl=en">the list of questions she gave to me</a>, unaltered, as a starting point.) As one might expect, the test has a number of questions that, yes, an average born-and-raised-in-Canada Canadian would flunk. (I would imagine the same is true of most countries.) Some of these are taken for granted, as just about everyone just accepts things as they are.<br />
But some of these questions are &#8230; well, let&#8217;s say that they just scream for alternative answers.<br />
<span id="more-1471"></span>I&#8217;m not going to put up every question because some of them are just darn obvious. Or otherwise boring, and have no particularly interesting answers. Again, if you want to see the original list, follow the above link. As for the answers, well, this is my take on them. So if you&#8217;re actually studying for the Canadian citizenship test, please, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada">for the love of the maple leaf, read Wikipedia</a>.</p>
<ol>
<li>Who are the Aboriginal peoples of Canada?<br />
Joe, Marge, Fred, Little Tom, Kinney, and Wilma.</li>
<li>Why are the Aboriginal peoples of Canada working toward self-government?<br />
If you&#8217;ve got the opportunity to not have to deal with the federal government, wouldn&#8217;t you?</li>
<li>Where did the first European settlers in Canada come from?<br />
Um&#8230; Europe?</li>
<li>Why did the early explorers first come to Atlantic Canada?<br />
Well, it was pretty bloody hard to go to Pacific Canada,   wasn&#8217;t it?</li>
<li>What three industries helped the early settlers build communities in the Atlantic region?<br />
Wal-Mart, McDonald&#8217;s, and Tim Horton&#8217;s.</li>
<li>Who were the United Empire Loyalists?<br />
A British football team.</li>
<li>What form of transportation did Aboriginal peoples and fur traders use to create trading networks in North America?<br />
<a href="http://www.ski-doo.com/">The ski-doo.</a></li>
<li>What important trade did the Hudsonâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s Bay Company control?<br />
Hockey cards.</li>
<li>What did the government do to make immigration to western Canada much easier?<br />
Made living in eastern Canada so unbearable that everyone fled west.</li>
<li>What is the Canadian Constitution?<br />
A piece of paper.</li>
<li>Which was the last province to join Canada?<br />
Newfoundland. (And while this is the truthful answer, it&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.newfiejokes.net/">newfie joke</a> all onto its own.)</li>
<li>Name two fundamental freedoms protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms.<br />
The right to bitch about the government and the right to apologise to anyone for no particular reason.</li>
<li>List three ways in which you can protect the environment.<br />
Again, a bit of a serious response &#8212; &#8216;cuz, yes, this is an actual question. I think it&#8217;s actually a survey question, because the federal government in Canada clearly doesn&#8217;t know how to do this themselves.</li>
<li>What are the two official languages of Canada?<br />
English, and French spoken really poorly by English-speakers.</li>
<li>What does the Canadian flag look like?<br />
<a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=canadian+flag+joke">Must. Hold. Back. Obvious. Joke.</a></li>
<li>What song is Canadaâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s national anthem?<br />
Duh! The <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ByKu8BwT5K4">theme to Hockey Night In Canada</a>!</li>
<li>Which animal is an official symbol of Canada?<br />
Okay, another serious one. The beaver. Seriously. How can you not love a country where it&#8217;s national symbol is the <em>beaver</em>. Ahem.</li>
<li>Where are the Great Lakes?<br />
Probably where you last left them.</li>
<li>Which country borders Canada on the south?<br />
Um. China? (Is this to trip up Americans applying for citizenship?)</li>
<li>What are the three main types of industries in Canada?<br />
Beer, hockey, and donuts.</li>
<li>In what industry do most Canadians work?<br />
Based on the NHL players, it&#8217;s definitely ice-related.</li>
<li>What is Canadaâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s system of government called?<br />
According to my dad, it&#8217;s &#8220;A Fucking Mess&#8221;.</li>
<li>What are the three parts of Parliament?<br />
&#8220;Goofy&#8221;, &#8220;Dopey&#8221;, and &#8220;Sleepy&#8221; come to mind&#8230; (On a serious note: Hey Canucks, did you know there were <em>three</em>?)</li>
<li>Explain how the levels of government are different.<br />
Well, all they tend not to do much. After that, it&#8217;s kinda dicey&#8230;</li>
<li>What do you call a law before it is passed?<br />
A joke.</li>
<li>How are members of Parliament chosen?<br />
Usually it&#8217;s the only person left after everyone else says: &#8220;I don&#8217;t wanna do it!&#8221;</li>
<li>Who do members of Parliament represent?<br />
Cynical answer: Themselves.</li>
<li>What is the government of all of Canada called?<br />
See #22.</li>
<li>How many electoral districts are there in Canada?<br />
Again, kinda serious&#8230; Are you fucking kidding me? Even the CBC doesn&#8217;t know this and has to look it up. I just laughed when I first heard this. Seriously? You want me to know this?</li>
<li>What three requirements must you meet in order to vote in a federal election?<br />
a) Be alive, b) not be totally drunk, and c) be ready to start bitching about the changes</li>
<li>What is written on a federal election ballot?<br />
Kinda like the electoral districts question, I was surprised by this one. I honestly have no idea, beyond the list of names of the people I&#8217;m supposed to choose from. Which, when you think about it, ain&#8217;t a lot of information to go on.<br />
Man, elections are kinda dumb.</li>
<li>What do political parties do?<br />
Again, I think this is a survey, because the government must be looking for suggestions on this one.</li>
<li>Which federal political party is in power?<br />
Funny, but somewhat true &#8212; right now, none. Minority governments mean no power. All of it is pure bargaining.</li>
</ol>
<p>Okay, those are my (somewhat) interesting responses. I know there are lots more, though. Anyone else care to add a few?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/canadian-citizenship-questions-are-kinda-funny/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1471</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Canada: I&#039;m going to break the law</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/21/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it would appear that short of an Act of God (or, heaven forbid, some actual common sense runs through Parliament), Bill C-61 will forever handcuff Canadians and prevent long-term technological evolution. It&#8217;s one of the worst-written pieces of legislation to hit Canadians in years, as it does not take real-world habits into account at &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dear Canada: I&#039;m going to break the law"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, it would appear that short of an Act of God (or, heaven forbid, some actual common sense runs through Parliament), Bill C-61 will forever handcuff Canadians and prevent long-term technological evolution. It&#8217;s one of the <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/3385/125/">worst-written pieces of legislation to hit Canadians</a> in years, as it does not take real-world habits into account at all (short of the negative views, of course), and penalises everyone for something most of them haven&#8217;t done.<br />
I&#8217;m going to get the Government in on a little secret. I&#8217;m breaking it. I refuse to let your ridiculous industry ass-kissing paperwork prevent me from moving with the evolutionary tide. I&#8217;m breaking the law and doing what I think is right.<br />
<span id="more-1102"></span>Well, I will if/when I return to Canada &#8212; I&#8217;m currently living in Costa Rica.<br />
Here&#8217;s my single major problem: You won&#8217;t let me evolve. DVDs are dead. They are ubiquitous, that I won&#8217;t argue. But they are dead. The whole Blu-Ray/HD-DVD argument was a total non-event because it didn&#8217;t matter who won &#8212; Apple had already beaten them to the punch. Download the movies at half the price, and with all of the quality. It&#8217;s not about physical media anymore &#8212; it&#8217;s about data files.<br />
Maybe you missed the whole MP3 revolution? Why do you think so many music stores are closing, or desperately clawing their way online to weather the storm? I can&#8217;t tell you the last time I bought a CD. But I can tell you where all my music is &#8212; on a networked drive.<br />
Yes, NETWORKED &#8212; already in violation of Bill C-61. It&#8217;s there for two reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>I don&#8217;t want to lose anything. Data files are much more volatile than CDs thanks to hardware failure. Loose a hard drive, and you lose your entire music collection. So my music is on a RAID 1 <acronym title="Network Attached Storage">NAS</acronym> device to ensure that loss doesn&#8217;t happen.</li>
<li>Since my wife and I combined our personal CD collections into a single unit, we want to be able to listen to them from our computers &#8212; both of them. Hey, maybe you didn&#8217;t know that many Canadian households are now have more than one computer? Well, fancy that!</li>
</ol>
<p>And I&#8217;m not stopping there.<br />
The concept of scheduled TV is dying. It ain&#8217;t dead yet, but it&#8217;s not far off. The TiVO was the first stab in the back, the DIY PVR was your sucking chest wound, and the release of TV shows to iTunes and Hulu &#8212; well, there&#8217;s your kill shot. (And I&#8217;m not even counting the illegal forms of distribution through the &#8216;net!) It&#8217;s here, folks, like it or not.<br />
I&#8217;m going to build a PVR. A big one. My friend Doug built his own &#8212; three TV cards so he can record two shows while watching a third, all at the same time. And why not? I don&#8217;t want to sit through 500 channels of shit. Most of what&#8217;s on the air these days is utter garbage, and the good stuff is often on when I&#8217;m either not near a TV (which is normal) or on at a time when I&#8217;m asleep. So I&#8217;m gonna watch what I want <em>when I want</em>.<br />
And now here&#8217;s where I&#8217;m really gonna piss you off&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;m going to put all of it on my home network. Yeah, that&#8217;s right, a network. My televisions (however many I end up having, it doesn&#8217;t matter) will be &#8220;smart&#8221; &#8212; they&#8217;ll have a little computer attached to them (say, like the Apple TV, an off-the-shelf product) that links into my media library.<br />
Oh, did you not notice that both Microsoft Media Center and iTunes were media libraries? How sad that the Government doesn&#8217;t even realise the <em>current</em> state of affairs, let alone plan for the future.<br />
I&#8217;ll be able to watch whatever I want from any TV in the house. All my music, TV shows, movies (yep, even the ones that were on the DVDs that I purchased legally), home movies, internet radio, and so forth, will all be accessible 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, from any computer in my house.<br />
But no, dear Government, I will not be broadcasting that to the world. I do have my limits, and the security of my at home network is paramount. It will be high-speed, but it will also be high-security, for a reason. Firewalled, encrypted, and monitored. Because this is my family&#8217;s stuff, not the public&#8217;s. And last I checked, Canada was still a constitutional monarchy, and not a socialist state.<br />
So, please fine me. Take me to court. I&#8217;ll be more than happy to take such a ridiculous set of legislation to the Supreme Court of Canada and have it struck down. I&#8217;ve got lots on my side, including musicians, artists, prior art, and &#8212; this is the hardest one to have in court, but I feel it&#8217;s the most necessary &#8212; <em>common fucking sense</em>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1102</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada&#039;s history is wasted on its youth</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 19:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/19/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The CBC published a news article about how Canada&#8217;s youth scores a measly 18% on a Canadian history quiz. Everyone is aghast at the marks &#8212; are we truly that bad at our own history? Of course we are. Because we haven&#8217;t the ability to appreciate it. This was a conversation point I had with &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada&#039;s history is wasted on its youth"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CBC published a news article about how <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2007/11/09/canadians-quiz.html">Canada&#8217;s youth scores a measly 18% on a Canadian history quiz</a>. Everyone is aghast at the marks &#8212; are we truly that bad at our own history?<br />
Of course we are. Because we haven&#8217;t the ability to appreciate it.<br />
<span id="more-858"></span>This was a conversation point I had with my mother- and uncle-in-law the other night over dinner. My uncle was recounting a cruise he had taken from New York City that wound up the coast to Boston, Halifax, Cornerbrook, Quebec City, and a couple of other places that I now forget. Along the way, the cruise was replete with history, with guides not only present on the ship, but also on the tours at the various ports of call.<br />
His point was that the trip really put together all the things he&#8217;d previously learned in his history classes as a youth. Back then, it was mere words on a page, dates he had to memorise, without the context needed to put everything together.<br />
And that&#8217;s the catch: context.<br />
I remember from my own history classes having to memorise large chunks of useless information. I state &#8220;useless&#8221; because as a teenager, none of it had any bearing on my current state of life. I no longer remember when the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decline_of_the_Byzantine_Empire">Byzantine Empire collapsed</a> or when the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_River_Rebellion">Rouge River (Metis) Rebellion</a> took place. Those dates are lost among the other detritus that regularly floats around in my noggin. What matters is the &#8220;why&#8221;, the &#8220;how&#8221;, the &#8220;what&#8221;. Not so much the &#8220;when&#8221;. Well, specific &#8220;when&#8221; &#8212; approximate &#8220;when&#8221; does help.<br />
For example: Kids are taught (in Canada) that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_Confederation">Confederation took place on 1 July 1867</a> in Charlottetown, Prince Edward Island. This brought about the creation of Canada as a nation. But that&#8217;s not the whole truth, and really glosses over a whole whack of things, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>We were still a colony of Britain <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statute_of_Westminster_1931">until much later</a>, when <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_Act_1982">other documents were signed</a></li>
<li>We didn&#8217;t have a <a href="http://www.pch.gc.ca/progs/cpsc-ccsp/sc-cs/df3_e.cfm">Canadian national flag</a> until the 1960s</li>
<li>Confederation was mostly to handle issues with business and trade, and not for the idealistic creation of a nation</li>
<li>Natives got screwed over badly, along with the entire Maritime region</li>
<li>Upper Canada was given the upper hand</li>
<li>The West was largely a footnote</li>
</ul>
<p>The problem is that a lot of history comes down to one thing: politics. (Mind you, that gets sub-categorised into greed, sex, religion, and a healthy dose of insanity.) This is something teenagers don&#8217;t understand. Politics is one of those things you truly can&#8217;t appreciate until you&#8217;ve personally participated in a few elections (as a voter, anyway) to see what crap goes on.<br />
&#8216;Cuz the same crap has gone on for millennia. People always want what they can&#8217;t have, want to establish complete control, or simply get the girl and wreak havoc in the process. Politics have created and ended civilizations (witness the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carthage#The_fall_of_Carthage">Fall of Carthage</a> &#8212; mostly due to politics.) It takes years of reading books, watching documentaries, and attending in-depth classes to start understanding why the world works the way it does.<br />
It&#8217;s only once you get the bigger picture that the finer details are appreciated. Suddenly, you can see more significance in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Civil_War">Spanish Civil War</a>. You understand how <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_War_I">World War I</a> was almost unavoidable. Why the discovery of Canada and its deep exploration was so important to world development. How Canada steered the development of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Nations_Emergency_Force">United Nations peacekeeping</a>. Why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Vimy_Ridge">Vimy</a> does (and should) matter to Canadian. You see why oil is possibly the worst thing humanity has ever found. And you see the patterns that have governed human civilization for thousands of years.<br />
The saying goes that &#8220;those who do not learn from history are doomed to repeat it&#8221;. History merely validates that we do not learn from it. (A rather interesting cycle, when you think about it.) I think it&#8217;s less about those who learn from history, but those who actually understand it. And not just individual parts &#8212; that only really gives you an edge on Jeopardy. You need to understand the big pictures, and be able to dive into the details to understand the motivating factors.<br />
A really neat show from the BBC that used to be shown on TLC (when it was still known as The Learning Channel) was <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connections_(TV_series)">Connections</a></em>. While a distorted view of history (the connections were sometimes a bit tenuous), it did a great job of demonstrating why the end result often comes from things seemingly unrelated. History is about that very thing, and memorising dates won&#8217;t give you the high view.<br />
Should Canada&#8217;s youth still be taught history? Yes. But not in terms of dates. Learn big picture stuff first. Formative years should cover world history: civilizations, developments, world religions, political systems. In the years that come, teach the deeper concepts through specific examples (e.g. the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Hong_Kong#Colonial_Hong_Kong_Era_.281800s_-_1930s.29">rise of Hong Kong through Britain&#8217;s colonial development</a>, or why many of the towns and cities in western Canada come from Scotland).<br />
Give our youth context. I didn&#8217;t understand history until I was in my 20s, well after leaving high school. Give them the pieces to start assembling the bigger picture. You can&#8217;t teach all of the World history to anyone &#8230; but you can give them the tools to understand it themselves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">858</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
