<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>DearChooChoo &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/dearchoochoo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; not of woman borne! &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. Well, mostly. That &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; <em>not of woman borne!</em> &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. </p>



<p>Well, mostly. That whole anti-K thing and all, as we remind you of every now and then. Which is almost a bizarre parallel to today: almost immediately after you were born, the doctors wanted to whisk you away to the NICU to ensure that the anti-K situation wasn&#8217;t affecting your health. You were isolated. </p>



<p>Ten years later, you&#8217;re isolated again. This time, none of our doing (biological or otherwise), but because of COVID-19. You&#8217;re spending your birthday apart from nearly everyone but your family. </p>



<span id="more-3685"></span>



<p>You had wanted a grand party for today, and had selected a pretty cool venue: Petland. With lots of animals and friends and cake and food and fun and &#8230; it was all cancelled. Everything non-essential is closing, or has already closed. School was cancelled, all classes for the rest of the school year. I hope you might remember this year for the longest summer ever, but who knows what is yet to come with restrictions. I&#8217;m not sure which you lament more, that you won&#8217;t have any friends for your birthday, or that you won&#8217;t have the party. You love your animals.</p>



<p>It seems today will be just the four of us. Mostly the three of you, I suppose, since I&#8217;m trapped in the basement, working from home. I hadn&#8217;t planned it this way, of course, and this is the World&#8217;s Lamest Excuse on a day like this while we&#8217;re all in this situation (I <em>am</em> in the house, after all), but this is the last card in my hand after playing all the others&#8230;</p>



<p>My vacation time this year was planned for next week, March break, as we were going to go Saltspring Island. And with today being a school day, you were <em>originally</em> going to go to school. (Admittedly, that changed, too, but by then my vacation time was all gone.) I was going to see you as much as possible today as I could. That was the plan. </p>



<p>Only three days ago, Sunday the 16th, the Government cancelled all classes. School out for summer. International travel was effectively banned. Albertans were <em>strongly </em>encouraged to not partake of any non-essential travel, effectively forcing a cancellation of vacation. The day after, my office went into full &#8220;work from home&#8221; mode, and I became one of the most needed people in the office to ensure that this was going to work. </p>



<p>Two days later, I&#8217;m in the basement, wishing I could have avoided this. I am sorry, Choo Choo. I wish this situation were different, very different. I wish I was with you the entire day, not just a part of it. I wish we could have your party, I wish we could go to the coast and see seals and whales and fairy doors. I hope that, somehow, we still manage to make today a good day for you, given the limitations on what we can &#8212; what we should responsibly &#8212; do. </p>



<p>One day, I hope, we will make this up for you. Maybe you&#8217;re 11th will be more memorable for the things we couldn&#8217;t do this year. Or, maybe, many years from now, you&#8217;ll reminisce on today: &#8220;Lemme tell you about my 10th birthday, when the whole world was on quarantine&#8230;&#8221;</p>



<p>Now that&#8217;ll be a story.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 5th Birthday, Choo Choo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 04:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m having some serious trouble, Choo Choo. You&#8217;re five. FIVE. You&#8217;ve hit that penultimate step from wee babe to being a grade-schooler (the last, obviously, is going to Kindergarten; at least we have a few months before that). But still, five. You&#8217;re a funny one, Choo Choo. You may be the oldest in your preschool class, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 5th Birthday, Choo Choo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m having some serious trouble, Choo Choo. You&#8217;re five. FIVE. You&#8217;ve hit that penultimate step from wee babe to being a grade-schooler (the last, obviously, is going to Kindergarten; at least we have a few months before that).<br />
But still, <em>five</em>.<br />
<span id="more-3425"></span><br />
You&#8217;re a funny one, Choo Choo. You may be the oldest in your preschool class, but you sure don&#8217;t act your age. And I&#8217;ll be honest, that is what I love about you. You&#8217;re playful, loving, accepting, and stupidly adorable (something you seem to instinctively know, and use to your advantage, I might add). You skip more than you walk or run (I call you &#8220;Skippy&#8221; for a reason). You love doing flips by holding my hands, walking up my legs and flipping over backwards. You&#8217;ll curl up on Mommy&#8217;s or my lap as readily as Asia. You&#8217;re trying to not grow up.<br />
And yet, you are. You&#8217;re taller than your sister was when she turned five. You&#8217;ve outgrown and/or destroyed several pairs of pants. You&#8217;re bigger than the bike you learned to ride last summer. You don&#8217;t fit in pretty much anything meant for a pre-schooler. Your car seat no longer uses its five-point harness. You can power back a pretty big chicken dinner.<br />
But my <em>lord</em> do you have the sweetest face, the most wonderful (and ear-piercing) shriek when you&#8217;re having fun, you tell the greatest stories, and your imagination runs rampant in ways I can&#8217;t even begin to describe. I know that the day you actually decide to let us teach you how to read, you&#8217;ll discover great new things.<br />
But I&#8217;m getting ahead of myself. You&#8217;re not there just yet.<br />
For now, you&#8217;re still my wee one. Even if you&#8217;re not so wee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodbye, my lovely three year-old</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/03/goodbye-my-lovely-three-year-old/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=goodbye-my-lovely-three-year-old</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/03/goodbye-my-lovely-three-year-old/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 05:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Choo Choo, today I&#8217;m having a &#8220;last&#8221; moment. Today was your last full day as a three year-old. Tomorrow is your birthday. Tomorrow, you turn four. And I will miss you being three immensely. You are my last three year-old. A long time ago, when Mommy was first pregnant with Monkey, she asked me &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/03/goodbye-my-lovely-three-year-old/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Goodbye, my lovely three year-old"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Choo Choo, today I&#8217;m having a &#8220;last&#8221; moment. Today was your last full day as a three year-old. Tomorrow is your birthday. Tomorrow, you turn four.<br />
And I will miss you being three immensely. You are my last three year-old.<br />
<span id="more-3413"></span><br />
A long time ago, when Mommy was first pregnant with Monkey, she asked me what year I was looking most forward to. I said &#8220;three&#8221;, though I wasn&#8217;t really sure why. I think I was mildly convinced, having absolutely no data to support my claim, that three was the perfect balance of wisdom (notably the ability to hold a conversation), and cuteness (still being a little kid without the burden of having to act like an older kid).<br />
It turns out I was right. Three really is the perfect age.<br />
I&#8217;ve been dreading this day for a long time. I&#8217;m losing the last real &#8220;child&#8221; in my life &#8212; you&#8217;re growing older, and getting bigger, and acting different with each day. It&#8217;s not an easy thing to appreciate, losing one&#8217;s innocence, and even less so when it&#8217;s someone else&#8217;s.<br />
I probably remember your birth day more clearly than Monkey&#8217;s. That&#8217;s mostly likely because it was highly scheduled, anticipated, and planned. Which, of course, meant that it was completely opposite of all that. And yet, despite the adversity, you turned out as beautiful as I could ever hope or imagine.<br />
Only last summer did I realize that you were no longer a baby, or even a toddler. I made the mistake of noticing that your legs extended some distance from your torso. It sounds like a strange thing to say, I know, but wee babes don&#8217;t have long legs; yours were longer than I&#8217;d remembered. And suddenly, you were no longer a wee babe.<br />
Tomorrow, you cease being three. And I&#8217;m having trouble with that. I&#8217;d keep you at three, if I could. I&#8217;d keep you as young, innocent, and wonderful as you are today. But I can&#8217;t. I can only pray that I can remember you as you are today, with your wonder and amusement at everything you see.<br />
I will miss you, Choo Choo at three years old. My wonderful little girl, who has given me so much joy.<br />
I hope that there are many years of joy yet to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/03/goodbye-my-lovely-three-year-old/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3413</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 3rd birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s one of those funny things you sometimes run into as a parent. In one moment, you&#8217;re nearly panicking at the seemingly rapid passage of time, that your tiny infant is suddenly racing around the house, reading books far too advanced for her age, and threatening to debate logical positivism. Then you look down and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 3rd birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s one of those funny things you sometimes run into as a parent. In one moment, you&#8217;re nearly panicking at the seemingly rapid passage of time, that your tiny infant is suddenly racing around the house, reading books far too advanced for her age, and threatening to debate logical positivism. Then you look down and see that one child is adorably cute and had been so for, also seemingly long, forever.<br />
Today, dear Choo Choo, you turned 3. And while the world seems to be spinning around me beyond my control, you sit there at the centre of the storm, giggling and playing and singing songs and making faces and smiling, smiling, smiling. Oh, how I cannot believe how much happier my life is when I get a big hug from you.<br />
Like this morning, when you got up&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3242"></span>It wasn&#8217;t the greatest of mornings, sadly &#8212; your sister, Monkey, was having trouble getting moving. It was a struggle to get her to school on time, and even that didn&#8217;t go particularly well (her water bottle leaked, soaking her snow pants, which then froze). Things were better when I got home, and got a big hug from you.<br />
Then you, Mommy, and I hopped in the car to go get your birthday presents. We decided to try something a little different this year, and let you choose what you got. So we headed over to Market Mall, where you played for a bit in the play area, and then marvelled at all the toys at the Toys &#8216;R Us.<br />
And I have to say, kiddo, you were pretty conservative with your choices. When I was a boy, I would have gone bananas in a store like that, and would have tried to clean the place out. You hung onto a teddy bear dressed a Woody from <em>Toy Story</em> for most of the time, passed up on the lightsabres (which was good, we&#8217;d have to buy two and they ain&#8217;t cheap!), fell in love with a <em>My Little Pony</em> set and a Duplo set with Ariel, and a pair of sunglasses (which you needed, anyway). Mommy added in a Richard Scarry boardgame with airplanes (you&#8217;ve been wanting an airplane since before Christmas). And, finally, you gave up the teddy bear (why, I&#8217;m still not sure) for a Bubble Guppies stuffie.<br />
As Mommy handled the transaction, you hugged your new stuffie tightly, looked at Mommy and I with big wide, eyes, and then gave us each a big hug.<br />
After finding a coffee for mommy (and a hot chocolate for you), I got Monkey from school and Mommy wrapped all of your presents so you could open them later. Then Mommy made a fresh carrot cake and I made dinner while you and Megan played. Then all of us went to go watch Monkey&#8217;s last dance class. You sat on my lap for most of the class. I got lots of big hugs.<br />
After a stop at the library to acquire a few new books, we returned home to find Grandma waiting for us. At first you were terrified of seeing Grandma (I have no idea why), though that quickly subsided and you were ecstatic to be around her again. You played with her until dinner time, and shovelled in your butter chicken, followed by your birthday carrot cake. (A note for next year &#8212; wait until we stop singing before you blow out your candles, okay?)<br />
Present opening and playing came next, which was rapidly ending the day &#8212; both you and Monkey were tired, and tensions began to run very thin. Monkey, sadly, was feeling left out because it wasn&#8217;t her birthday, and no-one was paying her as much attention as we were paying to you. It&#8217;s understandable, and I guess I&#8217;m thankful I don&#8217;t remember doing the same to Auntie Cathy.<br />
Finally, we packed you off to bed, where you settled into your warm sheets, your smile just as big as it was when you woke up. You talked about your new toys, and your new books, and were very happy about your new pyjamas. Then, with your turtle on, you lay down for sweet birthday dreams.<br />
Right after you gave me a great, big, awesome hug.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I hate you leave you in the morning, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/i-hate-you-leave-you-in-the-morning-part-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-hate-you-leave-you-in-the-morning-part-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/i-hate-you-leave-you-in-the-morning-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 04:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Where once there was one, Now there are two. But the patterns remains the same. Wakened by one, though with hugs from both. We sit. We eat. We chat. Stories, changing of clothes and preparing for the day. Teeth brushed. Please, just let Mommy sleep a little while longer. &#8220;Daddy, you going work?&#8221; &#8220;Yes, honey&#8230;&#8221; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/i-hate-you-leave-you-in-the-morning-part-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I hate you leave you in the morning, Part 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Where once there was one,<br />
Now there are two.<br />
But the patterns remains the same.<br />
Wakened by one, though with hugs from both.<br />
We sit. We eat. We chat.<br />
Stories, changing of clothes and preparing for the day.<br />
Teeth brushed.<br />
Please, just let Mommy sleep a little while longer.<br />
&#8220;Daddy, you going work?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Yes, honey&#8230;&#8221;<br />
&#8220;But I miss you!&#8221;<br />
Prometheus brought fire to man<br />
And endured the eagle every day.<br />
My heart faces the same eternity of destruction and healing<br />
For everyday that I must leave.<br />
Hugs. A kiss. A moment of love.<br />
It is a fleeting moment, like your innocence<br />
Too soon gone.<br />
It&#8217;s a lonely trek away from you<br />
Each step an ache<br />
A string strung too far<br />
Desperate to break.<br />
Days are long<br />
Time is short<br />
You grow up too fast<br />
Suddenly, another year passes<br />
What did I miss?<br />
I miss you. Every day.<br />
Always.<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/09/i-hate-to-leave-you-in-the-morning/">I hate to leave you in the morning.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/i-hate-you-leave-you-in-the-morning-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3150</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A walk in the (amusement) park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-walk-in-the-amusement-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amusement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kids, we missed the Calgary Stampede this year. That was partly intentional, to be honest. Yes, it was the 100th anniversary, and Choo Choo was old enough to actually do some of the things there, but &#8230; well, it was kind of crazy this year, and maybe the 101th anniversary won&#8217;t be quite so crazy. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A walk in the (amusement) park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kids, we missed the Calgary Stampede this year. That was partly intentional, to be honest. Yes, it was the 100th anniversary, and Choo Choo was old enough to actually <em>do</em> some of the things there, but &#8230; well, it was kind of crazy this year, and maybe the 101th anniversary won&#8217;t be quite so crazy. And you&#8217;ll be older, and slightly more &#8230; how can I put this? &#8230; <em>controllable</em>.<br />
That said, you both like rides, Monkey especially. (<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/">We found that out last year.</a>) So denying you two a trip to an amusement park, especially during what&#8217;s turning out to be Calgary&#8217;s best summer in a long time, is just plain criminal. So with Mommy&#8217;s acquired coupons, we packed you up, dragged out Grandpa, and all headed to Calaway Park.<br />
In a word? &#8220;WHEEEEEEEE!&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-3128"></span>We were a tad late leaving, because &#8212; completely stunning everyone &#8212; we all slept in. Well, most of us. Choo Choo, you were up, but you (in an extremely rare move) didn&#8217;t tell anyone you were up. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever made pancakes so quickly before.<br />
The park wasn&#8217;t busy when we arrived, though our arrival was a bit elongated as we tried to all find one another. But it wasn&#8217;t long before we were off into the park to wreak appropriate havoc.<br />
First up were bumper boats. I was mildly surprised that they had any water-based rides, but one of my favourites seemed to not be an issue. As I commented to Grandpa, they&#8217;re not the ones I grew up with. Those were using <em>real</em> outboard motors, and we had to wear life jackets (we were also on Lake Ontario). Calaway&#8217;s are electric, with built-in squirt guns (that really need to have the ability to aim up/down &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to hit the guy in front of you). Sadly, Choo Choo was too small, and Mommy wasn&#8217;t &#8220;suitably dressed&#8221; for water play, so they went off while Monkey, Grandpa, and I tried to soak each other.<br />
We found our way to a ride called the Samba Swing, which was a real definition of &#8220;spinny ride&#8221;. Not only did it go around in a circle, it raised on an angle like a tilted ferris wheel, but each of the pods could spin around on its own. Mommy and Choo Choo went in one, while Monkey and I went in the other. Sadly, the pods tended to spin, even if you didn&#8217;t try, as the centripetal force caused the heavier person to swing to the outside. Monkey, you giggled pretty much the entire time; Choo Choo, you didn&#8217;t dig it so much.<br />
Thankfully, merry-go-rounds are easier, and both of you seemed okay with that. We marched off in search of a train ride, which was preempted by a kids-sized rollercoaster (you&#8217;re still a bit too small for the big rollercoaster, Monkey, though you REALLY wanted to go on it). Mommy spotted a game called &#8220;Stinky Feet&#8221;, which we played. I won, and the game attendant let me get two (smaller) prizes for the two of you.<br />
The train ride was &#8230; well, slow. But at least fun. And not rainy, like the previous one we&#8217;d been on.<br />
After lunch, we went in search of more rides. We found the Berry Go Round, which was another spinny ride (but not as spinny as Samba). Monkey wouldn&#8217;t let us spin at all, though I have no idea why. That&#8217;s not to say that I didn&#8217;t try to get us to spin &#8212; even just a little. Then Monkey and Grandpa went on an airplane ride while Choo Choo went and played in a tugboat playset.<br />
We tried to find ice cream. You&#8217;d think this should be about, oh, ever metre in an amusement park in the summer? It&#8217;s not, which I found particularly odd. Our search took us over towards Shoot the Chutes, which is (so Mommy tells me) an original ride, which doesn&#8217;t appear to have changed much since Mommy was a kid. Monkey, Grandpa, and I got in line while Mommy and Choo Choo went off in search of ice cream &#8212; sadly, Choo Choo, you&#8217;re just a bit too small for my liking.<br />
It took nearly 45 minutes to get through the line, which went slower than it should have because they weren&#8217;t loading the boats completely full. When we finally got to the end, they had started maxing the capacity. As it stands, we ended up with a five-person boat; the three of us, plus a father and daughter.<br />
The first hill caused a spat of maniacal laughter in Monkey. I&#8217;ve never heard her laugh so wildly, declaring the ride was awesome.<br />
Well, that was the <em>first</em> hill. Which is about <em>half</em> the height of the full thing.<br />
When we go to the top of the second hill &#8212; the big one &#8212; Monkey wanted off. Now. Please.<br />
There&#8217;s a picture that gets taken when you go down the big hill. What you see is a look of abject terror on Monkey&#8217;s face, the sheer excitement of the kid behind her (that would be Monkey&#8217;s father, of course), and Grandpa looking like he was nearly asleep from boredom (Grandpa should play poker, really).<br />
At the bottom, our boat kicked up a huge wall of water, which fell right on top of Monkey. That elicited some tears, which is understandable. Thankfully, Mommy had thought to bring a zip-up fleece, which replaced Monkey&#8217;s soaked t-shirt. Then we were off &#8212; FINALLY &#8212; for ice cream.<br />
A clown found the both of you as the last of the ice cream went down, which you both loved (especially for the bubbles).<br />
Exhaustion having set in fully with Choo Choo, we headed for home; Choo Choo was asleep five minutes later.<br />
But worry not, we&#8217;re going back! Hopefully it&#8217;ll be as much fun as yesterday!<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/a-walk-in-the-amusement-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3128</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 2.5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-2-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 2.5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), and not far away, flooding is so bad that highways are being washed out.<br />
<span id="more-3121"></span>Yesterday started looking like it might rain, though it didn&#8217;t. That allowed us to bolt up the side of the mountain for a chance for you two to go in the bouncy castles. Sadly, only one of the three was set up, as they were all very wet (the one you were in was still a bit damp). It was so wet, and the clouds threatening a downpour so badly that we couldn&#8217;t decide whether or not to buy a day pass. Thankfully, the two attendants decided to let you two bounce anyway, as they didn&#8217;t get the other two castles set up until much later.<br />
We went for a snack afterwards: hot chocolate for both of you, along with (shared) slices of banana bread and devil&#8217;s food chocolate cake. After our snack, we all headed back to the S7 house for our lunch: Grandpa&#8217;s chili.<br />
Choo Choo went for a nap, Monkey went out with Mommy and Tia Nicole. It was quiet around the house for a little while.<br />
I attempted to make dinner. With a mostly-frozen chicken. The stupid heat-proof dish shattered, the chicken hadn&#8217;t thawed as expected, and I was thoroughly disgusted with my lousy attempt. We ended up having to order from a new restaurant nearby (that happens to make a fire roasted chicken with fries that is strongly reminiscent of those from a chain named for Alps-bound edifices).<br />
Post-dinner was our hot springs soak. Monkey, you&#8217;re getting better at swimming, but you&#8217;re still somewhat hopeless without a floatation device. We need to practice on your doggy paddle. And, I should also add, you finally took to the hot pool (which was significantly hotter than when Mommy and I had gone the night before). Choo Choo, on the other hand, could have just stayed there for hours.<br />
Sadly, that trip also put both of you well past your bedtimes; Monkey, you didn&#8217;t get to bed until nearly 22:00, which is dangerous for your overnight rest (as it stands, it wasn&#8217;t that good). But I can safely say Choo Choo had it worse.<br />
Laryngotracheobronchitis, to be exact. You picked it up yesterday morning, the wheezing very prominent. We had hoped it would pass, but it just got worse. So bad that a couple of times you woke up screaming &#8212; which wasn&#8217;t actually screaming, as you couldn&#8217;t really do much other than gasp and emit a raspy squeak. At 4:00, Mommy and I packed you into the car, and we were off to the hospital &#8230; nearly 30 kilometres away.<br />
The trip to Invermere was a bit difficult. I was anxious to get you there quickly, Choo Choo, but with dawn only just starting to dawn, it was still very dark, and light patches of fog randomly appeared. In any urban setting, I might not think twice about it &#8212; on Highway 93/95, which has a constant animal warning, I was more than a little worried about going too quickly.<br />
Ironically, I nearly hit the damn deer sitting in the middle of an Invermere street, less than 100 metres from the hospital, because I&#8217;d stopped watching for them.<br />
Invermere Hospital is small. Really small. The outer doors were locked, and we had to get buzzed in. Then we were met by the entire hospital night staff: Two Registered Nurses and a Practicing Nurse. A grand total of 12 emergency beds, and 8 overnight beds. We were the only ones there, so we had the entire hospital focused on you, Choo Choo. A far cry from the busy-ness of the Calgary hospitals.<br />
The Practicing Nurse almost immediately said &#8220;croup&#8221;, which is a nasty condition that stems from an infection of your vocal chords. Sadly, in small kids, it causes a tight constriction, leading to the wheezing and barking cough. That led to a phone call to the admitting desk &#8212; at some other remote location &#8212; and another call to the on-call doctor.<br />
In the meantime, we were whisked away to Bed #4 &#8212; as unoccupied as every other bed &#8212; where you got to lay down with a warm blanket. You were scared, Choo Choo, and I don&#8217;t blame you. There were two very nice ladies fawning over you, and you were somewhere you didn&#8217;t recognise at all. Then, to make things worse, you had some drops to drink (an oral steroid to help with your larynx), and then they put a mask over your face to help give you some ventalin to help you breathe.<br />
You really didn&#8217;t like that mask. It didn&#8217;t matter that it was painted to look a bit like a doggy, you just didn&#8217;t want it there, you didn&#8217;t want the mist, you just wanted it off. You cried. And I don&#8217;t blame you one bit. You were given a box of apple juice and two Digestive cookies for when you got it off, and stickers to put on while the mist did its work.<br />
When the doctor arrived, a very nice man I might add, he proceeded to do a quick check, and then took you and Mommy for a quick stroll outside to let the cool air help you breathe.<br />
I asked the nurses about the hospital, and learned how small it was, that we were in the &#8220;shoulder&#8221; season, between the high points of winter (dislocated shoulders and broken bones from the ski hills) and summer (not detailed, but I presume similar given the tendency for people to switch from one seasonal downhill activity to another).<br />
Finally, we left, thanking everyone for all their help. You munched on ice chips and your other cookie until we were back in Fairy-mont. We all went right back to bed &#8212; I curled up with you until you were asleep again &#8212; and managed to get some more rest.<br />
Breakfast was late, activities were (sadly) largely aborted. We managed to get in a short swim before eating lunch. Choo Choo went back down for a nap (in an effort to try get back to regular sleep patterns), and Monkey and I went for a (short) craft session, making Wiggly Worms.<br />
Monkey, you&#8217;ve been making cupcakes with Granny, and watching Wall-E. That&#8217;s where we are right now. Mommy just got back from a much-needed massage. Grandpa and Tia Nicole are in Invermere. The afternoon and evening are ahead of us; we shall see what comes.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 05:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kids, You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours. We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230; We started &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kids,<br />
You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours.<br />
We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3119"></span>We started early, all of us up before 7:00 this morning. I&#8217;d packed for our trip last night (and we&#8217;ve since determined that Daddy sucks at remembering certain important things), but we still had some last-minute things that had to be done at the last minute (turning off computers, internet, turning down the hot water heater, to name a few), and the packing of the last few things. I then packed the car &#8212; in the rain, I might add.<br />
Then we bolted to Sunterra for breakfast. This is our Saturday tradition. Every Saturday, we&#8217;re there when they open at 8:00 to have a good, hot breakfast that will usually keep us going for a few hours. (Well, most of us. Mommy&#8217;s current diet means she has to bring her breakfast with her, and it&#8217;s just never enough.) After breakfast, we did a tiny bit of shopping, and we headed out to North Glenmore Park.<br />
Today was the Race for Pace. This was a charitable event to raise funds for the Pacekids Program, which helps disabled kids. Amber, our next-door neighbour, informed us of the event, and it seemed like it would be a lot of fun. Y&#8217;know, in the rain.<br />
I joke, I joke! It didn&#8217;t rain &#8230; that much. It did rain, but nothing like when we woke up, which was a fair pounding. The rain had let up during breakfast. That said, the park was very wet, the ground very soggy, and we all got reasonably damp. Except in spirits. Once the two of you got your superhero capes, you were off like gangbusters. We did the 1 km Superhero race (Mommy and Monkey completed it; Choo Choo and I cheated a bit, only because you&#8217;re a bit of a slow walker, still, Choo Choo), which ended in a crowd of cheers, and medals on your necks.<br />
You played games and won prizes, too! The best was a &#8220;game&#8221; that originally started as an inflatable pool filled with shredded paper, in which were buried toys for kids to find. But it quickly evolved to a game where the kids threw around clumps of shredded paper (both in/out of the pool, and at each other), and pretty much ignored all the toys that were supposed to be &#8220;won&#8221;.<br />
After some slices of the 100th Anniversary Calgary Stampede cake, we headed back to the car, buckled in, and headed back to Sunterra (which, in our defence, was on the way out of the city) to get Choo Choo some diapers (which we&#8217;d forgotten to buy when we were there), hooked up the in-car DVD player (Kiki&#8217;s Delivery Service was the first movie up), and then hit the road.<br />
It rained.<br />
It rained off and on pretty much the rest of the day, really. It&#8217;s raining right now. It&#8217;ll be raining tomorrow. I really hope it stops raining.<br />
Anyway, we stopped in Canmore, rather than our usual habit, which is Banff. Mommy found a nice restaurant she could eat at, which turned out to be a wonderful place with good food, and colouring books. You two and I had grilled cheese sandwiches (mine also had ham, salami, and dill pickles, mind you) while Mommy had a spinach salad.<br />
We tried to find a playground afterwards, but it didn&#8217;t work out so well &#8212; the nearest one was further away than we&#8217;d planned. But we did find a toy store to stop at for short while.<br />
Finding Nemo was the next movie up, which carried us through Banff National Park, and well into Kootenay National Park. Choo Choo, you finally fell asleep as we approached Highway 93, and stayed asleep for about an hour, waking up at the Lodge, where we&#8217;ve often stopped for a short break. (In this case, it was a rather urgent potty break.)<br />
The rest of the trip went as it usually did &#8212; not anywhere near as fast as we&#8217;d like it to go. But soon we were out of the mountains, much to Choo Choo&#8217;s relief (your ears were apparently hurting), and turning south towards what Choo Choo had started to call &#8220;Fairy-mont&#8221;. (My spelling, of course.)<br />
After the obligatory stop in Invermere for groceries, we blasted to Fairy-mont, and checked in at the Mountainside Villas, barely minutes before Grandpa, Granny, and Tia Nicole arrived. We got the keys to our &#8220;new&#8221; house for this year, S7. Normally, we&#8217;re in B6, but it wasn&#8217;t available this week (this week being a traded week, since the timeshare schedule this year put us into Monkey&#8217;s first week of Kindergarten). S7 and B6 are similar, but there are notable differences. For this week, however, I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll be fine.<br />
The both of you ran amok around the house, running up and down stairs, jumping on beds (you&#8217;re still mystified at the Murphy bed; you have no idea where the bed keeps disappearing to). We had dinner (though both of you failed to eat much), you read some stories, and after a significant amount of struggle, we got you both to bed, both still far too excited to be here, and both passing out within minutes of hitting the pillow.<br />
Mommy and I made a run to the hot springs afterwards, and put some more thought into what we&#8217;ll do this week.<br />
Y&#8217;know, if it ever stops raining.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3119</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An apology to my kids</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/an-apology-to-my-kids/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-apology-to-my-kids</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/an-apology-to-my-kids/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 13:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Monkey and Choo Choo, Yesterday, I worked from home. This is not the first time I&#8217;ve done so. The reasons for working from home are also largely irrelevant. The point is that I was there, even though I really wasn&#8217;t. I was working, which means my mind is elsewhere. For you, I was home. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/an-apology-to-my-kids/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "An apology to my kids"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Monkey and Choo Choo,<br />
Yesterday, I worked from home. This is not the first time I&#8217;ve done so. The reasons for working from home are also largely irrelevant. The point is that I was there, even though I really wasn&#8217;t. I was working, which means my mind is elsewhere.<br />
For you, I was home. This &#8220;working&#8221; thing doesn&#8217;t make any sense to you, nor should it. I was at home; that&#8217;s all that matters to you. So you did what you should be doing when I&#8217;m at home:</p>
<blockquote><p>Daddy, I[&#8216;m&#8217;] hungry.<br />
Daddy, [can you] read [this] story [to me]?<br />
Daddy, can you take me around the block on my bike?<br />
Daddy, come play!</p></blockquote>
<p>Instead of &#8220;yes&#8221;, which is what you expected, you heard me say &#8220;no&#8221;, and far too often, angrily. And for that, I apologise. You shouldn&#8217;t have had to deal with me like that. I made you cry a couple of times, Choo Choo, for you understand the least. You know when I leave in the morning, I&#8217;m going to &#8220;work&#8221;. Even though I know you don&#8217;t really know what &#8220;work&#8221; means, you know I&#8217;m not at home. Lately, this elicits:</p>
<blockquote><p>I[&#8216;ll] miss you.</p></blockquote>
<p>See daddy&#8217;s heart. See daddy&#8217;s heart shatter into a million pieces. See daddy cry as he watches his kids&#8217; lives slip from his fingers.<br />
So I&#8217;m going to make a deal with you. I know you&#8217;ll accept, so this is more kicking myself in the butt to make sure I do it. I will never work from home again. That means that if I am at home, and you&#8217;re awake, I&#8217;m yours. If it&#8217;s a &#8220;normal&#8221; work day, I&#8217;ll shift my hours to a time when you&#8217;re asleep. If I&#8217;m at home, we do what you want to do. We play, we read, we go for walks.<br />
Because I can&#8217;t bear to say &#8220;no&#8221; anymore to the things that matter to you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/an-apology-to-my-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3104</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 2nd birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 04:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy 2nd birthday, my dear Choo Choo! It&#8217;s almost impossible to believe you been with us only two years, you shining little light. Two short &#8212; and somehow, impossibly long &#8212; years ago, you found yourself suddenly freezing, weighed, and then set upon by a dozen doctors and nurses who were all convinced you were &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 2nd birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy 2nd birthday, my dear Choo Choo!<br />
It&#8217;s almost impossible to believe you been with us only two years, you shining little light. Two short &#8212; and somehow, impossibly long &#8212; years ago, you found yourself suddenly freezing, weighed, and then set upon by a dozen doctors and nurses who were all convinced you were not exactly in the best of health. To see you running around today, inhaling chocolate cupcakes like they were air &#8230; well, if anything, I&#8217;d suspect those doctors would feel proud you&#8217;ve turned out so well.<br />
Goodness knows I am, kiddo.<br />
<span id="more-3000"></span>Today&#8217;s events started almost as normally as any Sunday could. We got up, we had pancakes. Of course, Grandpa being around was definitely a different thing &#8212; he&#8217;s here a lot, but not that often. And then we had no blueberries for our pancakes (we ran out, and I forgot to get more). And then we tore out the kitchen.<br />
Oh, did I forget to mention that, on your second birthday, we gutted the kitchen and Mommy&#8217;s and my bathroom and moved to another house?<br />
My dear, you will not remember our old kitchen. Monkey will, but likely only a little. You likely won&#8217;t remember it at all. We&#8217;ll show you pictures of it, and you might think it reminds you of something, but &#8230; well, Choo Choo, you&#8217;re not old enough. You&#8217;re only two.<br />
Funny thing is, you&#8217;ve been acting a lot older than two for a long time. I credit your sister with this &#8212; she has taught you a lot. And sadly, a lot of it is BAD HABITS (*ahem*, Monkey, thank you for that!). I&#8217;m not saying you act badly, Choo Choo, but you tend to put your foot down (literally) a lot more easily than perhaps you should. Your attitude has formed very early.<br />
As has your vocabulary. You still can&#8217;t say your sister&#8217;s name right, and you can&#8217;t say &#8220;milk&#8221;, either. You have, however, a wonderful little &#8220;click&#8221; in place of the &#8220;k&#8221;. You can say &#8220;cat&#8221;, &#8220;coat&#8221;, &#8220;cars&#8221;, and &#8220;cup&#8221; fairly well, though they do tend to sound more like &#8220;tat&#8221;, &#8220;toat&#8221;, &#8220;tars&#8221;, and &#8220;tup&#8221; a little more than anything. It&#8217;s developmental, though, and we&#8217;re hearing signs that you&#8217;ll be getting that nice hard-&#8220;k&#8221; sound soon. The question will then be how long it takes you to say &#8220;yellow&#8221; instead of &#8220;lellow&#8221; (Monkey went about a year before she got it right, much to Grandpa&#8217;s delight).<br />
After Daddy and the people who bought our kitchen cabinets were done, we went to the Cabin Cafe for lunch. You squealed though most of your baby bagel egger sandwich, and then we went back to the house for you to have a nap. When you woke up, we went over to our temporary house for dinner (roast chicken, potatoes, and brocolli &#8212; one of your favourites), and Mommy made you chocolate birthday cupcakes. You got some wonderful presents, including a new baby doll (&#8216;cuz this family needs a sixth baby doll&#8230;)<br />
Tonight, you&#8217;re trying to sleep in a bed. Well, on a mattress on the floor, anyway. You&#8217;re not in your crib, which is proving to be a bit of a problem. Mommy&#8217;s been in with you now for about 45 minutes, and you&#8217;re really just not interested with going to sleep. I foresee many nights coming up of you needing to be held before you go to bed. But don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s a problem, Choo Choo &#8212; your daddy is always willing to cuddle up with you.<br />
I hope you had a wonderful second birthday, even if you won&#8217;t really remember it. Next year&#8217;s birthday, if Mommy has her way, should not only be memorable, but should hopefully be one you do remember.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3000</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
