<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>basement &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/basement/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 23:19:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Basement renovation almost complete</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/basement-renovation-almost-complete/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=basement-renovation-almost-complete</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/basement-renovation-almost-complete/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 23:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sigh. Just in time for us to leave the house, too. Oh well, at least it&#8217;ll improve the overall value of the place, right? Here are the before/after pictures. Because it&#8217;s important to know what we&#8217;ve done here. We started off with a 70s reno gone wrong. We&#8217;ve ended up with a nice, modern space &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/basement-renovation-almost-complete/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Basement renovation almost complete"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sigh. Just in time for us to leave the house, too. Oh well, at least it&#8217;ll improve the overall value of the place, right?<br />
Here are the before/after pictures. Because it&#8217;s important to know what we&#8217;ve done here. We started off with a 70s reno gone wrong. We&#8217;ve ended up with a nice, modern space ready for almost anything.<br />
<span id="more-997"></span>From this:<br />
[flickr]photo:2109438852(small)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2108663391(small)[/flickr]<br />
To this:<br />
[flickr]photo:2566206074(small)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2566202822(small)[/flickr]<br />
From all this:<br />
[flickr]photo:2105882894(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2105882928(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2105882990(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2105883030(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2105105429(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
To all this:<br />
[flickr]photo:2566205284(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2565378819(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2566203860(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Assuming we come back to this house when (if?) we leave Costa Rica, we&#8217;ll do the upstairs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/basement-renovation-almost-complete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">997</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renovations nearing completion!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=renovations-nearing-completion</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 15:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flooring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a long, hard slog since all this began a year ago. Demolition, plumbing, heating, framing, electrical, gas, contractor nightmares, self-realisation, and now the end of the tunnel is fully lit. This weekend, barring disaster, the basement will be done. Just in time for us to leave the house and let someone else enjoy &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Renovations nearing completion!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long, hard slog since all this began a year ago. Demolition, plumbing, heating, framing, electrical, gas, contractor nightmares, self-realisation, and now the end of the tunnel is fully lit. This weekend, barring disaster, the basement will be done.<br />
Just in time for us to leave the house and let someone else enjoy it. I&#8217;ve still not really come to grips with that part.<br />
<span id="more-993"></span>But as you can see, the basement is looking pretty good. At this point, the outstanding issues are installation of the floor; getting the toilet, sink, and bathroom hardware in place; hanging the doors; putting covers on the rest of the holes left in the ceiling (e.g. vents); a second coat of paint on two walls (looks a bit thin); and fixing the cable in one bedroom (which is mysteriously non-functional).<br />
[flickr]photo:2549991526(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549167077(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549994298(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549169117(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549996906(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2549171725(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2551302668(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2550481817(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2551303876(thumbnail)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/renovations-nearing-completion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">993</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renovations Update</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/renovations-update/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=renovations-update</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/renovations-update/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 14:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since we went off world-hopping, a lot has happened. That&#8217;s not to say the basement is done yet. Sadly, we had hoped for completion by May. A couple of starting delays, and then a labour disruption with our contractor led to a bit of a slowdown. It&#8217;s almost the end of April, which means it&#8217;ll &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/renovations-update/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Renovations Update"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since we went off world-hopping, a lot has happened. That&#8217;s not to say the basement is done yet. Sadly, we had hoped for completion by May. A couple of starting delays, and then a labour disruption with our contractor led to a bit of a slowdown. It&#8217;s almost the end of April, which means it&#8217;ll be an Act of God to get the basement done by May.<br />
I think we&#8217;re okay with that. But it can&#8217;t go on much longer. Time&#8217;s a-runnin&#8217; out.<br />
<span id="more-960"></span>This is where we left off when we left:<br />
[flickr]tag:prevacation2008+renovations@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]<br />
Basically: framing, insulation (particularly in the theatre area), wiring, and plumbing. It looked pretty rough as we headed out the door for the airport &#8212; a few of those pictures were literally taken minutes before we left!<br />
Okay, so we&#8217;re back now, and progress has been made:<br />
[flickr]tag:postvacation2008+renovations@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]<br />
A lot of drywall at this point &#8212; almost at the point of doing finishing work. Flooring will be among the last things in. Alex is handling all the final beauty steps.<br />
We&#8217;re not really certain when it&#8217;ll be all done, but it&#8217;s definitely coming along. The biggest problem? It&#8217;s really going to make us want to do the upstairs&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/renovations-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">960</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renovations renewed</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/renovations-renewed/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=renovations-renewed</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/renovations-renewed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 01:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/14/renovations-renewed/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, as you already know, I&#8217;ve accepted the fact that I cannot renovate my own home. I&#8217;m neither skilled enough, nor have the time to handle it. (As it stands, there is considerable discussion that I&#8217;m not spending enough time with my family as it is.) Anyway, we finally decided it was necessary to get &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/renovations-renewed/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Renovations renewed"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, as you already know, I&#8217;ve accepted the fact that I cannot renovate my own home. I&#8217;m neither skilled enough, nor have the time to handle it. (As it stands, there is considerable discussion that I&#8217;m not spending enough time with my family as it is.)<br />
Anyway, we finally decided it was necessary to get a contractor to come in and finish the job.<br />
No, scratch that.<br />
To undo the mess I made, and do it right.<br />
<span id="more-911"></span>As you know, we already talked to one contractor who came back and suggested that it would cost over $50,000. Considering we had hoped to do all the house renovations, including our (apparently far more expensive than planned) heating system, for $100,000. It didn&#8217;t make sense to go with that.<br />
Fortunately, I have connections. Loose ones, but ones that led us to someone who believes in doing solid, effective work without all the cost of the Taj Mahal. We want nice, not museum.<br />
They officially started on Monday. So far the progress isn&#8217;t quite as fast as I thought it would be, but probably because I&#8217;ve got stupid expectations. The job is going to take them until May, which is an absolute hard date for us. So far, it&#8217;s mostly putting in bulkheads (which I&#8217;d never gotten around to), removing a wall that&#8217;s turned out to be effectively useless, and installing the framing for some closets (and for hiding pipes, sumps, and gas meters).<br />
So far, they do better work than I do. I can&#8217;t wait to see how this room looks when it&#8217;s all done.<br />
[flickr]photo:2333514539(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2334342656(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2333516469(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2333517081(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2334344700(thumbnail)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/renovations-renewed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">911</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My baby&#039;s back!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/my-babys-back/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-babys-back</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/my-babys-back/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 22:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/12/05/my-babys-back/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last week-and-a-bit, I&#8217;ve been without my family. Alex and the wee one were out in BC visiting with family. Me? On self-imposed exile in the basement to try and wrap up as much of the renovations as possible. Yes, I need to provide pictures of progress. But you&#8217;ll understand why I can&#8217;t in &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/my-babys-back/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My baby&#039;s back!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last week-and-a-bit, I&#8217;ve been without my family. Alex and the wee one were out in BC visiting with family. Me? On self-imposed exile in the basement to try and wrap up as much of the renovations as possible.<br />
Yes, I need to provide pictures of progress. But you&#8217;ll understand why I can&#8217;t in a moment&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-868"></span>When I got down to work last Monday, I had a huge mountain of work to deal with: installing the laminate floor (including laying down all the foam underlay first, cutting boards to specific lengths and widths), putting in insulation (and cutting to length), putting up vapour barrier, putting in drywall, and starting to mud.<br />
All of this so we can move stuff from the upstairs to the downstairs, so we don&#8217;t feel like we&#8217;re living in a storage locker anymore.<br />
By Monday just passed (3 December), most of this was complete. (I had also dreamt of tiling floors in a closet, the utility room, and the bathroom, but I abandoned that about two days in.) The only really outstanding parts are finishing drywall along one wall (my fancy-schmancy drywall drill bit gave out on me), finishing the mudding, and helping to organise the stuff upstairs so it makes more sense.<br />
Oh, and I cleaned up a bit, too.<br />
When I went to the airport last night to retrieve my family, I was exhausted. Several people remarked that I &#8220;looked like crap&#8221; (or some variant thereof). Which was true. Bags under my eyes, over a week&#8217;s growth of beard (which was itching like crazy, but I was more worried about renovation than shaving), I think the same pair of pants I&#8217;ve worn for a week (my only other pair of cold-weather wear developed a hole in an inconvenient location), my left hip hurts from what I think amounts to seven simultaneous sprains, and who knows what else.<br />
Alex laughed when she saw me. I was probably quite the site. I was happy to see her smile. It had been a while since the last time. I was even happier to see my baby again, who also smiled (and drooled), though likely wondering what happened to daddy&#8217;s face.<br />
It&#8217;s good to have my family back. If nothing else, this past week just reiterates how important it is for me to have them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/my-babys-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">868</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The heating system is complete</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/the-heating-system-is-complete/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-heating-system-is-complete</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/the-heating-system-is-complete/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 05:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/11/the-heating-system-is-complete/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s taken a bit longer to get this one sorted out than I would have liked, but the house is finally completely heated &#8212; upstairs and down &#8212; and with all the sensors needed to make sure it&#8217;s comfortable. Added bonus: we have continual fresh air to eliminate all the foul odours that periodically permeate &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/the-heating-system-is-complete/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The heating system is complete"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s taken a bit longer to get this one sorted out than I would have liked, but the house is finally completely heated &#8212; upstairs and down &#8212; and with all the sensors needed to make sure it&#8217;s comfortable. Added bonus: we have continual fresh air to eliminate all the foul odours that periodically permeate the inside.<br />
The biggest hurdle has just been getting the heated floors to work with our fancy new HRV-cum-fancoil. A problem because we had two different vendors do the install.<br />
<span id="more-844"></span>Canyon, as you know, installed the floor. They got it so we at least were getting warmth when it started to turn cold. But we also needed (by city code) to have airflow in the house, and the new code states thou shalt have an air exchanger. And since you don&#8217;t want to suck in -40 degree air into a warm house, you toss it through an HRV first. And since we have no direct heating source upstairs, we needed a heat source &#8212; a fancoil.<br />
Baker Heating found us a combination HRV and &#8220;fresh air furnace&#8221; (another name for a fancoil). We had to have a number of in-person chats with Phil (the installer) to make sure the furnace was placed properly, to ensure ducting went where we wanted, to align the air intakes and outlets, and to wire it all together.<br />
Technically, this all went well, as we now have a house without all the humidity we&#8217;d been plagued with for weeks and it doesn&#8217;t smell like musty concrete anymore. But it didn&#8217;t go perfectly.<br />
Miscommunication reigns supreme. We didn&#8217;t understand the size of the furnace. We didn&#8217;t realise that the spaces I&#8217;d left for ducting weren&#8217;t big enough. So doorways that I&#8217;d built into walls need to be moved. In other words, my previous exclamation that [[Framing is complete!|the framing was complete]] isn&#8217;t entirely accurate. I&#8217;ve got more work to do.<br />
But at least we can do it in the comfort of warmth. Important, as we&#8217;re likely only a few short weeks from the arrival of snow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/the-heating-system-is-complete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">844</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Framing is complete!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/framing-is-complete/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=framing-is-complete</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/framing-is-complete/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 14:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/02/framing-is-complete/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well&#8230; the walls are all in place, the doorways are in place, the bracing for the bulkhead is in place, and even some of the wiring has already been run. So far, we&#8217;re off to a (mostly) rousing start. But there&#8217;s still a lot left to do. Flooring still remains an issue. We&#8217;re expecting another &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/framing-is-complete/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Framing is complete!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well&#8230; the walls are all in place, the doorways are in place, the bracing for the bulkhead is in place, and even some of the wiring has already been run. So far, we&#8217;re off to a (mostly) rousing start.<br />
But there&#8217;s still a lot left to do.<br />
<span id="more-827"></span>Flooring still remains an issue. We&#8217;re expecting another quote back from Kensington One, which will hopefully lower the cost of the flooring a bit. Alex still wants someone with far more skill than I to handle the tiling (especially with the shower) in the bathroom. Can&#8217;t say I blame her, either &#8212; I&#8217;m not too keen on doing that, myself.<br />
Electrical is much better off than it was a couple of weeks ago. Lights, a fully-wired utility room, proper wiring for both the boiler/floor pump assembly (it had been hacked in for the time being) with a separate switch for the HRV (going in today), and now we&#8217;ve got all the electrical sockets in rec room wired and operational.<br />
As I mentioned, the HRV/fresh air furnace goes in today. That means &#8212; finally &#8212; we get fresh air back in the house. And hopefully all the damned humidity will be sucked out. It&#8217;s a 3-4 day job, having discussed it at length with Phil (the installer) last week. He&#8217;s got his work cut out for him, that&#8217;s for sure.<br />
I&#8217;ve got one wall insulated, but mostly so I could install the two dividing walls that define bedroom from bathroom from office. I still need to insulate the rest, but I want to give some more thought about electrical first. I&#8217;m thinking we&#8217;re fine in the walls now, as I&#8217;m more likely to run lights in the ceiling. That means I can start thinking about ordering drywall.<br />
But I think the floor is more important. That way we can get all of our junk currently wedged into corners upstairs moved downstairs, and empty our Public Storage locker.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/framing-is-complete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">827</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We have heat!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/we-have-heat/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=we-have-heat</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/we-have-heat/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 04:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/09/12/we-have-heat/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just as the first sub-zero forecast appears on our horizon, we have some heat to keep us from freezing. It&#8217;s taken a while longer than we planned, but thankfully it&#8217;s now up and running. The house is warm again (and not due to summer temperatures), and our old hot water tank has been permanently disconnected. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/we-have-heat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "We have heat!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just as the first sub-zero forecast appears on our horizon, we have some heat to keep us from freezing. It&#8217;s taken a while longer than we planned, but thankfully it&#8217;s now up and running.<br />
The house is warm again (and not due to summer temperatures), and our old hot water tank has been permanently disconnected.<br />
<span id="more-820"></span>So here&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve got in our basement:<br />
[flickr]photo:2109438328[/flickr]<br />
From right to left (there&#8217;s a reason for the reverse order) we have a new hot water heater, the boiler, and the &#8220;board&#8221; that distributes heat from the boiler.<br />
Okay, so first, the boiler. It&#8217;s a Laars Mascot 150. Technically, this is a pretty simple little doodad. It consists of a natural gas heater, a water loop, a blower, a small computer with temperature sensors, and a couple of solenoids to distribute the flow. There&#8217;s a wad of piping that comes in and out of the boiler, sending it to two places: the hot water tank and &#8220;the board&#8221;.<br />
[flickr]photo:2109438416[/flickr]<br />
The hot water tank uses what&#8217;s called indirect heat. In other words, there&#8217;s no flame under the tank to heat the water. Instead, a pipe of 160 degree water comes from the boiler to heat the cold domestic water. The tank is about twice the size of our previous heater. Alex can finally have that bath without running out of hot water!<br />
Finally is &#8220;the board&#8221;. This is what provides heat to the floor. Allow me to annotate what you see here.<br />
[flickr]photo:2109438384[/flickr]<br />
At the far left are two pipes &#8212; the return to the boiler and the inlet into the board. At the bottom left are the pipes that put water into the floor. On the bottom right are the pipes coming back into the board, with solenoids that open or close the circuits depending on the thermostats. At the top is a pump that forces the flow to continue.<br />
Now you might notice the inlet and outlet positions as being a bit &#8220;odd&#8221; &#8212; they&#8217;re right next to each other, with nothing (effectively) stopping the hot water from being sucked out and sent right back to the boiler. I thought this odd, too. Apparently, this is to protect the boiler.<br />
The boiler needs to always have circulation, otherwise pressure builds up and &#8230; well, it might not be good. The board is built such that if the board&#8217;s pump fails, the boiler remains unharmed.<br />
This equals heat. It&#8217;s not perfect &#8212; we still need to get air circulation and heat the upstairs, but this is a good start.<br />
Now I just need to get the framing all done, run electrical, get a floor laid, insulate, wallboard, mud, and paint.<br />
No problem&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/09/we-have-heat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">820</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
