<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bars &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/bars/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 19:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen. Thanksgiving &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thanksgiving in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen.<br />
Thanksgiving &#8212; for Canadians, anyway &#8212; comes on the second Monday of October. Officially, that&#8217;s today, but many Canadians tend to have the feast on the Sunday owing to a need to travel. And since Thanksgiving isn&#8217;t observed in Costa Rica (in fact, it&#8217;s barely known outside the expat community), it&#8217;s not even a blip on the radar.<br />
Which begs, of course, the question: How does one get their turkey fix?<br />
<span id="more-1134"></span>Well, luckily for us, there&#8217;s a whack of people who have that exact same problem, and are significantly better organised than we are at this point. They&#8217;re the <a href="http://www.canadianclubcr.com/">Canadian Club of Costa Rica</a>, a collection of former Canucks who want to preserve some of the feelings of home down here in the tropics. We&#8217;d first heard about them not long after first arriving, but hadn&#8217;t moved on anything due to the other aspects of trying to live here &#8230; like getting internet and a phone.<br />
I digress&#8230;<br />
Alex, though one of the other mothers in her playgroup, found out that the Canadian Club (why does this always <a href="http://www.canadianclubwhisky.com/">make me think of whisky</a>?) was holding a Thanksgiving &#8220;dinner&#8221; (more like a lunch) at &#8212; of all places &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/">Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo</a>, our (well, my) favourite bar in Santa Ana.<br />
The opportunity to sit down with other expats, chat, and have some turkey was rather appealing. So we signed up for a pair of seats. On Sunday, just after Mi Pequeña Niña woke up from her morning nap, we headed out to quell our turkey fix.<br />
A large Canadian flag was draped over one of the bushes out in front of the restaurant. Many of the people attending had to drive from much further distances, so it was helpful as a landmark. The restaurant was chosen (I think) mostly because the owner (I believe his name is &#8220;Paul&#8221;) is an expat from Vancouver.<br />
Upon entry, I quickly realised that the Canadian Club&#8217;s primary membership seems to be retirees. I hadn&#8217;t even considered that fact (rather stupidly!). Alex and I were among the youngest there &#8212; our daughter, included. Only two other children (no older than 10), and one couple that I could see that could have been in their late 20s.<br />
[flickr]tag:thanksgiving+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
We were at Table 13. Not the last table in the arrangement, but apparently the unluckiest &#8212; we were served last. We were seated with a man who&#8217;s been in Costa Rica about as long as I have (Steve) and his American friend, Jo. Jo has been here 17 years so seems more Costa Rican than she is American.<br />
It took a while for the MC to get everyone&#8217;s attention as the conversation just kept going. Ten minutes later, they were going over the details of the afternoon&#8217;s events (a funny hat contest, a raffle for a round-trip ticket on Continental, our meals, etc.), and that the Ambassador would be dropping by. It hadn&#8217;t even occurred to me that Canada&#8217;s ambassador to Costa Rica (whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten, and even Google can&#8217;t easily find it &#8212; bad architecture, Canada!) would come to such an affair. Nice guy, though. Flatlander from Saskatchewan.<br />
While we were waiting for things to get moving, we ordered up some beverages. I went with my usual Imperial (kind of hard to pass up on), Alex went with a white wine, Jo went with a Bavaria, and I think Steve only had club soda (Canada Dry Club Soda, to be precise). But we had to get ice &#8212; Alex&#8217;s wine came unchilled, and Jo seemed to like ice in her beer (a common practice here for some). The ice came in a large, red bucket with a pair of toothed metal tongs.<br />
MPN had fun for a while, laughing and giggling, but she didn&#8217;t take too well to being stuck in one place and not being able to walk around on her own. This happens frequently (usually after she&#8217;s finished eating, and especially on airplanes), and can sometimes lead to &#8230; incidents. Such as the one we had yesterday.<br />
Remember the ice bucket? What happens if you leave an uninsulated plastic bucket of ice out in a tropical climate? Right &#8212; you get water. Cold water.<br />
Ice cold water.<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña decided that the bucket would be fun to play with. (She does this with most things put in front of her, including (but not limited to) cutlery, glass bottles, plates, sunglasses, keys, paper, books, tablecloths, flowers &#8230; basically anything she can reach.) Sometimes she plays with those objects with other things in her hand, such as her small plastic feeding spoon. And sometimes, she gets just the right grip&#8230;<br />
Suddenly, I felt a wash of extreme cold in my lap. I thought she&#8217;d spilled her juice. Then I saw the bucket, heard MPN starting to scream (the shock got to her, too), and noticed that my lap was very wet. Ice cold, as it were.<br />
Lunch/dinner was actually pretty good, considering Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo isn&#8217;t exactly known for its Canuck cuisine. (It&#8217;s not known at all, to be frank.) But it was real turkey, with potatoes, stuffing (decent stuffing, at that), creamed beans, and cranberry jelly (which I fed to MPN). Dessert? Alex&#8217;s favourite &#8212; pumpkin pie.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stick around long after the meal was over. MPN was rapidly heading towards naptime, and the wetness of my shorts was finally getting to me.<br />
Sadly, not enough to induce turkey coma, but certainly better than if we&#8217;d gone with no turkey at all. I think we&#8217;re going to have to figure out how to get a turkey for Christmas, though &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to go another holiday without turkey. I honestly miss it too much, and there&#8217;s just such potential down here. With luck, we&#8217;ll be able to invite a few people over to make it worthwhile.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1134</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Second weekend in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=second-weekend-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heredia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You might be wondering: Gee, Geoff, where are all the posts you had for Costa Rica? Well, it&#8217;s not that I don&#8217;t want them up, it&#8217;s an issue of timing. I can&#8217;t really go into that right now, but let&#8217;s just say that this is the best way to have it for now. But on &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Second weekend in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You might be wondering: Gee, Geoff, where are all the posts you had for Costa Rica? Well, it&#8217;s not that I don&#8217;t want them up, it&#8217;s an issue of timing. I can&#8217;t really go into that right now, but let&#8217;s just say that this is the best way to have it for now.<br />
But on the bright side, there is more stuff to come shortly. Our month o&#8217; meetings continues as we head down to Panama [<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o5g2yyvdjrE">insert Van Halen here</a>] tomorrow for a client kick-off. This should be fun.<br />
First, though, let me recap our weekend just past.<br />
<span id="more-1011"></span>Friday night was another exploration for us. We&#8217;re still trying to figure out what all the local spots are, which ones are good and which ones we can skip. (Thursday night, after a meeting with Mama Luz &#8212; our realtor who has helped us so much in finding places to live &#8212; we&#8217;d found a place called &#8220;Bar Amigo&#8221;, which turned out to be a gringo place. It was okay &#8212; great hot dogs &#8212; but a place to visit rarely.) Across the road from Yakky&#8217;s was another restaurant/bar (they&#8217;re all restaurant/bars here) where we had a couple of drinks.<br />
[flickr]photo:2616702562(small)[/flickr]<br />
Realising that wasn&#8217;t the place we wanted to be, we shuffled out and drove back into downtown Santa Ana (which doesn&#8217;t have a &#8220;downtown&#8221; area, but it&#8217;s what most Westerners would associate with) to find a new place. The name I totally forget &#8212; yet we went back there on Sunday for the EuroCup final. It was more of a Tican place &#8212; menus in Spanish, and typÃƒ ­co food played heavily.<br />
I love Costa Rica for the seafood. I have not had such good seafood in a very long time. And it&#8217;s really inexpensive. (You can pay Western prices for seafood quite easily here, I should add. One of the reasons we&#8217;re looking around is to find where the locals eat, which is generally cheap and always tasty.) We even racked up a couple of pool games on tables that looked like they&#8217;d just been unwrapped.<br />
That&#8217;s when we met the owner, who&#8217;s name also escapes me. A tall, thin white guy from Vancouver, who felt that his life&#8217;s ambition was to open a bar. A business guy, no doubt by his demeanour, who really just wanted something simple to do with life. I&#8217;m really beginning to see the appeal.<br />
Mark and Jason decided that they just had to go clubbing. But I&#8217;m not the clubbing type. Never have been, and thankfully never will be. By that point, I was the sober one, so drove them to a club next to our temporary office space, and headed home.<br />
What happened to Mark and Jason, you ask? Well, I can&#8217;t speak for them. But let&#8217;s say that when I saw them the next morning, Mark had a big cup of coffee already in his hand, and the first word out of Jason&#8217;s mouth was: &#8220;COFFEE&#8221;.<br />
After a small desayuno at a small café in Escazu, we all headed into San José for something we wanted to do: check out the Central Market.<br />
The trip in wasn&#8217;t so bad. Thankfully due to two other runs into San José for meetings, we had a vague idea of where we were going. It wasn&#8217;t too hard to find our way to the Central area. But we weren&#8217;t in any hurry, so Jason took us on a bit of a detour around the Central area before coming back in to find a place to park. Easier said than done, let me tell you. But we actually managed to find a place right behind the Teatro Nacional (National Theatre).<br />
[flickr]photo:2621711390(small)[/flickr]<br />
We wandered around the Square a bit before walking up and down Avenue Central, which is largely a pedestrian mall in the centre of the city. On Saturday, the place is packed. Not quite wall-to-wall people but it was certainly more people than I remembered from January 2005, when Alex and I did the same walk. Line ups were everywhere. We&#8217;d seen a huge one at the hospital just west of the Central area, and every single ATH (the Spanish acronym for ATM) had at least 15 people waiting. The money changing lines were even bigger. Apparently, this was the big day to go out.<br />
Reaching the eastern end of the pedestrian area, we double-backed and headed west. Mercado Central (the Central Market) was at the other end. Everywhere we walked, the street was dotted with cows. Not real cows, but statues of cows. Sculptures, really. Calgary had done the same thing about 5-6 years ago. The cows here are more plentiful in number (the Multiplaza in Escazu has at least a dozen of them) and far more decorated. Some are just downright hilarious.<br />
[flickr]photo:2621713340(small)[/flickr]<br />
Lots of people selling all sorts of things. While Mark might be able to pass for a Tico (if he didn&#8217;t dress so snazzy), Jason (being tall and blonde) and I (being dorky and not at all Tican) stick out quite easily. That means everyone running up to us offering &#8220;Ray Ban&#8221; sunglasses and &#8220;Rolex&#8221; watches. I was sooooo tempted to look at the Rolexes just to see what they looked like. But somehow, I managed to refrain. Next time, I&#8217;m giving these guys the gears. Fakes aren&#8217;t as easy to come across in Costa Rica as I&#8217;d thought, but it&#8217;s far from hidden.<br />
At the other end of the mall, we found the Mercado Central. Somehow, Alex and I had missed this when we were there. It&#8217;s an entire block of twisting hallways barely wide enough for a person to walk through with all the stores&#8217; wares bulging beyond their walls. It&#8217;s dark, it&#8217;s crowded, your senses are assaulted by unknown sounds and smells, and in some areas you&#8217;re straining to see through the dark. In short, it&#8217;s <em>awesome</em>.<br />
[flickr]photo:2621714542(small)[/flickr]<br />
We stumbled up to a little coffee shop in the north-east corner. Hopping up on three stools, we stared as the coffee roasted in an oven, pouring into a massive cooling bin. The smell of roasting coffee wafted about, overpowering the fish stalls about 20 feet away. Mark and Jason were in need of coffee. I still don&#8217;t drink it (I promise to document the event when it does happen), so endulged in a hot chocolate. Mark and Jason swear that it&#8217;s the best coffee that they&#8217;ve had &#8230; outside of Italy.<br />
[flickr]photo:2620893469(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2621719596(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620898829(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620901037(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620902469(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
(Mark has a pretty good theory: the Italians haven&#8217;t invented a lot of foods. They imported coffee, tomatoes, pasta, and rice from other cultures. But they perfected them. There&#8217;s a reason why Italians are noted for those things, because they got them exactly right.)<br />
The rest of the market unveiled treasures the likes of which are hard to imagine. This is not a tourist market. This is a working market. Yes, there are a crapload of tourists here, and there are a number of stalls that cater only to tourists. But go in deeply enough, and there are foods you don&#8217;t recognise, smells you can&#8217;t identify, and more than a few sounds that would be foreign in almost any market in Canada or the United States.<br />
[flickr]photo:2620904215(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620905907(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620907961(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620909845(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620911323(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2621735674(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2621737606(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620917647(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620919179(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2620922181(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Finding our rented car still intact, we headed back out of the city and over to Cariari to find a music store for Mark (he wants a guitar). Turns out the Cariari Mall is quite the dive. We didn&#8217;t stay long, desiring to go to Escazu instead. Stepping outside, a good clap of thunder told us the sunny part of the day was officially over. By the time we got to the Multiplaza, we were in the midst of the heaviest rain we&#8217;ve seen since arriving. Outside for maybe 10 seconds (between the car and the mall entrance), we got a good soaking. The rain lasted over an hour and half.<br />
[flickr]photo:2621746892(small)[/flickr]<br />
Saturday night was a quiet one. I ate at home, though we all went out in search of something to do beyond bars. A bowling alley, or something. Movies here are limited, and <em>Wall-E</em> isn&#8217;t out yet. We ended up at Yakky&#8217;s again. Mark and Jason ate. I talked.<br />
On Sunday, Mark and I went into the office to access the internet. I feel bad about thieving internet at the apartment, and the signal hasn&#8217;t been reliable the previous few days. When all you have is a small blurry video and scratchy audio to see your wife and child, you&#8217;re willing to spend time in an office to see them. Sadly, they were out.<br />
Just before 13:00, we were back at the bar we&#8217;d found on Friday night, seated at a table in clear view of a big screen TV, watching the live broadcast of the Spain vs. Germany final game of the EuroCup 2008 series. I honestly expected more people to be in the bar, but I could also hear people in their homes not far away, too. Football here is popular (not American Football, which is what Canada and United States prefer to watch), and I&#8217;d heard &#8220;second only to religion&#8221;. Admittedly, I&#8217;m not sure how true that is.<br />
[flickr]photo:2624479679(small)[/flickr]<br />
It was a great game, though. Well-played, even if it there was only one goal.<br />
It started to rain as we drove home after a quick stop at the Auto Mercado for some things around the house. And it rained for the next 4-5 hours &#8212; a rarity here. Rain usually lasts at most an hour. But it did make for a nice cool night.<br />
[flickr]photo:2625319096(small)[/flickr]<br />
Coming soon: Scenes from Panama!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1011</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First weekend in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=first-weekend-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 19:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "First weekend in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, bought the things we need to make life reasonable (note: not &#8220;comfortable&#8221; &#8212; we&#8217;re still working on that), moved into a temporary office, got connected (still need cell phones), started working on new work, and had a surprising number of meetings given that there&#8217;s only four of us.<br />
So when we got to the end of the week, we had pretty much declared ourselves &#8220;beat&#8221;. Had we been a lot more set up than we are now, we&#8217;d probably have just gone home to our respective places, kicked back, and relaxed. But it&#8217;s hard to do that when you have to flag down a cab. Which you can&#8217;t here, for some reason.<br />
We rented a car instead.<br />
<span id="more-1010"></span>Sooner or later, you have to decide when enough is enough. Spending hours (I&#8217;m not joking, by the way) waiting for a taxi is not fun. While they&#8217;re fairly inexpensive (rarely more than a couple of dollars), it&#8217;s a colossal waste of time. As we&#8217;re all Type A people, it&#8217;s beyond frustrating.<br />
For the record, Jason wants to be a rally driver. I&#8217;m certain of this. We&#8217;ve got some dinky white Nissan that I swear could be foot-powered for all the oomph it has. But in Jason&#8217;s hands, that think could handle the Paris-Dakar race. On Sunday, we were exploring old Escazu, and Jason was whipping up and down roads like it was a marked course. No problems at all. This guy has adapted to Costa Rican driving.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603884205(small)[/flickr]<br />
Our first task with the car? Shopping.<br />
Yes, this was our wild Friday night. We went to the nearby Mas Por Menos (&#8220;More for Less&#8221;) store for various odds-and-ends that we&#8217;re all missing. I didn&#8217;t get much (I don&#8217;t want to get much; Alex and I are aiming for a more minimalist existence), but Mark filled a shopping cart.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603881365(small)[/flickr]<br />
After that, we went out in search of dinner. We searched for a Tican restaurant (we&#8217;ve done <em>gringo</em> to death) and found a place called Yakky&#8217;s. Kind of a dive, but by 21:00 the place was packed. The food was great, the beer was cheap (Imperial is the Costa Rican favourite, and it&#8217;s about $1 a bottle &#8212; markups are really small here). For the three of us, it was only $60 with a lot of food, several beers, and Mark and Jason endulged in a little JD. I drove us home.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603882479(small)[/flickr]<br />
Saturday was a trip into Escazu for some shopping. We were aiming for a place we thought was called &#8220;Se Marco&#8221; (turned out it was &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, which is a name of a department store ala The Bay). We found a box store called EPA, which is mostly a home improvement place. Mark loaded another shopping cart. Jason got keys cut for our office space, and we all got slop buckets and mops so we can actually clean our places. The cat hair in mine (Asia&#8217;s shedding like crazy) is getting out of hand.<br />
We found our way to Grau, a local chain of coffee shops. I still don&#8217;t drink coffee (I imagine it won&#8217;t be long before I do), but Jason and Mark were dying for one. I settled for a pineapple smoothie. It&#8217;s called a &#8220;batido&#8221;, which directly translates to &#8220;beaten&#8221;. Mixed with milk. Mmmmmm.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603885915(small)[/flickr]<br />
A trip to the mall found the real &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, and also the times for the English showing of <em>The Hulk</em> that we saw that night. (I have to say, a surprisingly good movie.) Not far from there was Aliss, another store that has a massive baby section that Alex will love.<br />
All the while, I should point out, Mark was searching for a french press so he could make coffee. This was almost an exercise in futility. French presses aren&#8217;t common here (yet). Unlike in North America, where you can about trip over all the Bodums, they&#8217;re a rarity even in the gringo centres. I kept telling Mark that he needed <a href="http://www.zurqui.com/crinfocus/cr/coffee.html">the Costa Rican method of making coffee</a>, but couldn&#8217;t remember the damn name of it (Chorreador de café), nor easily find it.<br />
Something I noticed as we went from store to store to store. The Euro Cup was playing on virtually every set. Everywhere we went, eyes were glued to sets. Football (&#8220;soccer&#8221; to us heathen North Americans) is second in importance only to the church. I think it even eclipses family when it comes to certain games. You really need to pull a sales guy away from the game to get his (or her, but they&#8217;re usually male) attention.<br />
We ate lunch in likely the last Chichi&#8217;s restaurant on Planet Earth. Might have been the prototype, too. Despite the disappointment in realising it was a restaurant chain, it was actually pretty good. Possibly the best fajitas I&#8217;ve had, actually.<br />
Sunday was notably quieter, with really only our excursion into old Escazu being a notable point. In fact, Ihad to work on a priority item for the Toronto office. It is nice to be wanted, though. Tricky part is the lack of connectivity at home, still. Weak internet means no phone or means of communication with the outside world. It&#8217;s a bit of a nuisance, admittedly. But slowly, adjusting.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603887367(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I love pubs</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/i-love-pubs/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-love-pubs</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/i-love-pubs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2005 15:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[england]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/02/i-love-pubs/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[This entry originally posted on How To Get Lost: I love pubs.] Last night, Amy and I decided to check out some of the local pubs near our hotel. Here&#8217;s what we noticed. Local pubs have a great atmosphere. Some don&#8217;t, and you can tell right away &#8212; when everyone stares at the &#8220;outsiders&#8221;. All &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/i-love-pubs/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I love pubs"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><cite>[This entry originally posted on <a href="http://www.howtogetlost.com/">How To Get Lost</a>: <a href="http://www.howtogetlost.com/2005/05/02/i-love-pubs/">I love pubs</a>.]</cite><br />
Last night, Amy and I decided to check out some of the local pubs near our hotel. Here&#8217;s what we noticed.</p>
<ol>
<li>Local pubs have a great atmosphere. Some don&#8217;t, and you can tell right away &#8212; when everyone stares at the &#8220;outsiders&#8221;.</li>
<li>All food and drink is ordered at the bar. Ain&#8217;t no waitstaff.</li>
<li>Guinness comes in two varieties: &#8220;Normal&#8221; and &#8220;Cold&#8221;.</li>
<li>Guinness tastes <em>way</em> better in England.</li>
<li>Pubs aren&#8217;t as smoky as we&#8217;d expected.</li>
<li>Pubs close at 23:00. What the heck is up with that?!</li>
<li>Fish and chips isn&#8217;t just a meal &#8212; it&#8217;s almost a religious experience.</li>
</ol>
<p><a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03532.JPG" alt="A typical British pub ... and dark" width="300" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/i-love-pubs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">520</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes-Benz meetings, team building</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mercedes-benz-team-building</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2005 04:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/03/mercedes-benz-team-building/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Allard and I hit the restaurant in the main atrium for breakfast, joined shortly thereafter by Christian and a very tired-looking Jules. Powdered eggs aren&#8217;t exactly the breakfast of champions. Jules has been up late working on presentations for today. Allard and I are thankfully exempt from any actual presentations. We&#8217;re more or less along &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mercedes-Benz meetings, team building"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Allard and I hit the restaurant in the main atrium for breakfast, joined shortly thereafter by Christian and a very tired-looking Jules. Powdered eggs aren&#8217;t exactly the breakfast of champions. Jules has been up late working on presentations for today. Allard and I are thankfully exempt from any actual presentations. We&#8217;re more or less along for the ride.<br />
Actually, me more than Allard. Allard, at least, is the Technical Director. He needs to be there because the client knows who he is. He needs to be there because some of MBIT will be there. Why do *I* need to be there? Well, I can&#8217;t say for sure, because I really don&#8217;t know, but I think it comes down to the Client-Side Rearchitecture project that I&#8217;m spearheading, and that Allard won&#8217;t be here tomorrow (he&#8217;s only here for a day).<br />
<span id="more-406"></span>We hit the office briefly, just long enough for a quick email check and my morning run at the comics. We were starting at 9:00, and soon we were off &#8212; just across the road, mind you &#8212; to the Chicago Tribune building. The Tribune is one of Chicago&#8217;s oldest and most respected newspapers. Its head office is a massive neo-gothic edifice hovering near the shore of the Chicago River. It&#8217;s not huge, at least by modern standards. The outside is adorned with ornate stonework, flying buttresses (or at least would be, were they on the ground), and even has 500 stones from various places around the world (and the moon).<br />
The inside is almost as impressive as the outside. The main lobby is condensed (the footprint is about the size of a regular squash court), but with a high, wood-lined ceiling, and etched stonework (containing a variety of quotes by a lot of people I don&#8217;t know). This is the sort of stle that used to be put into buildings. Everything is pre-fab, now. They just don&#8217;t make &#8217;em like they used to. Opposite the doors is the security desk. The building is secure &#8212; you can&#8217;t enter without an employee or guest pass. We went to the desk, one at a time, got our guest passes, and found our way to the elevators to take us to the meeting rooms.<br />
The Huron meeting room is in the second sub-basement. No windows. No fresh air. Complete, total, and utter isolation from everything. In theory, a great location for a meeting. (In reality, it&#8217;s a tad harsh.) The Mercedes team was a bit late arriving, no doubt due to traffic (air and ground). Before long, we were set up and ready to roll.<br />
First up on the agenda were introductions. Most of us knew the rest, either through previous meetings or through email and phone conversations. When you have over 40 people in a room, it often helps to know who each person is, what they do, and how they&#8217;re going to contribute to everything. One at a time, we went around, saying our names and what we did. It was Jerry, Critical Mass&#8217; CEO, who had the best opening:<br />
&#8220;Hi, my name is Jerry, and I&#8217;m an alcoholic.&#8221;<br />
I&#8217;d been waiting for *years* to hear someone say that during introductions. I&#8217;d debated many times on saying it, myself, but had never got up the gumption to do so. &#8216;Course, now that someone has said it, I&#8217;ll have to refrain from using it for a while, lest someone think I&#8217;m trying to copycat Jerry.<br />
The meetings were long and a little dull. The same can be said of any meeting I attend that I&#8217;m not directly involved in. In fact, I&#8217;ve been known to fall asleep in them. (I nodded off at one point during today&#8217;s.) Why? I&#8217;m not sure. Could be stimulation, or more importantly, the complete lack thereof. It doesn&#8217;t even matter how much sleep I get. I found university exceptionally hard, because few of the professors really cared about the students, and preferred to ramble on and on about whatever topic they liked talking about. (Thankfully, I had a number of professors who were quite engaging.) It might explain why my marks weren&#8217;t exactly stellar.<br />
The meetings ended with the introduction of the team building event. Last year, we engaged in the Amazing Freeze (see [[The Amazing Freeze]]), which I found to be quite directed. This one was much more free-form. We didn&#8217;t really have the same level of competition, either. This time, we split into groups (four to five people, not unlike last year), and were given a topic upon which to &#8220;research&#8221;. My team (Andrew, Eric, Jules, Lark, and myself) received &#8220;Integration of Experience&#8221;.<br />
If you&#8217;re looking at that and wondering what on Earth that means, you&#8217;re not alone. The five us were thinking the same thing.<br />
Our first stop was the hotel. We wanted to dump off our bags (laptops, and in Lark&#8217;s case &#8212; her bags, she hadn&#8217;t checked in yet) and get changed for the dinner after the event (we were told to dress nicely). We met in the lobby along with a couple of the other teams (we weren&#8217;t the only ones with the idea) and rolled out.<br />
We had been given several potential locations to go to in the process of working out our topics. They included the Sears Tower, Millennium Park (not be mistaken with Calgary&#8217;s skatepark), the Zoo, and Navy Pier. We decided that we didn&#8217;t want to run into the other teams, and chose the John Hancock Tower, the little brother to the Sears Tower. We piled into two cabs (Andrew and I in the first; Eric, Lark, and Jules in the second), and promptly lost track of each other.<br />
Yeah. So not a way to start off a team-building event.<br />
The problem is that our cabs didn&#8217;t really coordinate with each other. Our cab stopped on the north side of the building, while the other cab stopped on the south. We looked all over for each other, but never caught sight while we were at ground level. Andrew and I decided we&#8217;d hit the Observation Desk in a vain effort to find them. Even doing what Andrew called a &#8220;Keystone Cop&#8221; (starting at the same point, walking in opposite directions, meeting at the opposite side), we couldn&#8217;t find them. Back down to the ground floor, we tried the 96th floor, which has a bar. Tucked away in a dark corner, we found them.<br />
Eric had spied a sign outside of the Contemporary Art Museum a couple of blocks away on the way to the tower. We hiked over, and the four of them posed in front of the &#8220;Experience&#8221; sign while I took the picture. A strange sculpture of a Yugo towing a trailer, jacknifed vertically, gave us the inspiration for Jules playing the role of Superman.<br />
From there, we walked over to the Water Tower, one of Chicago&#8217;s landmarks. The Water Tower sits in a traffic island. One side is north-bound traffic, the other south-bound. To the east is a large sandstone building (which was related to the tower at one point in its history). From what we could tell, it was a pumping station. Curious to see if it was still a pumping station, we peered in the windows. This lead us to our epiphony.<br />
Integration of Experience: Every municipality of any size needs water. It&#8217;s one of our basic needs. The infrastructure that supplies that water is complex and so necessary that deprivation of mere hours can be troublesome. The water pumping station was old &#8212; probably dating back to the earlier days of Chicago. It&#8217;s definitely 1800s or earlier. Yet the equipment inside is much newer &#8212; maybe only a couple of decades older. Somewhere along the line, they had to rip out the old equipment and insert the new without depriving downtown Chicago one of its primary puming stations. And so we have our integration of experience: without the ability to integrate the old and the new, a lot of people would have had a lousy experience.<br />
Hey, we&#8217;re a marketing company. We&#8217;re paid to bullshit well.<br />
We celebrated our successful venture with drinks at &#8220;Iron&#8221; Mike Dytka&#8217;s bar, a few blocks away. After the libations, the five of us crammed ourselves into a very small cab (it certainly felt like that in the backseat &#8212; Eric, the Chicago native, sat in front) and we found our way to Marche, a very chic little joint west of downtown. It&#8217;s in the old warehouse district, now completely refurbished into the chic restaurant district.<br />
Marche was described as being French. I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s a particularly accurate description, since it doesn&#8217;t really look or feel French. I&#8217;d say more nouveau cuisine than anything else. The interior matched the style of the food &#8212; eclectic and funky, and making use of the features inherent to the building. High ceilings were decorated, the old elevator shaft doors decorated (or removed entirely). The inner courtyard to the complex (which we could see through windows) still bore the names of the companies that had once lived here.<br />
Like I said before, Chicago has a lot of history. I could come to love this city.<br />
Returning to the hotel after dinner, we adjourned to the BiG Bar, the lounge in the atrium of the Hyatt. It runs the full width of the atrium, about 100 metres or so. Along the glass wall that looks out onto Wacker St. and the Chicago River were four levels of various kinds of booze. It looks very impressive on first glance; when you look closer, you&#8217;ll see that there are duplicates.<br />
A small group of us grabbed a table and began to settle in for a nightcap. Martinis &#8212; chocolate ones &#8212; were the main order for the first round. I have to admit that I didn&#8217;t particularly like the one I had (I&#8217;ve had much better), and switched to a beer afterwards. Elenor and Mabel went for what I can only call a bad idea: the BiG martini. A 48 fluid ounce, gut-busting monster that shocked the both of them. I don&#8217;t think anyone had really realized just how humungous this drink was going to be.<br />
Oops.<br />
A live band took to the stage, playing some of the great Motown tunes, only very badly. (Well, not really badly, but I&#8217;ve heard them much better.) Christine, already quite into the groove, decided that she was going to run up on stage and dance very badly &#8212; y&#8217;know, to fit in with the music. Mabel declared that she was following. Taro, just to make things interesting, bet Mabel $50 that she couldn&#8217;t. So the two of them pranced off to prove Taro wrong.<br />
At first, it looked like Taro&#8217;s bet was safe, as the musician nearest to the edge of the stage wasn&#8217;t about to let them up. A couple of songs later, though, we heard a distinctly familiar, albeit quiet, &#8220;Hi!&#8221;. We turned around to see Mabel leaping into the air, trying to speak into a microphone that was a good two feet higher up than the top of her head (the musician was quite tall). Returning triumphant, Taro presented Mabel with her winnings.<br />
The betting didn&#8217;t end there. Next up, Mabel was then challenged to drink the remaining 47 oz of the drink she had left. In less than two minutes. This caused a huge round of &#8220;you gotta be kidding!&#8221; laughter. Mabel, of course, stepped up to the challenge.<br />
Using her hands, she scooped out all the ice in the drink (there was quite a bit of it), and the clock started. You&#8217;ve never seen such a serious look on someone trying to drink so much so fast. We joked that Benno was falling in love. I held mostly-official time by the clock on my cell phone. Christine recorded the entire event for posterity with her digital camera. We all egged Mabel on.<br />
One minute, 45 seconds. With a belch to boot.<br />
The table rotated its compliment a few times before Mabel convinced Benno to go clubbing. The rest of us carefully backed out and made a run for the elevators to our rooms. We still have another day of meetings to live through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#039;s Wedding</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2004 22:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irako]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/28/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I woke just before sunrise. I probably should have gotten up to look around, but decided that I&#8217;d rather sleep a bit more. I had a sneaky suspicion that it was going to be a long day. I woke again around 7:00, when my alarm went off. Jen sounded like she was still asleep (though &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#039;s Wedding"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke just before sunrise. I probably should have gotten up to look around, but decided that I&#8217;d rather sleep a bit more. I had a sneaky suspicion that it was going to be a long day.<br />
I woke again around 7:00, when my alarm went off. Jen sounded like she was still asleep (though she claims she wasn&#8217;t), so I opted not to disturb her and went to go see what the area looked like with the rising sun.<br />
<span id="more-335"></span>Back up to the roof and the observation deck, I took in the morning glory of Irako, and the mouth of the bay beyond the tip of the peninsula. Smog lined the shores on the other side, it&#8217;s thick, brown haze unmistakable. (By noon, the brown would be replaced by a thick, white haze, obscuring the other shore.)<br />
We headed down for breakfast around 8:00. The buffet was a little different than the night before. Still offering miso soup and soba noodles, the selection also offered fruit, eggs, and a variety of Japanese and western choices. Chris convinced Garth, Jen, and I to try a Japanese plum, which is sour and salty. Garth liked it, but Jen and I found it less palatable.<br />
Mind you, the same division in tastes exists among the Japanese. Like with several things (like natto), they either love it or hate it. Few just accept or tolerate.<br />
Shinichiro and Riko appeared soon after Mr. and Mrs. May appeared. Tony would straggle down a little later, not looking much different than he had the night before. (As Tony put several times, life on Saipan is slow, so as a result, he&#8217;s slow. Take that for what it&#8217;s worth&#8230;)<br />
Jen and I had come prepared for a little excursion down to the beach following breakfast, and took our leave of the others before they had finished. We took a steep set of stairs from an exit on the west side of the hotel down to a service road of some kind, which took us to the hotel&#8217;s driveway, and down to the main road that runs along the coast. Along one side is a cycling path, which guided us down and around the windy coastline.<br />
It took a while to find a break in the dense tropical vegetation that would show us a path down to the beach. The time wasn&#8217;t poorly spent, however, since the walk was warm, and the sounds of songbirds were an absolute delight. But as we came closer to the surf, the rushing of the waves would become the dominant music.<br />
The trail down to the beach was not maintained, formed over years of people trying to get down to the beach from the road. It&#8217;s about 100 feet in elevation, and you need to be a bit of a mountain goat to do it easily. Fortunately, both Jen and I do a lot of hiking, so the trail wasn&#8217;t an issue.<br />
The beach is long &#8212; a couple of kilometres in total length, following the curve from the point to the bulge that the hotel sits on. The beach mostly disappears there, before reforming on the eastern side of the bulge. The section we were on is littered with tetrapods &#8212; concrete forms with four &#8220;legs&#8221; sticking out at 120 angles to each other. They form an interlocking pattern that creates a barrier against beach erosion.<br />
We wandered the beach a little while, taking pictures and enjoying the sound of the waves on the shore. Jen played chicken with the incoming surf, looking for unique shells, while I walked around taking pictures. But we couldn&#8217;t stay long, and soon had to head back to get ready for the wedding.<br />
I ironed out the wrinkles formed from packing my suit (thankfully minimized), showered, and shaved. Jen showered and dressed, then packed up our collective collection o&#8217; crap and headed back down to the lobby. We had to check out prior to the wedding, and put our bags in a holding room for the day.<br />
Tony and I had been drafted to greet incoming guests, having them sign their names, presenting them with drink tickets, and showing them to a waiting area until they were ready for us at the chapel.<br />
Tony and I had a good laugh at this. Here were two gaijin white guys (one of whom knows enough Japanese to be dangerous, the other can say &#8220;hello&#8221;, &#8220;please&#8221;, and &#8220;sushi&#8221;) greeting people who know a couple words of English and telling them what to do. As Tony said several times: &#8220;Better to laugh, &#8216;cuz crying ain&#8217;t gonna do anything for you.&#8221;<br />
At a little after noon, we were directed towards the second floor (one floor below the lobby), and out to the chapel. The chapel is a small building with a tall spire, just slightly separated from the hotel building. (The Irako View Hotel must do a lot of weddings.) The inside was nice, if perhaps a little austere. But it was small, so it didn&#8217;t seem too awkward.<br />
We entered through a door on the north side of the building, and entered the octagonal chapel room. The western three sides had massive windows that overlooked the water and across the bay. (It would make taking pictures a little difficult.) Chris&#8217; family and friends (totalling eight, including Shinichiro, who was doubling as photographer) sat on the left side of the room, while Kaz&#8217;s family and friends (totalling about 30) sat on the right side of the room.<br />
The emcee was one of the hotel&#8217;s employees, who regularly performs this duty (it&#8217;s not hard to tell). She&#8217;s quite good, although her English is a little forced. While a very nice service overall, I was a little perturbed by the woman&#8217;s need to inject a bit of a sales pitch for wedding services at the hotel. Probably normal, though I couldn&#8217;t imagine anyone of us single, English-speaking folk really interested in getting married there.<br />
With Enya playing over the speakers, the doors to the chapel on the east wall opened, and Mrs. May walked in her son to be married. They bowed at the door and entered. It&#8217;s not easy to take pictures when you can&#8217;t see for the tears in your eyes. They walked to the west side of the room, where they faced the audience over a white-draped table. A moment later, Kazumi and her father followed, bowing, and taking their positions next to Chris and his mom. The two parents then left the soon-to-be-newlyweds behind. The last ones through the doors were Kaz&#8217;s nephews (both about three years old), who brought in a small teddy bear with their rings. (As far as I know, the same rings they bought two years ago &#8212; see [[A Surprise Engagement]].)<br />
No-one stood for Chris and Kaz. This is a bit of an odd service, at least by western standards. The emcee guided the audience through the ritual, which went as follows. First, the register was signed by Chris, Kaz, their parents, and then everyone in attendance. This is, I assume, to prove that the civil service was approved by everyone in attendance. Jen was a little confused at first, not sure what she was supposed to do. I just told her to follow what everyone else was doing.<br />
It was a little odd signing the register. I&#8217;ve never signed one before. At the time I was signing it, it was just me putting my name down. But as I rose to leave, Chris said: &#8220;Thanks, Geoff&#8221; That&#8217;s when it hit me. This wasn&#8217;t just a signature. This was an affirmation of the marriage, of Chris&#8217; love for Kaz, and my love for him.<br />
Following the registry signing, they exchanged rings, and exchanged vows, Chris reading in Japanese and Kaz reading in English. The ceremony was short, but simple. The married couple then walked down the aisle. I took pictures that I could not see.<br />
I always seem to cry at weddings.<br />
Once outside, we all engaged in attempts to take pictures of Chris and Kaz, before being directed to a pair of benches so we could take a large group photo. This was nigh-excrutiating, as we were not only looking directly into the sun, but were also subjected with a bright flash. My eyes felt like they were burning out of my head. I hope that my eyes don&#8217;t look too screwed up from trying to keep them open.<br />
After all this, Chris can actually say that I&#8217;ve gone to the ends of the Earth for him.<br />
After the group shots were more photos, done with Shinichiro. We took a barrage of rather confusing instructions and eventually figured out where we were supposed to stand. Finally, we followed Chris and Kaz back into the hotel, and over to the wedding reception room for the family meal (Jen, Tony, Shinichiro, Riko, and I were considered extended family).<br />
The reception was a little odd, being a little more dramatic than I thought it would be. Once we were all seated around the long table, the drapes were drawn over the windows looking out onto the bay, the lights dimmed, and a spotlight put on Chris and Kaz as they entered the room to their place at the head of the table. Then champagne was poured for everyone, and the two fathers read out speeches (Chris translated his father&#8217;s speech for Kaz&#8217;s family).<br />
The drapes were reopened, and the meal began. And what a meal it was! Three dishes awaited us right away: a salad of seaweed and fish egg sacks, a lettuce-based salad, and one other thing I can&#8217;t remember now. Why can&#8217;t I remember? Because that was the first of about 10 rounds of food,including smoked salmon, lobster mousse, lobster with a chili sauce served in a lobster shell cut in half length-wise, sushi, clear soup, noodles, and two or three desserts, including the wedding cake. Garth, Jen, and I couldn&#8217;t believe that the food just kept coming.<br />
Mind you, there really wasn&#8217;t a lot of food, all told. In total, it would have amounted to maybe four large courses at a regular wedding. Still, it was a lot more food than any of us were expecting.<br />
And of course, there was drink. In addition to the champagne, there was beer. Tradition holds that everyone offers to fill the groom&#8217;s glass at least once. After a while, people start going around, filling other&#8217;s glasses. It&#8217;s impossible to tell how much beer one consumes over the course of the meal, but I think it safe to assume that Garth<!--, Jen,--> and I consumed far too much, mostly thanks to Shinichiro.<br />
During a break between rounds, Mrs. May and I talked a bit about the wedding, and she suddenly announced that I was next. Stuart and Therese got married in 2002, and now Chris. That means I&#8217;m the last one. Maybe in 2006&#8230;<br />
After the meal finally ended around 16:00, we headed out to collect our bags (some changed into more comfortable clothes), gathered our bags, and boarded the bus for Toyohashi. We were changing to the Associa Hotel, and then going to a reception party in the city.<br />
The bus ride back took a different route than the one going out, and though a little more direct, seemed to take longer. Tony and Shinichiro slept, and I swear Jen dozed once or twice. But it was a lot quieter on the way back than it had been on the way out.<br />
Back at the hotel, we checked in, hauled our stuff up to our rooms, and then prepared to head out. Jen and I were down first, followed shortly by Garth. Tony was a few minutes behind, wearing the infamous monkey suit.<br />
Yes, Tony has a monkey suit. It&#8217;s a costume he picked up a couple of years ago for a party. He has no qualms about wearing it, even to a large dinner party. He&#8217;s worn it on the plane from Saipan to Narita, and almost wore it on the shinkansen to Toyohashi. Garth convinced him to wear it for the dinner.<br />
A little late leaving (Kaz wanted to hear her wedding dress), we arrived a little late at the Bali-Hai restaurant. Inside waited about 80 or 90 people, only one of whom I knew &#8212; Alex, a friend of ours from Calgary, who&#8217;s teaching English in Nagoya (about 20 minutes by shinkansen).<br />
The dinner was a strange one, featuring several asian dishes I&#8217;d never had before. All quite tasty. We all played bingo, for some reason, which offered prizes to anyone who managed to get five in a row. The closest I got was four. Jen won a shampoo/body wash set, for which she was extremely happy.<br />
And yes, there was drink. Quite a bit of it. Beer, mostly, though Shinichiro had me try so-ju, which Tony described as &#8220;watered-down vodka&#8221;. It tastes a little like mildly alcoholic oolong tea. And of course, there was beer. Lots of beer. Jen couldn&#8217;t stop laughing or giggling.<br />
We had to leave before 21:00, as there was another reservation coming in. We all headed back to the hotel to dump off a few things, dress down a bit, and head out for an izakaya to have a little more fun. We had to wait a while, unfortunately, as Chris and Kaz lost track of time for a while.<br />
This gave Tony and I a bit of time to try to sort out tomorrow&#8217;s shinkansen schedule. Jen and I are heading to Hiroshima, and we need to be in the city by noon. Shinkansen run fairly often, but the trick is to catch the right ones so we don&#8217;t waste too much time. Luckily, the hotel provided paper schedules that we&#8217;ll take with us.<br />
Finally, around 23:00, Tony, Jen, Garth, Chris, Kaz, Shinichiro, Riko, and I gathered to go to the izakaya. An izakaya is a Japanese public house, where people get together for a lot of loud talking, heavy drinking, and a little bit of food. The place, called Fuku, was already full when we arrived, but they managed to clear some space for us.<br />
And yes, more drinking. Garth and I split warm sake, but the real surprise was Jen. Cold sake. A full bottle, all to herself. And about half of the second warm bottle, too. Her parents are gonna kill me. Surprisingly enough, she wasn&#8217;t too bad off, something I&#8217;ll attribute to body mass and metabolism.<br />
Although we were not privy to most conversations (Chris is quite capable of holding his own when talking with others; Garth, Jen, and I talked amongst ourselves or with Shinichiro and Riku), we were periodically brought in by Chris when something interesting was raised. Such was the case when he suddenly told Jen and I to stand up. We did. (We assumed, correctly, that this was to compare heights.) Chris then asked those sitting near him how old they thought Jen was.<br />
One said 28, another 27, and another would only go so far as &#8220;late-20s&#8221;. Chris then asked Jen to tell them how old she really is. She privately asked Chris first how to say her age in Japanese, which she then repeated to the three men. Their jaws dropped when they found out she&#8217;s only 15.<br />
Last call came, and we all headed out into the cool night air to return to the hotel. Jen had a new souvenir, a &#8220;gift&#8221; from Shinichiro &#8212; one of the two warm sake serving bottles. Doesn&#8217;t matter what country you&#8217;re in, people like to take stuff from restaurants.<br />
Jen and I need sleep. Tomorrow is going to be another longish day.<br />
[flickr]tag:irako+march+2004+&#8221;28&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]<br />
(Also see <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/chris-and-kazumi/">photos from Chris and Kazumi&#8217;s wedding</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">335</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
