<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>banks &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/banks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>It&#039;s Mañana Time!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-manana-time</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s Mañana Time!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of shape only makes things go more slowly. (And no, totally slacking off doesn&#8217;t cause the reverse.)<br />
For us up-tight North Americans, this is the single hardest thing to contend with. Uncertainty is the name of our game, so unknown things aren&#8217;t a problem. It&#8217;s the ability to do simple little things.<br />
Like call each other. Hard to do when you have no phone.<br />
<span id="more-1008"></span>For those of you old enough to remember, it&#8217;s like when you were in high school, and couldn&#8217;t use the phone to call your friends (your sister/brother/parents were hogging it or you were grounded) and had to wait until <em>the following day</em> to talk about anything. Oh, the days of yore!<br />
When &#8212; like us &#8212; you&#8217;ve become accustomed to always-on internet access and cellular phones, it&#8217;s really hard to go back to having nothing. Literally nothing. Jason and I have to &#8220;borrow&#8221; internet from unsecured sites around our respective complexes; Mark is left high and dry. Planning requires an intricate set of where we&#8217;re going and when, and plans in the event we don&#8217;t exactly meet up as planned.<br />
(It also doesn&#8217;t help that we&#8217;re wholly reliant on taxis for now &#8212; we haven&#8217;t been able to figure out the bus system &#8212; which are notoriously unreliable for being available in all places, or being anywhere near punctual. It&#8217;s especially bad if you&#8217;re out late, such as we were Monday night when we tried to catch a taxi after going to the grocery store. It was almost an hour before we could find one.)<br />
At the office, we were struggling to get anything to work, stealing internet from an adjacent office (given, we were told the password). With Lee here, we had carte blanche to purchase a wireless router (yes, Clay, it&#8217;s a D-Link) and a printer. The router allows us to use an existing connection (which only started working properly this morning), and the printer is WiFi-enabled so we can put it wherever it makes sense to put it.<br />
And the speed at which it takes to get them done. We&#8217;re used to &#8220;right away&#8221;. Here, it&#8217;s &#8220;mañana&#8221;, which requires a lot of grains of salt. There&#8217;s just so many things that we would like to have happen now, so we don&#8217;t have to worry about them for long periods of time. But no, it don&#8217;t work that way.<br />
Take Mark, for example. He&#8217;s been in his condo since Monday afternoon. He still doesn&#8217;t have air conditioning installed (despite being told it would be done the day he moved in) and his dryer doesn&#8217;t work yet. It&#8217;s happening, just really slowly.<br />
It&#8217;s not uncommon for someone&#8217;s email system to fill because there just isn&#8217;t a rush to empty it.<br />
Collectively, we&#8217;ve got a whack of things we need done, and we&#8217;ve no idea how fast/easy these will happen. And believe me, this is causing us concern. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>How do we open a bank account? It&#8217;s not as easy as walking into a bank with a few bucks in your hand.</li>
<li>How do we purchase a car? Apparently, it&#8217;s like buying a house in North America, complete with lawyers.</li>
<li>How do we get a driver&#8217;s license? And get one of those fancy &#8220;medical&#8221; certificates?</li>
<li>How do we get the insurance? And handle the annual mechanical inspection?</li>
<li>How do we get cell phones? More importantly, how do we get the number for any phone? Unless you&#8217;re a permanent resident, you can&#8217;t get a number (although you can get the phone).</li>
<li>What health care will we get?</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there&#8217;s the visa process. This is really an entirely separate topic, which I&#8217;m not sure I can really do justice. The whole process is a living nightmare, which Jason and Jen have been trying to wrangle to the ground. Sadly, the consulate keeps giving us new information which amounts to &#8220;oh, by the way, you need to do this too, which I realise totally throws off everything you were already doing&#8221;. More on that later, though.<br />
So this is live in Costa Rica. No, I&#8217;m not complaining. I&#8217;m not changing my mind. But a lot of people wanted to know how it&#8217;s going. Now you know.<br />
Which begs the question: If knowing is half the battle, what the heck is the other half?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BMO locked me out AGAIN</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/bmo-locked-me-out-again/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bmo-locked-me-out-again</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/bmo-locked-me-out-again/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bank of montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/12/31/bmo-locked-me-out-again/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GAH! [[Bank of Montreal, I hate your security&#124;I already hate BMO&#8217;s online security.]] Now I hate it more, if it is in fact possible to hate something more than &#8220;totally&#8221;. I just wanted to into my account. Nothing serious. But the password they made me assign apparently has changed, or is something completely different than &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/bmo-locked-me-out-again/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BMO locked me out AGAIN"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>GAH!<br />
[[Bank of Montreal, I hate your security|I already hate BMO&#8217;s online security.]] Now I hate it more, if it is in fact possible to hate something more than &#8220;totally&#8221;.<br />
I just wanted to into my account. Nothing serious. But the password they made me assign apparently has changed, or is something completely different than I can remember. It&#8217;s not like I already have 8,349,204 passwords that I need to remember (thank you, Sarbanes-Oxley) and I must&#8217;ve made something up on the spot, wrote it down and then immediately burned the paper without looking at what I wrote.<br />
That must&#8217;ve been it. No way it could be BMO. Not a chance.<br />
Augh.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/bmo-locked-me-out-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">882</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bank of Montreal, I hate your security</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 19:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bank of montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/14/bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oh. My. Lord. I haven&#8217;t been this pissed off in a very, very long time. I actually yelled at the poor person on the phone trying to help me. It&#8217;s not her fault. It&#8217;s the Bank of Montreal. Who obviously has NO FUCKING CLUE what it&#8217;s like to live in the digital age. Allow me &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Bank of Montreal, I hate your security"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh. My. Lord.<br />
I haven&#8217;t been this pissed off in a very, very long time. I actually yelled at the poor person on the phone trying to help me. It&#8217;s not her fault. It&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.bmo.com">Bank of Montreal</a>. Who obviously has <strong>NO FUCKING CLUE</strong> what it&#8217;s like to live in the digital age.<br />
Allow me to elaborate&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-860"></span>BMO (the short form of Bank of Montreal) recently introduced new security procedures for their online banking. In addition to your card number and PIN, you choose an image and provide a password. (This is all to prevent phishing.) I welcomed this, since I had similar functionality on my <a href="http://www.ingdirect.ca/">ING</a> account for a couple of years.<br />
So, choose an image, provide a little info, toss in a password. No problem.<br />
Until I came back. Suddenly, my previously wonderful password doesn&#8217;t work. No idea why. Could swear I&#8217;ve got the right one. Try again. And again. And suddenly, I get a page telling me that my card is locked (thankfully, only online) and to call BMO to have it unlocked.<br />
Which I got around to today. And boy, I can&#8217;t think of a worse experience. Ever.<br />
When you need access to personal financial information through your institution, you generally get asked the Big 6:</p>
<ul>
<li>Name</li>
<li>Birthday</li>
<li>Address</li>
<li>Phone number</li>
<li>Social Insurance (or Social Security) Number</li>
<li>Mother&#8217;s maiden name</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, admittedly, anyone wanting to steal your identity could dig this information up and put it to nefarious means. So to that extent, I see that BMO&#8217;s approach for more information is necessary.<br />
Their additional questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>What investments do you have? (I have none with BMO, so this question is invalid)</li>
<li>What are your monthly mortgage payments?</li>
<li>What were the last three transactions in your account &#8212; including the name of the institution and the dollar amount?</li>
</ul>
<p>I need to get at least two of those right in order to be validated as me. Problem: <em>I DON&#8217;T HAVE ACCESS TO MY FUCKING ACCOUNT!</em>  So how the hell am I supposed to know?<br />
No, I don&#8217;t memorise <strong>every bloody number</strong> that goes in and out of my account. That&#8217;s what <em>monthly statements</em> are for. Or, better yet, the online banking website that <em>I don&#8217;t have access to!</em> I don&#8217;t want to know what my monthly mortgage payments are &#8212; I just want to know that they&#8217;re being paid, and that my mortgage is being paid down.<br />
This is the digital age, folks. People actively try not to know numbers. I can&#8217;t count the number of people I know who don&#8217;t know their own <em>phone numbers</em>, let alone their last three transactions. Besides, as you already know (because you asked) &#8212; <em>I&#8217;m married</em>, so <em>I don&#8217;t know the last three transactions because I might not have made them!</em><br />
This is an open letter to BMO: Find a process that does not require someone to have up-to-the-moment financial history. It&#8217;s not feasible, and it&#8217;s (obviously) too difficult for some of us poor schmucks who are more worried about forgetting their wife&#8217;s birthday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/bank-of-montreal-i-hate-your-security/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">860</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
