<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>management &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/management/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 16:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Why your manager sucks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/why-your-manager-sucks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-your-manager-sucks</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/why-your-manager-sucks/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 16:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3652</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This year, I celebrate 15 years operating as a manager, in one form or another. I am by no means an expert, I certainly wouldn’t be the sort of person to conduct high-priced seminars that espouse “empowerment” or “entrepreneurism”. I&#8217;ve had the luxury of having some really good managers over the years, who were solid &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/why-your-manager-sucks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why your manager sucks"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year, I celebrate 15 years operating as a manager, in one form or another. I am by no means an expert, I certainly wouldn’t be the sort of person to conduct high-priced seminars that espouse “empowerment” or “entrepreneurism”. I&#8217;ve had the luxury of having some really good managers over the years, who were solid mentors, able to point out what it would take to guide others, to handle problems practically, and offer feedback in constructive ways.<br />
My many years of not being stuck in the weeds has also allowed me to look around at those with similar roles, and see how they approach the same challenges. The ability to talk to them, to see the results of their labours, to hear from those they manage also lets me get a better idea of what I’m doing right, and where I can improve. That&#8217;s given me a strong sense of what makes a good manager.<br />
Like I said, I ain’t perfect. But if your manager fails any of the following, they’re doing it wrong.<span id="more-3652"></span><br />
Management is a tough gig. Well, <em>good</em> management, anyway. Our popular culture is replete with examples of terrible ones, from <em>Dilbert</em>’s Pointy-Haired Boss to <em>The Office</em>’s David Brent/Michael Scott to <em>Office Space</em>’s Bill Lumbergh. Sure, there’s also some examples of good managers, but they don’t stand out as well as the bad ones. And that’s telling — bad managers stand out, hurting like the hammered thumb. They hurt for a simple reason: their impact is damaging to individuals on their team, to the dynamics of their team, and to the dynamics of other teams that interact with theirs.</p>
<h2>Managers Come Last</h2>
<p>So many times have I see situations where a manager accepts the success and praise for work that someone on their team delivered. It’s bad enough when it’s a group of peers (like a manager’s meeting), but it’s a straight-up insult when that person is also present. It’s my single biggest pet peeve with management: taking credit for others’ work.<br />
Some people get into management because they like the thought of power, of being the one in control, of directing the big show and delivering the great success. The reality couldn’t be further removed: a good manager is someone who supports the team from sinking into the muck, opens the doors to dangerous places and walks in first to discover the traps that lie within, duels with the dragons that threaten the team and its success, tends to the weak and injured to bring them back to health, finds new comrades for their cohort, all the while remaining invisible until needed.<br />
<strong>In short: stow the ego, manager. <a href="https://www.inc.com/ron-gibori/great-leaders-take-blame-pass-along-credit.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This is about your <em>team</em>, not about <em>you</em>.</a> If your team can’t shine, you won’t either.</strong></p>
<h2>Micro-Management Never Works</h2>
<p>I’ve seen my share of micro-managers. I’ve had the ones who dictated the approach to a solution; I’ve seen the ones who lean over shoulders, seizing mouse and keyboard, saying “just let me in here a moment”. It’s the worst example of control: a manager who doesn’t trust in their own people. As a manager, you have to accept that your team is not going to do something the way you would do something. It doesn’t matter if you like that or not, what matters is that your team feels empowered to do the work without interference.<br />
Bonsai trees are a wonder of Asian culture: perfect, living miniatures of full-grown bushes and trees. In reality, they’re stunted aberrations, constantly retarded in growth by their owners who repeatedly prune and restrict. As gorgeous as they may appear, the plant itself will never grow to its potential. Instead of treating your staff as tiny plants, let them loose in the rainforest, and monitor the fires that threaten to burn them. You’ll find they grow to heights you can’t imagine.<br />
So here&#8217;s rub: If you don&#8217;t trust your team to do the work, odds are they won&#8217;t do it. They&#8217;ll resent your involvement, and pile all the work back on you. Or worse, quit, and you&#8217;re having to start all over again. Next thing you know, you&#8217;re doing the work of the team, and I won&#8217;t have to tell you twice that you&#8217;ll be sorely wishing you had someone who could do all that work.<br />
<strong>In short: if you can’t trust in your team, the fault isn’t with the team.</strong></p>
<h2>Develop Your Team</h2>
<p>Following on the heels of letting the trees grow in the forest, you really need to take a position of a cultivator, not a harvester. The success of a manager is your team, so you’d better make sure it’s the best possible team it can be. Any team that doesn’t operate well, falls. I’ve been through enough (formal) training to know the Forming, Storming, Norming, Performing thing, and I’ve been through all four stages with multiple teams. The worst part, hands down, is the Norming.<br />
Yes, I said Norming: the part where you figure out where everyone fits into the picture so that everyone can start finding their groove. It’s a subtle step, and one that is grossly overlooked. A lot of managers either believe their constantly Storming (with personality clashes) or Performing (their teams are good); in my experience, Performing only comes with structure and planning, and Storming only really happens if the manager isn&#8217;t paying attention.<br />
Your team succeeds as a group, and it fails because of individuals. A single person who is unwilling to work in a team, or is oblivious to the team’s needs, isn’t a risk — they’re a bucket of water on a fire. That single person can kill relationships, murder creativity, and slaughter enthusiasm. It’s the manager’s responsibility — for the benefit of the team — to coach that person and bring up their abilities, or remove them entirely.<br />
<strong>In short: Cultivate your team to grow the best apples, ever; but make sure the one bad apple doesn’t spoil the batch.</strong></p>
<h2>All For One, One For All</h2>
<p>Your team is a forest make of individuals: when the individuals are strong, the team is strong. When someone weakens, they can be like their arboreal counterpart and weaken the rest around them. As much as you need to watch your team, you need to care for the people in it, too.<br />
One person can become significantly overburdened and stressed, another can become overly negative because they&#8217;re overlooked, another could be bored and uninterested in working. These sorts of behaviours can lead to extreme behavioural problems that must be addressed for the sake of your team: the diseased tree will infect those around them.<br />
A good manager will identify those individuals who require help, even those who claim they don&#8217;t need it, and work with them to return to strength. Doing so shows care for the individual, an acknowledgement of that individual&#8217;s part in the team and their contributions, and letting the team know that its overall health is assured.<br />
<strong>In short: Don&#8217;t forsake the team for a single person who needs attention.</strong></p>
<h2>Management Has Many Partners</h2>
<p>(Almost) No team ever works alone. (Almost) Every team works with other teams to achieve a goal. And as a result, any good working relationship is pretty much akin to a marriage: partners who are willing to live together under the same roof, for better or for worse, through thick and thin. They have to be willing to listen to one another, to speak their mind without fear of retribution, to know that concerns are heard so that things can be handled. Arguments will happen, but in the end everyone walks away, hand in hand. Of course, because (almost) every team works with other teams <i>plural</i>, this marriage is … well, polyamorous.<br />
That means that the managers need to not only recognize that there are many partners in the same bed, but everyone needs attention. This — and I know the metaphor is well-entrenched at this point, so I do apologize for the statement coming next — is where things get uncomfortable.<br />
One-to-one relationships are infinitely easier to manage. When you stray into multiple-sided relationships, the fairness isn’t as clear, and can very easily become lop-sided, with one partner taking more from multiple partners than they give back. As a manager, it’s a recognition of unfairness, and knowing that — if not resolved — that unfairness will one day come back to haunt you. Understanding your partners’ needs will help ensure an even playing ground, and build up those all-important karma points for the days when you might need to call in that all-important favour.<br />
There is, however, an insightful portion to the equation as well: knowing that not all marriages are equal, and where you sit in that relationship. There will always be situations where one partner must come before others, for a litany of reasons (such as politics, inexperience, incorrect analysis, poor communication), and trying force a different scenario leads only to trouble. Off-set relationships lead to disagreements, and ultimately failure when the other partner(s) become(s) unable to address the concerns adequately.<br />
<strong>In short: Knowing what value you and your partner(s) bring(s) to a relationship is often more important than what the relationship produces. </strong></p>
<h2>First Line of Defence, Last One Standing</h2>
<p>The role of a manager is beset on all sides by the inequity of reality: people need things done, and your team is the one in the way. Whether it’s in the way for the right reasons (delivering the answer) or the wrong reasons (the figurative scrapegoat) isn’t the issue — it’s where the manager stands as part of that line of fire.<br />
As mentioned in Managers Come Last, a manager stands at the front of their team, with a shield, to deflect the things that distract a team from doing their jobs. The manager addresses the issues, and either removes them as concerns or ensures that they’re dealt with directly and consistently. That line of defence keeps teams focuses from unnecessary distractions, and from the periodic hurtfulness that sometimes comes around.<br />
There’s also a flip-side: covering your team’s butt. Like it or not, vacations and illness will happen, people will move on. If you’re not taking that into account, your team is doomed to hit that very uncomfortable bump on the road that sends your proverbial car airborne, destined to land in very bumpy ways. The only way to ensure that your car’s trip is as soft as possible is to make sure there’s shock absorbers: redundancy.<br />
Any good manager will build redundancy into their team, and make sure that there’s a primary and a secondary for nearly every task. That doesn’t mean that there’s <i>perfect </i>redundancy (that’s not only expensive, but difficult beyond most reasonable expectations), but <em>functional</em> redundancy: your team can continue in the short-term until a person returns, or a replacement is found. And in the event if Real Disaster<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, it’s the manager who should fulfill that role.<br />
I personally don’t expect any manager to be a perfect backfill for anyone. But I do expect a considerate amount of understanding of what happens within their team. Does that mean things get resolved at the same pace? No. But it should mean that serious issues don’t hold the team up as a whole, or lead to team failures. In the end, any competent manager should have enough knowledge to at least understand the challenge of a given role within their team, if not backfill it for a short period of time.<br />
<strong>In short: If you don’t understand your team and what they do, you’ve already failed.</strong></p>
<h2>In Short</h2>
<p>I won’t lie, there are days I wish I wasn’t a manager. I wish I was in the corner, working on just what I needed to work on, and doing nothing else, worrying about no-one else. But the reality is that I’ve been there, and I’ve seen what happens with teams that don’t get the support they need. It’s why I ended up doing what I do — to help others be better at what they do, so teams can be better.<br />
I’m not perfect, I’m never going to be paid to talk about my experience, but hopefully a few pointers help others be better managers. Because if we have better managers, we can all be better people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/why-your-manager-sucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3652</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The importance of experience</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/the-importance-of-experience/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-importance-of-experience</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/the-importance-of-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 16:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3636</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Experience&#8221; is a tough word to use in the digital marketing industry. Quite often, it&#8217;s used to encompass one&#8217;s adventure and awareness through a user interface of an application. It&#8217;s one of the most common applications for &#8220;experience&#8221;, but it&#8217;s not the only one. There&#8217;s also the definition that includes knowledge and wisdom, held by &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/the-importance-of-experience/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The importance of experience"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Experience&#8221; is a tough word to use in the digital marketing industry. Quite often, it&#8217;s used to encompass one&#8217;s adventure and awareness through a user interface of an application. It&#8217;s one of the most common applications for &#8220;experience&#8221;, but it&#8217;s not the only one.<br />
There&#8217;s also the definition that includes knowledge and wisdom, held by those who have spent years honing skills, learning from mistakes, and becoming enlightened from real-world execution.<br />
And it&#8217;s the latter that I&#8217;m finding, more and more, to be a key to delivering the former.<br />
<span id="more-3636"></span><br />
Throughout my career, there has always been a struggle with experience. Early on, it was to <em>get</em> experience. Everyone starts with a blank slate; you&#8217;re not born with knowledge, you have to earn it. Later on, it was to <em>define</em> experience. My experience differed from others, so how do we determine whose experience is correct, or how do we determine which parts of said experience are worth learning? That was followed by <em>using</em> experience. It&#8217;s all fine and dandy to showcase a resume with a lot of who&#8217;s-who, but if you have no method for explaining that history to anyone else, your collected wisdom accounts for little. In my current position (whether this remains a final state remains to be seen), it&#8217;s about <em>recognizing</em> experience in others, and getting them to their next steps.<br />
Early in my career, there were precious few who understood digital delivery. Some had a sense of how it worked, but exceedingly few had anything under their belts of any significance. Most of us ended up figuring it out collectively, step by step, bit by bit, success and failure. But learn, we did, and we built on those events much like someone builds a wall: stone by stone, with the mortar of validation to cement things in place.<br />
Back then, experience was also a liability. Because, back then, experience meant &#8220;expensive&#8221;. Experienced folks could (usually) deliver at a faster, more reliable pace, which commanded a higher dollar. And while that&#8217;s not uncommon to the digital marketing industry &#8212; it&#8217;s common pretty much everywhere in the knowledge industries &#8212; everything was kept tight and slim, and expensive wasn&#8217;t an option. Ironically, we compensated for expensive experience, with cheap inexperience.<br />
I cannot adequately convey the imbalance of that comparison. Inexperienced staff are liabilities: they don&#8217;t have the knowledge or wisdom, which means they don&#8217;t have insights to their own faults or flaws. It takes a team to make an inexperienced person into a valuable asset, through assessment and management, reviews and feedback. Left unsupported (or to their own devices), inexperienced staff will under-deliver.<br />
In my (far-too-many) years in this industry, I have seen countless inexperienced staff produce poor results. It doesn&#8217;t matter if this is creative, technical, analytical, or managerial &#8212; the end result is a detriment. Worse still, an inability or unwillingness to identify and correct situations such as these invariably leads to personality conflicts. The manager&#8217;s challenge is to identify these situations early, and coach individuals through these difficult periods. It&#8217;s a poor manager who can&#8217;t identify the problems; it&#8217;s a terrible manager who refuses to help.<br />
Once experience is defined, the next challenge is often comparative: faced with someone <em>else&#8217;s</em> experience, who is correct? No two experiences are the same, even if faced with the exact same challenges. Everyone is moulded by their backgrounds, education, psychological leanings, and their own individual histories prior to a shared event. This is, after all, why humans are often so very different from one another.<br />
Assessing where one experience is more dominant, or more accurate, or has more depth than another requires tremendous insight, and open-mindedness. Typically, someone with a lesser experience will feel threatened by those who come with a broader or deeper level of skills and knowledge. Humans are driven by ego (even those who claim not to be so), and it&#8217;s only those with sufficient insight and self-awareness who can willingly accept those with a deeper wisdom.<br />
This is where clashes form between different groups (such as between two divisions of the same department), or between two classes of the same skillset (such as salaried staff vs. contractors). There&#8217;s an almost automatic sense of fear (someone knows more than me) that quickly leads to distrust (they will make me look bad to my manager). It&#8217;s an observant manager who either ensures a division between permanent and temporary staff; it&#8217;s an engaged manager who encourages one team to learn from another.<br />
Putting experience to use requires a leap of faith, especially for hiring managers. As I have written many times before, managers cannot be directly hands-on: there is not the time, and it&#8217;s the manager&#8217;s responsibility to care for the team. As time wears on, a manager&#8217;s former skills will naturally wane; in the digital field, that is highly accelerated, and it does not take long for unused skills to become redundant. At some point, a hiring manager must come to terms with the reality that bringing someone into their team means allowing that person to have more knowledge.<br />
The assumption is also that the new team member will also bring their experience to the team as a whole. However, how that person will use their skills and knowledge is another matter. The comparative nature is still present: someone who isolates themselves, ignores feedback, and promotes themselves to others who do not share the same perspective, will encounter objection and distrust. This difficult situation requires careful management, not unlike someone who is trying to define their own level of experience.<br />
In this case, it&#8217;s more about coaching someone to apply their experience in more effective manners. With more senior staff, this is likely a matter of attitude and ego, which often forms over years of successes. (This is particular prevalent in the technical fields, leading to the &#8220;superstar&#8221;, who eschews outside feedback for their own tried-and-true successes.)<br />
Here, the manager must look beyond the personality, disregarding opinionated behaviours to focus on the skills that lie underneath. It also means a careful ear to hear the important parts of the experience, understanding the value, and applying a direction that makes use of a person&#8217;s skills without belittling or affronting their sensibilities.<br />
I have failed on that many times, myself. Finding someone with a strong skillset is often not the challenge; getting past someone&#8217;s own sense of self-worth to see the true value is a skill unto itself. I have had to learn to listen to a particular person&#8217;s need to apply their skills, and help them apply that knowledge in a team context.<br />
Experienced staff often have difficulties within teams, largely having to be self-reliant for their own development. That&#8217;s both a burden and a boon: someone will naturally be saddled with long lists of reasons why things need to be done a certain way; however, that can also be a form of mentorship. In my experience, those people can become great teachers, helping the less experienced with their challenges, and bringing new perspectives.<br />
Relatedly, there is also the rarer case of inexperienced staff moved into more senior roles, where the expectations create false support, and similarly difficult attitudes. Many organizations have individual such as this, and while they do tend to stand out, these are not as common as we would generally like to believe. (Otherwise, organizations would fail far more frequently.) In cases like this, people tend to panic: they&#8217;re asked for information they cannot understand, and they become unable to process requests because they have no experiences to provide an adequate framework for common comprehension.<br />
As a manager, you either have to take responsibility for promoting someone ill-prepared for the role, or you have to accept that you&#8217;ve adopted someone who isn&#8217;t capable of handling a role. In either case, as a manager, you have a responsibility to support that person with their development, and to ensure that the team as a whole does not suffer from a lack of support. These are difficult situations that are not easily addressed, and often require that the under-experienced person be aware of the challenge that&#8217;s before them, so that they can be more receptive to external feedback.<br />
And that comes to recognition of experience. My previous employer&#8217;s original basis for hiring was fairly simple: only senior staff. That seems counter-intuitive to some (refer back to my comments about using cheap, inexperienced staff), but by using well-heeled employees, there was less of a need for management, there were fewer mistakes, and there was a faster delivery. Because people understood the jobs and the industry, it was easier to engage with new clients, as the general models were already well-known, and the more specific questions could be asked right away.<br />
To be fair: that&#8217;s an ideal scenario, and it&#8217;s hard to do at scale. You can&#8217;t hire only senior staff. Besides the cost component (remember, experience = expensive), you also have ego (experience means opinion, too). Not to mention the fact that some would much rather work on the &#8220;fun&#8221; work, and leave the dull, dreary, repetitive stuff to others. And for that, you need inexperienced, junior staff, who can learn from the seniors.<br />
The challenge of the manager in these cases is to determine appropriate blends of experienced vs. inexperienced staff. Experienced staff tend to be more mobile; it&#8217;s easier to find new positions elsewhere by mere fact of experience. Inexperienced staff may linger longer, but they haven&#8217;t the oversight of more knowledgeable folks to validate approaches and teach techniques.<br />
There is one other risk of experience, which is often overlooked: pride. Experienced staff have validation through the work they&#8217;ve done, from awards and accolades, from feedback and reviews. And when these people are <em>not</em> engaged to assist with new work, that pride quickly turns to insult. Senior staff deeply appreciate hearing their opinions heard, their experiences put to use; ignoring, disregarding, or outright avoiding engagement is nothing more than a slap to an experienced person&#8217;s history, all the way back to their first steps into the working world.<br />
Managers need to be keenly aware of people&#8217;s knowledge and experiences, leverage them when appropriate, and never disregard the sage advice when its given. Not accounting for these sorts of engagements leads only to disillusionment, impudence, and indignity. Ultimately, that leads to poisonous environments, and team breakdown.<br />
A person&#8217;s experience is a difficult topic. It&#8217;s hard to gauge, it&#8217;s hard to apply, it&#8217;s hard to manage, and it&#8217;s hard to acquire. The challenges exist for a given individual, for a team working with that individual, and for managers responsible for the individual&#8217;s assignments. It&#8217;s a strong individual who can respect and understand where their own experiences lie, how they should be applied, and how to identify those with valuable lessons.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/02/the-importance-of-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3636</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to be a Technical Writer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-be-a-technical-writer</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3135</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s surprising how often I&#8217;ve been asked this question over the last few months. Once upon a time &#8212; some dozen years ago &#8212; I was a technical writer. I wrote manuals, technical documentation, and various forms of other literature for a living. And, to be quite honest, I hated it. Well, hate is a strong &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to be a Technical Writer"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s surprising how often I&#8217;ve been asked this question over the last few months. Once upon a time &#8212; some dozen years ago &#8212; I was a technical writer. I wrote manuals, technical documentation, and various forms of other literature for a living. And, to be quite honest, I hated it.<br />
Well, <em>hate</em> is a strong word. I got bored of doing it. (Long story, suffice to say, I ended up making websites for a living.) But certainly the skill has never left me (I still write documentation to this day as part of my job), and I do know a few things about writing clearly and effectively.<br />
Sadly, it&#8217;s not something that is done particularly well&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3135"></span>If you&#8217;re reading this, you&#8217;re (obviously) on the internet. And you&#8217;ve seen how badly the internet has been written. Spelling mistakes aside (even today&#8217;s modern spell checkers miss grammar and some syntax resulting from correctly-spelled, but incorrectly-used words), many people have trouble forming a cohesive idea, and an even harder time expressing it. As much as some scholars have said that the internet has (overall) improved the habit of written communication, I personally find the quality a bit lacking at times.<br />
These days, you can easily find some fantastic how-to books on how to write documentation. This is not a new field, by any means &#8212; humanity&#8217;s been writing stuff like this for a couple hundred years, really. But over the years, I&#8217;ve found that most of the details can be boiled down to a few key points that you always keep in mind, and then you need to practice them over and over and over and over and over and over.<br />
Oh, and you need to have a vicious editor. (Ideally, another writer with more experience.) Someone who can <em>objectively</em> tear apart your work, show you what&#8217;s good, what&#8217;s not so good, and help you improve your work. I learned more about the art of technical writing from two editors than I did from any book or professor, and I&#8217;m thankful for those people&#8217;s efforts (regardless of any heated arguments at the time). Writing is a two-person job: the author and the editor, and I&#8217;ll debate anyone who says otherwise&#8230;<br />
There&#8217;s six fundamental parts to any good documentation (technical, or otherwise):</p>
<ol>
<li>Organisation of concepts</li>
<li>Understanding your audience</li>
<li>Clarity</li>
<li>Brevity</li>
<li>Visual reinforcement</li>
<li>Consistency</li>
</ol>
<h2> Organisation</h2>
<p>This is Number 1 on the list for a reason. Even if you bugger everything else up in your documentation, you <em>need</em> to get this right. How you divide your document really speaks to how you introduce the concepts, explain them, and allow people to dig into things at a pace that&#8217;s comfortable for them.<br />
As a general rule, you always start at a very high level &#8212; you <em>introduce</em> the very thing you&#8217;re about to explain. For example, imagine you&#8217;re writing a document on a plane. Your document may eventually detail the specific bolt that&#8217;s used to attach the engine, but you <em>first</em> have to start by telling the reader what a plane is, what it does, and (in some cases) even a wee bit of history. (Incidentally, a lot of Wikipedia articles are organised like this, and many are good examples of documentation.)<br />
You then break your document into sections (or chapters, whatever you want to call them), which are the major topics of discussion. In the case of a plane (for example), you might want to have sections for the fuselage (the basic chassis of a plane), the powerplant (what makes a plane move), the wings (what makes a plane actually fly), the avionics (what helps the pilots steer the plane), the landing gear (because everything that goes up eventually has to come down), and the empennage (basically, the rear control mechanisms at the tail that allow steering).<br />
Then, within each of those sections, you can more succinctly break down the topic more independently, allowing each section to have isolation from the other sections. Though not <em>total</em> isolation &#8212; any good documentation should refer to other parts of itself, or other documents, that provide additional detail.<br />
It&#8217;s a simple mantra: start big, go small.<br />
Thus we get to headings! All documentation has headings &#8212; it&#8217;s what breaks it up into parts that are digestible. All documentation has a heading hierarchy, too: always going from the first heading (often called Heading 1) to the second, to the third, and so on. You <strong><em>never, never, ever</em></strong> skip a heading. If you feel the urge to skip a heading, you have a flaw in your organisation.<br />
The depth of heading hierarchies (how many heading levels you need) depends on the document. Some documents can get away with two; some (and I&#8217;ve written ones like this) need six or more. Don&#8217;t creating heading levels you don&#8217;t need &#8212; always keep a document as shallow as you can &#8212; but don&#8217;t be afraid to use them when you&#8217;re discussing a complex thing that needs a lot of breakdown.<br />
It should be noted, especially with software documentation, that a heading hierarchy isn&#8217;t always a heading (such as &#8220;Organisation&#8221;, above). Sometimes it&#8217;s a function or a method that you need to document. For people reading API (application programming interface) specifications, the name of the function is in many cases far more valuable than heading you could create.</p>
<h2>Understanding your Audience</h2>
<p>It might sound trite, but you&#8217;re not writing a document for yourself. You&#8217;re writing it for someone else. You should always keep this in mind, as it will help focus the language you use, and the detail you need to provide.<br />
Again, consider the plane documentation. There&#8217;s several different audiences who may need such a document: the people building the plane (they&#8217;ll need detailed specifications, including assembly instructions), the mechanics who&#8217;ll fix the plane later (similar to the build specifications, but they&#8217;ll also need information on best practices for repairs), pilots (who need to know how to fly the plane), and even passengers (they want to know more about the plane, and especially safety procedures). All of these audiences need special attention, and (frequently) very different information.<br />
You would (almost) never write a general document that would address all people. It&#8217;s not to say that it can&#8217;t be done &#8212; it&#8217;s done every day, and done badly &#8212; but such a document becomes very hard to read, and even harder to understand. Writing different documents often helps make sure you&#8217;ve got the right subject and language for the right people.</p>
<h2>Clarity</h2>
<p>This is a tough one, and it relates to the previous two items. The more complex your topic, the more clarity you may need to provide. By &#8220;clarity&#8221;, I mean the ability to explain an inherently complex thing in (reasonably) simple terms.<br />
I&#8217;ve written loads of technical documentation regarding software development and server architecture, often for project managers and clients who do not possess my level of understanding. (This is usually because I have to get budgets approved, and simply saying &#8220;we need to rewrite some code&#8221; isn&#8217;t good enough.) I&#8217;ve had to explain a problem in detail, propose the solution, and draw potential conclusions from the actions. All of it in such a way that someone who doesn&#8217;t need (or want) to understand the details.<br />
I won&#8217;t lie: this is <em>hard</em>.<br />
So how do you do it? <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaphor" target="_blank">Metaphor</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simile" target="_blank">simile</a>. (I provided links, in case you can&#8217;t remember what those terms are. And yes, you could use <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allegory" target="_blank">allegory</a> as well, but it takes a lot more effort, and we&#8217;re trying to keep things simple.) You need to convert the concept into something more familiar to the audience at hand.<br />
For example, in software, we often talk about using a &#8220;framework&#8221; when building complex things. A framework is like being given a lumbermill to carve up an entire tree, rather than having to use a handsaw to do it all by yourself.<br />
See what I did there? You&#8217;ve probably never sawed an entire tree by yourself &#8212; but you can imagine how much work it is. You don&#8217;t have to know what a &#8220;framework&#8221; really does, but you suddenly have an idea of what it can do for programmers. Hence, the importance of explaining things a different (but still valid!) way.<br />
It&#8217;s important that you&#8217;ve explained a concept sufficiently. You have to carry an explanation all the way to the end, so that someone has a complete thought. Imagine if I&#8217;d stopped halfway through my framework definition, and left it at &#8220;lumbermill&#8221;. You&#8217;d probably be wondering where I was going with the idea, and likely no better off than when I&#8217;d started.<br />
You also need to be specific. Avoid using vague words when you can use the actual term instead. This is particularly important as your detail increases. At a high level, you can talk about the bolts that go into assembling a plane; when you get to the exact bolt needed to attach a winglet to the wingtip, you&#8217;d better have the part number to go along with it.</p>
<h2>Brevity</h2>
<p>Those of you who know me will be snickering at me for this one. Yes, you need to try write the shortest documentation you can, all the while building on the items I&#8217;ve already mentioned. I say this because, generally, I still struggle with it.<br />
It is very difficult to not want to explain everything in huge amounts of detail. I&#8217;ll tell you this (because I&#8217;m always telling it to myself): give people just <em>enough</em> information, not <em>all</em> the information &#8212; let someone learn enough to know what they need to get going, and they&#8217;ll (usually) figure out the rest for themselves.<br />
Also, you keep it short because people just don&#8217;t want to read lots of words. They want the information, and move on. We&#8217;re a society of soundbites, not one of novels. That also means writing short sentences and short paragraphs &#8212; long ones are fine for telling stories, but they suck at instruction.</p>
<h2>Visual Reinforcement</h2>
<p>When you&#8217;re writing some documentation, you&#8217;ll come across the need to explain something that is inherently so complex that it&#8217;s difficult to write in words.<br />
So don&#8217;t.<br />
The saying &#8220;a picture&#8217;s worth a thousand words&#8221; is <em>very</em> true, and a single picture can eliminate the need to write lengthy explanations. In some cases, a diagram is the <em>only</em> way to properly provide information (such as technical specifications for the previously-mentioned airplane mechanics).<br />
Do you have to make these diagrams yourself? Not always, but often a simple drawing tool will save you hours of hunting through the internet for an appropriate picture, or waiting for someone else to make it for you. Visio and Omnigraffle are life-savers when it comes to building quick and easy diagrams, especially where complex ideas like process flows need to be explained.</p>
<h2>Consistency</h2>
<p>I have this as a &#8220;last&#8221; important point, but it&#8217;s no less important than the previous two (<strong>Brevity</strong> and <strong>Visual Reinforcement</strong>). It&#8217;s important not because it helps convey information any more easily &#8212; it&#8217;s because it won&#8217;t annoy your reader.<br />
Consistency, in this case, is about your writing style. You need to make sure you&#8217;re always approaching your writing in the same manner, in the same style, in the same voice, throughout an entire document. (This is where an editor really comes in to save a day, incidentally.)<br />
Changing styles, or how you write, does not change the information you&#8217;re providing. But it does cause the reader to unconsciously start to hate you, because it&#8217;s difficult for a human to read different styles or word usage from page to page (or section to section).<br />
Stick with your choice of spelling. You&#8217;ve probably noticed that I use &#8220;organisation&#8221;, not &#8220;organization&#8221;. I use a version of Canadian spelling. (This is in itself a bit debatable, as some Canadian spelling is British, and some is more American.) But once you start using it, keep using it. (Incidentally, I don&#8217;t normally use &#8220;organisation&#8221; &#8212; I&#8217;m using here to illustrate the point.)<br />
You should also stick with your choice of terms. Once you start using a term, you need to keep using it, and use it in the correct context. As mentioned with the bolts earlier, if you ever mention a &#8220;19 mm close tolerance bolt&#8221;, you need to keep using that term, lest someone get confused with a different kind of bolt.<br />
Similarly, once you start using a particular meme for your metaphors, you need to stick with them. If you start using planes as your metaphor, <em>keep talking about planes</em> &#8212; don&#8217;t switch to using trees and lumbermills. (See what I did there?)<br />
Yes, this is a bit of psychology. But you want someone to read your document, and hopefully recommend it to someone else.</p>
<h2>Some Final Notes</h2>
<p>It ain&#8217;t easy summarising an entire career into a single blog post. Heck, it&#8217;s fool-hardy, really. But still, there&#8217;s a few other things that you might want to consider looking into.<br />
First of all, read some examples. You don&#8217;t need to <em>learn</em> the material, but look at them for what they are. I&#8217;ve already mentioned Wikipedia, which is maintained by an army of editors, for whom I have the deepest respect. Also consider reading some books &#8212; things like the <a href="http://www.dummies.com/" target="_blank"><em>For Dummies</em></a> series and pretty much anything out of <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/" target="_blank">O&#8217;Reilly</a> are great examples of complex ideas broken down into digestible terms.<br />
Your style is important, but not critical. Still, there are a few things you should keep an eye on:</p>
<ul>
<li>There is no &#8220;I&#8221; in technical writing, so don&#8217;t use it (the author might have a fancy picture on the cover, but inside the book they shouldn&#8217;t make themselves known)</li>
<li>There is a &#8220;you&#8221; &#8212; always speak to your reader, it helps them attach themselves more to the topic</li>
<li>Companies (et al) are referred to in the third person; avoid &#8220;we&#8221; if you can</li>
<li>Avoid colloquialisms, vulgarity, stereotypes, catchphrases, and so on &#8212; those are for literature, not documentation</li>
</ul>
<p>Learn some of the typographical aspects of writing. For example, the difference between a dash, an &#8220;en dash&#8221; and an &#8220;em dash&#8221;. You&#8217;d be surprised how often a simple change like that can affect the readability of a document. Similarly, spacing between headings and paragraphs, how to create legible lists, and simple formatting go a long way to making a document &#8220;friendly&#8221;.<br />
Practice. You won&#8217;t get it right the first time. Or the second. Or the tenth. But you will get better, if you keep at it, and have a (trusted) person review your work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Annual Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-annual-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 20:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2968</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Sorry for the long silence, folks. I&#8217;ve been a very, very busy boy the last couple of months, and &#8230; well, writing hasn&#8217;t really been a high priority for me. Family, as always, comes first, with my job (which provides for said family) a very close second. Sanity has eeked its way into third place &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Annual Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the long silence, folks. I&#8217;ve been a very, very busy boy the last couple of months, and &#8230; well, writing hasn&#8217;t really been a high priority for me. Family, as always, comes first, with my job (which provides for said family) a very close second. Sanity has eeked its way into third place &#8230; and anyone who knows me also knows how much attention <em>that&#8217;s</em> getting as of late. Writing is in fourth, which is a very sad last in terms of actual attention.<br />
So why now? Well, let&#8217;s go back to that second point. Today is my first anniversary of (full-time) work with Evans Hunt. While I had been kicking around here since January of last year, the full-time aspect is more recent, and in this case, also important&#8230;<br />
&#8230;it&#8217;s Annual Review Day.<br />
<span id="more-2968"></span>Unlike in my previous company, reviews here are very informal. Basically, you go to lunch with your department head (in my case, Allard) and one (or both) of the principals (Dan and Bill). You talk, you listen, you chat, you reminisce, and if it&#8217;s a particular bad review, I imagine you&#8217;d slink off to a bar following lunch and promptly get hammered&#8230;<br />
After the requisite mock-disparaging  comments, we engaged in what I would have (in my previous company) described as the single most glowing review I&#8217;ve ever received. And considering what I&#8217;ve done in the last 12 months, that is actually a point of note: I&#8217;ve gone from being a high-fallutin&#8217; managerial-type who used to do real work and who spent most of his time in Outlook, to someone who was setting up web servers, writing XML parsing code, and pulling together disparate data feeds into a unified views. In short, getting shit done.<br />
For the record, I highly value and appreciate Bill and Allard&#8217;s commentary and feedback. But I was suprised &#8212; if taken a bit aback &#8212; that there wasn&#8217;t much in the way of &#8220;constructive&#8221; feedback. In ye olde days, that was the list of things you should really &#8220;stop&#8221; doing, and start doing differently. The one that would stand out for most around here is my &#8220;passion&#8221; (I use the term loosely) towards the things I believe in. I tend to come across &#8230; well, kind of like <a href="http://youtu.be/xP1-oquwoL8?t=30s">Nicholas Cage in some of his more livid moments</a>. But around here, it&#8217;s an <em>asset</em>.<br />
There&#8217;s a point of comfort in that. I&#8217;m ancient in this business. I&#8217;m 39, and been doing this sort of work for nearly 17 years. If I haven&#8217;t done it myself, I&#8217;ve seen it and probably know someone who helped build it. I&#8217;ve gone from custom-build-everything to near-LEGOâ„¢ assembly of projects. I, like nearly everyone here at Evans Hunt, am a veteran. And veterans, as it happens, really have no time or patience for the crap that often occurs in our industry. Because we&#8217;ve dealt it. We&#8217;ve swam in it, in many cases, and somehow we&#8217;ve emerged, perhaps not smelling of flowers, but definitely not of the very effluence in which we felt we were drowning. So for a company to tolerate my idiosyncracities as a benefit (or at least tolerate it) is pretty significant in my books.<br />
And yet, the lack of the kind of criticism I used to receive seemed &#8230; odd. I&#8217;m still not quite sure what to make of it. I suppose, in part, it&#8217;s due to our size &#8212; we&#8217;re a small company, only about 36 people, so our fewer individualities tend to stand out better against the noise that comes from having many more personalities. We have to accept them, even encourage them, because that&#8217;s what makes things tick around here. Personalities go a long way to defining your working relationship with someone. Normally, I&#8217;d be getting input like &#8220;work better with project managers&#8221;, and &#8220;say &#8216;yes&#8217; more often to designers&#8221; (that&#8217;s a paraphrase, by the way &#8212; the actual feedback was more along the lines of &#8220;constructive dialog&#8221;).  Here? &#8220;Please, keep on being you.&#8221;<br />
Chalk up another phrase to add to the &#8220;Ways To Make People Feel Awesome&#8221; list.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long year here. We&#8217;ve done a lot, and there&#8217;s still a lot to do in the remaining two months. And that&#8217;s a good thing &#8212; better busy than bored, I say. And somewhere in all of that, maybe there&#8217;s room to push a bit more.<br />
&#8216;Cuz, really, I just don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;m doing my job right until someone&#8217;s calling me names.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The need for the Big Picture</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-need-for-the-big-picture</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 12:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2945</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[On Saturday, my wife Alex and I went out on our own. (We manage to do this every couple of weeks thanks to Alex&#8217;s mother, who comes over to watch the kids so we can behave more like adults for a while.) On our little excursion, we spontaneously decided to go up the Calgary Tower, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The need for the Big Picture"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, my wife Alex and I went out on our own. (We manage to do this every couple of weeks thanks to Alex&#8217;s mother, who comes over to watch the kids so we can behave more like adults for a while.) On our little excursion, we spontaneously decided to go up the Calgary Tower, for no other real reason than to take a look.<br />
The sun was getting low in the sky, and the horizon was nearly completely obscured by haze (likely due to the city drying out from a few days of light-to-heavy rain). The shadows cast through the downtown were fantastic, the trees (most of which now have leaves) and the fields of grass were bright green, and light glinted off the glass of a hundred skyscrapers.<br />
And I realised &#8212; almost surprisingly &#8212; that from way up there, Calgary really does look quite beautiful.<br />
<span id="more-2945"></span>It seems like a weird statement, so let me elaborate. Like with over 95% of Calgary&#8217;s population, I&#8217;m not usually afforded a high-level view of Calgary &#8212; all I ever see is the dirt and chaos present at the ground level, where the work is being done. It&#8217;s messy, things don&#8217;t always go right, and I sometimes find myself wanting to scream at brick walls (screaming at actual people would have the same overall effect) for things to get better. Progress is hard to see, and my little corner(s) of Calgary seem just as ugly and insignificant as they always do.<br />
From on high (a bit of a joke, admittedly, since there are plenty of buildings much higher than Calgary Tower, now), it&#8217;s very different. Calgary looks different. The choking dust of construction is harder to see, the traffic mayhem isn&#8217;t as prevalent (it was also 20:45 on Saturday evening), and even the barebones of The Bow building (Encana&#8217;s new headquarters, still under construction) have a certain industrial appeal.<br />
Yep, there&#8217;s a business angle to this, too. &#8220;The Big Picture&#8221; is one that is often used, as is &#8220;Forest for the Trees&#8221;. It&#8217;s the same principle &#8212; at a low enough point, you can&#8217;t see the larger collection. You&#8217;re in the proverbial weeds, dealing with the problems that need to be solved. It&#8217;s ugly and often frustrating work, and down there it&#8217;s almost impossible to see how things will get any better.<br />
I think that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s necessary for everyone &#8212; not just management &#8212; to take those necessary steps backwards/upwards to see what they&#8217;re doing contributes to the whole. To see what&#8217;s going on, how everyone&#8217;s tasks feed into a larger entity. Especially in cases where there are dozens or hundreds of people involved, those on the ground need to witness for themselves what else is going on around them.<br />
Why? Two reasons, I think. First: understanding. People get tired, people get complacent, and often people end up getting angry because they can&#8217;t see past where they are. Knowing how others are doing, and how their own personal work may affect others can help focus tasks more effectively. Second: job satisfaction. Similar in nature, yes, but a separate effect &#8212; it&#8217;s almost surprising how much someone can feel that much better knowing how even a seemingly menial task can achieve a milestone.<br />
For me, right now, I can safely say that it&#8217;s easy for me to see the big picture at Evans Hunt. My project teams are less than 10 people in total, and often under 5. It&#8217;s very easy to take a step back and see what&#8217;s going on. Heck, I rarely even need to get out of my seat for that!<br />
In former lives, it was much more difficult, and I remember the struggle to see what was happening around me, let alone across the company. And I know I wasn&#8217;t the only one in that situation &#8212; the gossip and rumours (however accurate) often spawned around a need to fill in the missing gaps.<br />
So I offer this to you, dear readers: if you feel stuck, struggling to understand, maybe even lost, take time to find the highest possible observation deck in your town or city (most have something). Plan to go there about an hour or so before sunset, and take the time to look around. Look at the buildings you pass every day, look towards your home (even if you can&#8217;t see it), find the place you work. Look for the things that you see each and every day and tend not to give them a second (or even first) thought. See how different they look from up above.<br />
Reflect on that perspective &#8212; it&#8217;s an important one. On the next work day, see if you can find something similar in your daily life. Talk to a manager, to an executive (if you can), other people in other departments. Try to recreate that sense of wholeness that you felt looking down from above. Understand not only how you play your part, but also how everyone else factors in as well.<br />
Maybe then, things won&#8217;t seem so haphazard and chaotic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The fork in the road</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-fork-in-the-road/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-fork-in-the-road</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-fork-in-the-road/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 03:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2777</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not so long ago, when I managed a team, I used to coach people in their career directions. (How well I coached people is another matter, and I can only leave it to those people to assess my real effectiveness.) I&#8217;d help them understand their successes, their opportunities, and help them avoid the pitfalls that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-fork-in-the-road/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The fork in the road"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not so long ago, when I managed a team, I used to coach people in their career directions. (How well I coached people is another matter, and I can only leave it to those people to assess my real effectiveness.) I&#8217;d help them understand their successes, their opportunities, and help them avoid the pitfalls that were common with advancement. Everyone wants to get ahead, after all.<br />
One thing I always cautioned more senior people was the &#8220;fork in the road&#8221;, the point at which you decided on your &#8220;next&#8221; direction. One avenue would take you down the road of the specialist, the code ninja who could seemingly pull miracles out of thin air. The other avenue was expanding one&#8217;s view beyond the initial skill to encompass the Big Pictureâ„¢. In other words, management.<br />
Watch out for that wrong turn &#8212; here be dragons.<br />
<span id="more-2777"></span>The fork will hit many people over the course of their careers. Companies prefer to rely on known quantities &#8212; they&#8217;re trustworthy, they get results, and have proven themselves time and time again under stressful circumstances. In theory, that sort of person would make a good leader, and someone who could &#8220;look after&#8221; teams and projects. That&#8217;s usually how a specialist finds themselves taking on the responsibilities &#8212; in effect taking the turn at the fork &#8212; and going down Management Lane.<br />
At a high enough level, you could almost see it as &#8220;six of one, half a dozen of another&#8221;. The person still has a job, and new opportunities are a good thing. This makes a person more valuable, and ultimately provides more benefit to the company. But there&#8217;s a catch (of course) &#8212; at a high enough level, you don&#8217;t see the complications that come with taking the wrong fork.<br />
Not everyone should be a manager. In my career, I&#8217;ve only met a small number of people who do it well (and despite my history, I&#8217;m reticent to include myself in that group). The right person is patient, attentive, trustworthy and trusting, and protective of their team. The right person instills faith in the larger group, makes sure that unnecessary noise (such as problems that do not affect the team directly) are kept silent, and can help solve the team&#8217;s problems when they arise. All while understanding the team&#8217;s work, the plan for the team, and the long-term vision.<br />
With all of that comes a necessary need to relinquish the practices that they used to, such as programming. Why? Because both require considerable focus and attention, and any attempt to split across both will ultimately cause trouble in both &#8212; you can&#8217;t do two full-time jobs at once with the same level of quality.<br />
And that&#8217;s where some managers fail. They try to do both, to the detriment of their work, and (in really bad cases) their team. It&#8217;s certainly not the person&#8217;s intention (&#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_road_to_hell_is_paved_with_good_intentions">the road to hell&#8230;</a>&#8220;) &#8212; no-one ever intentionally plans to fail. But it does happen.<br />
The trick? Well, there lies the rub. The person reaching the fork &#8212; and it isn&#8217;t always obvious when you are &#8212; needs to think long and hard about what they want to do. Are they willing to give up the previous job for a new one, to operate at higher levels? Or do they want to become the expert, the person who can deliver anything that&#8217;s asked.<br />
There are always avenues for the specialists, too. I&#8217;ve yet to see a situation where someone has practiced their trade so well that they&#8217;ve effectively taken themselves past the point of usefulness (dying trade/technology, or pricing themselves out of the market, notwithstanding). In my many years in the technology industry, there have been the &#8220;experts&#8221;, the people who know a technology, practice, or methodology so well that they are able to execute a solution almost asleep. Those skills are highly valuable and should never be discounted. I know plenty of developers who are still developers after many years, taking only promotions within their particular expertise, practicing a level of skill the likes of which I can only imagine.<br />
Me? I took the management fork, to the detriment of my development skills. <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/">I&#8217;m kind of paying for that decision now,</a> but that&#8217;s the way life goes, sometimes. Do I regret it? Not one bit. The experience is incalculable, and I think also helps me be a little more critical of the directions I take in the work I do now. Would I do it differently, knowing what I know now? Possibly&#8230;<br />
(Yeah, cop-out answer, I know. I&#8217;ve learned not to dwell on &#8220;what if&#8221; situations. They&#8217;re painful spirals of doom.)<br />
So I leave this as a cautionary tale for those of you on the way up: think carefully about what you want to do, and where you want to go. Be careful of the road you choose, and know the potential dangers of going down the &#8220;wrong&#8221; path &#8212; sometimes, it is far less pretty than it appears.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-fork-in-the-road/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2777</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The development in my life</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-development-in-my-life</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2775</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[If I were to summarise the last ten years of my career prior, specifically from about June 2000 to June 2010, it would look something like this: web developer, specialised web developer, senior web developer, junior manager, manager, director, technical architect. What, in many ways, looks largely like an &#8220;upward&#8221; progression in knowledge work. During &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The development in my life"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If I were to summarise the last ten years of my career prior, specifically from about June 2000 to June 2010, it would look something like this: web developer, specialised web developer, senior web developer, junior manager, manager, director, technical architect. What, in many ways, looks largely like an &#8220;upward&#8221; progression in knowledge work.<br />
During these last ten years, and notably the latter five, I trended more and more away from programming and more into management. I managed people, I managed projects, I managed implementations, and pretty much managed to avoid coding of any kind. I convinced myself that it made more sense for me to focus on the higher-level technology planning than it did on the actual implementation &#8212; there were others who did it better than me, and it was a waste of effort to try do it all.<br />
And suddenly, I found myself checkmated.<br />
<span id="more-2775"></span>In June, it became painfully clear that my role as a technical architect was going to run out, and soon. (I ended up taking all of August off &#8212; partly because I&#8217;d planned to do so many, many months ago, but also because work for my role had run out.) And despite looking around, there just didn&#8217;t seem to be a demand for mid-level technology managers with an emphasis on internet applications. I&#8217;d managed to &#8212; quite literally &#8212; position myself out of a career.<br />
My father ran into something like this himself, after his company rather callously raped him of his respect after a great many years of service and profit. He, had risen from a junior employee to a manager after many years (even running an entire division of the company), and his fall was painful. He was 50 at the time, and starting out new again ain&#8217;t easy. After the shock wore off, however, my father strived to reinvent himself, doing what he did best: sell. He went from construction equipment to selling oil-absorbing peat moss (in effect, going green long before it was common knowledge, let alone trendy).<br />
I now face a similar need to reinvent. I&#8217;m only 38, so it should be easier, right? (Right?) But I have a problem. Unlike my dad, I&#8217;m not a specialist anymore. I was, about ten years ago, but I&#8217;ve since become a generalist &#8212; in both the best and worst cases. I know a lot about my industry, but in most cases I don&#8217;t know quite enough to be truly useful in specific situations. And add to that, my specialist skills have rusted. They&#8217;re out-of-date, and some of my knowledge includes developing for now-unsupported platforms.<br />
The newer libraries are unknown to me, and I&#8217;ve never been particularly good with object-oriented programming (the OOP style was not harped on when I was in school, so I&#8217;m a functional programmer). But today&#8217;s environments require me to know how to use these tools. The guys I work with can make them sing and dance, and I feel as if I&#8217;m lucky to get them to just stand up.<br />
I still plan to use my management years for their wealth of experience &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot to be said for the things you learn while trying to make sure everyone else has an easier time fo their job. Those skills, however, don&#8217;t offer me a current job as a manager. Going back to my older skills is proving quite a challenge. I gotta tell you, it&#8217;s been like watching someone restore a rusted engine, and try to get it to turn over for the first time.<br />
I also can&#8217;t help but see the irony that the very same interview questionnaire that I helped write over a decade would now exclude me from being hired.  I almost feel like that guy you&#8217;ve hear about, laid off from a job he had for 30 years, whose industry has waned, having to do something totally different now.<br />
Make no mistake, I am <em>retraining</em> &#8212; relearning something I knew how to do (and do well), to keep my skills strong enough to keep me employed. Unlike formal programs, I have to do this on my own, without a teacher. I have only the contacts I&#8217;ve made over a decade as assistance, and more RSS feeds and Twitter accounts than I care to think about. Ultimately, I have to rely on my aged brain to do things it used to find trivial, and now finds difficult.<br />
It&#8217;s stressful. I feel like I&#8217;m having to learn to walk again. I&#8217;ve had to do the simple projects, to re-master the basics. (You gotta walk before you can run.) I&#8217;ve spent many late nights reading all forms of documentation and standards, and in particular, I&#8217;ve been reading Drupal documentation voraciously (helped in part by my much-stronger colleague Brian) &#8212; the concept of a CMS I understand; it&#8217;s the implementation I need to know. It&#8217;s also learning deeper PHP (and PHP frameworks), jQuery, more complex SQL, and learning the newer tricks found in HTML 5, and CSS 3. If I had the time, I might even try my hand at ActionScript. But I already feel overwhelmed. There&#8217;s just not enough time in a day.<br />
It&#8217;s a different mindset, too, and refocusing it onto code has been a challenge. I find myself planning out implementation strategies, and not focusing on the current need. I try to do a simple implementation, and I&#8217;m soon debating whether I should build an XML parser, or go straight to a simple CMS build to side-step some of the issues. I&#8217;ve had to rely on friends to help fix implementations, only to see the fix and slap myself in the forehead for not thinking of it myself.<br />
It&#8217;s coming, though. Every day makes greater strides, and working under others with deeper experience is helping rebuild the skills I had feared lost. It will take time. But I&#8217;m strong. And I will survive.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2775</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Geeqee</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/get-geeqee/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=get-geeqee</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/get-geeqee/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problem solving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2756</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Back at the beginning of the year, I took a different direction in my career. Until December, I&#8217;d been a career man &#8212; work for one company. Work your butt off, be the cog in the machine, and do the best you could to stay safe. It was what I knew, and it generally worked &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/get-geeqee/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Get Geeqee"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back at the beginning of the year, I took a different direction in my career. Until December, I&#8217;d been a career man &#8212; work for one company. Work your butt off, be the cog in the machine, and do the best you could to stay safe. It was what I knew, and it generally worked well. Or rather, worked me well. (I&#8217;m sure you know what I mean&#8230;)<br />
Things changed, and I went the route of contracting, something I hadn&#8217;t really done since I left university. Initially, it was with my friends over at Evans Hunt Group. The result was VisitCalgary.com. Since then, I opted to take a vacation, and now it&#8217;s time for me to get my own little consultancy off and running.<br />
It&#8217;s time for me to <a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/">Get Geeqee</a>.<br />
<span id="more-2756"></span>Yes, it&#8217;s pronounced &#8220;geeky&#8221;. I could have done the 1337 thing and spelled it like &#8220;G33k&#8221; (already taken, I might add), but I liked the way &#8220;Geeqee&#8221; actually looks. (True story: the idea came to me while I was sitting in a meeting discussing need to get &#8220;visitcalgary.com&#8221; for the website project.)<br />
I didn&#8217;t do much with it right away &#8212; I was already too busy with my existing projects, and I wasn&#8217;t in a rush to spend my vacation working. So, some nine months after purchasing the domain, I&#8217;m proud to announce&#8230;<br />
<a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/"><img class="alignnone" title="Geeqee Technical Services" src="http://www.geeqee.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/geeqe-logo.gif" alt="The Geeqee Logo" width="410" height="90" /></a><br />
<a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/">Geeqee</a> is my professional side. I&#8217;m leaving Sowrey.Org as my blog and general havoc-wreaking area. I need something a little cleaner, a little more polished for anyone who might wish to use my services.<br />
Speaking of services, there is the question of what I do. Well, let&#8217;s keep in mind that, as a geek, I tend towards technical services, and generally related towards interactive marketing (namely, websites). Over 15 years of experience in this business has given me a lot of experience, and thanks to an exceedingly long list of teachers and mentors, I have a lot of skills I can throw at a given problem. I&#8217;ll free admit that I&#8217;m not an expert in everything (rather difficult to do that, if you ask me), but I&#8217;d like to think that I&#8217;m more than good enough to do the job.<br />
What job, you ask? Well, try these on for size:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/development-programming/">Development / Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/technical-direction-strategy-and-architecture/">Technical Direction, Strategy, and Architecture</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/technical-documentation/">Technical Documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/business-and-functional-analysis/">Business and Functional Analysis</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/website-analysis/">Website Analysis</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/team-leadership/">Team Leadership</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/offshore-development-management/">Offshore Development Management</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/hosting-administration/">Hosting Administration</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/release-engineering-and-code-management/">Release Engineering and Code Management</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/systems-administration/">Systems Administration</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.geeqee.ca/services/technical-support/">Technical Support</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Think I might be able to help you or someone you know? Drop me a line, I&#8217;d love to chat!<br />
Geeqee. No bull. Just what you need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/get-geeqee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2756</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visit Calgary: You&#039;re Very Welcome!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2681</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When we returned from Costa Rica, our plans had been pretty simple: take off the month of December to get settled, and then head back to work in January. Plans changed shortly after arriving back home, and suddenly I found myself without a job. Bills still had to be paid, food purchased, and because we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Visit Calgary: You&#039;re Very Welcome!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When we returned from Costa Rica, our plans had been pretty simple: take off the month of December to get settled, and then head back to work in January. Plans changed shortly after arriving back home, and suddenly I found myself without a job. Bills still had to be paid, food purchased, and because we live in a city that is far too unfriendly to public transit, we also had to buy a car.<br />
A few years ago, this probably would have put me into a panic. And a few years ago, it would have been just me to worry about. Now I have a wife and two kids (well, one at the time, and one on the way) to support. Really, that should have put me off the deep end. Having lived through a significant amount of adversity over the last couple of years, though, I found myself not even concerned about the prospect of unemployment.<br />
I attribute that to having kept contact with just the right people.<br />
<span id="more-2681"></span>And so it came to pass that on 5 January, I walked into a meeting room on the 2nd floor of 805 10th Ave SW, and sat at a table with nine other people. <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/7422595138">Nine people I already knew.</a> Nine people I&#8217;d already worked with before at another company. I couldn&#8217;t help but smile.<br />
I was working &#8212; and still work &#8212; for the <a href="http://www.evanshunt.com/">Evans Hunt</a> Group, a small interactive marketing agency made up, largely, of former employees of Critical Mass. The principals of the company, Dan Evans and Bill Hunt, were both my managers at Critical Mass at one point or another, and Bill had been the one who started up the Costa Rica operation. My long-time mentor and also former Critical Mass manager, Allard Losier, is the technical lead, and the one who really convinced me to come in.<br />
[flickr]photo:4685617342(small)[/flickr]<br />
That conversation had occurred at the Cabin Cafe on Bow Trail and 45th St. SW, on 22 December. He and I had sat down over a coffee (two, in my case), and had a long conversation about events of the last 18 months, and potential events for the future. I hadn&#8217;t made any decisions at that point, although there had been heavy hinting at coming in to work for Evans Hunt, and I was rather enjoying the not-working aspect of my life.<br />
The conversation had really shown me the things that I had really missed over the previous 18 months: mentorship and trust. I had <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/">lost my mentor when Allard had left Critical Mass</a> shortly before I went to Costa Rica. And I had felt since about that time that there hadn&#8217;t been much trust in me, and always felt on the defensive. Going anywhere else was &#8230; well, it needed to be the right place.<br />
My project &#8212; the reason I was brought in &#8212; was to help Tourism Calgary with their website. The project, at least at a high level, was pretty simple: site overhaul. (Yes, at the high level, that&#8217;s all it is. Once you start going down in the levels, you really find out what kind of trouble you&#8217;re creating for yourself.) My job? Lead the tech team, work with the PM, and help deliver the final product. Time was originally pegged at about three months, and we&#8217;d see where things would go from there.<br />
I didn&#8217;t get a consulting agreement for three weeks. Normally, that would probably freak most people out entirely, my Mom being one of them. From her perspective, which I totally understood, I was working without any legal backup, and was likely to get screwed somewhere along the line. From my perspective, I wasn&#8217;t working for a company &#8212; I was working with friends. Friends I trusted, and who trusted me. People I knew wouldn&#8217;t pull anything shifty, so long as I didn&#8217;t do the same.<br />
That level of trust has permeated my now five-month tenure here at Evans Hunt. Knowing that the right people are there, that the right things will happen when they need to. All of that led us to the launch of our newest little baby, <a href="http://www.visitcalgary.com/">VisitCalgary.com</a>. Today, I supported Jim at a presentation by Tourism Calgary to the tourism industry at the Glenbow Museum (chosen because of Calgary&#8217;s recent bout of inclement weather &#8212; originally, it was supposed to be outside), and got to see the reaction first-hand of the very people we&#8217;re trying to support.<br />
And that&#8217;s when it really hit me. I&#8217;m not working for some massive multi-national conglomerate. I&#8217;m working for a group who&#8217;s trying to bring in tourists to the city I live in, to bring in money to the businesses that exist in the city I live in, to support the families of the people who work for the companies in the city I live in. I had disconnective issues working with American and European vendors for a very long time, partly because they never really affected me in any way. But this? This, I can get behind.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long project, and a little harder than I&#8217;d thought it be. The site, for the record, runs on Drupal. (For those of you unfamiliar, I suggest checking it out. Very powerful tool, Drupal.) I approached the project with a lot of confidence, believing that we&#8217;d be cruising along in no time. That&#8217;s when reality hit me.<br />
Drupal wasn&#8217;t at all like any content management system I&#8217;d ever worked with. And as a result, I was giving bad directions. It wasn&#8217;t until we started to engage Brian, one of Evans Hunt&#8217;s developers, that I began my Drupal education. A content management system, it is not. As Brian put it, it&#8217;s a content management framework. Yeah, I know, I know &#8212; splitting hairs, right? Not really.<br />
In every other CMS I&#8217;d spent significant time with, the rule of thumb was to build your templates first, and then embed the CMS functionality into them to build out the site. But with Drupal, you do it the other way around &#8212; let Drupal define the structure, and then make it look pretty afterwards. We lost time because of my direction.<br />
Thankfully, we also had some very talented developers. The first up was <a href="http://openhouseconcept.com/about">Lorne of Open House Concept</a>, who was the initial developer, and was the core layout guru. <a href="http://www.katokalen.com/">Kalen</a> jumped on not long after to work on templates, and then buzzed back in towards the end of the project in a weird little game of leap-frog. <a href="http://portfolio.brianc.info/">Brian</a> joined the project, which got us pointed in the right direction again (notably, correcting my oversights), and we brought on <a href="http://seeboriscode.blogspot.com/">Boris</a> to help us with the backend data synchronisation.<br />
It sounds like a lot of people, but in truth we only had three developers running at any one time. And considering I can barely code my way out of a paper bag, I am truly amazed at what the four of them did to get this site out the door. Especially considering that the office is just finishing a near two-month renovation, which had us working remotely from our PM-extraordinare January&#8217;s house for over a week.<br />
And yes, there were a lot of hours put into this project. They kept us working late, and more than a couple of weekends. This is where, in the past, I would lament the time away from my family. But this is also where that aforementioned trust comes in. Working from home is encouraged (assuming you don&#8217;t need to be in the office), and working at hours that suit your schedule is not a problem (provided you get your work done). End result: long hours, but still got be a family man.<br />
So, damn right I&#8217;m a happy camper. All told, I would say this has been one of my more favourite projects, and I&#8217;ve had a few doozies to compete with, too.<br />
And, really, you can never go wrong working with friends. (And yes &#8212; <em>with</em>, not for.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2681</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mentorship is a must</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/mentorship-is-a-must/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mentorship-is-a-must</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/mentorship-is-a-must/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2634</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No-one is ever born knowing everything. Like all animal life, we enter the world devoid of knowledge, having only the instincts innate to our species after countless eons of evolution, adaptation, and survival of the fittest. But those instincts can only grant us so much in the act of survival &#8212; they do very little &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/mentorship-is-a-must/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mentorship is a must"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No-one is ever born knowing everything. Like all animal life, we enter the world devoid of knowledge, having only the instincts innate to our species after countless eons of evolution, adaptation, and survival of the fittest. But those instincts can only grant us so much in the act of survival &#8212; they do very little for us as higher-intelligence beings. Instincts can only assist survival, in near-epic troglodytic proportions.<br />
We need teachers to help us move past mere instinct towards self-sufficiency, and self-learning. They teach us mathematics, communication, sciences, and art. As intelligence grows, we shift away from teachers, and look more towards peers &#8212; people who are similar, but have more experience. They are our mentors, ones who offer their abilities as examples for us to learn from, and models upon which we can hope to improve ourselves.<br />
And anyone who thinks they can survive without a mentor has truly never had one.<br />
<span id="more-2634"></span>Mentorship comes in many forms. As previously mentioned, we have teachers or professors. These are the ones most readily identified, and the ones that we often credit with success. Interestingly enough, they&#8217;re also the only &#8220;professional&#8221; mentors &#8212; ones who are trained for that very task. Also consider:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your manager, be it the one from your high school days at the local burger joint, or the one sitting in their office across your cubicle at work</li>
<li>If you work in trades, it could be the one who&#8217;s helping you through your journeyman&#8217;s ticket</li>
<li>The clergy of your church, mosque,  synagogue, or temple</li>
<li>Your best friends, who won&#8217;t shy away from telling you when you&#8217;re wrong</li>
<li>And lest we forget the most underrated and undervalued mentors of all: our parents</li>
</ul>
<p>In the industry that I work in &#8212; interactive marketing, with a particular focus on technology &#8212; there is always the need for mentorship. No business can truly operate without mentorship, at least not without a hope of guidance or improvement. Without mentorship, you might as well be flatlining, in all connotations of the word.<br />
Mentorship, in its simplest form, is guidance. Every human is capable of thought, of decision, of education. But on their own, every human is going to lack the lifeguard that will help them when they start to drown. The mentor is the one who&#8217;ll guide them back to shallow water, or offer the hand to pull them to safety.<br />
Note something particular with that analogy, too: mentorship is a two-way street. It only works if there is someone offering, and someone accepting.<br />
Mentorship does not exist if you are looking to someone for help that they&#8217;re simply not willing to give, or have enough care to give decently (it can be argued that too little guidance is no guidance at all). Similarly, someone willing to offer guidance has no impact to someone who doesn&#8217;t want to listen (there is <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/05/the-blinding-effect-of-an-ego/">a blinding effect, usually tied to ego</a>, that can drown out a wise voice). Failed mentorships can lead to breakdown in team structures, loss of confidence in team members&#8217; abilities, and usually poor performance.<br />
A mentor should be someone who offers insights that a person does not have. Since insights can come from virtually anyone, mentors are not bound by age, sex, creed, religion, ethnicity, career direction, relationship, educational background, time zone, or any other possible criteria that could potentially be considered a detriment or block. And there is nothing stopping someone from having more than one mentor &#8212; in fact, multiple mentors allow a person to gain multiple insights in different things.<br />
When I moved over to Evans Hunt Group at the beginning of this year, I regained my long-time mentors Dan, Bill, and Allard, as well as one of my more recent mentors, Tori. All of them have been crucial in teaching me not just the hard skills of my job, but also the things that help my day-to-day life: organisation, calmness, focus, direction, caution, daring, courage, and even bravery.<br />
Today, for example, I had particularly good reminder of why I need a mentor. I&#8217;m the technical lead for a large project that we&#8217;re due to deliver in about a month-and-a-half. As part of my operating procedure, I like to keep Allard in the loop of what&#8217;s going on. It&#8217;s a good practice for redundancy, but also because it&#8217;s good to get a sanity check &#8212; if nothing else, make sure that your &#8220;solution&#8221; is sound, and not going down the wrong road.<br />
Allard (proverbially) whacked me over the nose with a rolled up newspaper and said &#8220;bad dog!&#8221; for part of an architecture. At the time, naturally, I objected to the accusation, feeling that the direction was sound and would offer the best chance of success. But &#8212; and this is where my previous note really applies &#8212; I remained open to Allard&#8217;s thoughts. It took us a while of discussion (partly because it was Allard&#8217;s gut check went off first, and it took a little while for his elocution to catch up), but ultimately I could only see that he was right &#8212; I&#8217;d made a fundamental flaw in my own logic, and actually introduced risk.<br />
Truly, mentorship need not be a full-time occupation. A competent person will not always need guidance, and not always from the same person. Likewise, a mentor doesn&#8217;t always have time to offer. A good relationship will usually balance itself naturally.<br />
And if you don&#8217;t have a mentor, or are at least readily able to identify them, don&#8217;t worry. Often, all you need to do is merely start talking with someone. Eventually, you&#8217;ll talk to the right person, and you&#8217;ll find the guidance you need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/mentorship-is-a-must/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2634</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
