<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>failure &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/failure/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Failure is an option</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/failure-is-an-option/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=failure-is-an-option</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/failure-is-an-option/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 19:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One afternoon, a few years ago now, the head of my department uttered something completely heretical while we were in a fairly high-stressed meeting about some technical difficulties we were having on a project. It was one of those utterances that made everyone take pause, look at him, and wonder if he was off his &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/failure-is-an-option/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Failure is an option"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One afternoon, a few years ago now, the head of my department uttered something completely heretical while we were in a fairly high-stressed meeting about some technical difficulties we were having on a project. It was one of those utterances that made everyone take pause, look at him, and wonder if he was off his rocker.<br />
He wasn&#8217;t, for the record. In fact, he was striving for us to not view impending doom as a bad thing. While his two words were at first shocking (especially to the Account Managers present, who&#8217;d ultimately have to deal with the client), it was also one of those moments you sat back and actually thought about what you were doing.<br />
So what did he say?</p>
<blockquote><p>Embrace failure.<br />
<cite>&#8211; Allard Losier</cite></p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-1361"></span>We are taught almost from the moment we enter this world that failure is bad. Failing means punishment, ridicule, losing respect, or in particularly awful situations, death. In the business world, it can also lead to reassignment, demotion, or even loss of a job. And to be sure there are varying degrees of failure, but they&#8217;re all generally perceived as negative.<br />
So naturally, when Allard made his proclamation, I was just as surprised as the others. But unlike some of the others (those who have to deal with budgets, scheduling, and the client had a tougher time accepting it), I quickly began to see the wisdom behind it, and the necessity of that point of view.<br />
At the time, we were in the midst of a particularly tough project, and it wasn&#8217;t going really well. Depending on whom you asked, it stunk. It wasn&#8217;t because of ability &#8212; I am proud to say that I was working with a gifted team of developers. Nor was it because of a poor schedule &#8212; we&#8217;d (originally) allotted for enough time.<br />
So what stunk? Risk.<br />
Risk is one of those things that few people like. Even investment bankers who claim to like risk only go so far because too much risk could potentially ruin any gains.  Â And in the world of business, no-one likes to pay for something that isn&#8217;t guaranteed.<br />
That&#8217;s a major problem. Not the risk itself, but in the unwillingness to take risk. No risk means status quo. It means doing what&#8217;s already been done. It means not moving forward &#8230; or even keeping pace. In advertising, this is deadly.<br />
When you&#8217;re dealing with technology, you need to always be at least looking forward, if not moving forward. And your development team will almost always push for the latter. Developers, for the most part, hate doing things the same way when they know there&#8217;s a better way. Well, at least my experience with gifted developers suggests they prefer a better way.<br />
The &#8220;better&#8221; way involves risk. You have to do things differently. For you to be able to take that risk, there is one thing you need to do: accept the fact that you could <em>fail</em>. Not that you will fail, but that you might not achieve what you&#8217;d planned. And it&#8217;s not just you that needs to accept that failure is a possibility: your team needs to know this, your project management needs to know this, as does your account team, client team, and the client themselves.<br />
Awareness is important. Aside from a position of being honest, you really should make sure that everyone understands the risk. (It won&#8217;t always happen reliably.) This is a point you should never avoid &#8212; fill in the details. No, you won&#8217;t gain complete comprehension, but you&#8217;d rather have a problem of glazed eyes than have those eyes firing laser beams when you have to tell them that you&#8217;re not able to deliver because you took a risk no-one knew about.<br />
We&#8217;d walked into our project with a considerable amount of confidence that we would deliver. There was risk that we wouldn&#8217;t hit our launch dates, but we felt &#8212; all of us &#8212; that the direction was better for the end product. Still, it required us to take leaps of faith that we could build what we&#8217;d promised, not just internally, but also from our client.<br />
I encourage you to consider the same: failure is always an option. Saying that you cannot fail means that you cannot consider possibilities that might lead to failure. But allowing yourself to consider things that might not work, you&#8217;ll give yourself a better view not only of the problem but also of the solution spectrum. And while you might not be able to properly decide on a course of action yourself, your insight can lead to the right answer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/06/failure-is-an-option/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Funny things in emails</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=funny-things-in-emails</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I got into a fairly typical email exchange with Paul, one of our Release Engineers. Since I&#8217;m no longer on Rolex, I wanted to be taken off the email lists. This was how it went down: Me: Hey Paul, Now that Torin&#8217;s running the Tech show, can you pull me from the Rolex Monitoring alias, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Funny things in emails"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got into a fairly typical email exchange with Paul, one of our Release Engineers. Since I&#8217;m no longer on Rolex, I wanted to be taken off the email lists. This was how it went down:<br />
Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hey Paul,<br />
Now that Torin&#8217;s running the Tech show, can you pull me from the Rolex Monitoring alias, please?<br />
*sniff*<br />
Thanks,<br />
G.</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-976"></span>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>No. You will forever get paged.<br />
MUAHH HAHAHAHAHAHA</p></blockquote>
<p>Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>I don&#8217;t get paged. Just emails. And they get dumped into a folder I barely read.<br />
Nyah nyah nyah nyah nyah nyahhhhhhhhhhhhh</p></blockquote>
<p>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>Well since I now control the alias&#8230; and I know your cell number &#8230; well you do the math.</p></blockquote>
<p>Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Well, since I&#8217;m moving to Costa Rica and you don&#8217;t have my Costa Rican cell number &#8230; go right ahead. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f61b.png" alt="ðŸ˜›" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p></blockquote>
<p>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>EPIC FAIL <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f641.png" alt="ðŸ™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">976</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Microsoft ever admit that Vista was a bad idea?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 02:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/04/will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It takes a big person to admit that they&#8217;ve made a mistake. Companies, regardless of how large they become, were reticent until recent years to come clean with their blunders. Microsoft ain&#8217;t one of them. They still think Vista is good. And why not &#8212; they&#8217;ve sold 60 million licenses for it. But I&#8217;d be &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Will Microsoft ever admit that Vista was a bad idea?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It takes a big person to admit that they&#8217;ve made a mistake. Companies, regardless of how large they become, were reticent until recent years to come clean with their blunders.<br />
Microsoft ain&#8217;t one of them. They still think Vista is good. And why not &#8212; they&#8217;ve sold 60 million licenses for it. But I&#8217;d be really curious to know how many of those people would have preferred Windows XP.<br />
<span id="more-829"></span>In case you haven&#8217;t heard &#8212; and it looks to be kept fairly quiet &#8212; <a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20070928-amid-disappointing-vista-uptake-microsoft-relents-on-xp-execution.html">Microsoft is giving Windows XP a longer shelf life</a> before it&#8217;s put permanently out to pasture. This is a result of all the vendors asking the XP be kept longer due to the demand (or more specifically, the lack thereof) for Vista.<br />
The scary part is that Microsoft hasn&#8217;t really clued into this yet. Yes, they&#8217;re keeping XP on life support, but they don&#8217;t want to acknowledge why.  Microsoft is trying too hard to earn money by ramming a less-than-mediocre product down their user&#8217;s throats. They completely misunderstood their market, created a sub-standard product, and were surprised when no-one bought it.<br />
Microsoft missed the paradigm shift. Suddenly, half-assed isn&#8217;t good enough. Linux caught up. Apple released something far sexier and more compatible (and snagged a few percentage points more market share in the process). And security issues have been dogging the Big M for years, now. Why would anyone want to choose the devil they didn&#8217;t know over the one they&#8217;ve managed to get locked down?<br />
And then let&#8217;s also consider the companies that have to deal with this infrastructure. Vista doesn&#8217;t cohabitate well with XP environments. Yes, they talk, but Vista prefers Vista. And Vista needs hardware. Lots of it. Too much of it. <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/products/windowsvista/editions/systemrequirements.mspx">A recommended business solution requires</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>1 GHz 32-bit (x86) or 64-bit (x64) processor</li>
<li>1 GB of system memory</li>
<li>40 GB hard drive with at least 15 GB of available space</li>
<li>Support for DirectX 9 graphics with:
<ul>
<li>WDDM Driver</li>
<li>128 MB of graphics memory (minimum)</li>
<li>Pixel Shader 2.0 in hardware</li>
<li>32 bits per pixel</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>That&#8217;s just to use Microsoft Word. Am I on crack, or [[Microsoft Vista is a failure|does that just seem a bit much]]? Or maybe it&#8217;s Microsoft&#8217;s acknowledgement that Word is a bit of a resource pig. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="ðŸ˜‰" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br />
No IT department is looking at Vista as a great thing. (Our IT team at Critical Mass is avoiding it like the plague.) It&#8217;s a burden, not just from support (those <a href="http://movies.apple.com/movies/us/apple/getamac/apple-getamac-chooseavista_480x376.mov">Apple commercials</a> <a href="http://movies.apple.com/movies/us/apple/getamac/apple-getamac-tech-support_480x396.mov">might be funny</a>, but <a href="http://movies.apple.com/movies/us/apple/getamac/apple-getamac-security_480x376.mov">they&#8217;re also true</a>) but also from a cost point. Who wants to pay more for a basic need?<br />
You think the vendors haven&#8217;t figured that out? Dell, HP, Lenovo, Gateway &#8212; they&#8217;re not seeing the sales of Vista-ready machines. People don&#8217;t want it. This is pure supply and demand economics at work, folks. The demand ain&#8217;t there. No-one wants it. Forcing everyone to Vista isn&#8217;t in the vendors&#8217; best interests &#8212; especially when XP still sells well.<br />
I hope someone at Microsoft finally takes a hint from this. Ditch Windows. It&#8217;s done. Gone. Over with. Get smart and do what Apple did &#8212; base your next operating system on something better (like UNIX), and give it a much nicer interface. You&#8217;ll get the benefit of better memory management, better file system support, you get rid of the anachronistic registry, and ultimately better security.<br />
You wonder why people are shifting to Macs? It ain&#8217;t for the logo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/will-microsoft-ever-admit-that-vista-was-a-bad-idea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="http://movies.apple.com/movies/us/apple/getamac/apple-getamac-chooseavista_480x376.mov" length="3529974" type="video/quicktime" />
<enclosure url="http://movies.apple.com/movies/us/apple/getamac/apple-getamac-security_480x376.mov" length="3591501" type="video/quicktime" />

		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">829</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
