<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>yotsukaido &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/yotsukaido/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2004 23:14:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Tsukiji Market</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2004 23:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chiba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsukiji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/09/turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why had I gone to Shinagawa to kill time? Simply put, it was far enough away from Tsukiji that walking alone would eat up some time, but not so far that I would be exhausted by the time I got to my destination. I had originally thought Shibuya, but a quick glance at a map &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Tsukiji Market"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why had I gone to Shinagawa to kill time? Simply put, it was far enough away from Tsukiji that walking alone would eat up some time, but not so far that I would be exhausted by the time I got to my destination. I had originally thought Shibuya, but a quick glance at a map ruled it out immediately.<br />
To add to my time getting to Tsukiji, I also planned to walk to Tokyo Tower for some night photographs. Beyond that, I was making up everything as I went. That wasn&#8217;t too hard, considering I didn&#8217;t really know where I was going. I wasn&#8217;t looking at a map, I was just using my sense of direction (usually very reliable) and certain landmarks to know where I was.<br />
<span id="more-347"></span>It&#8217;s almost creepy to think that I&#8217;ve been in Tokyo long enough (this year and last) that I know actual landmarks.<br />
The streets of downtown Tokyo are rather interesting at night. Despite what movies have shown, the majority of Tokyo is quiet. Areas such as Shibuya will be raucous most of the night, but areas like the one I was walking through are surprisingly desolate. Aside from bursts of traffic, 24 hour convenience stores, drunk people either stumbling down the road or urinating in planters, and the odd bicyclist, the streets are very serene. There is a strange, almost zen-like quality about Tokyo at night.<br />
I found Tokyo Tower rather easily. (I stopped along the way only once, at a 7-11 to get a Coke and a salmon onigiri to keep my energy up.) Not by looking at a map, but because it&#8217;s very easy to see at a distance. The lights stay on all night, so make for an ideal photography subject. I know this because I wasn&#8217;t the only one taking pictures of it. It&#8217;s wonderful to observe not only at a distance but also close-up. It would be even nicer to go directly underneath, as you can with the Eiffel Tower (which Tokyo Tower is modelled after), but someone decided to put a rather large building right underneath the tower, ruining a chance of that.<br />
Leaving three drunk Japanese men taking strange photos of themselves in front of the tower with a keitai, I continued my walk to Tsukiji.<br />
Quite poorly, I might add.<br />
Not really thinking about which direction I&#8217;d been going in (I cut through Shibya Park, pausing to take photos at the shrine in the dark), I ended up accidentally doubling back on part of my route. I cursed myself when I realized that I&#8217;d done. But at least I&#8217;d still had a good walk and used more time.<br />
I found my way back to the World Trade Center Building, and continued down to Hama-Rikyu Gardens, which is wedged between Hammamatsucho and Tsukiji. I walked along the north side of Hama-Rikyu, trying to avoid the plethora of construction that seemed to run every few hundred metres. I can only assume Tokyo runs their road construction crews at night as not to interfere with traffic during the day.<br />
Construction crews in Tokyo, and probably over the parts of Japan that we saw, are models of people-use. There are always two to three people (almost always men &#8212; I only ever saw one woman on the crews) who direct pedestrians. One at either end of the construction zone, and one in the middle, if the zone is quite long. There&#8217;s usually at least one foreman, and a number of workers, depending on what&#8217;s happening. All wear safety vests (those near vehicular traffic have vests with blinking lights) and hardhats.<br />
The roads leading into Tsukiji were already lined with trucks, delivering produce, waiting to pick up produce, or in the process of being loaded. (The market is so busy and overloaded that the roads immediately next to the market are filled with loading equipment in the wee hours of the morning.)<br />
Inside the market, the level of activity was far beyond anything I&#8217;d ever expected. Beehives aren&#8217;t this busy. Forklifts carry large flats of crates, smaller three-wheeled carts whizz around (often haphazardly) with all manners of cargo. I really had to watch where I was going as not to be hit by anything.<br />
That&#8217;s the first rule when visiting Tsukiji market: Your presence is tolerated, though not necessarily welcome. Reality: This is a place of business, no different than your office building or construction site. These people aren&#8217;t a Disney show, this is the real thing. If you go there, you stay out of their way. Those who bring Tsukiji to life do not have the time for mindless tourists who want to get in the way because they are tourists. Imagine if they got in the way of you trying to do your job&#8230;<br />
Despite the activity, the market was only just starting to come to life. Most of the vendors hadn&#8217;t yet arrived, and the buyers would be behind them. Already, however, tuna was beginning to be laid out for the auction. The frozen tuna, each weighing a couple hundred pounds or more, were dumped unceremoniously on the floor, almost as one would dump a cord of wood. Frozen completely stiff, you had to look hard to realize that this was fish, and no something else.<br />
The pre-packaged area was already well underway, the massive stacks of styrofoam containers being arranged and rearranged, full of almost every conceivable (and edible) seafood, ready to be sent to stores for sale. These were mostly uninteresting to me. I was more for the tuna auction, and the live (or recently alive, but not processed) produce.<br />
I wandered around until almost 4:00, at which point the sheer insanity of the whizzing carts and constant dodging of people finally sent me out of the market in search of a bit of rest. A nearby Lawson&#8217;s provided a quick snack and a Coke for a much-needed caffeine burst.<br />
In the scant half-hour that I was gone, most of the fishmongers had arrived and were in operation. Live fish were being sorted and crated, cut and filleted, and packaged for shipping. Ice vendors were chewing up huge blocks (at nearly CDN$27 per block, from what I could tell), and the fresh tuna was laid out for inspection. Also arrived were tourists, bussed in for the auction.<br />
I felt oddly superior. I had been there since earlier that morning, had stayed up late so I could experience this. The rest came with tour groups. Most blatantly ignored the signs that forebade entry into the auction warehouses without permission (it was quite easy to see through the door).<br />
On the auction floor, the fish had been prepared for inspection. The frozen tuna had portions cut open so buyers could inspect for quality. The fresh tuna had slices cut off the end for inspection, and the tails (previously cut off, but kept) were available to check the quality of the meet.<br />
Inside the massive rooms were hundreds of people: buyers, sellers, and what I can only assume were the officials that kept the whole thing running. Buyers were easy to spot &#8212; they wear hats with blue cards that denote who they are buying for. I don&#8217;t believe the tuna purchased at Tsukiji is destined for canning, I think most is destined for processing of some kind &#8212; especially the fresh tuna (much of that is bought for sushi restaurants). Admittedly, though, I&#8217;m not really sure where it all goes. Other than it goes very quickly.<br />
The auctions begin at 5:20 in almost all the four warehouses (three frozen, one fresh). Tuna is on the ground floor, and I gather other kinds are bought and sold in rooms above. The tuna auctions are fast. One of the sellers rings a bell (most sellers have a unique bell ring) that signifies selling is about to being. Those buyers wishing to engage in the sale all come over, and the fish are sold individually, and very rapidly. A single sale might take five seconds or less. Larger fish fetch high prices (one massive beast was hungrily viewed by five or six business men, dressed in their finest).<br />
Unfortunately, tourists here tend to get in the way. Once sales are complete, carts immediately appear to whisk the tuna away. (Frozen tuna is often carted to one of the fishmonger stalls, many of which are equipped with bandsaws for the sole purpose of cutting up tuna.) One particular putz was oblivious to the work going on around him, while talking on this cellphone. I wanted to go over and smack him, because one of the fishmongers was almost yelling at him to get out of the way.<br />
Putz.<br />
Auctions over, I wandered around the market, now in full swing. Fish of almost every variety was in sight, much of it still alive. I watched in amazement, becaue I knew that all of it would be gone within six hours. That kind of efficiency in a place so small is unknown in North America. Tsukiji is huge, make no mistake, but it could easily be twice the size to handle all the needs. That&#8217;s what fascinates me so much about it &#8212; unique in the world for the role it fulfills, and few people ever really think about what it does for life in Japan.<br />
I found my way to the sushi restaurant Chris and I had gone to last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Tsukiji Fish Market]]) for a bit of breakfast. Although you can get good sushi no matter where you are in Tsukiji (including a couple of 24 hour sushi sens in the Outer Market), this particular place I rather liked. Not only were the staff very kind and pleasant, I really liked the green tea and especially the miso soup.<br />
And not knowing Japanese isn&#8217;t a problem. They know enough English to offer you a set (definitely the best way to get it), and tell you the price. (They&#8217;ll also tell you which pieces don&#8217;t need soy sauce.) Although small for what I&#8217;ve been known to eat for sushi, it was exactly what I needed to have for a meal.<br />
With that, I bade Tsukiji farewell, and headed towards Tokyo station. It was still early, so I wasn&#8217;t going to head back to Yotsukaido right away. First, I thought I&#8217;d kill some time at the Imperial Palace, specifically the East Gardens.<br />
I hadn&#8217;t planned to go to the main gate with the double-bridge. But the light from the rising sun and the relative clarity of the skies (Japan seems to be hugged with perpetual smog, no matter where you go), that I couldn&#8217;t pass up a few photos of things I had taken pictures of last year.<br />
As I wandered around to the gate for the East Gardens, I realized that it was Friday. The Gardens, sadly, are closed on Mondays and Fridays, meaning that I would have to wait until the next time I come to Japan to see them. One day, perhaps.<br />
With that, I returned to the station and boarded a train for Chiba. I fell asleep even before the train had left the underground portion of the line. Switching to a local train in Chiba, I almost didn&#8217;t wake up in time for Yotsukaido. I didn&#8217;t take a bus back to the apartment, deciding to save some yen and walk the way back. It gave me my third wind.<br />
Chris was awake when I got to the apartment. We talked a bit about the things I&#8217;d seen and done. Kaz soon came out and the three of us chatted. Kaz made rice and miso soup for breakfast. I could hardly pass up the chance to eat a little more. The activity of the day so far had taken a lot out o me. Finally, Jen woke up and proceeded to shower. Chris tortured me with a taped episode of the live-action Sailor Moon TV show. It you thought the animated version was bad, check out the live action one.<br />
I pray it never comes to North America.<br />
Shortly afterwards, I went to bed. It was just after noon, and I really needed some sleep. I set my alarm and dropped off&#8230;<br />
&#8230;awaking to a loud clatter of doors, bags, and voices. At first, I had no idea where I was. For a brief moment, I wasn&#8217;t even sure who *I* was. But it came back very quickly, like a wave rolling onto the shore. Jen and Kaz were returning from what sounded like shopping. But it was already dark outside &#8230; I&#8217;d only planned to sleep for a couple of hours.<br />
I&#8217;d slept for over five.<br />
We were going to Chiba that night, to dinner with friends. I showered to prepare. I told Kaz to tell Chris we&#8217;d meet him at the station for 20:00 (you have to do that with him). We caught a bus, met up with Chris, and the four of us headed to Chiba.<br />
Shinichiro had called ahead and reserved a table for six at the couches upstairs. Although a bit warm up there, it was more comfortable for eating and chatting. We were quite early, though, and would have to wait for Shinichiro and Riku to arrive. That gave us time to order some drinks, have an appetizer or two, and chat.<br />
Soon, all six of us had assembled, and we were in full chatting and eating modes. Laughter, jokes, and a few English and Japanese lessons flew around. Naome joined us about an hour later, and the seven of us cajoled until well after midnight.<br />
I had only barely known Shinichiro before Chris&#8217; wedding, having met him the first night I was in Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]). Now, he was a friend, as much as Kaz or Naome had become. People I would be more than happen to open my home to, should they decide to ever visit Canada. I will miss them.<br />
We returned by taxi, and I went right to bed. Long nap or not, I needed rest.<br />
[flickr]tag:japan+tokyo+april+9+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tsukiji-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">347</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (more still)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2004 23:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tsukiji]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/08/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We got up a bit later than I&#8217;d hoped for, mostly because I&#8217;d accidentally turned off the alarm instead of snoozing it. We took the first train we could get to into Tokyo. I stood, wedged in a space between the door and the side of the bench, watching the scenery pass. At the time, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (more still)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We got up a bit later than I&#8217;d hoped for, mostly because I&#8217;d accidentally turned off the alarm instead of snoozing it.<br />
We took the first train we could get to into Tokyo. I stood, wedged in a space between the door and the side of the bench, watching the scenery pass. At the time, I had thought this to be my last trip into Tokyo. Having been to Japan twice in two years, I can&#8217;t honestly imagine returning any time soon.<br />
<span id="more-346"></span>We switched to the Yamanote line after getting to Tokyo, then to the O-Edo subway line. We were going to Tsukiji market, and walking (though great exercise) was something I was trying to avoid. Jen was not feeling particularly genke (Japanese for &#8220;energetic&#8221; &#8212; if you hear a Japanese say: &#8220;genke deska&#8221;, they are asking you how you are doing, it&#8217;s a common greeting that literally translated means &#8220;are you energetic&#8221;), and I didn&#8217;t want to make her walk too much.<br />
Arriving at the market, Jen didn&#8217;t honestly believe that we were there. At first glance, it doesn&#8217;t look like a market at all. Near the main entrance, it&#8217;s trucks, forklifts, and countless styrofoam containers. It&#8217;s only once you get past the stall shops that you can see something that makes a little sense. But only when you&#8217;re in the fishmonger stalls inside the market building that you can really see it.<br />
Sadly, by the time we got there, the market was closing down for the day. Most of the buyers and sellers were gone, the tuna long since vanished. Most of the stalls were vacant, showing no signs of any recent use. There simply wasn&#8217;t much to see.<br />
We did a quick circuit of the inside, and left by the east entrance, passing by the south side of the Tsukiji outer market. We were in search of the Ginza area. Before leaving the apartment that morning, I&#8217;d decided that we needed to stop into the Sony building, and witness the newest in Sony consumer electronics. I had no idea if we&#8217;d see anything we hadn&#8217;t already seen in Akehabara, but it couldn&#8217;t hurt to look.<br />
We were half-blindly wandering around. Only once did I look at a map, just to verify that we hadn&#8217;t, in fact, missed the correct road to find the Sony building.<br />
In the process of wandering, we found two things we hadn&#8217;t really been searching for. The first was an ice cream cone (soft serve). That wasn&#8217;t unusual on it&#8217;s own, but the flavour was odd. Black in colour, we had assumed black sesame. However, it&#8217;s just as likely the flavour was squid ink, since we couldn&#8217;t place the taste at all.<br />
The second was a teapot. One of our instructions was to find a cast iron teapot for Aunt Brenda. Not a particularly hard task, but we didn&#8217;t really know what we&#8217;d find when we looked. The one we eventually bought has a red patina of sorts, but one that you might almost miss in dimmer light. We hope it&#8217;s a good pot.<br />
Downtown Tokyo is a strange place. Not all roads have names, some roads have more than one name, some roads seem to only have some sections named, or have different sections with different names. I was looking for Ginza 4-chome (one of eight major north-south roads running through Ginza), on which we&#8217;d find Sony. When we finally found the name of the road we were on, it was Ginza 5-chome.<br />
We&#8217;d overshot our goal by a block. But as it turns out, this was a fortunate thing. As we reached the major east-west road in Ginza, we found the Apple store.<br />
I know this doesn&#8217;t sound like much, but the Apple store opened to tremendous fanfare, with line-ups that had run, quite literally, for blocks. The line-ups were long gone, and it was time to take a bit of a gander.<br />
The building is divided into five floors. The first is home and professional products, the second photographic needs, the third is an Internet cafe, the fourth a theatre, and the fifth various accessories and software. It&#8217;s a small store. So small that the only way to get between floors is by elevator. The elevators are totally automatic, running without having to press buttons for the floors at all.<br />
We headed west to 4-chome, and turned north towards the railway tracks. A block away, we found the Sony building. It&#8217;s an unassuming place, particularly odd for a company with such influence and power in the entertainment and electronics industries.<br />
From the first floor, spiralling up to the third, is a showroom of Sony products and technologies, broken only on a &#8220;floor between the first and second&#8221; that features a BMW &#8220;store&#8221;. (It has a car in there. I have no idea how on earth they got a car in there. Maybe by taking out the windows, but that just doesn&#8217;t seem right.)<br />
We started on the first floor (a massive video wall showcased a new product &#8212; a bipedal robot capable of standing back up if it falls over), then took an elevator to the third floor (we were a little apprehensive about going through the BMW store at first).<br />
There was little in the store that we not had not seen before. About the only thing that I saw that truly impressed me was a remote control system built for use with the Sony WEGA plasma TV systems. It&#8217;s more than just a mere remote control, however. You can surf the web, find TV channels and video signals, &#8220;throw&#8221; them onto the big screen, or alternatively capture them back to the remote. It&#8217;s a pretty slick device, and I&#8217;m more than a little afraid to find out how much it costs.<br />
We circled down, perusing the other wares, finding nothing else of real interest. Eventually, we exited back into the cooler outside air. We walked down to the Shimbashi JR station, about 3/4 of a kilometre from the Sony building. From there, a Yamanote train to Harajuku.<br />
By this time, Jen&#8217;s unwellness had turned into a full migraine. She moved slowly, and deliberately. She barely had the energy to walk from the station, down Takeshita St. to Meiji-dori, and back. (Maybe a kilometre, all told.) We did stop into a couple of stores, and did have lunch at a restaurant that featured ton-katsu (breaded pork cutlets).<br />
We headed back to Chiba and Yotsukaido. I tried to see if we could catch an NEX train &#8212; I&#8217;ve wanted to ride one for a long time &#8212; but we couldn&#8217;t get one that stopped at Chiba anytime soon. We had to take the Yamanote back to Tokyo station, and then a regular rapid Sobu train that went directly to Yotsukaido (saving us the additional train at Chiba).<br />
Kaz was out with her friend and Chris was at work. Having no key, we had to stop in briefly at the school to pick up Chris&#8217; key. We then hopped a bus back to the apartment, where we relaxed.<br />
It was then that I made my decision. I wasn&#8217;t going to be denied seeing a fish auction at Tsukiji. I needed to see it. Not just because of sheer interest, but also because the present market won&#8217;t exist in a couple of years &#8212; it&#8217;s being replaced by a newer one elsewhere in Tokyo harbour. For me, it was a case of now or never.<br />
This was a trip I would do alone. I knew Jen wouldn&#8217;t want to do the overnight in Tokyo, going without sleep, and wandering around in the market for at least a couple of hours. Although I wasn&#8217;t too keen on leaving her behind (alone, too, since neither Chris nor Kaz were home when I left), I headed to the bus just before 22:00, and caught the first train to downtown Tokyo.<br />
This is my last trip into Tokyo for the foreseeable future. Unless there is a pressing need for me to return, I doubt I&#8217;ll be back for a number of years. I had thought about that fact this morning. But not on this trip in. Rather, I slept. Well, as much as I could, considering I was rather excited about being downtown, wandering around at will, effectively killing time until I could see something at Tsukiji.<br />
The market officially opens around midnight, but things generally don&#8217;t start moving until about 2:00. The actual tuna auction isn&#8217;t until 5:20. And with train service ending at midnight, the only way I could see the auction was to do something until there was something worth seeing at Tsukiji.<br />
This led me to the Shinagawa station, courtesy of the Yamanote line. There, I took a couple pictures on the platform (streams of late-running salarymen heading in the direction of home), then headed out the exit into the night air. My rail pass has expired, it will serve no more purpose. Tonight, I am on my own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kamakura</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kamakura</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 23:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/07/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were up a little earlier than the previous few days, so we could catch a good train out to Kamakura, our excursion for the day. Kamakura is a small town south of Tokyo, about an hour and three-quarters away from Yotsukaido. From 1192 to 1333, Kamakura was the feudal capital of Japan. There are &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kamakura"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were up a little earlier than the previous few days, so we could catch a good train out to Kamakura, our excursion for the day.<br />
Kamakura is a small town south of Tokyo, about an hour and three-quarters away from Yotsukaido. From 1192 to 1333, Kamakura was the feudal capital of Japan. There are no signs of its previous governmental past today, but the marks of its present status as a religious centre are very clear. The area is peppered with no less than 84 shrines and temples. Less than Kyoto, but Kamakura is a much smaller area.<br />
<span id="more-345"></span>We had outstanding timing this morning, arriving at the Yotsukaido station mere moments before the train to Zushi arrived. The Zushi train comes only once an hour. It comes from Narita Airport, and runs the full length of the Sobu / Yokosuka line. Had we not caught the Zushi train, we&#8217;d have had to take a local to Chiba and change there for a Zushi train.<br />
Originally, I thought we&#8217;d have to change trains at Zushi and take a local to Kamakura. But as luck would have it, the map I&#8217;d looked at wasn&#8217;t particularly clear, and we could take that train all the way to Kamakura without changing once.<br />
We had to stand all the way into Tokyo before we could sit down for the rest of the trip. Jen snoozed, even I caught a few minutes of additional sleep. We got off at the small station of Kita-Kamakura, which the guide book recommended as the starting point for the walk.<br />
First on the list was the Engakuji Temple. A facinating little walk, the temple was considered second among the five great zen temples of Kamakura. Accented by stands of cherry trees, the grounds even featured a new building under construction. Unfortunately, we couldn&#8217;t get close enough to see what it looked like.<br />
We walked from there down to Kenchoji Temple. First among the five great temples, this was a temple I did on my own. Jen had her fill of temples after the second one, and decided that she wasn&#8217;t visiting any more without good reason. While I was at first very disappointed to hear that, I could certainly understand her perspective. I remember thinking that there were far too many churches and cathedrals when I was in the Soviet Union (see [[Behind the Iron Curtain: My Trip to the Soviet Union, Touring Odessa]]).<br />
The approach to the temple was lined with cherry trees, and the interior was laid out with a zen perfection that we had not seen before. I almost found it quite annoying that I could not wander around a while longer and find more things to see. Such as it was, however, I didn&#8217;t want to keep Jen waiting too long.<br />
I know that Jen was a little tired of all this wandering around small towns, seeing the same shrine over and over again. But the point of travelling is to see the country you&#8217;re in. And that&#8217;s hard to do when you don&#8217;t want to see it. It&#8217;s even more hard when one of you wants to see it, and the other does not. I promised to avoid any more temples unless they were really interesting, until we got to the Great Buddha.<br />
I managed to keep us walking, eventually reaching the main downtown of Kamakura. The main road through downtown has a cherry tree-lined walkway down the middle, dividing the two lanes of traffic. I can only imagine how wonderful it must look like at night.<br />
We arrived at the Kamakura station. There, we took the Enoden Line to Hase, on a small, old single-tracked tram line. This brought us much closer to the Great Buddha, saving us a bit of a walk. Although it is nice to have nice, warm weather, walking around in at least 20 degree weather gets a little uncomfortable after a while.<br />
The walk up to the Kotokuin Temple (home of the Great Buddha) was nice, marked with a few shops and restaurants. Prices for similar items climbed the closer you got to the Buddha, of course. We perused a bit as we climbed.<br />
The Great Buddha was created in 1252 by sculptors Ono-Goroemon and Tanji-Hisatomo. This massive structure was cast in bronze (in several large sections) and housed in a massive temple. In 1498, a massive tsunami reached the heights of Kotokuin temple, destroying the wooden structures but leaving the 13.35 metre-tall, 121 ton structure intact. Since the tsunami, the statue has been exposed directly to the elements.<br />
It is an impressive structure. Despite its massive size (and weight), the statue doesn&#8217;t really look all that large. It&#8217;s an impressive design that takes something so large and make it seem a little more inviting. Its peaceful stance (in the traditional buddha sitting pose) brings on similar feelings in those who visit it. It&#8217;s with no surprise that the Great Buddha is one of the main attractions at Kamakura.<br />
Having taken in the grandeur of the Buddha, we headed back towards the Hase tram station to return to Kamakura station. But instead of taking the tram, we opted to walk the 1.7 km (this was Jen&#8217;s suggestion, not mine). We had half-thought that we might be able to find something to eat along the way. Much to our surprise, most of the stores and restaurants appeared to be closed. It seemed completely contrary to normal logic for a tourist-rich location.<br />
Finally, we reached a short pedestrian mall that led us down to the Kamakura JR station. After getting a quick snack at a food stand of sorts, we caught the first Narita Airport-bound train. That would take us all the way back to Yotsukaido without having to change trains.<br />
We left Kamakura at 15:18, and arrived in Yotsukaido at 17:00. That left us plenty of time to hit the toy store near the station. We&#8217;d gone in very briefly last night before coming home, but had to leave early because the store was closing. This time, we had plenty of time to peruse.<br />
Perhaps too much time. As we came out of the store, the bus we needed to catch pulled away. And following with the completely inconsistent nature of the bus schedule, the next wouldn&#8217;t appear for almost an hour and a half.<br />
So we walked back to the apartment.<br />
Mind you, we had no real way of knowing whether or not Kaz was actually home. We had tried to get a hold of her a couple of times, but with no answer, we didn&#8217;t know if she was actually home. As it stands, she had only come home not long before we arrived, as a convenient happenstance. She had been out with her friend, who would be spending the night with us.<br />
Kaz was very kind to make us dinner, flavoured pasta. Kaz and her friend watched a &#8220;Friends&#8221; DVD (a show that I cannot particularly stand) translated in to Japanese. I sat and wrote my journals, while Jen watched, waiting until she could get access to the Playstation to continue playing &#8220;Devil May Cry 2&#8221;.<br />
Finally, just after 23:00, Chris appeared for the first time since Sunday. We won&#8217;t get much time with him today, so hopefully, we&#8217;ll make the most of it now, so we can have some time before we leave for home.<br />
[flickr]tag:kamakura+april+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2004 23:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/05/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The household woke up slowly. The events of last night (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba]]) had done us all in. Kaz and Chris were tired from all the attention they&#8217;d been getting. Jen and I were tired from all the things we&#8217;d done and drinks we&#8217;d had. As such, we were in &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The household woke up slowly. The events of last night (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba]]) had done us all in. Kaz and Chris were tired from all the attention they&#8217;d been getting. Jen and I were tired from all the things we&#8217;d done and drinks we&#8217;d had.<br />
As such, we were in no hurry to do anything. I was the first up, my bladder calling attention to itself, and sat down to catch up on my journals. Chris and Kaz were up shortly afterwards. Chris needed to go back to his apartment before going to work, and suggested that I come along to collect last night&#8217;s laundry.<br />
<span id="more-343"></span>Chris was already half-dressed for work (pretty much everything, actually, save the tie) when we left. We stopped briefly at the 7-11 near his old apartment for breakfast, and continued to his place.<br />
There&#8217;s not much left. The bulk of his things have been brought to the new apartment. It&#8217;s now mostly clothes and odds and ends. By the 10th, he&#8217;ll be completely moved out, and probably a lot happier for it. The apartment was good to him, but in all honesty, he needed something better. It&#8217;s a little too dingy and not terribly clean (though that&#8217;s not for fault of Chris cleaning &#8212; it&#8217;s more the building/environment).<br />
We ate, chatting about stuff (we do that from time to time), and collected all the wet clothes to take back to the new apartment to dry. (There aren&#8217;t really driers in Japan &#8212; people generally hang out the washing to dry. The new apartment has a south exposure, which will help immensely for drying.)<br />
Returning to the JR Station (where the bus stops; Chris stayed at the apartment), I boarded the bus Chris had said would take me back to the new apartment. Within a couple of blocks, I knew I was in trouble. It wasn&#8217;t going where it was supposed to be going. I gave the driver one block to turn back the way I needed him to before I hit the button and got off.<br />
Apparently, the bus I had thought was was right, wasn&#8217;t.<br />
Having kept track of where I was, I walked back to the main road (Dianichi), and walked the rest of the way. It only takes about 20 minutes &#8212; if you walk as fast as I did &#8212; and it was turning out to be a beautiful day. Returning home, Jen was awake, and playing &#8220;Devil May Cry 2&#8221; on Chris&#8217; Playstation. She&#8217;s declared that she needs a Playstation so she can play this game. I can hardly blame her.<br />
Around 13:00, we headed to the JR station, and boarded the first train to Chiba. As we switched to a train to Tokyo, an idea suddenly hit me. We could catch a Limited Express. That would take us to Tokyo much faster, and save us the agony of having to hit every stop. The Shiosan 6 Limited Express, an old, somewhat odd-looking train that I&#8217;d seen many times before blitzing through Yotsukaido, took us to Tokyo station 1/3 faster than any of the regular trains.<br />
Can&#8217;t complain about that!<br />
Once there, we switched to the Yamanote line. This line runs in a circle around the core of Tokyo, hitting about 40 stops. The key places to visit in Tokyo are here: Akehabara, Shibuya, Shinjuku, Harajuku, Ueno, or puts you within a short distance of them.<br />
We started off in Akehabara, the electronics district of Tokyo. Usually, this is the best place to find the most recent, coolest, bleeding-edge thing to take back. Unlike last year, however, nothing stood out for me. The collection of keitais seemed to have doubled, the number of cameras shrank, and the one thing I was looking for &#8212; MP3 players &#8212; were almost non-existant.<br />
That didn&#8217;t stop us from wandering around the stores, seeing what was offered for sale, running in and out of the arcades, and popping 100 yen coins in a few vending machines. But even that has limited appeal. After about an hour and a half (trust me, Akehabara can suck up a whole day, if you let it), we returned to the train, and headed for Shibuya.<br />
We took the long way around, so Jen could snooze a bit on the train. She&#8217;s turning more and more Japanese with each day.<br />
We exited the train station and found ourselves on a side I wasn&#8217;t familiar with. Realizing that we were on the wrong side, we went around the corner of the station building, and emerged into the main Shibuya intersection. Jen uttered a half-breathless, half-astonished &#8220;wow&#8221;.<br />
I let Jen pick the direction at first, which was basically straight across the intersection, running diagonally from the station, into one of the many narrow, pedestrian-packed streets. It was almost as if by instinct as she led us right to HMV.<br />
Jen had wanted to take a look inside a Japanese CD store since we&#8217;d arrived. See what&#8217;s available, listen to a few things, maybe find a couple of albums that you can&#8217;t get elsewhere. And with six floors of auditory gold, how can you go wrong?<br />
I listened to a lot of music, but didn&#8217;t really find anything that I wanted to buy. Jen, on the other hand, had some difficulty retraining herself from the available options. She simply couldn&#8217;t resist a copy of Audioslave&#8217;s first album &#8230; on vinyl. One very good score, if you ask me. You can probably find it in North America, if you knew where to look. And it wasn&#8217;t a bad price, even with the exchange.<br />
We headed out the other door, in search of our next quarry: Mandarake. For those who love manga, this is the store to go to, if you know where it is. Theoretically, I knew where it was, but because I took a wrong turn coming out of the HMV, it took a while to remember where it was. For a while, I was a little concerned that my memory was going to fail me completely and we would end up going home empty-handed. But somewhere in the deep depths of my subconscious, my map of Shibuya directed me. Mandarake appeared as if finding Shangri-la.<br />
Jen&#8217;s eyes nearly bugged out of her head when she saw the rows of manga books, reaching well over her head, disappearing back into the depths of the store. It think I actually saw her drool.<br />
The catch, obviously, is that all the manga books are in Japanese. There are no English translations. That didn&#8217;t matter to Jen, since she was looking specifically for Japanese books for herself, and for friends who had asked for some special requests while she was in Japan.<br />
We both had special requests. My friend Paul had asked for anything to do with Godzilla (Gojira), specifically Mothra, if I could find any. I figured that Mandarake would be the best place to find this sort of thing. You&#8217;d think that a store dedicated to manga and manga-related paraphernalia would be the ideal source. You&#8217;d think. Nuthin&#8217;. Not even a blob of plastic that might resemble a giant flying insect attracted to bright lights. (You&#8217;d think they&#8217;d have tried that in the movies, incidentally&#8230;)<br />
Figures. Sorry, Paul&#8230;<br />
Instead, I found something for me. At first, I thought it was just a little model of a train. But when I looked closer, it was &#8230; well, it wasn&#8217;t a Transformer, but a really cheesy version that turned the front part of the locomotive into a little robot. I couldn&#8217;t stop giggling when I saw it. The idea was just so ludicrous. My guess is that it had been someone&#8217;s brilliant idea that had failed miserably, resiging them to the Ranks of Unwanted Toys. I rescued three of them &#8212; for a mere $7 a pop, how could I resist something like that?<br />
Exiting the store, we went around the corner into the Namco Infi arcade, where we successfully managed to jam the air hockey table (a fortunate happenstance, since Jen was in the process of kicking my ass), and played a couple rounds of Time Crisis 3 before we went back to the JR station. We paused for me to retake a panoramic shot I&#8217;d done last year (that had been completely screwed up). Then it was back to Tokyo station and off to Chiba.<br />
The train, when we left, was listed as &#8220;For Chiba&#8221; (on the JR, the &#8220;for&#8221; station is where that train ends it&#8217;s service in that direction, and either reverses or goes out of service). For some reason, though, it reversed and became a &#8220;For Tokyo&#8221; train. Naturally, everyone who could understand the Japanese announcements got off, leaving Jen and I on the train.<br />
We&#8217;d experienced this once before, in Kyoto. The subway we were on for Karasume-Oike suddenly went out of service, but both Jen and I had missed the announcement. The lights went out, and we very quickly exited the train before the doors closed.<br />
As soon as we realized we were the only ones, we hastily exited for the new train to Chiba. The remaining two stops came quickly, and we arrived in Yotsukaido, Kaz waiting for us at the station. She&#8217;d been over at Chris&#8217; old apartment, packing things up. She was going to give us a hand understand how to take the bus back to the apartment. My experience that morning showed that we needed some help.<br />
We popped into Yac&#8217;s for some food for dinner, mostly noodles, and some snacks. Then it was back to the apartment for food and games.<br />
Tomorrow, we&#8217;re going to try for Nikko. It&#8217;s going to be an early morning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">343</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-chiba-party</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2004 23:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chiba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We woke up several times this morning. Once when the phone rang (Mike and Brenda checking in on us), when Kaz and Chris&#8217; new refrigerator showed up, when the phone rang a second time, and when the earthquake hit. And this time, I&#8217;m not joking. It was a light one, maybe only a 3 on &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We woke up several times this morning. Once when the phone rang (Mike and Brenda checking in on us), when Kaz and Chris&#8217; new refrigerator showed up, when the phone rang a second time, and when the earthquake hit.<br />
And this time, I&#8217;m not joking.<br />
<span id="more-342"></span>It was a light one, maybe only a 3 on the Richter scale, but enough that the building swayed (I&#8217;ll assume for the moment that they&#8217;re designed to do that). For a moment, I wasn&#8217;t sure what was happening. Then I rolled over and went back to bed.<br />
Small earthquakes here are common. Chris doesn&#8217;t even bother to tell us about them anymore. This was the first earthquake I was actually awake for that I could feel. When I lived in Vancouver, we supposedly had one or two, but I never felt one. When I worked at Black&#8217;s Camera back in high school, one hit Oakville. It was very deep and nothing really shook. Instead, it just sounded like there was a garbage truck parked right next to the store (which was impossible, since there was a store next to ours &#8212; I found out later that it had been an earthquake).<br />
Pretty much everyone slept in. This was going to be a long day, so sleep was on the order. Chris and Kaz were up early for the arrival of the fridge, but Tony would remain comatose until well after 10:30. That would be about when the household started to rise and move forward with the day.<br />
Chris shaved (mostly his head) while Kaz and I took turns showering.(The bathroom space allows for a shower and a shave independently, but only if the showerer and the shaver can handle being that close to each other). Jen had to wait until Chris and Kaz were ready to head out the door to Chiba.<br />
They had to leave early for preparations of some sort. Jen and I would head over later, around 17:30. Until that time, Jen played video games, and I read.<br />
The day was cold and miserable, and waiting for the bus to take us to the station was not a particularly enjoyable experience. Luckily, we both had umbrellas, and I had brought a pair of gloves for just such an emergency. We wouldn&#8217;t go directly to the train, however, since we needed to do a bit of laundry at Chris&#8217; old apartment first (the new apartment doesn&#8217;t have a washing machine yet).<br />
On the walk over, the phone rang. It was Chris. They had forgotten a guest book at the apartment for people to sign their names in. It was something that had been used at one of the previous parties, which I had never seen or used before. They wanted it for the party there, and asked that I go back for it.<br />
Dropping the laundry off, we returned to the station. Jen waited (and ate cake) while I hopped in a taxi and handed the keitai to the driver so Chris could give him instructions. Despite my near non-existant Japanese and his near non-existant English, we seemed to have a fairly interesting conversation, though I have no idea about what specifically. Returning to the station, Jen and I headed to Chiba.<br />
Despite not having been there for almost a year, I knew where the bar was. For a while, I almost doubted my memory and thought I might have to call Chris for directions. But before I knew it, the glowing breasts of the bar&#8217;s namesake (and no, I&#8217;m not kidding) appeared. It was then I suddenly remembered some of decor. Fortunately, someone had the smarts to remove all the decorations that wouldn&#8217;t be particularly appropriate for some.<br />
Unlike the party in Toyohashi, most of the people spoke English, which made our mingling a lot easier. The fact that I also knew more people here also helped. Scott was at the door the moment we walked in, as was his girlfriend, Miyuki. The last time I&#8217;d seen them was when we&#8217;d left Club Mix after a full night of bar-hopping last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Tokyo and Shibuya]]). I don&#8217;t know if Miyuki remembered me, but Scott did.<br />
Shinichiro was taking pictures of everyone as they arrived. People would later sign the photos and give them to Chris and Kaz (although some didn&#8217;t make it into their hands, one of which was Tony in his monkey suit). Shinichiro and Scott planned the party, though I got the impression from Scott that Shinichiro did most of the work (Shinichiro lives in Chiba, but Scott lives in Narita &#8212; the distance does have a bit of a factor).<br />
Kaz and Chris were hiding in the &#8220;Love Room&#8221;, a secluded room in the back, until Scott and Shinichiro announced that it was time for them to be introduced to the awaiting audience. When the time finally came, the cue was &#8220;Mr. and Mrs. May&#8221;.<br />
I don&#8217;t think Kaz is changing her family name, but the announcement did hit home. Chris and Kaz were engaged almost two years ago &#8212; they met almost exactly two years ago. For that length of time, they were together (even if they were living apart) such that I just saw them as more than just a couple. But they&#8217;re married now. My best friends are almost all married now. Gerry, Stuart, Therese, and Chris. Of my closest friends, only Kathryn and I remain. And Kathryn is in no rush (as she put it).<br />
Chris and Kaz tried to do the circuit of people, but had significant difficulty,mostly because everyone wanted to talk to them. Eventually, Scott called for the toast, and the party officially got underway.<br />
The food was excellent (there was a breaded shrimp in some sauce that might as well have been liquified crack for how good it tasted), the beverages flowed freely, and the conversations as I travelled around the room lively.<br />
I was initially afraid that Jen might feel more out of place than usual. She might be taller than me, and look older than she is (the &#8220;Guess Jen&#8217;s Age&#8221; game continued; the nearest guess was 18), but the simple fact was that she didn&#8217;t know a lot of people here. That said, however, she dove into a couple of conversations and did quite well for herself. Of course, it didn&#8217;t hurt that many of the conversations were with guys, who for all I know were hitting on her.<br />
Jen discovered that sake isn&#8217;t the only drink she likes. Someone introduced her to a &#8220;China Blue&#8221;, a drink with blue curacau, some other liquor, and grapefruit juice. Before the end of the night, Jen would have had several of those, a couple beers, and a smattering of other things. My aunt and uncle are gonna kill me if they hear about this any time soon. At least Jen&#8217;s with people she knows and there&#8217;s far less risk involved than if she were out doing the same things with other people.<br />
Scott had planned a game of bingo &#8212; similar to a team-building game I had one once with the Mercedes Benz USA team back in January. You&#8217;re given a sheet with the bingo grid, but no numbers &#8212; the fields are blank. You go around the room, meeting new people, and get their name. You add it randomly to the fields, and then a draw of names might get you a bingo.<br />
I didn&#8217;t play. Instead, Brian (one of the guests) and I sat, talked, drank, and gave our names to everyone who came by. We figured: &#8220;Why go to the effort if people will come to us?&#8221; It was immense fun, and we had a good laugh as a result.<br />
There were many bingos, and many prizes. Jen won a &#8220;personal massager&#8221;. I think I almost died laughing.<br />
Naome and I had several conversations, and at least one kung-fu tickle fight. Unfortunately, Naome isn&#8217;t as ticklish as I am, so there wasn&#8217;t much I could do to her. I had to try, though.<br />
Slowly, but surely, the crowd emptied out into the cold, wet night until it was Chris, Kaz, Jen, Scott, Miyuki, Shinichiro, Riku, Naome, and Cory (another teacher). We were all looking to head home. This had Jen supremely disappointed because there had been much talk, from well over a month and a half ago, about going to karaoke.<br />
I&#8217;m not a singer. Never have been. Yes, I was in the Concert Choir back in high school (see [[Music Trip to Orlando, Introduction|Music Trip to Orlando]]), but that was as an ulterior motive to go down to Florida. So going to karaoke was never really high on my list of priorities.That said, though, get enough drink in me, and you&#8217;ll have a far easier time convincing me of some things. Like singing.<br />
In the eventuality of karaoke coming around, I&#8217;d even planned some of the songs I&#8217;d wanted to do, mostly Elvis and Tom Jones tunes (they suit my voice far better than, say, Avril Lavigne). Such as it was, that was something I didn&#8217;t have to worry about.<br />
Those of us heading back to Yotsukaido climbed into two cabs, the rest headed off in different directions. It had been a long night, and a long sleep was in order&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:japan+chiba+erotikava+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">342</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 23:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much. Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much.<br />
Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up the Karasuma line to the Kyoto Imperial Palace. I really wanted to see what it&#8217;s like in there.<br />
But first, we had to pack up and check out. Which wasn&#8217;t easy &#8212; we&#8217;d spread ourselves all over the room. Although it didn&#8217;t take me long to pack, Jen had to take a bit longer out of necessity. It&#8217;s safe to say that, either way, both of us officially have too much stuff.<br />
<span id="more-341"></span>I had some troubles at the front desk trying to pay for the bill. It came to about 85,000 yen for the four days (about CDN$1,000).<br />
Yes, this is what people refer to when they say that Japan is expensive. Last time, I hadn&#8217;t noticed this because I&#8217;d stayed with Chris. Now I know better.<br />
For whatever reason, my Mastercard wasn&#8217;t accepted. Neither was my VISA. Not by the hotel &#8212; by their system. Quite odd, and highly annoying. So it had to be cash, and I needed a post office for that. First, though, Jen and I brought our bags down to put into storage.<br />
Luckily, there&#8217;s a post office about a block and a half from the hotel, and unlike Canada&#8217;s post offices, was open on a weekend. But my financial woes didn&#8217;t end &#8212; for whatever reason, I couldn&#8217;t withdraw more than 60,000 yen, barely covering our hotel cost with the money I already had. I think I have only about 10,000 yen to get me through the weekend. I hope I make it.<br />
This prompted a long series of emails to and from North America (over the keitai), specifically to my sister, to try and figure out what happened to my bank account. My paycheque should have gone through two days ago (even with the time change). Thankfully, my money is still there, I just can&#8217;t get to it for some reason.<br />
We got to the Imperial Palace and walked over to the Household Agency, which governs the operation of the Palaces and grants the tours.<br />
On weekdays. We&#8217;d forgotten that it&#8217;s Saturday. I knew there was a reason I&#8217;d wanted to go to Osaka today and not yesterday.<br />
After taking a bit of a leisurely tour through the palace grounds, we returned to the hotel to collect our things and head off to the shinkansen. The 12:37 Hikaru would put us in Tokyo a little after 15:00, and have us at Chris&#8217; door by 16:30 or so. (As it stands, we arrived at 17:00.)<br />
Nearing Kyoto Station, the unmisstakable sound of women running in high heels echoed through the tiled hallways. (In the hotel room, women running down the road in high heels always seemed to sound like horses clip-clopping.) Women always seem to be running in heels here. If there was an Olympic event for running in high heels, Japan would capture the gold every time.<br />
The train ride out was mostly uneventful, Jen and I snoozing most of the trip from Kyoto to Tokyo. Arriving at Tokyo, we found our way down to Sobu underground track #4, where we waited for the 15:50 to Chiba. For the first time since I started taking trains in Japan, one was actually late.<br />
By five whole minutes.<br />
Chris and Kaz were kept appraised of our location at all times. Chris was off to work again, so Kaz would pick us up at the train station. How did I know all this? The rented cell phone, of course. Today, if anything, has proven why renting a cell phone in Japan is a good thing &#8212; being able to confirm a bank account balance or make sure you meet up with friends is not only extremely handy, but really cuts some of the guess work out of things. So if you&#8217;re planning to come to Japan and know people here, really consider renting a phone. It&#8217;s almost too convenient not to have one.<br />
Arriving at Yotsukaido, Kaz directed us to the taxi. I didn&#8217;t think Chris&#8217; apartment was so far away that we needed a taxi, but after a long trip, taking a ride seemed far more pleasant. As we would find out, however, we were not going to Chris&#8217; apartment. Suddenly, the slightly garbled phone conversation I&#8217;d had with Chris made sense. We were going to Kaz&#8217;s (and now also Chris&#8217;) new apartment.<br />
It you get off on the taxi/bus side of the station, and go down the road that runs perpendicular to the station for about three kilometres, hang a left at the Eneos station, and go up about a block, you&#8217;ve found their place. It&#8217;s not as convenient as Chris&#8217; old apartment, but it is really nice. Brand-new (it was finished only days before we left Canada) and full of gadgets (the hot water for the bath/shower is turned on from the kitchen/living space, all electronic, and actually says something &#8212; in Japanese, of course). It&#8217;s pretty sweet.<br />
It&#8217;s a bus ride from the station, or taxi, or a long walk. So we won&#8217;t be hoofing it all that often, especially after a long day. No big deal, especially for such a nice place &#8230; even if it is going to be a bit cramped for the next couple of days. (Tony&#8217;s here tonight, and probably tomorrow night, too.)<br />
Kaz and I took the bus back to the station after dumping our things out (Jen stayed behind to read and draw), and then walked to the local Home Depot-like store. They&#8217;d purchased a gas range so they could cook, but had to pick it up. Although a fairly light piece of equipment, it&#8217;s just awkward enough that you needed to borrow a truck to take it home. We took the opportunity to pick up a few things from the apartment.<br />
Like the heater&#8230;<br />
&#8230; the TV &#8230;<br />
&#8230; the VCR, DVD player, Playstation, movies, books, CDs, CD burner, a small cabinet, boxes of who-knows-what, and anything else we could pack in the back of the truck.<br />
I should point out that this is a *Japanese* truck. One that could fit in the bed of most large American pick-up trucks. So there wasn&#8217;t that much room for us to store stuff. Not that it was a big deal of any kind. It was weird to sit in because it was so small. You literally felt like the steel of the cab wrapped right around you to conserve space.<br />
Chris arrived just as we were finishing up, and we quickly packed the remainder. Kaz and I drove over in the truck while Chris biked. Due to rush hour traffic, Chris arrived before we did. A quick unpacking, and Chris and Kaz whipped off to take the truck back before they&#8217;d run out of time.<br />
Jen and I waited around, either drawing (in Jen&#8217;s case) or writing (in mine). It took a while, but they eventually returned to the apartment. They ran into Jen on her way back from coffee run (now that we&#8217;re in the Tokyo area, we&#8217;re actually able to find Georgia Max coffee again &#8212; the southern part of Japan seems to be devoid of it).<br />
With that, we were off to dinner at a nearby restaurant. We went for something called okonomiyaki, which is basically food that comes in a bowl, is mixed together, then cooked on a grill that&#8217;s built into the table. It&#8217;s sort of like a Japanese omelette or fritatta. It&#8217;s very tasty. We also had some grilled beef and pork, along with noodle and gyoza.<br />
Tony (yep, the Monkey Man) finally appeared around 22:00, after repeated attempts to try and get a hold of him. The five of us sat around, ate a little, before heading back to Kaz and Chris&#8217; apartment. We stopped first into a 24-hour drug/grocery store to pick up snacks and various things for around the house (they&#8217;re still moving in, so don&#8217;t have a lot of things). Jen bought three more Georgia Max coffees, and had downed two of them before we&#8217;d walked the block and a half to the apartment. She was still wired when we went to bed three hours later.<br />
Upon returning was the Great Soul Calibur II Matchup. Chris and Jen had been talking about this for a long time. Chris is very good at this game, as is Jen. Chris has a sort of &#8220;home field&#8221; advantage because this is a Playstation 2, whereas Jen plays on a GameCube. Doesn&#8217;t sound like it should matter, but it does. Jen won only a single game. Chris thoroughly trashed her in all the others. I just looked over at Jen, smiled, and said:<br />
&#8220;Now you know how I feel when I play you.&#8221;<br />
We called an end to Jen&#8217;s repeated &#8220;just one more!&#8221; requests, turning to the movie &#8220;Zatoichi&#8221;, a Japanese film about a blind master samurai and how he changes the lives of others. It&#8217;s a fairly violent film, but intermixed with comedy and some rather good rhythm (Stomp-like performances appear at various points in the movie). The ending&#8217;s a little disjointed, in my opinion, but it&#8217;s still a good film.<br />
And with that, we went to bed. Tomorrow is light: sleeping in, laundry, and the Fourth Party for Chris and Kaz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2004 22:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irako]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/27/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone. Jen and I proceeded to get &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone.<br />
Jen and I proceeded to get on with our morning. For me, showering and shaving (showering when it&#8217;s eight degrees in the shower room is a bit of an odd experience), gathering our things from the previous night, laying out Chris and Kaz&#8217;s wedding gifts (that they don&#8217;t yet know about), and getting breakfast.<br />
<span id="more-334"></span>This meant a trip to the 7-11. I knew what I wanted, but Jen really didn&#8217;t know. She was about to find out that her typical breakfast foods either don&#8217;t exist here, or are different enough to cause problems. This was most notable when she bought what she thought was normal milk (which bore the slogan: &#8220;Milk as milked&#8221;). Apparently, the Japanese like their milk sweetened, which Jen found thoroughly repulsive.<br />
About 9:45, we headed out to the train station to meet up with Tony, one of Chris&#8217; friends. Tony used to be a teacher with the same company Chris now works for. He&#8217;s since moved to Saipan (an American protectorate) where he works as a &#8220;beach boy&#8221; at a resort. Tony is trouble incarnate, at least as far as Chris has described him.<br />
After grabbing a bite to eat at the bakery (Tony hadn&#8217;t had breakfast yet), the three of us boarded the train for Tokyo. It was already standing room only when we boarded, and was crammed full until about two stops before Tokyo station. We stood the whole way.<br />
Once in Tokyo, we found our way up to the main level, where Tony bought something to eat for lunch, and then headed out to the Shinkansen area. Took a bit to find the right train (none of the signs were in English), and waited for our 12:23 departure. We took one row of two seats, flipped it 180 degrees so they faced the two seats behind them, and the three of us sat down to enjoy our 2.5 hour trip to Toyohashi.<br />
Tony and I talked almost the whole way. Jen slipped in and out of consciousness while listening to her music. The scenery zipped by at a leisurely 250 km/h. We even got a good look at Mount Fuji (it had decided not to hide itself from us). Shinichiro (another of Chris&#8217; friends) found us, and gabbed a bit with Tony. We would meet up with him and his girlfriend Riko again when we got to Toyohashi.<br />
Chris and Kaz were waiting for us when we arrived at the station. It was good to see them again, though it was a short-lived reunion with Kaz. Chris led us to the shuttle bus, where we found Chris&#8217; parents Tony and Carole, and Chris&#8217; uncle, Garth (Carole&#8217;s brother).<br />
I had thought that the hotel we were staying at was close to the train station. I was so wrong. The Iraku View Hotel isn&#8217;t even in Toyohashi &#8212; that&#8217;s just the nearest train station. We had another hour on a shuttle bus to the hotel. A long, albeit nice ride through and around the Aichi Prefecture&#8217;s countryside, which appears to be primarily agricultural.<br />
The hotel sits on top of a small mountain, overlooking a large bay. The view here is &#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say there&#8217;s a reason why &#8220;View&#8221; is in the hotel&#8217;s name. It&#8217;s amazing. Chris picked a heck of a location.<br />
The hotel room arrangements had changed from the last time I&#8217;d talked with Chris. Originally, Chris, Tony (friend, not father), and I were going to share a room, and Jen and Kaz would share another. Now it was Chris, Tony, and Garth, with Jen and I sharing a room. (We don&#8217;t see Kaz again until tomorrow.)<br />
Admittedly, I was a little disappointed. But I&#8217;m certainly not in a position to complain in any way. These are the way things have to be. It&#8217;s called &#8220;life&#8221; &#8212; you get used to it after a while. (Actually, I almost prefer it this way. At least Jen won&#8217;t be with a stranger. Admittedly, though, I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen if there is a desire to go out drinking.)<br />
The room is pretty nice. More western in style, there are twin beds, a desk, TV, small table, two chairs, Japanese-style bathrobes, a Japanese-style western toilet (complete with electronic bidet controls and seat warmer), and a complementary water heater and green tea bags.<br />
But I need an iron. My suit is a little wrinkled.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Jen and I went exploring, to see what this hotel has to offer. It&#8217;s quite interesting. There&#8217;s a great view of the area from the hotel&#8217;s roof (you&#8217;re actually allowed up there), an arcade, a couple of restaurants, a kareoke bar, a bowling alley, and birds in the lobby. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd hotel.<br />
Following our exploration, Jen and I watched a bit of the local Japanese TV. Very odd things to watch, such as a commercial for what we think was a car, but featured two kids in cat costumes who steal fish from the back of a fish truck.<br />
We all met up and went for dinner just after 19:00, at the Sunset Restaurant, which features a buffet. It&#8217;s quite good (for a buffet), including such favourites as sashimi, seafood-flavoured miso, gyoza, and a few things I&#8217;d never even heard of before.<br />
Chris and his family sat at one table, while Shinichiro, Riko, Tony, Jen, and I sat at another. We talked, joked, learned a little more about each other, and drank. (Well, we did &#8230; Jen didn&#8217;t, for obvious reasons.)<br />
Following our dinner (we finished just after 21:00), the six of us (the rest of Chris&#8217; family headed to bed) went in search of the bowling alley. Chris&#8217; last night as a single man would be demonstrated on the lanes.<br />
Unfortunately, Chris didn&#8217;t do all that well &#8212; mind you, neither did I &#8212; as he was distracted by conversations with Kaz. I&#8217;m going to have to make sure that his cell phone is either left behind, or confiscated by either Tony or myself so he can actually enjoy tomorrow, and not spend it talking to others.<br />
The game finished (Shinichiro came first, Jen a close second), we adjourned to Shinichiro and Riko&#8217;s room for a bottle of melon wine. An odd flavour, to say the least, but still pleasant. Shinichiro and Chris took it upon themselves to try and teach Jen some new Japanese words. Tony tried to figure out how to use some of the features on his new phone.<br />
But it&#8217;s late, and we all need sleep. Tomorrow&#8217;s going to be a long day.<br />
[flickr]tag:tokyo+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:irako+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">334</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2004 22:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/26/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept like crap. And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh? It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept like crap.<br />
And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh?<br />
<span id="more-333"></span>It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel companion, I&#8217;m Jen&#8217;s legal guardian for the next two weeks (I&#8217;ve got the documents to prove it). I&#8217;m responsible for her safety, her well-being, and certainly to some extent, her life. I have to make sure that all is taken care of so there&#8217;s little concern about what will happen or where we will go.<br />
The Kyoto guest house worries me a bit. The map I have isn&#8217;t horribly clear. I&#8217;ll have the chance to review the map when we get to Chris&#8217; place later &#8220;today&#8221;. But there&#8217;s also the cell phone that I supposedly reserved, but never received confirmation on. I hope we can get that, because it will be very handy for communication. That, and I&#8217;d hate to get charged for something I never got to use.<br />
Getting to Chris&#8217; is actually the least of my worries. Even though Chris was generous in sending me a &#8220;refresher&#8221; map to guide me around Yotsukaido (Chris won&#8217;t be meeting us when we get there &#8212; he&#8217;ll already be off to Toyohashi), I&#8217;m pretty sure of my memory of the area. Then it&#8217;s just a matter of catching the correct trains on Saturday to get us to Tokyo, then to Toyohashi, on time so we can catch a shuttle bus.<br />
I think once I&#8217;m in Toyohashi, I can relax a bit.<br />
Although I was awake before 6:00 this morning, I didn&#8217;t rise until 6:30. I proceeded to shower and dress, while Brenda made us all breakfast. Maggie (the dalmatian) was going insane &#8212; she knew something was up because of the activity and the bags being packed. Fried eggs, sausages, hashbrowns, and cheese bread toast.<br />
Then it was off to the airport. Brenda drove, Mike ran shotgun, while Jen and I sat in the back. It was a quiet ride up. There seemed to be a lot of anxiety in the car. Not that I noticed &#8212; I was telling myself over and over that this wasn&#8217;t a big deal, and being responsible for more than just myself was not a problem.<br />
Sooner or later, I hope to start believing it.<br />
Security was an issue. Normally, I breeze through it. Every so often, they ask to turn on my camera or start my Minidisc player. But this time, I&#8217;m carrying wedding presents for Chris and Kaz from friends back home. I had packed a few of them in my carry-on. And that&#8217;s what they wanted to look at.<br />
Specifically, it was the juicer that Karen and Mark were sending. It had never dawned on me that it could be a problem. It was extremely light, so I figured it was plastic. But what about blades, or some moving part? I hadn&#8217;t actually <em>seen</em> the juicer &#8212; Karen and Mark had already wrapped it. But security wanted to. I had to open it.<br />
My hands were shaking. I couldn&#8217;t let them confiscate it. I <em>needed</em> to take this, and had no-one else who could get it from me. For a moment, I forgot about Jen.<br />
I realized quickly why security wanted to see this thing. Although it had no moving parts or &#8220;sharp&#8221; edges, the outline on the x-ray machine really must&#8217;ve set off some alarms. It&#8217;s shaped like a tripod: three legs that rise not quite vertically, in a slight curve, towards a central node. The node rises from the union of the three legs to a roughly egg-shaped and -sized pod. The pod has the grooves common with hand-operated juicers. The whole thing is one-piece aluminium. And thankfully, not a threat.<br />
With that, we headed to the gate to wait for our plane to arrive, deboard, restock, and for us to get on. While we left a little late, our arrival in Vancouver should be roughly on time.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
We&#8217;ve about five hours to go before we land at Narita. So far, we&#8217;ve had lunch (ravioli), watched one movie (&#8220;Master and Commander&#8221;) and are most of the way through a second (the classic &#8220;Roman Holiday&#8221;, with Gregory Peck and Audrey Hepburn). I fell asleep not far into the second movie, owning to what I can only describe as sudden, inescapable exhaustion.<br />
But it&#8217;s what I needed. Earlier, I was stressed out. I wasn&#8217;t rested, I wasn&#8217;t ready. I wasn&#8217;t looking forward to arriving in Japan. You could almost say I was scared.<br />
Not now. I&#8217;m looking forward to it. I think the nap was all I needed. I&#8217;m awake, alert, and eager. This is going to be fun. Best part is, the usual headwind going in this direction isn&#8217;t as strong, so we&#8217;re moving at a faster clip than usual, arriving about a half hour earlier. This is a good thing.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if Jen is excited or terrified. Apparently, she was talking her head off yesterday, repeatedly saying she wasn&#8217;t excited. (Riiiiight.) Jen&#8217;s been pretty quiet, though. Her usual half-giddiness is almost non-existent, and hasn&#8217;t said much since we left the house earlier this morning. She claims she&#8217;ll be excited once we get there. We&#8217;ll see.<br />
A little under five hours to go&#8230;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Our flight arrived even earlier than predicted, which was fine with me. It was good to get off the plane &#8212; my back was beginning to give me some trouble, and my feet were dying to be used. Sitting down for nine and a half hours really isn&#8217;t my cup of tea.<br />
We came in at a different point in the airport than I had come into last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]) &#8212; a completely separate building for Terminal 2. (This is a really flipping huge airport.) We even had to take a short shuttle ride from one building to the next.<br />
Immigration was about the same as last year, but a little quicker. This time, I didn&#8217;t have to explain myself to the clerk. I had the immigration form filled out correctly, so there was no questions about what I was doing. Jen passed through with equally as little trouble.<br />
Customs was a little more trouble than I would have liked (the clerk wanted to look at a few too many things in my duffle bag), but we passed through again without much affair.<br />
And before we knew it, we were in Japan. There were three things I needed to do before we left for Yotsukaido: Get more money from the Post Office ATM, pick up the rented cell phone, and pick up our rail passes.<br />
The Post Office was easy &#8212; I vaguely knew were it was. The desk for G-Call (the company we were renting the cell phone from) was a little harder to find. The information desk didn&#8217;t quite understand, so we ended up on the third floor before being directed to the first floor. But we found the place. The clerk spoke just enough English to understand most of what I was asking, but not enough for me to understand him.<br />
It&#8217;s amazing what you can communicate with hand gestures.<br />
Cell phone in hand, we then went to the JR Office to get our passes. Took a little while (the people in front of us were very good at monopolizing time), which was fine, as we&#8217;d missed the 16:04 train to Yotsukaido, anyway. As soon as we&#8217;d done that, Jen promptly proceeded to lose her mind.<br />
Jen had spotted a couple of the infamous Japanese vending machines while we were running the quick errands. Now she was in full vending machine glory. She had to personally inspect each and every machine in sight. She kept apologizing for the exuberant (if perhaps a bit odd) behaviour. No big deal as far as I was concerned &#8212; it was all a good laugh for me.<br />
I went through the same thing last year.<br />
Jen immediately bought a can of hot tea, which she found to her surprise (and partial dismay) to be actually hot. (It was very warm, but not discomforting.) Can in hand, we headed off in search of a train.<br />
The JR platform was, in stereotypical Japanese fashion, spotless. Jen was thoroughly fascinated by this. But no more so with the continued abdunance of vending machines. By the time we got on the train at 17:04, she had four cans, one of which was mine.<br />
The trip to Yotsukaido was fairly easy. Upon arrival, we headed over to the Yotsukaido ALS school (where Chris works) to grab a key for his apartment. After a quick conversation with his coworkers, Jen and I were off to the apartment.<br />
Chris called while Jen was showering. He suggested I call Tony and make arrangements to get together with him the following day for our trip down to Toyohashi. Made sense to me. So while Jen dried and dressed, Tony and I worked out a couple of details for tomorrow.<br />
The next order of business? Food. We needed food. Luckily, I know where the Mos Burger is around here, thanks to Kaz showing me the first night I came to Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]). Jen had a hamburger.<br />
Hey, at least it wasn&#8217;t McDonald&#8217;s!<br />
Home again (following a quick run to 7-11 for green tea ice cream), we settled down for a well-deserved rest. Not counting a couple of cat naps on the plane, we haven&#8217;t slept in almost 24 hours. Hopefully, jet lag won&#8217;t be a big deal this time around.<br />
It&#8217;s good to be back.<br />
[flickr]tag:narita+march+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2003 18:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/05/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today was my last full day in Japan. There was so much I still wanted to see and do. I couldn&#8217;t do everything &#8230; but I darn well tried! Chris had to work, so would stay behind in Yotsukaido. Kaz, her friend, Ellesen, and myself went into brave the city of Tokyo and what wonders &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was my last full day in Japan. There was so much I still wanted to see and do. I couldn&#8217;t do everything &#8230; but I darn well tried!<br />
Chris had to work, so would stay behind in Yotsukaido. Kaz, her friend, Ellesen, and myself went into brave the city of Tokyo and what wonders there were yet to find.<br />
<span id="more-279"></span>I bade Ellesen and Kaz&#8217;s friend farewell at Tokyo station. I had a very rigorous trip planned for myself, and I didn&#8217;t want to drag people to somewhere they didn&#8217;t want to go. Kaz and I agreed to meet back at 16:30 (we parted ways at 13:30). It didn&#8217;t give me a lot of time, but then, that&#8217;s part of the challenge.<br />
My first stop was at the Imperial Palace. There were a couple of things I wanted a picture of that I didn&#8217;t get on the bus tour. That, and it was actually somewhat sunny for a change. I hurried through the complex. It took almost 30 minutes, counting traffic lights, photographs, and the fact that the palace grounds are very large.<br />
Then it was back towards the Yamanote line, which I would follow to the stop before Hamamatsucho, where I had previously spied a steam locomotive on static display. The day was becoming quite warm, and I was sweating quite a lot. Another reason why I was glad not to have anyone else with me.<br />
Along my route, I saw a few things I hadn&#8217;t seen before. Most of it was architectural, but there were a few interesting things and views. One of the strangest was when I was held up at a crossing by a traffic cop. At first I couldn&#8217;t tell why, since there was no traffic. But then I saw it. Or rather, heard it.<br />
It was a parade, of sorts. All marching bands, and all Japanese, so far as I could tell. I assumed it was for some sort of competition. I didn&#8217;t have time to find out, though, and blasted past to find my steam locomotive.<br />
A few blocks away, I found my quarry. Although I couldn&#8217;t read the sign, I could only gather that this was a switcher, or short-distance locomotive. Tank engines usually didn&#8217;t go too far. As near as I could tell, it was based on a British design, but Japanese-built. It had served its last a long time ago, and now served as decoration next to the JR lines supporting both the ring railway and the shinkansen lines. The only passengers the locomotive handles now are eager children and birds.<br />
Turning away from the locomotive, I navigated my way through the maze of streets at the edge of the Ginza district to find my way to the Hama-rikyu Garden. Formerly the private hunting grounds of the Edo shogun, it&#8217;s now a public park (with a 300 yen admission). It&#8217;s a beautiful place to spend an afternoon.<br />
I didn&#8217;t have an afternoon. I had about 20 minutes. I figured I&#8217;d blast through the park, come out the other side and hit the JR train at Hamamatsucho, going up to Ueno. Little did I know, however, that I was going to be blocked by one little crucial detail: The park has only one entrance and exit. Of course, I didn&#8217;t realize this until I was on the other side of the park. But this gave me a chance to see the large tidal pond, the bridges, the pathways, and the 300 Year Pine (actually only 295 years &#8212; it was planted in 1708).<br />
By the time I got to the JR Hamamatsucho station, my feet, legs, and back were discussing mutiny from the rest of me. Couldn&#8217;t blame &#8217;em, though &#8212; I&#8217;d been through a very long walk in a very short period of time. I still had about 45 minutes.<br />
Ten minutes later, I was in Ueno Park. I made a beeline for the first drink machine I could find. I was dying of thirst, and quickly guzzled half of a 3/4 litre bottle of Coke. I still had a lot of walking to do, so got started.<br />
Ueno was once a forest on the outskirts of the shogun&#8217;s city. Now firmly wedged in the Yamanote area of Tokyo, Ueno is the location of a large park, the zoo, Art Museum and National Museum. It&#8217;s very much like Central Park in New York, except that you&#8217;ll also find shrines scattered throughout the park. It&#8217;s very picturesque and calming. I only wish I had more time to see it.<br />
My ultimate goal was to visit the Shogun Tokugawa Graveyard at the north end of the park before boarding the train back to Tokyo station. Not being able to read Japanese, I accidentally took a wrong turn when I exited the main part of the park, taking myself away from the park and the JR station. Luckily, my spidey senses told me I was going the wrong way, and got myself going the right way again.<br />
The cemetery is quite large, and very old. (It holds the mausoleum for the 7th shogun.) It&#8217;s very Zen. Japanese graves are elaborate, yet very simple. Clean lines, but are often shrines onto themselves. I would have loved to wander a bit more, but had to hurry. I was already late for getting to Tokyo station.<br />
I was about 15 minutes late meeting Kaz. We still had some time to kill &#8212; Chris didn&#8217;t get off work until 20:30. This meant I could do two things that I hadn&#8217;t got the chance to do: buy me a small digital camera in Akehabara, and raid Shibuya for the infamous 100 Yen shop and music stores. Luckily, Kaz was more than willing to indulge my whims.<br />
Our first stop was Akehabara, where I made a beeline for the Laox store. (Supposedly one of the best places to purchase electronics.) They also deal in duty-free sales. I have no idea how one would apply for duty-free status, but suffice to say, I&#8217;m glad they do. Twenty minutes and one new digital camera later, we were back out on the street and heading for the train. It was off to Shibuya.<br />
Shibuya&#8217;s darn near on the opposite side of the Yamanote circle, so it was almost a half hour before we got to Shibuya station. Once outside, there were two destinations: HMV, and the 100 Yen store. I had promised a friend of mine to pick up some Japanese albums for him while here, and I knew HMV would have what I wanted.<br />
As it turns out, the first store we hit crossing the intersection sold CDs. Since CDs are the same price (or pretty darn near) at every store, we skipped the HMV in favour of a closer quarry. (After we had a quick drink at the Starbucks, of course.) Having Kaz with me proved very helpful again, since she&#8217;s able to read Japanese, allowing us to find the albums we were searching for.<br />
Then it was off to find the 100 Yen store. A little more of a challenge, but a few questions to others walking around soon led us to spendthrift heaven. Four floors of all sorts of things for 100 yen. The 100 Yen stores are very similar to the Canadian dollar stores, with one major difference: unlike the dollar stores where things can cost several dollars, every last item in the 100 Yen stores is 100 yen. No exceptions. (100 yen is worth roughly CDN$1.25.)<br />
I walked out with 2,300 yen worth of stuff, most of it dinnerware.<br />
We returned to the station, and started back towards Tokyo station. There was one more stop I wanted to make before I left Tokyo for the last time (at least on this trip): see Tokyo at night. Tokyo gets dark by about 19:00. Luckily for me, the World Trade Centre is open until 20:00. Arriving with 30 minutes to spare, Kaz and I took a look at nighttime Tokyo from 40 floors up.<br />
Arriving back in Yotsukaido around 21:30, we immediately went to Chris&#8217; apartment to dump our things, and so I could change into a less smelly set of clothes. Because it was already so late, going to Chiba wasn&#8217;t a great idea &#8212; we&#8217;d end up taking a taxi back again. Instead, we would hunt down a local restaurant. We ran into Jan (doing a midnight garbage run), who recommended a restaurant that was open until 05:00. Jan is a connoisseur of these restaurants.<br />
What&#8217;s with the midnight garbage run? It&#8217;s so he can dispose of his garbage, of course. In Japan, space is at an absolute premium &#8212; landfills are extremely few. So recycling is vigorously practiced, as is the separation of combustible and non-combustible refuse. Garbage collection, as a result, is fairly complicated. Jan ends up having to distribute his stuff over a fairly wide area, lest he put it all in one place. Or that&#8217;s so I gather&#8230;<br />
The restaurant was nothing particular special, but the food was good &#8230; just like the company I had. We ate and talked until well after midnight, when the table next to us finally got too loud, and it was time for us to leave.<br />
[flickr]tag:tokyo+may+&#8221;5&#8243;+2003@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">279</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Trip to Japan, Yokohama</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-yokohama/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=trip-to-japan-yokohama</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-yokohama/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2003 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/05/04/trip-to-japan-yokohama/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another day, another adventure. Today, though, we would throw in a different nationality. We all rose at basically the same time and quickly prepared for our departure. We needed to be in Yokohama by about 10:30, which meant we had to leave fairly early. It&#8217;s just shy of two hours to Yokohama. The city of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-yokohama/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Trip to Japan, Yokohama"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another day, another adventure. Today, though, we would throw in a different nationality.<br />
We all rose at basically the same time and quickly prepared for our departure. We needed to be in Yokohama by about 10:30, which meant we had to leave fairly early. It&#8217;s just shy of two hours to Yokohama.<br />
<span id="more-278"></span>The city of Yokohama is all part of the same massive metroplex that is the Greater Tokyo area. You never really leave the city area, you just go from one area to the next. And so it was with Yokohama that we eventually arrived at a station that was outside of Tokyo proper.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long in Yokohama, though. We were headed for Shin-Yokohama. We immediately hopped on the Yokohama local line, and travelled two station stops along with a few hundred fans of a Japanese boy band playing at the Shin-Yokohama arena. They made the station a bit tight for space.<br />
We were to meet a friend of Chris&#8217; at the station, but had a great deal of trouble trying to find her. As such, we ended up abandoning that search and decided to meet at our ultimate destination. After dropping off a bag or two in a locker, we headed through the subway pedestrian tunnels, heading north. We found Chris&#8217; friend almost as soon as we exited the tunnels.<br />
I should point out that I had somehow ended up leading our little band through Shin-Yokohama having no map nor ability to read Japanese. This happened only after saying I could read a map, and knew that the tunnel would lead us in the approximate direction of our first quarry of the day. I came close &#8212; I was in the right area, on the perpendicular street, but missed the actual road by one block.<br />
Not too bad for someone who can&#8217;t Japanese, eh?<br />
Our first target of the day was the Shin-Yokohama Raumen Museum. It&#8217;s dedicated to the history and manufacture of ramen &#8212; Japanese noodles. I know what you&#8217;re thinking: A museum dedicated to noodles? I thought the same thing when I first heard about it. (In Kannai, just to the west of Yokohama, is a museum dedicated to curry.)<br />
It&#8217;s not really that impressive a museum &#8230; it&#8217;s more of a glorified ramen restaurant than it is a museum. In fact, only the main floor has any historical information. The two basement floors are a recreation of 1958 Tokyo, filled with about eight or nine ramen shops. The interior is planned in such a way so that guests don&#8217;t mind waiting upwards of two and a half hours for their noodles.<br />
Yes, two and a half hours.<br />
When we arrived, the museum had set up a giant tent across the street to hold the hundreds of people waiting to visit. A big sign indicated how long it would be before we could enter, and how long a wait there was just to have a bowl of ramen at each of the shops. Although Ellesen and I were heart-broken to do so, we all opted to forego with noodles, and just visit the museum.<br />
Finally our group number (32) was called, and we headed into the museum. Lineups were immediately visible for the ramen shops. We skipped over the lines and went down into the main part of the museum. This area is known as Raumen Town, and is a recreation of the Shitamachi downtown area of Tokyo, circa 1958. The roof is painted to look like early evening, and the lighting matches it appropriately. It&#8217;s a quaint setting, and strangely comfortable.<br />
We walked around the &#8220;top&#8221; level of Raumen Town, passing by the people lined up for restaurants, looking at all the decorations. Then it was into the Dime Store, which is roughly what a candy shop would be like &#8230; if it were stocked with the candies of today, that is. The effect was roughly the same. We only took pictures of the lower level, since it was little more than space to queue people so they could eat.<br />
Like I said, it was a glorified noodle restaurant.<br />
Back up to the main floor, we checked out the actual museum part of the museum. Three hundred ramen bowls, some examples of noodles, a model of the first ever bowl of noodles made in the 17th century, and the ubiquitous gift shop. I think the gift shop was bigger than the museum section.<br />
You can&#8217;t leave a ramen museum without a souvenir. For me, it was &#8212; what else &#8212; a ramen bowl. I don&#8217;t have one at home, and the store had some extremely nice ones. Although I was tempted to get a gilded one, I chose a more dishwasher-safe piece.<br />
Following the museum, we decided to grab a bite to eat. Most of us were now quite hungry, especially having been to a museum about food. We would not have noodles, however, and had to settle for the Mos Burger next door.<br />
It was back to the locker to store our things before heading to our next stop: China Town. This would present a problem, however. I had a sneaky suspicion that storing our things in Shin-Yokohama would be detrimental to our return trip home. Sure enough, a review of the map showed that we would have to travel to the other side of Yokohama to get to China Town &#8212; we&#8217;d have to double-back on our route later on to retrieve our things. Chris ended up going back for our bags before we went on.<br />
Arriving in Kannai station, we dumped our things into a locker, and went in search of China Town. It seemed a little weird to be looking for a China Town in Japan. There always seems to be a China Town, no matter where you go.<br />
Yokohama&#8217;s China Town is quite large, and has an outer China Town and an inner China Town. The outer &#8220;ring&#8221; looks like Calgary&#8217;s Chinatown &#8212; a few shops, restaurants, but nothing fancy. In fact, I was a little disappointed that we hadn&#8217;t seen anything more interesting. That was until we rounded a corner and were presented with a huge gate into the heart of China Town, through which streamed an impossible number of people.<br />
This was Main Street China Town. And it is perhaps the most impressive I&#8217;ve seen. (I hear San Francisco&#8217;s is pretty nice, but I haven&#8217;t seen the whole thing yet.) Sardine cans aren&#8217;t as well-packed as this area was. Luckily, there weren&#8217;t many black men, balding white guys with black backpacks, or near-six foot tall white women with pig tails. Even though we periodically got separated, it wasn&#8217;t too hard to find each other again.<br />
As we walked down one of the streets, we passed by a stand selling lemonade. That in itself wasn&#8217;t odd &#8212; but the seller was a mid-20&#8217;s Caucasian male. He was speaking Japanese as if he&#8217;d been speaking it all his life. It was a little strange to see. Just as we passed him came a voice we didn&#8217;t expect to hear. No-one we knew, but you wouldn&#8217;t normally expect to hear a Brooklyn accent booming out:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hey! How ya enjoyin&#8217; ya Golden Week?</p></blockquote>
<p>At one point, Chris spotted people drinking from coconuts &#8212; the milk, that is. Just a simple coconut with a hold drilled in the top. The coconut had been refrigerated to make it nice and cool. He bought them for most of us, even me &#8212; although apparently I was a bit of an accident. The milk is a bit thick, slightly sweet, but not rich in flavour. I could only drink about half before I started to feel a bit ill, though, and had to throw out the rest.<br />
Though we&#8217;d been searching for an all you can eat dim sum restaurant (there were a couple, but the lines were long), we eventually settled on a normal restaurant that offered some dim sum dishes in addition. In typical form, we ate too much. But it was very good. It doesn&#8217;t seem to matter where you go, Chinese food doesn&#8217;t change much.<br />
Rolling out of the restaurant, we waddled back to the Kannai station, retrieved our things, and headed for the train. Changing at Yokohama, we boarded a train that went all the way to Yotsukaido. I was asleep before we reached the next station. I slept all the way to Ichikawa, about 25 minutes out of Yotsukaido.<br />
Back at the ranch, we hung out, and watched Ping Pong a second time &#8212; this time to benefit Kaz&#8217;s friend, who had come back with us for the night. Having already seen the movie once, I didn&#8217;t need to worry so much that there were no subtitles. (We had to turn them off because there were a few bits of dialogue in Chinese that Kaz&#8217;s friend needed the Japanese translation for).<br />
Tomorrow is my last full day in Japan. Depending on weather, I&#8217;ve got a busy day ahead of me.<br />
[flickr]tag:yokohama+may+2003@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-yokohama/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">278</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
