<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>elections &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/elections/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:30:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>What Canadian politicians have forgotten</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.] Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every three years, on average). And in Alberta, a province &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/what-canadian-politicians-have-forgotten/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What Canadian politicians have forgotten"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><em>[It should go without saying that this is an opinion piece: my opinion. It may not be yours. Politically, I&#8217;ve been centre most of my life. Today? I genuinely don&#8217;t know.]</em></p>
<p class="p1">Alberta has entered another provincial election, our fifth since the beginning of the millennium (that’s every <i>three years</i>, on average). And in <strong>Alberta, a province of wealth and entitlement</strong>, that means the old guard fending off competitors who dare lay siege to the castle, <strong>replete with feces-slinging</strong> (we’re well past mere mud), ethically-laden promises, and scare tactics, from all sides.</p>
<p class="p1">Canada is also heading down the road to a <strong>federal election</strong>, which by schedule we will see this fall. We will likely see <strong>the same slinging and fearmongering</strong>, not only because the same mentalities are at play, but because we’ve been witnessing the preamble for several months, now.</p>
<p class="p1">And all of it has shown one thing: that <strong>our politicians have forgotten about Canadians</strong>.</p>
<p class="p1"><span id="more-3428"></span>The squabbling alone is like <strong>listening to the group of neighbourhood kids fight over a favoured toy</strong>. The younger ones are petulant, the older ones use their physical strength and bully to get their way. Some of the other kids in between ages argue logically, but receive neither support nor a sympathetic ear. All I hear, as the parent who wishes them to sort anything out, is crying, fighting, and threats of tattling to parents.</p>
<p class="p1">The same thing happens in our political landscape, just without the benefit of (somewhat) impartial parents to sort out the mess and restore order. The parents we should have — <strong>the Canadian people</strong>, acting through an election — <strong>have become disillusioned, disaffected, and apathetic</strong>. As a whole, we have stopped caring. And as much as I, and others, have tried to blame this on the Canadian people, the reality is that we cannot blame the people. Individual persons, perhaps, but as a collective, the Canadian people have lost faith in government.</p>
<p class="p1">For a person to care, they <strong>need to feel attachment</strong> to something. To get that attachment, we need three things, in order:</p>
<h2 class="p1">Vision</h2>
<p class="p1">Most important of any politician’s toolbelt should be a concept of what they want to achieve, something that they know their constituents need. Sadly, most politicians fall short into short-term or simple goals: lower taxes (which politicians never lower), more jobs (which politicians don’t control), better education (which politicians take neither accountability nor responsibility), and so forth. <strong>We’ve all heard these promises, every single election.</strong></p>
<p class="p1">These are not visions, <strong>these are <em>tactics</em></strong>. Real vision comes from things that are far more intangible, such as understanding the division between the wealthy and the poor, looking to the health and welfare not of today’s children but those who will come in two generations, looking at how we are truly perceived on a global stage and knowing we could be better, preparing for a world with an ever-expanding population with less space.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Our governments do not offer vision. They offer fear.</strong> Ruling parties tell us we are in danger, so take away the freedoms of the many to benefit the extremely few; they tell us we cannot have sustainable incomes from a consistent tax base, to placate business, they tell us that the present is failing and sacrifice our future. Our opposing parties are no better, instead choosing to define themselves only by how they will reverse ruling party’s efforts, or how they will do things different.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Such actions offer no inspiration, no dreams, no hope.</strong> They serve only to oppress and defeat, leaving Canadians with nothing more than apathy. Without vision, we fall into mere name-calling, and petty arguments. We don’t have anything new to believe in, so we fall back on what we already believe, regardless of how flawed it may be. And we’ll fight to the death to protect those beliefs, because <strong>we’re human, and we loathe others telling us what to believe</strong> in the absence of new thought.</p>
<h2 class="p1">Charisma</h2>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Part of the problem of vision, even when it is available, is an inability to connect with Canadians. While making public appearances, they certainly glad-hand everyone they can find with big, wide smiles … but this is not a connection. After such events, <strong>Canadians will no more relate to a politician as they will to the politician in a sound bite on TV</strong>. We relate better to actors in trashy B-movies than we do the people we’re supposed to trust with our future. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">The leader of our nation, Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper, has the <strong>personality of a cardboard cutout</strong>. Hon. Thomas Mulcair, the leader of the official opposition, is <strong>identifiable more by his beard</strong> than anything he has said or done. And our supposed saviour, Hon. Justin Trudeau, scion of Canadian political legend, has somehow managed to turn himself into a bizarre punchline, where lately his <strong>only defining attribute is reverse-parroting</strong> nearly everything the Prime Minister says. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Nevermind our provincial woes: a recently-elected Premier who, starting off with supposedly open eyes, has turned a deaf ear; the official opposition imploded; and <strong>the polls show the province tearing itself down the middle</strong>, with divisions widening daily. There is not a single person who has stepped up within the province to show a new way to think, nothing beyond promises of old that have been broken time and time again. <strong>Not a single party who defines hope</strong>, not a single hope for the change we so desperately need. </span></p>
<p class="p1">Sadly, <strong>our politicians appear to have started to ignore us</strong>. They only truly care when elections are in the wind, for obvious reasons. Otherwise, they&#8217;re more preoccupied with each other, with in-fighting, name-calling, petty one-up-manship, and throwing people under busses (figuratively speaking that is; if that ever turns literal, we&#8217;ll have bigger problems to solve). The net result isn&#8217;t even entertainment, anymore. It&#8217;s irritation.</p>
<p class="p1">Worse still, we <strong>Canadians still end up dividing on ideological lines</strong>, blindly painting ourselves Blue, Red, and Orange because &#8230; well, because that party is how I&#8217;d <em>like</em> to think. But that paint is a two-way street, and <strong>the actions and words of the politicians flows down to the people</strong>, tarnishing the ideal of what that paint was supposed to be, and the Painted People argue about what&#8217;s ideal, despite the reality.</p>
<p class="p1">It’s not like Canada has not seen charismatic, even idiosyncratic politicians before. I&#8217;ll sidestep an obvious one, largely because my province has a ridiculously long memory and a terribly short sight.</p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Instead, I&#8217;ll look to the late <strong>Hon. Jack Layton, who set a benchmark in Canada</strong> for the very things that Canadians were longing for: helping Canadians, not scaring them. He ignored personal attacks, choosing instead to inspire. He made fun of himself on <i>This Hour Has 22 Minutes</i>, engaged Quebecois in their language, and despite a strange police run-in (an unproven but suspected smear campaign), his trustworthiness amongst those polled topped out at 97%. In the following election, the NDP — the “left wing” party, formerly the butt of many political jokes — became the official opposition for the first time in federal politics. When Layton died in August 2011, the nation mourned the loss of <strong>our last great statesman</strong>.</span></p>
<h2 class="p1">Leadership</h2>
<p class="p1">This leads me to the last major problem with our politicians: their inability to lead. They are defined as leaders of their respective parties certainly — they are elected from within the party for that very purpose. That does not, however, necessarily define them as leaders of Canadians.</p>
<p class="p1">Imagine, if you will, a crowd in a large field. A single person steps from the crowd, raises their hand, and promptly marches off in a direction. Some of the crowd will undoubtedly follow, either because they know the person or because they have a like mind. The rest may follow over time, some due to not wishing to remain in the field, some due to the pressure of others leaving. Some will remain, and possibly follow someone else who marches off in a different direction.</p>
<p class="p1">Now imagine that same crowd in a dark tunnel. There are two ways to go, and almost no-one knows the right way. One person, armed with a flashlight, walks ahead to look for dangers: open holes, tripping rocks, unstable walls, and so forth. Nearly all will follow, if just not to be left in the dark.</p>
<p class="p1">These are the <strong>two leadership patterns we see in Canada: follow by choice, or follow by fear</strong>. Both are problematic, though most people, when asked, would prefer the choice. It doesn’t matter whether or not your choice may lead you off a cliff, you just wish to know that you feel right about something. In both cases, <strong>the key missing element is education</strong>. With fear, you’re offering only the downside: follow me, or else. With choice, you’re selling only the benefits: follow me, for I have cookies!</p>
<p class="p1">So what’s best? <strong>Follow by understanding.</strong> Yes, we have cookies, and they are delicious, but some have raisins, and we know they’re not for everyone. Allow people to know what you stand for, why that matters, why you think you’ll make mistakes, where you will draw lines, and how much you’re willing to risk to bring your vision. <strong>A rare politician is one who does not worry immediately about the next election</strong>, but more about the people they represent.</p>
<h2 class="p1">But Where’s the Proof?</h2>
<p class="p1">It took me a long time to realize that we had an example of how it <i>could</i> be done. And, somewhat ironically, it exists in a place we don&#8217;t expect to see greatness: in municipal government. I can look at my own city and see the proof. Calgary is a microcosm of Canada: a right-leaning, multi-cultural, fast-growing city that has, historically, had a lacklustre governing body.</p>
<p class="p1">Until 2012, the general impression of City Council was anything but transparent, ruled largely by old guard red tape, with but a few who fought for real change. Then in 2012, the change happened: a man with a vision of what Calgary could be, that flew in the face of some of that old guard, asked <strong>people to believe not necessarily <em>in</em> him, but <em>with</em> him</strong>. And people could, because he had a personality that was infectious, one that made you <em>want</em> to believe. He followed through, showing people how things could really be done.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>Mayor Naheed Nenshi proved to a right-leaning city that had stopped caring, that you <i>could</i> do different.</strong> For his first term, Calgary became a very different place. It felt more energetic, more interesting and vibrant, more passionate. He did so well, that he got reelected. He continues to express his opinions, his vision, his desire for change, and his will to put himself out for public approval.</p>
<p class="p1">Is Mayor Nenshi popular with everyone? Of course he isn’t — he rubs some people badly, and they would love to see him unseated. And, to some degree, Mayor Nenshi doesn’t seem to care. <strong>Opposition is seen as a healthy thing, to foster debate, to find middle grounds, to develop long-lasting solutions.</strong> And despite perceptions of some city councillors working more for corporate interests than their constituents, the City of Calgary functions more like the Canada I knew as a child: with mutual respect, honest debate, and a desire to do Calgarians proud.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>This is what our politicians are missing: pride.</strong> They’ve forgotten how to inspire through vision, engage through charisma, and gain a following through leadership. This Alberta election is a farce, and our next federal election will be like watching poo-flinging monkeys.</p>
<p class="p1">Our only hope is that someone recognizes this, and brings change.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada&#039;s Two Political Parties: Conservative, and Other</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 20:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Federal election time here in Canada. Which means it&#8217;s a fast-and-furious stream of incoherent messaging all tantamount to white noise as the various political figures attempt to sway Canadian passions (which are, at best, as politically frigid as Winnipeg in February). Adding to all of this are, new to this run, a number of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada&#039;s Two Political Parties: Conservative, and Other"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Federal election time here in Canada. Which means it&#8217;s a fast-and-furious stream of incoherent messaging all tantamount to white noise as the various political figures attempt to sway Canadian passions (which are, at best, as politically frigid as Winnipeg in February).<br />
Adding to all of this are, new to this run, a number of social media-style services all helping to add &#8220;information&#8221; (and likely being more like more noise to the signal) to help people align themselves with the political party of choice. I came across one, recently, and suddenly realised that despite the fact we have five major political parties vying for seats, they&#8217;re really only divided two ways.<br />
Which means you either vote Conservative, or you don&#8217;t.<br />
<span id="more-2925"></span>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not advocating voting Conservative. Frankly, I have serious misgivings of how they&#8217;ve been running things the last few years, and I would very much like them deposed from the throne. The reason I say you either vote one way or the other really boils down to a graphic presented by the <a href="http://csdc-cecd.mcgill.ca/">Centre for the Study of Democratic Citizenship at McGill University</a>, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canadavotes">CBC</a>/<a href="http://elections.radio-canada.ca/">Radio Canada</a>, and the <a href="http://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/~socsci/">Department of Social Sciences at the University of Toronto</a>.<br />
It&#8217;s part of a service they created called <a href="http://federal.votecompass.ca/">Vote Compass</a>, and it strives to help people understand our political parties. It&#8217;s important, because some of the parties are awfully darn hard to differentiate in a meaningful way. With some of the issues, it&#8217;s quite easy to see which party you should look towards. But with others, it&#8217;s more like splitting hairs. That&#8217;s why the service ends up providing 35 questions (30 general ones, 3 regarding the parties&#8217; leaders, and 2 about the parties themselves), which ultimately determine what your best political party would be.<br />
And that&#8217;s really the key thing &#8212; your local candidate, regardless of how awesome they are, ultimately contributes a seat to the overall picture, allowing a party to rule. Your individual candidate, unless they become a Cabinet Minister, is little more than a hand raised during votes and can only hope to offer changes via private member&#8217;s bills. Remember, your party has already chosen its leader, and the one leading the winning party automatically becomes prime minister. (On a cynical note, I also strongly believe that anyone voting Conservative is therefore directly a supporter of Stephen Harper.)<br />
At the end of your questions, Vote Compass produces &#8230; well, a compass, showing you which way you lean, politically-speaking. Mine (currently) looks like this:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Vote-Compass.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2928" title="Vote-Compass" src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Vote-Compass.jpg" alt="" width="471" height="471" /></a><br />
(The checkmark is me, incidentally. Yes, I&#8217;m socialist. I believe very strongly in Canada&#8217;s history of helping others, including ourselves.)<br />
See the split? See how the Conservatives are in one corner, and the other four parties are up in the other? (Given, the Liberals are much more centre, but still&#8230;) This is what I mean by &#8220;you&#8217;re either voting Conservative, or you&#8217;re not&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;But,&#8221; you say, &#8220;that&#8217;s not true! I vote for my non-Conservative party! What&#8217;s wrong with that?&#8221;<br />
Allow me to rephrase my point slightly, then. You either cast a vote for the Conservatives, or you cast your vote against them into a <em>diluted</em> pool.<br />
This has also been my primary gripe with the &#8220;ABC&#8221; campaign (&#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anything_But_Conservative">Anyone/Anything But Conservative</a>&#8220;) that has been popular in parts of Canada since the 2008 federal election. Sure, don&#8217;t vote Conservative &#8230; but now you&#8217;re spreading out a vote amongst (up to) four other parties, reducing the potential power of those votes so much that&#8230;<br />
&#8230;drum roll, please&#8230;<br />
&#8230;you end up with <strong>minority governments</strong>. Two of them so far, as a matter of fact, and from what I&#8217;ve seen, we&#8217;re likely looking at a third. Which means another call for a coalition government, which will likely be nearly as useless with all the in-fighting.<br />
This is one of those few times when I look to the American two-party system and admire its simplicity. You go one way or the other. (&#8216;Course, really, they&#8217;re all the same, just one tends to more open and honest about liking guns than the other.)<br />
What I would like is for one of the other four parties to stand out from the others, and really make themselves out to be a strong contender to the Conservatives. Although the NDP seems to be gaining some serious ground this time out, they&#8217;ll have to do something about the Prairies if they hope to make a serious run. Which, really, leaves the Liberals who don&#8217;t look to have recovered from Chrétien&#8217;s era (nor show any signs of such).<br />
Or better still, have organisations/movements like ABC pick a party. Just one. Please. The message should be &#8220;don&#8217;t vote Conservative, vote for &#8230;&#8221; so long as it&#8217;s focused. Lack of focus equals lack of success. That&#8217;s about as simple a rule as it gets, however it gets applied: in school, in business, how my kids clean up their toys. Focus, please.<br />
T minus 9 days. I actually fear for my country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/canadas-two-political-parties-conservative-and-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2925</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suggestions to our political &#034;leaders&#034;</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=suggestions-to-our-political-leaders</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 04:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re barely a week into the 2011 Canadian Federal election, and it already feels like a month. I suppose if there&#8217;s one good thing about elections up here, it&#8217;s that they&#8217;re short &#8212; none of this near-two year campaigning that goes on south of the border. Already, the various political parties are &#8230; well, failing. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Suggestions to our political &#34;leaders&#34;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re barely a week into the 2011 Canadian Federal election, and it already feels like a month. I suppose if there&#8217;s one good thing about elections up here, it&#8217;s that they&#8217;re short &#8212; none of this near-two year campaigning that goes on south of the border.<br />
Already, the various political parties are &#8230; well, failing. I&#8217;m rather stunned how fast that happened, actually. You&#8217;d think they&#8217;d actually try to get out a message first, but they stooped to mud-slinging pretty much out of the gate. Yeah, real positive way to foster respect and attract voters, folks&#8230;<br />
So I feel that, as a Canadian with some significant sense of civic duty (and certainly more than enough know-it-all-ism), I need to offer up some suggestions to our so-called &#8220;leaders&#8221; (read: I choose not to lay insults as they are neither interesting nor constructive) if they have any hope of inspiring Canadians to vote for them &#8230; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/">if at all</a>.<br />
<span id="more-2897"></span>Let&#8217;s start with the <a href="http://www.ndp.ca/">New Democratic Party</a>&#8230;<br />
So far, to be honest, I haven&#8217;t heard much out of you. Not here in the west, anyway. Yes, you need to acknowledge that we exist. Hate to break it to you, but if you have any hope of beating out either the Conservatives or the Liberals for a seat, you need to be <em>seen</em>. Guess whose ads I&#8217;ve yet to see plastered all over TV? I had to Google them, Jack. That required action: a <em>vested interest</em>. You want an audience? You&#8217;ll need to go <em>to</em> them. Maybe all the pick-up trucks scare you off? I don&#8217;t know. But I do know this: First basic rule of marketing &#8212; unless you&#8217;re highly visible, you won&#8217;t be remembered.<br />
Checking out your website is kind of informational, but you&#8217;re stooping to attacking your opponents right away. Your message? A little hard to see past the oh-so-thinly veiled attack on Ignatieff. (Look, if you want to question something he may or may not have done, get some facts. Nothing kills off a campaign run like a damn good scandal. A mere question will go unanswered, and will not sway <em>anyone</em>.)<br />
And the bit about more doctors and nurses? Hey, great, that&#8217;s awesome! What about the people who support the doctors and nurses? What about the hospitals for them to work in? And can you provide the details on how you&#8217;re going to prevent new grads from going elsewhere (like the States)? A few details will help prove that these are more than words. Remember, most Canadians will not shlep down to the local candidate to have a discussion. The internet will help, but only if your message is complete enough to convince someone beyond a simple belief.<br />
And for the love of pete, can someone in your IT group make sure that your website works for both &#8220;ndp.ca&#8221; and &#8220;www.ndp.ca&#8221;? That&#8217;s a pretty low bar, and you&#8217;re tripping over it&#8230;<br />
Next up, the <a href="http://www.liberal.ca/">Liberals</a>.<br />
Iggy, can you actually go a day without saying the word &#8220;Harper&#8221;?  I don&#8217;t think you can. I&#8217;m actually beginning to fear that you have no actual message at all, other than to oppose the Conservatives. I&#8217;m not kidding &#8212; <a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=site%3Awww.liberal.ca+harper">on your website alone, there are over 6,400 mentions of &#8220;Harper&#8221;</a>! Exactly <em>whose</em> side are you on?<br />
You talk about Accountability on your website. How about some examples? Goodness knows that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Harper">your BFF</a> has offered you countless examples upon which you can found your statements. But despite being the only party willing to post your policy points &#8212; you skimp over the details like a cheap restaurant that uses watered down tomato sauce and passes it off as pasta al fresco.<br />
Or how about your digital policy? You offer up a mere <em>three paragraphs</em>, and nothing else? Have you not paid a single shred of attention to all the C-32 and UBB nonsense? Might I remind the lauded Liberals that there are many Canadians who have a <strong>very vested interest</strong> in what plans you say you have, and would likely keenly vote if they made sense. <em>Cough, cough.</em> You might also want to <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Hicock2010/cprs-part-2-nenshi-campaign">chat with Mr. Nenshi&#8230;</a><br />
Here&#8217;s a free I&#8217;ll throw you: &#8220;a Liberal government will not allow corporations and/or regulatory agencies to restrict Canadians access to critical resources through uninformed and/or falsified statements regarding resource use, either as a result of profit or security&#8221; as a broad statement, backed up by a list of proposed bills you intend to introduce to Parliament in your first 100 days. Just saying.<br />
Oh, and Iggy, if your party is going to hold up Laurier, Pearson, and Trudeau as the models for Liberal leadership, you might want to consider <em>finding your own identity</em> so we can pick you out of the noise.<br />
As for the <a href="http://www.conservative.ca/">Conservatives</a>&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve seen <a href="http://www.conservative.ca/multimedia/our_tv_ads/">your ads</a>. They&#8217;re wonderful, truly. They&#8217;re masterful of propagating the fear that right-leaning political groups love to instill in the populace. There&#8217;s nothing quite like creating an identity of evil for you to gain trust. (Hey, it worked in the church &#8212; nothing like the Devil to steer you straight, right?)<br />
Here&#8217;s a thought: you&#8217;ve gone two elections without winning a majority. (With me so far? Good.) See a problem? Here&#8217;s a hint: it&#8217;s not that you didn&#8217;t win a majority. Let me spell it out: your tactics haven&#8217;t changed &#8212; it&#8217;s still about fear. The way I see it, you&#8217;re not going to get much further, as you&#8217;ve scared all you can. It might have worked a couple of years ago when the economy was going through the grinder, but since we&#8217;re on the recovery and things are generally looking decent &#8230; well, you haven&#8217;t really got much, do you? Another problem: highly-educated people tend not to frighten easily. You want the rest of us to vote for you? You&#8217;d better come up with <strong>something more <em>intelligent</em></strong> than mere propaganda.<br />
Speaking of which, I went to your website to look for what you&#8217;re bringing to the table. The only thing under &#8220;Policy&#8221;? The 2011 Budget. That&#8217;s your policy? Nothing about Aboriginal rights? Nothing about the Environment? Not even Corporation support (which, we know, you do so very, very well)? You&#8217;re not really offering much, here. Your tax cuts aren&#8217;t offering much, either, since they don&#8217;t really fit the bill of Canadians&#8217; needs. Yes, we do need more doctors &#8230; but we don&#8217;t need billion-dollar warplanes. <em>Subtle hint.</em><br />
Yes, I know I&#8217;m missing out on the other parties out there: The Bloc Québécois (hint: give a crap about just one person not from Quebec), The Green Party (you need to distance yourself a bit more from the granola crowd), and a retinue of other parties &#8212; all of whom have a ways yet to go. All have a similar problem: appealing to the masses. Canadians, as a whole, are generally accepting, but historically-speaking, generally only vote for Conservative (right) or Liberal (centre). You don&#8217;t fit into those mentalities, you&#8217;re effectively fringe, at least at the federal level.<br />
So, to those who are leading the charge into our electoral fray, can we please dispense with the bull? Can we drop the mud, please, and actually have a real dialogue? It would be nice to know that there is more to our political system than mere bitching.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/suggestions-to-our-political-leaders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2897</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Canada, grow a backbone!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=dear-canada-grow-a-backbone</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 22:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Canada, we&#8217;re in another pickle. The on-going &#8220;me, too!&#8221; power struggle that has dogged us for five years is now going into Round 3, thanks to a non-confidence (read: get enough people to whine the ruling party out of power) vote. In just over a month, we&#8217;re back at the polls, likely to do &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dear Canada, grow a backbone!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Canada, we&#8217;re in another pickle. The on-going &#8220;me, too!&#8221; power struggle that has dogged us for <strong>five years</strong> is now going into Round 3, thanks to a non-confidence (read: get enough people to whine the ruling party out of power) vote. In just over a month, we&#8217;re back at the polls, likely to do what we did last time, and the time before that: <strong>Make no decision whatsoever</strong>.<br />
I dunno what it is, but we Canadians seem to really love to not rock the boat. We don&#8217;t want heavy-handed politics, but we also want our cake and eat it, too. We want our health care, dammit, but <strong>we don&#8217;t want to pay for it</strong>. We want to leave our lights on 24/7, but please don&#8217;t raise our energy bills. And above all, we still want to be the &#8220;Nice&#8221; people in North America.<br />
Let&#8217;s face it, folks, <strong>we&#8217;re a bunch of pansies</strong>.<br />
<span id="more-2888"></span>Yes, you. I&#8217;m talking to you, Canada. Yes, you who <strong>hasn&#8217;t voted in several elections</strong>, you who doesn&#8217;t vote because you&#8217;re convinced <strong>your area only ever votes one way</strong>, even you who voted last time (and has done so since eligibility) because it was the right thing to do, but you <strong>didn&#8217;t actually spend any time</strong> to figure out who you should vote for &#8212; you just marked the person in your area whose sign you saw last.<br />
The last previous two elections have created, for all intents and purposes, <strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lame_duck_(politics)">a lame duck Parliament</a></strong>. Minority governments, at least in this country, are less effective than a eunuch in a Red Light district. Everything gets argued, <strong>nothing gets done</strong>. Meanwhile, budgets inflate, services break, money gets wasted, and the bitching about it all goes on unabated.<br />
What this country needs is a majority government. Yeah, they&#8217;re usually fraught with some sort of bullshit that&#8217;s common with power &#8212; some idiot who forgets that he&#8217;s <strong>there to service the people</strong> (not the other way around) and makes a few deals that sweetens his pocket. Next thing we know, we&#8217;ve got scandals, Royal Inquiries, and more than a few newspaper headlines about how so-and-so did such-and-such, and boy wasn&#8217;t that a bad thing. And no-one pays any attention to the dozens of other things that the same ruling party managed to accomplish, and suddenly <strong>Canada is itching for that next election</strong> to vote the offending party out so we can have something &#8220;better&#8221;.<br />
Well, &#8220;better&#8221; is our current problem. Right now, you&#8217;ve got (really) three options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Conservatives: Right wing, business-focused, tax-raising, and money-spending. They&#8217;ve been <strong>bought by American interests</strong> to push through horrible <a href="http://www.speakoutoncopyright.ca/">copyright policies that do not reflect Canadians</a>&#8216; interests, allowed Canadian companies to <a href="http://theubbdeception.ca/">push through billing practices that hurt the majority</a> of us, <a href="http://www.embassymag.ca/page/view/purchase-07-28-2010">want to buy warplanes</a> (and somehow, this is a good thing), and the <a href="http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/blog/climate/canadas-lacklustre-environmental-record-causes-stir-20091130">environment is about as important as a rapidly-covered-up pimple</a>.</li>
<li>Liberals: Led by someone <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Ignatieff#Early_life_and_education">who should know better</a>, all the Liberals have managed to do for the last five years is (effectively) state how bad Stephen Harper is, how much better than Stephen Harper they are, boy isn&#8217;t Stephen Harper a bad example for Canada, <a href="http://www.calgarysun.com/news/Stampede/2010/07/10/14671501.html">Stephen Harper</a> <a href="http://www.nowpublic.com/world/liberal-leader-ignatieff-harper-your-time">Stephen Harper</a> <a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=site%3Atwitter.com%2Fm_ignatieff+harper">Stephen Harper</a>. The <strong>Conservatives should really pay the Liberals for all the free advertising</strong> &#8212; it would only be fair. It would be far nicer if the Liberals stopped whining and actually <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Just_watch_me">sounded like Pierre Trudeau</a> again. Yeah, Trudeau might have been a pompous ass from time to time, but he still reigns as one of the best and most influential politicians from the last century.</li>
<li>NDP: I&#8217;d love for Jack Layton to be a stronger leader, I really would. I would also love the NDP to <strong>have a fiscal policy that had more of a balance</strong>; they lead almost as far to the left as the Conservatives do to the right. It would also be nice for them to recognise those of us who don&#8217;t have the luxury of working in a union, but are (generally) worked far harder that unions for far less payoff. Support the working person, and not just the few organised groups, and the rest of us would appreciate it immensely.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Bloc? Quebec doesn&#8217;t have the population to win Federal control from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_Canada">Rest of Canada</a>. (And if, by some freakish miracle, they did manage to get the minority control, you&#8217;d see a Coalition struck up that would make even the most jigsaw Frankenstein reel in sheer horror.) The Green Party is so much more left that the NDP look Liberal; Canada would need a serious slide back into socialism for Green to gain any significant footing.<br />
Guess what? <strong>We&#8217;re looking at another minority government.</strong> Because of what I said above, and you know it. There is no clear choice, and I don&#8217;t care who you are, where you live, or what you do. If you <strong>sit down and <em>truly think</em></strong> out the options (not just rote spit out your default answer), you would see that we&#8217;re basically screwed. You either choose a party who wants Canada to be America (for all intents and purposes), or you choose one of two groups who, frankly, <strong>have no message worth listening to</strong>.<br />
What this means &#8212; I hate to say it &#8212; that we&#8217;re going to vote for status quo. We&#8217;re not going to take a stand in our federal <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parliamentary_system">parliamentary democracy</a> (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constitutional_monarchy">constitutional monarchy</a> notwithstanding) and demand of our elected (or want-to-be-elected) representatives to <strong>stop acting like bickering children</strong>. We won&#8217;t take the responsibility to properly vet out the people we send to Ottawa, ask them the <em>hard questions</em> that prove they&#8217;re capable, and call them out when they do wrong. Because, in the end, <strong>we&#8217;re all spineless</strong> and just want things to be <strong>simple and easy</strong>. We want to have a few people make the real decisions, cast our vote in  acquiescence, and <strong>reserve our right to bitch</strong> about it afterwards.<br />
Want to rant back at me? Leave a nasty comment? <strong>Don&#8217;t waste my time</strong> &#8212; you want to prove me wrong, show up for your MP&#8217;s sessions (elected or nominated) and demand to know where they stand. Hell, record it so when they vote opposite of what you wanted, you can post it on YouTube for the world to see. <strong>I&#8217;m not your audience</strong> &#8212; you are. Your family &#8212; your children and theirs &#8212; depend on you making the right decision. (And no, I&#8217;m not going to tell you who to vote for &#8212; I may generally vote Liberal, but unless Iggy gets his head of out Harper&#8217;s ass, I&#8217;m not going to lining up for a red shirt this year.)<br />
This is going to be a bad election. I&#8217;m hoping &#8212; nay, <em>praying</em> &#8212; for a miracle that something truly significant happens. But I&#8217;m betting it won&#8217;t, and we&#8217;ll be right back where we&#8217;ve been, <strong>slowly rotting away under ineffective leadership</strong> from all sides, who want nothing more than to climb to the top of the dirt pile and claim that they&#8217;re the King of the Castle.<br />
Oh, Canada&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/dear-canada-grow-a-backbone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2888</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to win the next Canadian federal election</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/how-to-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/how-to-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 03:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Honourable Michael Ignatieff MP, I recently read a CBC article where you made public a video of Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper in less than a positive light (http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2009/09/10/ignatieff-harper-speech.html). The article, including references to the video and a few comments from yourself, aimed to effectively attack Rt. Hon. Harper&#8217;s character and credibility. While this action &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/how-to-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to win the next Canadian federal election"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">Dear Honourable Michael Ignatieff MP,</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">I recently read a CBC article where you made public a video of Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper in less than a positive light (http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2009/09/10/ignatieff-harper-speech.html). The article, including references to the video and a few comments from yourself, aimed to effectively attack Rt. Hon. Harper&#8217;s character and credibility. While this action may very well be justified in terms of raising awareness to the Canadian public, I (and likely many other Canadians) see this only as a prelude to what will likely be the fourth federal election in as many years.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">What you have before you is a problem, Hon. Ignatieff: you might be right, but Canadians are going to hate you for it. We&#8217;re going to hate you for doing exactly what every other politician running for a major office has done for the last quarter of a century: make the election personal.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">Canadians pride themselves on multiculturalism. We happily point to the different patches of our country that identify themselves as being distinct and unique. These are not faults, but are facets of a jewel that would not shine any other way. Along with those facets come &#8212; as an absolute requirement &#8212; differing perspectives, attitudes, and personalities. In effect, it ensures that no two people will approach the same scenario in the same manner.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">You must remove personalities from the equation. All that mudslinging achieves is to showcase pettiness and desperation. If all you have to bring up is someone else&#8217;s poor judgement, it makes us all wonder what you can bring to the table. It does not matter what Rt. Hon. Harper has personally said, regardless of how inflamatory those comments may be. Your position should be a higher one, not of a tattle-tale elementary schoolyard child, but of the correcting teacher who directs a class to overcome a poor decision.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">The Conservatives have something in their favour that the Liberals do not: since coming into power in 2006, the Conservatives have not made any serious mistakes &#8212; things that would normally cause Canadians to vote differently. That is a level of inertia that the Liberals &#8212; and you, as their leader &#8212; need to overcome.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">You have another inertia to overcome as well: Canadian political apathy. As you may recall, the 2008 federal election had the lowest turnout in Canadian history. If you wish to turn the tide, you have to encourage everyone not just to perform their civic duty, but be engaged in the direction of their country. That is a task that no Canadian political leader is willing to, at the risk of being attacked by the others. However, this is a risk you&#8217;ll need to take.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">And you need to take that risk to the west. I&#8217;m sure you saw the electoral map from the previous election (http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/72/Canada_2008_Federal_Election.svg) &#8212; the west is a sea of blue, and your party acquired only seven seats. Alberta, in particular, love their Conservatives &#8212; attacking Harper will only lend sympathy rather than turning a tide. You need to appeal to the Western Canadian, and have them feel that Western Canada is as important to Canada as Quebec has been in previous elections.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">So, how? I don&#8217;t presume to preach to a politician, author, professor, and journalist. Instead, I would like to talk to you as a fellow Canadian. You don&#8217;t need to tell us what&#8217;s wrong with other politicians &#8212; you need to tell us what&#8217;s wrong with us, with our nation, with the things that we hold as dear and true to our identities as toques, beavers, hockey, and the maple leaf. And then inspire us to help repair those things, so that we become part of the solution, so we don&#8217;t just hand our problems to our government and expect everything to be fixed.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">We do not need promises or assurances. We need truths, no matter how hard they might be to hear. We need to be told &#8212; plainly &#8212; what has to happen. We need to be told that even the difficult is possible, and that hope isn&#8217;t just a word. We need to believe. We need to want.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">Ignore Rt. Hon. Harper. Ignore Hons. Duceppe, Layton, and May. Rise above them. Rise above the petty bickering. Make your message speak for itself, and speak to Canadians. Make us believe that you have a vision that means something more than merely acquiring office. If we are to go to the polls again, we have to know it&#8217;s for a good reason, and not because of a political spitting match. If you can bring faith back into Canadian politics, you may also bring greater enthusiasm and support.</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">Sincerely,</div>
<div id="_mcePaste" style="width: 1px;height: 1px">Geoff Sowrey</div>
<p>Dear <a href="http://www.liberal.ca/en/michael-ignatieff/">Honourable Michael Ignatieff MP</a>,<br />
I recently read a CBC article where you made public a <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2009/09/10/ignatieff-harper-speech.html">video of Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper in less than a positive light</a>. The article, including references to the video and a few comments from yourself, aimed to effectively attack <a href="http://pm.gc.ca/eng/default.asp">Rt. Hon. Harper</a>&#8216;s character and credibility. While this action may very well be justified in terms of raising awareness to the Canadian public, I (and likely many other Canadians) see this only as a prelude to what will likely be the fourth federal election in as many years.<br />
What you have before you is a problem, Hon. Ignatieff: you might be right, but Canadians are going to hate you for it. We&#8217;re going to hate you for doing exactly what every other politician running for a major office has done for the last quarter of a century: make the election personal.<br />
<span id="more-2150"></span>Canadians pride themselves on multiculturalism. We happily point to the different patches of our country that identify themselves as being distinct and unique. These are not faults, but are facets of a jewel that would not shine any other way. Along with those facets come &#8212; as an absolute requirement &#8212; differing perspectives, attitudes, and personalities. In effect, it ensures that no two people will approach the same scenario in the same manner.<br />
You must remove personalities from the equation. All that mudslinging achieves is to showcase pettiness and desperation. If all you have to bring up is someone else&#8217;s poor judgement, it makes us all wonder what you can bring to the table. It does not matter what Rt. Hon. Harper has personally said, regardless of how inflamatory those comments may be. Your position should be a higher one, not of a tattle-tale elementary schoolyard child, but of the correcting teacher who directs a class to overcome a poor decision.<br />
The Conservatives have something in their favour that the Liberals do not: since coming into power in 2006, the Conservatives have not made any serious mistakes &#8212; things that would normally cause Canadians to vote differently. That is a level of inertia that the Liberals &#8212; and you, as their leader &#8212; need to overcome.<br />
You have another inertia to overcome as well: Canadian political apathy. As you may recall, the 2008 federal election had the lowest turnout in Canadian history. If you wish to turn the tide, you have to encourage everyone not just to perform their civic duty, but be engaged in the direction of their country. That is a task that no Canadian political leader is willing to, at the risk of being attacked by the others. However, this is a risk you&#8217;ll need to take.<br />
And you need to take that risk to the west. I&#8217;m sure you saw the <a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/72/Canada_2008_Federal_Election.svg">electoral map from the previous election</a> &#8212; the west is a sea of blue, and your party acquired only seven seats. Alberta, in particular, love their Conservatives &#8212; attacking Harper will only lend sympathy rather than turning a tide. You need to appeal to the Western Canadian, and have them feel that Western Canada is as important to Canada as Quebec has been in previous elections.<br />
So, how? I don&#8217;t presume to preach to a politician, author, professor, and journalist. Instead, I would like to talk to you as a fellow Canadian. You don&#8217;t need to tell us what&#8217;s wrong with other politicians &#8212; you need to tell us what&#8217;s wrong with us, with our nation, with the things that we hold as dear and true to our identities as toques, beavers, hockey, and the maple leaf. And then inspire us to help repair those things, so that we become part of the solution, so we don&#8217;t just hand our problems to our government and expect everything to be fixed.<br />
We do not need promises or assurances. We need truths, no matter how hard they might be to hear. We need to be told &#8212; plainly &#8212; what has to happen. We need to be told that even the difficult is possible, and that hope isn&#8217;t just a word. We need to believe. We need to want.<br />
Ignore Rt. Hon. Harper. Ignore Hons. Duceppe, Layton, and May. Rise above them. Rise above the petty bickering. Make your message speak for itself, and speak to Canadians. Make us believe that you have a vision that means something more than merely acquiring office. If we are to go to the polls again, we have to know it&#8217;s for a good reason, and not because of a political spitting match. If you can bring faith back into Canadian politics, you may also bring greater enthusiasm and support.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/how-to-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2150</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the world really dying to see results from the US election?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/is-the-world-really-dying-to-see-results-from-the-us-election/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=is-the-world-really-dying-to-see-results-from-the-us-election</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/is-the-world-really-dying-to-see-results-from-the-us-election/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 22:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1154</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Maybe not the entire world, but certainly the wired world &#8212; the people online. All day, ever since I logged on, I&#8217;ve seen Tweets, blog posts, momentiles, and the like about people who are absolutely dying to see the results from the US election.   Most of those people want to see Obama win. (Or &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/is-the-world-really-dying-to-see-results-from-the-us-election/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Is the world really dying to see results from the US election?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maybe not the entire world, but certainly the wired world &#8212; the people online. All day, ever since I logged on, I&#8217;ve seen Tweets, blog posts, momentiles, and the like about people who are absolutely dying to see the results from the US election.  <br />
Most of those people want to see Obama win. (Or at least those are the ones I&#8217;ve seen.)<br />
I wonder, is this the most-watched election of all time (I say that because it likely is) due to Obama (and his chances of winning) or because of social networking bringing everyone out into the open?  <br />
There&#8217;s a thesis in this, I&#8217;m sure&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/is-the-world-really-dying-to-see-results-from-the-us-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1154</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada, you can blame Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canada-you-can-blame-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 03:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sigh. Well, thanks to the residents of Calgary Centre-North, Canada is now stuck with Jim Prentice again.  And I&#8217;m just too darned tired to rant. Wasted effort at this point.   But I reserve my right to call &#8220;I told ya so!&#8221; when the lawsuits start.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sigh.<br />
Well, thanks to the residents of Calgary Centre-North, Canada is now stuck with Jim Prentice <em>again</em>.  And I&#8217;m just too darned tired to rant. Wasted effort at this point.  <br />
But I reserve my right to call &#8220;I told ya so!&#8221; when the lawsuits start.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conservatives win the next Canadian federal election!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 02:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This isn&#8217;t a predictive headline, folks. This is truth. The Conservatives will win the election in October. I, as an Expat, can&#8217;t vote in it, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that I don&#8217;t take at least a sense of interest in it. Or stock in the fact that the Conservatives are finally getting what they wanted &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Conservatives win the next Canadian federal election!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This isn&#8217;t a predictive headline, folks. This is truth. The Conservatives will win the election in October. I, as an Expat, can&#8217;t vote in it, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that I don&#8217;t take at least a sense of interest in it. Or stock in the fact that the Conservatives are finally getting what they wanted the last time: Complete control.<br />
For the last two years, Canada has been living in the most blessed of political states: a minority government. As close to having the car in neutral as it gets. It means the least chance of political scandal (the &#8220;ruling&#8221; party doesn&#8217;t want to make mistakes that&#8217;ll haunt them come election time), and the opposition enjoys a place of perceived power as they get courted by the ruling party to help push through votes.<br />
Well, that&#8217;s all coming to an end now. So brace yourself, Canada &#8212; things are likely to get worse.<br />
<span id="more-1086"></span>Here&#8217;s the reality: The Conservatives are keen on setting the dial back a number of years. Estimates vary between 5 and 50. They want a world that&#8217;s white-bread, heterosexual, and very business-friendly. As opposed to being morally and ethically stalwart.<br />
Now, for the record, I&#8217;m not holding up the Liberals to that standard. As we all know, their 13-year run in office went seriously afoul and rotten towards the end. Not a problem with the Liberals per se, but with a lack of government controls. Things like that make it hard to keep office.<br />
Unlike the Liberals, the Conservatives are also very straight-forward with what they want. They will:</p>
<ul>
<li>Turn a blind eye to the environment, crying an attack on the economy every time</li>
<li>Repeal the same-sex laws</li>
<li>Keep the GST artifically low to make good with the Canadian public, despite a perpetual deficit</li>
<li>Raise an issue with Canadian sovernity over the arctic waters</li>
<li>Claim the Liberals are liars</li>
</ul>
<p>My arguments to these?</p>
<ul>
<li>You can focus on the economy now, or deal with the disaster later when the environment is in serious trouble. We know global warming has started to thaw the arctic, has accelerated the melting of glaciers (and will turn parts of Alberta to desert within 30 years), the abysmal record of the oil sands is ruining massive tracts of northern wilderness, the rise of temperatures is causing more and more issues with farming, and a never-ending dependence on gasoline is ruining air quality across the country. So what&#8217;ll it be, Harper &#8212; deal with the problem while it&#8217;s still manageable, or worry about your next meal ticket.</li>
<li>I hate to say it, but this is coming. There are too many intolerant people in the Conservative party, and I full expect them to dig this corpse out and force a repeal.</li>
<li>News flash, folks &#8212; you might be paying less GST, but you&#8217;re suffering for it when you go to the doctor or have to pay more for your childrens&#8217; education. Where do you think this money was coming from before? Yep, taxes. It&#8217;s a bit of a &#8220;duh&#8221;, but I&#8217;m regularly amazed at how many people complain about both high taxes and difficult medical care. I suggest picking one and sticking with it.</li>
<li>Canada has a place in the arctic &#8212; defending the rights of those who live there, and protecting the delicate environment that&#8217;s rapidly falling apart. And that should be it. This isn&#8217;t the Panama Canal, folks; even thinking of charging a toll for passage is just asking for conflict.</li>
<li>Everyone lies in politics. The trick is identifying it. That&#8217;s your reponsibility as a Canadian citizen, I might add &#8212; not theirs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here&#8217;s my problem with this election: There are no alternatives. Dion is totally the wrong person for the job. He has even less charisma than Harper (yes, it is possible). The Liberal Party chose wrong. They went with a Francophone in the interests of preserving national unity. But a Francophone does not represent the new powerhouse of the West (Alberta outclocks Ontario, folks, by quite a large margin when you look at the per capita). Canadians like money, and Harper comes from a province with stinkloads of it.<br />
It doesn&#8217;t matter what the Liberals should have done &#8212; that&#8217;s old news, now. It&#8217;s how they&#8217;re going to handle this election. The Liberals are going to take a serious hit. The Conservatives have done an excellent job of not pissing anyone off, and have a track record to be envious of. The Liberals? Whine, whine whine. Not smart.<br />
NDP? Please. Don&#8217;t make me laugh. The Bloc also serves no threat &#8230; except to the Liberals. See above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is America ready for Obama + Clinton?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 22:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love American politics. It&#8217;s my form of WWE &#8212; all the cheers and jeers with all the spectacle to go along with it. One day, I think the American presidency will go the way of the President of the Galaxy from Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy and be little more than a distraction from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Is America ready for Obama + Clinton?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love American politics. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.wwe.com/">my form of WWE</a> &#8212; all the cheers and jeers with all the spectacle to go along with it. One day, I think the American presidency will go the way of the <a href="http://hhgproject.org/entries/president.html">President of the Galaxy</a> from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker's_Guide_to_the_Galaxy"><em>Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy</em></a> and be little more than a distraction from the real power.<br />
Heck, it could be like that already, for all we know.<br />
Today, it was announced that <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2008/POLITICS/06/03/election.democrats/index.html">Hillary Clinton would be willing to consider a Vice-Presidency</a> with Barak Obama as top billing. But here&#8217;s a thought: Are Americans ready for this?<br />
<span id="more-983"></span>Let&#8217;s review the American presidential history, shall we?<br />
43 Presidents. Every single one of them a white male. The closest the United States has ever gotten to breaking that mould was with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geraldine_Ferraro">Geraldine Ferraro</a> in 1984 &#8212; an election I remember well, notably due to her Presidental candidate <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mondale">Robert Mondale</a>. (Refer to a previous post featuring [[The Shrub is back|lack-lustre Democratic nominees]].) It was a risky time to attempt such a running mate. Abortion was a hot topic of the day, and the United States was a lot more conservative back then.<br />
A black man (or African-American male, if you prefer)? The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jesse_Jackson">Rev. Jesse Jackson</a> tried twice, in 1984 (defeated mostly as a result of himself) and 1988 (defeated by, of all people, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Dukakis">Michael Dukakis</a>). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:African_American_United_States_presidential_candidates">He wasn&#8217;t the first African American to try</a>, but he&#8217;s been the only one until Obama. And by far the most successful. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_Powell">Colin Powell</a> declined not to run, though he might have done well.)<br />
But the question remains: Given the history of the last two elections (one being a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_presidential_election,_2000">near-travesty of democracy</a>), will this work? I think that both Obama and Clinton could stand on their own. They&#8217;ve broken through the problem of charisma (they&#8217;ve both got it in spades, which accounts for the delay in getting the nomination pinned down), and could stand well against <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_mccain">John McCain</a>.<br />
But together on the same ballot?<br />
It almost seems too liberal to me. Personally, I&#8217;d love to see it, but I have my doubts that even after eight years of Bush&#8217;s rather dubious leadership that they would turn to an idea that radical. (Remember the United States&#8217; tendency for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_states_and_blue_states">Red vs. Blue states</a>, and a number of states that <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/6383353/">voted out gay marriage</a> in pure terror of change.)<br />
Maybe I&#8217;m being too cynical. Maybe I&#8217;m not giving enough credit.<br />
I know this much, though: McCain had better watch himself. The mere second he even thinks of using race or sex as part of his stance, he&#8217;ll immediately alienate a huge section of voters. If nothing else, this will be the most politically-correct election you&#8217;ve ever seen. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/is-america-ready-for-obama-clinton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There was an election?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/there-was-an-election/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=there-was-an-election</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/there-was-an-election/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 04:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/04/there-was-an-election/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yep, believe it or not, there was an election in Alberta yesterday. Provincial. New MLAs, new premier (in theory), all that jazz. In most provinces, it&#8217;s usually time of actual change &#8212; old regimes are voted out, new ones come to power, more scandals (from different angles), and (this is the important part) an opposition &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/there-was-an-election/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "There was an election?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yep, believe it or not, there was an election in Alberta yesterday. Provincial. New MLAs, new premier (in theory), all that jazz. In most provinces, it&#8217;s usually time of actual change &#8212; old regimes are voted out, new ones come to power, more scandals (from different angles), and (this is the important part) an opposition party that actually has some teeth.<br />
But this is Alberta. Nothing ever changes in Alberta. The PCs being in an overwhelming majority is like the sun coming up in the morning.<br />
<span id="more-908"></span>Alberta is the most conservative province in Canada. That&#8217;s not an opinion, that&#8217;s fact. This is a province that barely tolerates anything considered &#8220;out of the norm&#8221;. Even in the major cities (notably Calgary and Edmonton), where the non-PC parties gain most of their support, the vast majority still vote conservative.<br />
Which is why we have exactly the same government we had two days ago. It hasn&#8217;t changed. The names might change, but the thing still works the same. Ed Stelmach loved to talk about how there was a mandate from the people and how this is a reassurance of support.<br />
Somehow, I doubt 40% is all that reassuring a number there, Ed. Seems to me that most people believed that little would change, and frankly didn&#8217;t see any significant reason to vote otherwise.<br />
A point of note to the Liberals, the NDP, the Green Party, and whoever else wants to run against the PCs in this province:<br />
<strong>PICK A FREAKING PLATFORM, AND STATE IT CLEARLY.</strong><br />
Merely stating that you think the PCs are dumb and their ideas aren&#8217;t good is about as effective as saying: &#8220;I know you are, but what am I?&#8221;<br />
Take a lesson from our neighbours to the south: Get in tight spots. Shoot your mouth off. Create controversy. Raise a stink. But for the love of all things political do <em>SOMETHING </em>than just stand there.<br />
At least it would make the election more than a passing footnote&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/there-was-an-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">908</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
