<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>star trek &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/star-trek/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 16:54:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>An evening with the crew of the Starship Enterprise</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 16:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Calgary&#8217;s Comic Convention seems to be growing by leaps and bounds every year. While I&#8217;ve never been, I&#8217;d heard how Leonard Nimoy had been scooped a couple of years ago (they even managed to take him out to Vulcan &#8212; no joke). Last year&#8217;s event was the biggest, ever. This year? Well, &#8220;record-setting&#8221; isn&#8217;t the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "An evening with the crew of the Starship Enterprise"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calgary&#8217;s Comic Convention seems to be growing by leaps and bounds every year. While I&#8217;ve never been, I&#8217;d heard how Leonard Nimoy had been scooped a couple of years ago (<a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/calgary/story/2010/04/23/vulcan-nimoy-spock-visit-star-trek-comicon-calgary.html">they even managed to take him out to Vulcan</a> &#8212; no joke). Last year&#8217;s event was the biggest, ever. This year? Well, &#8220;record-setting&#8221; isn&#8217;t the right term, really. <a href="http://www.calgaryherald.com/entertainment/Chaos+comic+expo+with+thousands+turned+away/6536346/story.html">When the Fire Marshall has to tell people to disperse</a>, you&#8217;ve got a number of problems &#8212; good and bad &#8212; to work yourself through.<br />
But in particular, this year was important, because they&#8217;d somehow managed to arrange for the first-ever complete reunion (and the first gathering in celebration of the 25th anniversary year) of the complete (original) cast of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em>. And for one night only, they&#8217;d all be on the same stage in an event called &#8220;<a href="http://www.calgaryexpo.com/tng-exposed/">Star Trek: TNG Exposed</a>&#8220;.<br />
Like I wasn&#8217;t going to go&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3079"></span>Now, for the record, I only heard of the event through my friend Tamara, who despite calling me a &#8220;nerd&#8221; more emphatically than most, is the one who actually went to the Calgary Comic Convention, stood in lines, got signatures, and so forth. So draw your own conclusions, there. But she was the one who first caught wind of the TNG Exposed event. And knew when the tickets were going on sale, and she was not going alone, and my presence was a requirement for my continued existence.<br />
How exactly Calgary had managed to score this event is a matter for some debate. There are those who think Calgary effectively won the Convention circuit lottery, and paid the most to win the event. There are those who thing it was a matter of providence, where a couple of the cast members had already signed up, and it happened to line up with the rest. And then last night, it was suggested that, really, the rest of the cast was merely waiting for Sir Patrick Stewart to say &#8220;yes&#8221;&#8230;<br />
At any rate, it was my first solo outing in &#8230; well, so long, I can&#8217;t even remember the last one. I met up with Tamara, our friend Adrian, and a couple of Tamara&#8217;s friends at Wurst, a restaurant on 4th St. that happens to have the best &#8220;homemade&#8221; mustard in town (challenge me otherwise, if you dare!), and some of the best bratwurst I&#8217;ve ever had. The beer is, regrettably, overpriced and when my headache hit me full-on during the event, I also began to question how often they clean out their lines. I may not be returning anytime soon as a result.<br />
We got to the Stampede Corral just after 6:30, and wound our way through the rather extensive (but swift-moving) lineup to find our seats. Tamara had got the two of us a pair of seats in the sixth(!) row; poor Adrian was scattered into the Nether-regions of the bleachers somewhere. And we waited.<br />
While waiting, we talked with a couple of folks around us (all geeks, and a surprising number of people who you may work with and never have a clue that they were Trekkies), and listened to <a href="http://www.johnnysummers.com">Johnny Summers</a> and his Little Big band, a local jazz-influenced performer who has a collection of some disturbingly talented performers (note: if you live in Calgary, you need to see these folks perform, it&#8217;s something else!).<br />
Finally, just after 7:00, Emily Expo, the &#8220;mascot&#8221; of the Calgary Comic Convention (a 20s-ish woman with fire-red hair, who is pretty much just as geeky as everyone else in the audience) came out to introduce the show. The cast wouldn&#8217;t be seen until much later, but first there was an introduction of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garrett_Wang">Garrett Wang</a> (who played Ensign Harry Kim on <em>Star Trek: Voyager</em>), and a former director of <em>Star Trek: TNG</em> (whose name I&#8217;ve sadly forgotten), who regaled a few interesting notes about how the future they had conceived in the late 1980s, taking place some 400 years in the future, was already coming true today (witness the iPad, the US DoD&#8217;s research on cloaking, devices that effective operate as a phaser set to &#8216;stun&#8217;, and so forth). As he repeated stated: &#8220;we are living in Star Trek&#8221;.<br />
Then came a reel that the Expo team had compiled of interviews Emily Expo conducted at the Emerald Con back in January. It opened not with any actor, but none other that Calgary&#8217;s most well-known geek, Mayor Naheed Nenshi, who was adamantly distressed about the fact that he was missing the show. (I doubt it was an act. No offense intended, your Honour, but you&#8217;re a lousy actor. You&#8217;re a much better geek.)<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/calgarys-awesomely-geeky-mayor-naheed-nenshi/' title='Calgary&#039;s awesomely geeky Mayor, Naheed Nenshi'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Calgary-s-awesomely-geeky-Mayor-Naheed-Nenshi-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignleft wp-image-3357" alt="Calgary&#039;s awesomely geeky Mayor, Naheed Nenshi" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/7124750677/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The reel showcased Emily Expo interviewing people such as Christopher Judge (Teal&#8217;c from <em>Stargate SG-1</em>), the most awesome Edward James Olmos (notably of the revamped <em>Battlestar Galactica</em> series, but I grew up with him from <em>Miami Vice</em> and <em>Blade Runner</em>), Adam Baldwin (a sci-fi regular, seen mostly on <em>Firefly</em>), Robert Picardo (The Doctor from <em>Star Trek: Voyager</em>, but Picardo has been seen in my sci-fi outings), Walter Koeing (obviously for his role as Chekov from the original series, but I would be remiss to not mention his awesome portrayal of Bester from <em>Babylon 5)</em>, and the legendary George Takei (yes, his voice really is that awesome). Also included in the reel were people who you might not recognise on site, but their voices are also well-known: John Di Maggio (who performs Bender on <em>Futurama</em>; his reading of &#8220;Space, the Final Frontier&#8221; should be recorded for all time, by the way), and the prolific voice actors Rob Paulsen and Jess Harnell (best known for the Warner Brothers Yakko and Wakko, from the <em>Animaniacs</em>).<br />
Then we had an intermission. Which seemed like a little bit of a let-down, but it was really understandable. And necessary, as both Tamara and I desperately needed to drink some water.<br />
During the break, however, Tamara pointed out the Garrett Wang &#8212; seated barely five metres away &#8212; was seemingly chatting it up with various people. How could I resist? Waiting patiently, he very graciously spent about a minute having a short conversation with me, and I got to shake the man&#8217;s hand. He was enthusiastic, to say the least.<br />
Now, before you all leap over me with &#8220;Garrett Wang?!&#8221; or &#8220;but you were there to see the TNG cast!&#8221; and such stuff, let me elaborate a bit. For the record, <em>Star Trek: Voyager</em> was not my favourite Star Trek series &#8230; it was, actually, dead last. By a wide margin. There were a number of things about Voyager that had always bothered me, the most notable being the ever-present &#8220;reset button&#8221;, whereby no matter how badly the Voyager (the ship, not the show) was damaged in any given episode, it was restored to perfect condition by the next episode. Personally, I&#8217;d have preferred if the ship had been near-unrecognisable by the end of the series, held together with futuristic duct tape. But I digress&#8230;<br />
The one part of the show I had always liked was the character of Harry Kim. He was the most junior officer, the least experienced, the most naive. He was also the one who regularly grounded the show, keeping it from leaping off into &#8220;no problem&#8221; territory (whereby the other characters would perpetually overcome the issue seemingly without effort); Kim made sure that everyone understood the problem and that, no, it wasn&#8217;t easy. That kind of a character is not easy to portray, and I felt Wang had done an excellent job of it. I had to thank him for it, too. (I left out the part where I felt he was really the only saving grace of the show, other than Robert Picardo.)<br />
Finally, Emily Expo came back and introduced the &#8220;moderators&#8221; for the evening: the cast of Space channel&#8217;s <em>Inner Space</em> news show: Ajay Fry (who repeated stated that he was a mere four years old when TNG premiered), Cynthia Loyst, and Teddy Wilson. I don&#8217;t watch Space anymore (or hardly any TV, for that matter), so I really had no idea who these people were, and the tall &#8220;captain&#8217;s&#8221; chair that we had thought reserved for Patrick Stewart was summarily occupied. There was a brief chat, and then came the crew&#8230;<br />
First out was Denise Crosby (Lt. Tasha Yar), who came out wearing a Calgary Flames toque. She was followed by Michael Dorn (originally Lt. Worf, who went on to be Lt. Cmdr. in Star Trek: Deep Space 9), whom I had seen at a Star Trek convention back in the early 1990s when TNG was still filming), and then Marina Sirtis (Deanna Troi), who filled the right-most couch.<br />
Then came Levar Burton (Lt., then Lt. Cmdr. Geordi LaForge), who received a lot of applause. Gates McFadden (Dr. Beverly Crusher) came out next. (I had a wicked crush on her back in the 1990s; she still looks almost as fantastic today at age 63!) She was followed by Brent Spiner (Lt., then Lt. Cmdr. Data).<br />
The final couch was filled by the last three: Wil Wheaton (Wesley Crusher), who garnered the second-loudest cheer on his arrival; Johnathan Frakes (Cmdr. William Riker); and the loudest cheer went to the arrival of Captain Jean-Luc Picard (and Professor Xavier) himself, Sir Patrick Stewart.<br />
(Sorry, can&#8217;t seem to get the video to embed. You&#8217;ll have to watch it <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/sowrey/7124973007">here</a>.)<br />
It was interesting to see how the cast had aged over the years. Patrick Stewart I had seen out-of-character only once before, as a guest on BBC&#8217;s Top Gear (he was a Star in a Reasonably Priced Car). At the time, I&#8217;d been rather surprised by the fact that he seemed to be behaving much like Picard had acted when he&#8217;d &#8212; in more than one episode &#8212; ended up an old man. Frakes looked like he&#8217;d just gotten out of bed, or had been sitting at an editing desk for far too long. Wheaton, who&#8217;d left the series at age 18 after thinking he could do better on his own (oops!) had aged the best, but he&#8217;s also by far the youngest. Spiner looked quite dignified with his whitened hair (compared to Dorn, who had no hair at all). Burton seems ageless, save for the slight greying. Sirtis, like McFadden, seems to only get better with age &#8212; she would do well on a sitcom, I think. Crosby, the quietest of the lot, seemed the only one to be struggling a bit, which I might even pass off as a result of the dinner the cast had supposedly shared before arriving (which might also explain some of the overly giddy nature shared by all of them).<br />
Once the chaos had died down, the interview started. But it wasn&#8217;t really much of an interview, so much as the &#8220;moderators&#8221; starting a conversation and letting the cast run with it from there. There was much laughing as the various stories (likely been told many times over the last 25 years) were told again, likely in different ways, with a few new twists. There were new stories as well, made obvious by the casts&#8217; reactions to hearing them.<br />
Some questions came from the audience as well, courtesy of a contest that had been run earlier. There were only five lucky people, so presumably they had to make sure they were really great questions. They were certainly amongst the best I&#8217;d ever heard asked of people who&#8217;d been asked such questions for a quarter century. A sixth was added by a &#8220;sick boy from Vancouver&#8221;, who was revealed to be actor Aaron Douglas from the rebooted <em>Battlestar Galatica</em> (he was declared to be &#8220;sick&#8221; because he supported the Vancouver Canucks). But by far the most interesting question was: What question would you ask of yourselves, that you&#8217;ve always wanted to ask?<br />
This caught the cast off-guard (clearly not asked before), and even made the audience go &#8220;ooooooh&#8221; at the thought. The cast exchanged glances a moment before Michael Dorn responded: &#8220;Well, we pretty much know everything about one another. I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anything left to ask!&#8221;<br />
That elicited a round of laughter. But then Wil Wheaton, who has the enviable position of not only being a former cast member, but also being a convention expert (as easily one of the biggest geeks in the room), leaned forward. &#8220;Actually, I have one.&#8221; He bent towards Patrick Stewart. &#8220;Just how cool is it really to be in <em>X-Men</em>?&#8221;<br />
Possibly the best question that could ever have been asked, in the manner that it was asked.<br />
After the cheering and laughter died down, Patrick Stewart noted that the coolest part was &#8220;arriving at the make-up trailer each morning, and passing by all the mirrors, saying &#8216;good morning&#8217; and kissing Halle Berry, Anna Paquin, Famke Janssen, and Rebecca Romijn-Stamos&#8221;. Sir Stewart is a lucky, lucky man.<br />
The moderators then asked a simple question: &#8220;Who was your greatest adversary on the show?&#8221; Audience answer: Q. After a bit of consultation on the left-most couch, the answer was &#8220;Daimon Bok&#8221;, a Ferengi character who had challenged Picard on a few occasions. The audience kind of nodded, but I didn&#8217;t buy it. It felt like a set up for something else. Which it was.<br />
&#8220;That&#8217;s a load of poop!&#8221; came a voice over the speakers, but it wasn&#8217;t from those on stage. It was a familiar voice. And for the record, I (likely as many others) expected this.<br />
John de Lancie, the actor who had played the intergalactic pain in the ass, Q (my favourite character) marched out from the rear of the auditorium, down the aisle passing within inches of me (excuse me whilst I sqweeeeeeeeee like a little girl), a large bouquet of flowers over his head. The cast, supposedly, had no idea he was going to be joining them, but since he was already at the Calgary Comic Convention, I doubt it was a complete surprise.<br />
And suddenly, all the principal actors from the very first episode, <em>Encounter At Farpoint</em>, were all on stage again. Likely for the first time since that episode had been filmed, now that I think about it.<br />
And then, all too soon, it was over. Patrick Stewart had &#8220;another engagement&#8221; (it was 10:00, so one could only imagine what he was trucking off to), and the actors all left the stage. John de Lancie would go out to the lobby for autographs (a two-hour lineup formed almost immediately; as much as I would have loved to meet Q himself, it would sadly have to wait for another time).<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/all-good-things/' title='All Good Things...'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/All-Good-Things--300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignleft wp-image-3358" alt="All Good Things..." /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/7124979101/">Geoff S.</a><br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/john-de-lancie-q-does-autographs/' title='John de Lancie (Q) does autographs'><img width="224" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/John-de-Lancie-Q-does-autographs-224x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignleft wp-image-3359" alt="John de Lancie (Q) does autographs" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/7124981613/">Geoff S.</a><br />
My head, by this point, was splitting. My headache had started just after the cast had taken the stage, and I was fearful that I&#8217;d have to leave so I could throw up (the pain was really that bad). So I was thankful to get outside, and even more thankful that Adrian drove us home (and I didn&#8217;t have to suffer on the bus).<br />
So ends my evening of geekiness, for it will likely be some time before I get to do something that ridiculously nerdy again&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/an-evening-with-the-crew-of-the-starship-enterprise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I think of the new Star Trek movie</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 15:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night, I saw J.J. Abrams&#8217; re-envisioning of Star Trek. It didn&#8217;t suck. But I&#8217;m not about to stand up and laud the praise that so many others had. I&#8217;m not convinced it deserves it (or the #71 ranking in the IMDB&#8217;s Top 250), but it&#8217;s a vast improvement over some of the shlock that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What I think of the new Star Trek movie"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I saw <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0796366/">J.J. Abrams&#8217; re-envisioning of Star Trek</a>. It didn&#8217;t suck. But I&#8217;m not about to stand up and laud the praise that so many others had. I&#8217;m not convinced it deserves it (or the #71 ranking in the <a href="http://www.imdb.com/chart/top?tt0796366">IMDB&#8217;s Top 250</a>), but it&#8217;s a vast improvement over some of the shlock that Star Trek movies have been of late.  <br />
I went in, admittedly, with higher than normal expectations (press is hard to ignore entirely, and even <a href="http://wilwheaton.typepad.com/wwdnbackup/2009/05/geek-in-review-star-trek-has-been-reborn-and-it-is-spectacular.html">Wil Wheaton claimed it was awesome</a>). So there is a certain amount of disappointment. But now that I&#8217;ve had time to ruminate on the film, the plot, the acting, etc., I&#8217;d like to think I&#8217;ve got a decent view.  <br />
And for those of you who haven&#8217;t seen the movie: Beware! <strong>Thar be spoilers ahead!</strong><br />
<span id="more-1363"></span>Okay, first off, let&#8217;s cover all the stuff that J.J. Abrams + Co. did (very) well:  </p>
<ul>
<li>Casting was spot-on. Excellent choices, there were the right people doing the right roles. Pine was an excellent young, rebellious, and a sooner-than-TOS captain (read: more brash, more in-your-face). Quinto might as well be Nimoy&#8217;s actual son for his ability to look like a young Spock.</li>
<li>Acting was well-suited. A few people have called out Urban&#8217;s portrayal of Bones McCoy as being a bit &#8220;odd&#8221;, but the more I think about it, the more I actually like his mildly pissed-off, slightly backwater personality. I&#8217;m curious to see how he and Spock pit themselves together in successive movies (yes, I&#8217;m assuming sequels).</li>
<li>Special effects done exceptionally well. Gone are the days of models (which I lament), but the CG executed in the movie is very good, almost seamless in some places. The collapsing Vulcan was oustanding.</li>
<li>Many excellent references to previous movies and series episodes, for those of you paying attention.  </li>
<li>Sulu still fences, but he has a switch-blade katana, and saves Kirk&#8217;s life.  </li>
<li>Star Trek finally adopts the &#8220;used universe&#8221; for its sets. Using a brewery for the inside of a massive ship was a brilliant stroke of genius, as it made the ship look more &#8220;real&#8221;. (Although because I knew it was a brewery, I couldn&#8217;t quite get into the fact that it was supposed to be a starship.)</li>
<li>The introduction of the alternate reality.  </li>
</ul>
<p>I want to focus on that last point for a moment. This bugged me at first, but then I not only saw the wisdom in this decision, but also came to praise the breaking from pattern that came with it. In the movie (<strong>SPOILER ALERT</strong>), an event 129 years in the future creates a black hole through which Nero (the bad guy) and the Original Spock (Nimoy) get sucked back in time. This creates an alternate reality (which is actually acknowledged by the characters in the movie) where things do not follow the previous Star Trek canon.  <br />
Namely, the planet Vulcan and most of the Vulcan civilisation is destroyed.  <br />
In pretty much every previous incarnation of Star Trek, some event occurs in the course of the given episode/movie that allows the regular timeline to be returned to normal. But Abrams and crew deliberately avoided hitting the &#8220;Reset Button&#8221; (<a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Voyager">Star Trek: Voyager</a>, I&#8217;m looking at you!). Result? Uhuru and Spock are love interests, Vulcan is still destroyed, Kirk is a captain much earlier than in the regular timeline, and the technology is more advanced that it would be normally (though this pattern was started with <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Enterprise">Star Trek: Enterprise</a>).  <br />
What does this mean? It means Abrams (and future Star Trek movie makers) are not tied to the previous canon, and are free to create some of their own. We&#8217;ll likely see certain characters return, albeit slightly different, and some characters may never enter the new world (it&#8217;s possible we&#8217;ll never meet <a href="http://khaaaaaaan.ytmnd.com/">KHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAN</a>!).<br />
The other thing it means is it (mostly) shortcuts all the nitpickers. Trekkies and Trekkers alike are nitpickers. They love tearing apart episodes and movies for continuity errors, plot issues, scientific problems, acting (especially important given the brand new cast), and gaffes. Because of the alternate reality, they can&#8217;t start claiming that something isn&#8217;t canon, or that a character wouldn&#8217;t do X, or that the planet Vulcan was never destroyed.  <br />
I say &#8220;mostly&#8221;. Because there are some problems with the movie, too, that transcend the alternate reality. Remember, I&#8217;m a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/?s=reformed+trekkie">reformed Trekkie</a>, which also makes me a nitpicker.  </p>
<ul>
<li>Supernovae destroy solar systems, not whole galaxies. That&#8217;s a pretty damned big plot hole to have, as it negates the events that lead up to the alternate reality being created in the first place.  </li>
<li>Last I checked, anything &#8212; even a speck of dust &#8212; that enters a planetary atmosphere will start to heat up from friction (hence shooting stars). Yet Kirk, Sulu, and the ill-fated-red-shirt Olsen all &#8220;space dive&#8221; without ill effect.  </li>
<li>Kirk is promoted to captain (from an officer cadet with no serving experience) after receiving a commendation for his actions in the movie. Spock, a &#8220;distinguished graduate&#8221; already holding the rank of Commander, who literally puts his life on the line (was mere heatbeats from colliding the small ship he was piloting into Nero&#8217;s ship to stop an attack), is apparently overlooked entirely and made subservient to someone who&#8217;s barely graduated the academy. I&#8217;m all for the Kirk/Spock relationship thing, but I&#8217;m having some trouble with this one.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s a new world for Star Trek, and Abrams&#8217; approach to setting up that new world was done (mostly) wisely. For an odd-numbered Star Trek movie, it&#8217;s also pretty good (the only other exception being <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek_III:_The_Search_for_Spock">Star Trek III: The Search For Spock</a>, which I like mostly due to Christopher Lloyd&#8217;s Kruge). But it definitely doesn&#8217;t top the charts for me. I think it sets a good precedent, though, and I am eager to see what they can come up with next.<br />
May the new Trek live long and prosper!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Star Trek went wrong</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/where-star-trek-went-wrong/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=where-star-trek-went-wrong</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/where-star-trek-went-wrong/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 05:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many years ago, I wrote an article for the University of Waterloo&#8217;s student newspaper, The Imprint, where I laid into Star Trek: Generations (page 24) as a not-so-great adaptation of a television show to a movie. To say that I was a tad harsh is to characterise me as a tad off-beat. The fact that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/where-star-trek-went-wrong/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Where Star Trek went wrong"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many years ago, I wrote an article for the University of Waterloo&#8217;s student newspaper, The Imprint, <a href="http://imprint.uwaterloo.ca/pdfarchive/1994-95_v17,n19_Imprint.pdf">where I laid into Star Trek: Generations (page 24)</a> as a not-so-great adaptation of a television show to a movie. To say that I was a tad harsh is to characterise me as a tad off-beat. The fact that I referred to William Shatner as a &#8220;carpet head&#8221; is now thoroughly embarrasing (I have significantly more respect for him than I did 15 years ago).   <br />
I considered this a bit of a coup, myself. Not the lambasting of the movie &#8212; the fact that I managed to get the article into the school&#8217;s newspaper which, at the time, had a policy of first-received, first-published. For those of you who won&#8217;t know, the <a href="http://uwaterloo.ca">University of Waterloo</a> once held the lofty position of Geek Central. (It&#8217;s now a trendy school, apparently. I&#8217;m having trouble coming to terms with that.) There were more Trekkies per capita at that University than for 1,000 kms in any direction.  <br />
What I didn&#8217;t realise at the time was that I&#8217;d actually missed something extremely significant about the movie, that would come back to haunt Trekkies and Trekkers alike many years later. Something so important not only to Star Trek, but to the genre as well, that there&#8217;s a serious need to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retcon">retcon</a> that movie.  <br />
Kirk shouldn&#8217;t have died.<br />
<span id="more-1314"></span>At least, not in the way he ended up dying. He died because, effectively, a bridge fell on him. A pretty lousy way to go, if you ask me. Maybe if he were trying to hold up the Golden Gate Bridge, then at least we&#8217;re talking something more impressive. But a flimsy catwalk? C&#8217;mon, this is not the way you end a legend.  <br />
Yes, legend. Kirk was &#8212; and is &#8212; legendary. Within the world of Star Trek, he was The Man. Everyone either wanted to be him, be with him, do him (c&#8217;mon, you&#8217;ve seen the <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_The_Original_Series">Original Series</a>, admit it), was awed by him, or was afraid of him. Kirk did the things no-one else had the cojones to do, and never thought twice about doing something potentially stupid. The entire Klingon race was scared of him, for crying out loud!<br />
This is not how you treat a legend, killing him with a bridge in a barely so-so movie.  <br />
Yes, I&#8217;m a Trekkie. Actually, a &#8220;reformed&#8221; Trekkie. I used to know a lot about Trekdom, but have long since given it up &#8212; I needed the space in my brain for other nonsense (like all these damned passwords I have to remember). I went to the conventions (two of them), and I own most of the Star Trek movies (I refuse to own <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek_V:_The_Final_Frontier">Star Trek V</a> or <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Insurrection">Star Trek: Nemesis</a>). I know the Star Trek universe enough to know when it went wrong.<br />
This is about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mythology">mythology</a>, and as silly as it might sound, Star Trek is every bit mythological as it is scientific. It plays upon myth and the mythic style of story-telling, and creates characters and situations that play exactly into mythic tale-telling. The heros are not just bigger-than-life, they&#8217;re epic. Their actions are bold and decisive. Their conquests are immense and impossible. Their foes are terrifying and strong.<br />
How should a hero die? In mystery. How they died should be completely unknown, only that they&#8217;re no longer around. As if to suggest that it&#8217;s possible they might one day return. (Or at the very least rise from the dead, become omnipotent, and then disappear.) This is how legend and myth are created: by deliberately avoiding the details that would otherwise ground the story in fact. Which as we all know is gloriously dull.<br />
Want a great example of how a hero should walk off stage? <a href="http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/Luke_Skywalker">Luke Skywalker.</a> Not the one from the movies &#8212; the one that&#8217;s lived on in books and comics. That Luke Skywalker goes on to found a new Jedi order, turns to the dark side (and back), defeats a clone of himself, saves the galaxy a few times over, and so forth. By the time his storyline runs out, he&#8217;s over 150 (a fary cry from Yoda, but pretty good for a human). How does he die? No idea. And George Lucas refuses to let anyone write it. That&#8217;s the way it should be &#8212; without detail.<br />
<a href="http://www.ntua.gr/lurk/">Babylon 5</a>, long maligned as a &#8220;wannabe&#8221; against <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Deep_Space_Nine">Star Trek: Deep Space 9</a> (though I consider B5 a much tighter story-teller) had a perfect ending for its central hero, John Sheridan. Knowing he had only days left to live went off to say goodbye to the galaxy and waited for the First Ones (basically near-omnipotent beings) to find him. All anyone found was his ship floating adrift in deep space. Heck, even DS9 ended with its principle character, Benjamin Sisko, disappearing into a supposedly firey death only to be rescued by the wormhole entities &#8230; and told he&#8217;d return when the time was right (which could be anytime, or never).<br />
Best death in all of science-fiction? Spock. (Some people say Lorne Greene&#8217;s Adama. I say no way.) Spock realises that over 200 people will die if the Enterprise&#8217;s badly damaged warp core isn&#8217;t fixed. Knowing he can do it, rushes into the reactor chamber and does it himself, exposing himself to a fatal dosage of radiation in the process. The needs of the many must outweigh the needs of the few &#8230; or the one.  <br />
Best. Death. Ever.  <br />
Kirk? Felled by a stray piece of metal.<br />
This is not the way <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/James_T._Kirk">James Tiberius Kirk</a> should go out. Kirk&#8217;s death should be more dramatic. He should go out in a major battle, delivering the great final blow that leads to victory &#8212; but himself mortally wounded like Wolfe at the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Plains_of_Abraham">Plains of Abraham</a>. (And no, I in no way compare the ending of <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek_Generations">Generations</a> to even close.) Or vanish while doing what he did best: exploring. The only decent line in Star Trek V (which although I hate as Star Trek canon, brings one good aspect to Kirk):</p>
<blockquote><p>I&#8217;ve always known I&#8217;ll die alone.</p></blockquote>
<p>Kirk was never meant to be an old man. Spock lived to a very old age (Vulcans do that). Scotty hid himself in a transporter and survived to 80-odd years in the future. Bones lived to the point where he was practically walking dust. (Who knows what happened to the rest of the original crew.) But Kirk? Kirk shouldn&#8217;t have lived much longer past <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek_VI:_The_Undiscovered_Country">Star Trek VI</a>, and he shouldn&#8217;t have met Picard.<br />
So I choose to ignore the fact that Kirk died in Generations. Wasn&#8217;t him. A clone, maybe. The real Kirk? He found an unknown planet populated by beautiful women and life goes on forever.<br />
And he&#8217;s in no hurry to come back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/where-star-trek-went-wrong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1314</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 40th Anniversary Star Trek</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/09/star-trek-40th-anniversary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=star-trek-40th-anniversary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/09/star-trek-40th-anniversary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 07:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[know-it-all]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Space. The Final Frontier. Forty years ago today, a little under six years before I was born, Star Trek took to the air for it&#8217;s original three-year run before being cancelled. It would spawn off an animated series, comic book series, toys, four spin-off television series, 10 movies, and more parodies than you could shake &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/09/star-trek-40th-anniversary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 40th Anniversary Star Trek"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Space. The Final Frontier.<br />
Forty years ago today, a little under six years before I was born, Star Trek took to the air for it&#8217;s original three-year run before being cancelled. It would spawn off an animated series, comic book series, toys, four spin-off television series, 10 movies, and more parodies than you could shake a tribble at.<br />
I honestly don&#8217;t know the first time I watched Star Trek in any form, though I&#8217;m relatively sure it was TOS (The Original Series). I know I was an addict for the entire run of TNG (The Next Generation). From there, I progressed to DS9 (Deep Space 9), Voyager, and finally the too-short-lived Enterprise series. Following TNG, my addition tempered and waned, especially as many of the episodes seemed to have lacklustre writing and stints of not-so-great acting. (Yes, it can be argued that none of the series had great acting as a whole. Particularly when it comes to asking what &#8230; have you done &#8230; with &#8230; Spock&#8217;s brain?!)<br />
&#8220;Trekkie.&#8221; The word evokes four possible responses: Laughter, ignorance, revulsion, acceptance. Some know what a trekkie is and merely laugh at the idea. There are those who have no idea what a trekkie is. There are those who do know and thoroughly object to being considered a &#8220;trekkie&#8221;, staunchly preferring &#8220;trekker&#8221;. And there are those who like the idea (and the connotations) that come with the epithet.<br />
I was a trekkie. (Note the past-tense.) I considered those who wanted to be called &#8220;trekkers&#8221; to be far too pretentious for their own good. I was all for the campiness, the humour, the perceived silliness that comes out. I went to Star Trek conventions (two, to be exact &#8212; one in Toronto and another in Buffalo). I had the pins, knew most of the characters, all the TNG episodes, could recite most of The Wrath of Khan by heart. And I wasn&#8217;t ashamed about it, either.<br />
Somewhere along the line &#8212; once I&#8217;d graduated university, it seems &#8212; I&#8217;d began a long, slow decline in my trekkiness. Today, I&#8217;d consider myself having turned my card back, no longer allowed to consider myself one amongst the crowd. &#8220;Reformed&#8221;, &#8220;ex&#8221;, &#8220;former&#8221; &#8212; pick a euphimism. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I still love Star Trek in its various forms (although Voyager&#8217;s &#8220;reset button&#8221; habit still ticks me off), I just don&#8217;t devote a significant portion of my brain to it anymore. I&#8217;ve got a variety of other things to cram in there.<br />
Like generally useless trivia. It&#8217;s part of being a know-it-all.<br />
But you have to give Star Trek something. Despite all the wacky behaviour with fanatics, the show has done a surprising amount of good. Well, maybe &#8220;good&#8221; is subjective. It breathed life into the entire nearly-dead science fiction genre and gave rise to Star Wars, among other things. It also kindled new interest in science itself, creating several generations of scientists, physicists, explorers, and astronomers.<br />
The creator is gone. Gene Roddenbury died when I was in university. DeForrest &#8220;Bones&#8221; Kelly followed a few years later. James &#8220;Scotty&#8221; Doohan passed into the final frontier last year. Forty years takes its toll. They may be gone, but the legacy will live on. Maybe even to the 23rd century.<br />
Live long, and prosper.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/09/star-trek-40th-anniversary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3533</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
