<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kyoto &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/kyoto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 23:06:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 23:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much. Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much.<br />
Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up the Karasuma line to the Kyoto Imperial Palace. I really wanted to see what it&#8217;s like in there.<br />
But first, we had to pack up and check out. Which wasn&#8217;t easy &#8212; we&#8217;d spread ourselves all over the room. Although it didn&#8217;t take me long to pack, Jen had to take a bit longer out of necessity. It&#8217;s safe to say that, either way, both of us officially have too much stuff.<br />
<span id="more-341"></span>I had some troubles at the front desk trying to pay for the bill. It came to about 85,000 yen for the four days (about CDN$1,000).<br />
Yes, this is what people refer to when they say that Japan is expensive. Last time, I hadn&#8217;t noticed this because I&#8217;d stayed with Chris. Now I know better.<br />
For whatever reason, my Mastercard wasn&#8217;t accepted. Neither was my VISA. Not by the hotel &#8212; by their system. Quite odd, and highly annoying. So it had to be cash, and I needed a post office for that. First, though, Jen and I brought our bags down to put into storage.<br />
Luckily, there&#8217;s a post office about a block and a half from the hotel, and unlike Canada&#8217;s post offices, was open on a weekend. But my financial woes didn&#8217;t end &#8212; for whatever reason, I couldn&#8217;t withdraw more than 60,000 yen, barely covering our hotel cost with the money I already had. I think I have only about 10,000 yen to get me through the weekend. I hope I make it.<br />
This prompted a long series of emails to and from North America (over the keitai), specifically to my sister, to try and figure out what happened to my bank account. My paycheque should have gone through two days ago (even with the time change). Thankfully, my money is still there, I just can&#8217;t get to it for some reason.<br />
We got to the Imperial Palace and walked over to the Household Agency, which governs the operation of the Palaces and grants the tours.<br />
On weekdays. We&#8217;d forgotten that it&#8217;s Saturday. I knew there was a reason I&#8217;d wanted to go to Osaka today and not yesterday.<br />
After taking a bit of a leisurely tour through the palace grounds, we returned to the hotel to collect our things and head off to the shinkansen. The 12:37 Hikaru would put us in Tokyo a little after 15:00, and have us at Chris&#8217; door by 16:30 or so. (As it stands, we arrived at 17:00.)<br />
Nearing Kyoto Station, the unmisstakable sound of women running in high heels echoed through the tiled hallways. (In the hotel room, women running down the road in high heels always seemed to sound like horses clip-clopping.) Women always seem to be running in heels here. If there was an Olympic event for running in high heels, Japan would capture the gold every time.<br />
The train ride out was mostly uneventful, Jen and I snoozing most of the trip from Kyoto to Tokyo. Arriving at Tokyo, we found our way down to Sobu underground track #4, where we waited for the 15:50 to Chiba. For the first time since I started taking trains in Japan, one was actually late.<br />
By five whole minutes.<br />
Chris and Kaz were kept appraised of our location at all times. Chris was off to work again, so Kaz would pick us up at the train station. How did I know all this? The rented cell phone, of course. Today, if anything, has proven why renting a cell phone in Japan is a good thing &#8212; being able to confirm a bank account balance or make sure you meet up with friends is not only extremely handy, but really cuts some of the guess work out of things. So if you&#8217;re planning to come to Japan and know people here, really consider renting a phone. It&#8217;s almost too convenient not to have one.<br />
Arriving at Yotsukaido, Kaz directed us to the taxi. I didn&#8217;t think Chris&#8217; apartment was so far away that we needed a taxi, but after a long trip, taking a ride seemed far more pleasant. As we would find out, however, we were not going to Chris&#8217; apartment. Suddenly, the slightly garbled phone conversation I&#8217;d had with Chris made sense. We were going to Kaz&#8217;s (and now also Chris&#8217;) new apartment.<br />
It you get off on the taxi/bus side of the station, and go down the road that runs perpendicular to the station for about three kilometres, hang a left at the Eneos station, and go up about a block, you&#8217;ve found their place. It&#8217;s not as convenient as Chris&#8217; old apartment, but it is really nice. Brand-new (it was finished only days before we left Canada) and full of gadgets (the hot water for the bath/shower is turned on from the kitchen/living space, all electronic, and actually says something &#8212; in Japanese, of course). It&#8217;s pretty sweet.<br />
It&#8217;s a bus ride from the station, or taxi, or a long walk. So we won&#8217;t be hoofing it all that often, especially after a long day. No big deal, especially for such a nice place &#8230; even if it is going to be a bit cramped for the next couple of days. (Tony&#8217;s here tonight, and probably tomorrow night, too.)<br />
Kaz and I took the bus back to the station after dumping our things out (Jen stayed behind to read and draw), and then walked to the local Home Depot-like store. They&#8217;d purchased a gas range so they could cook, but had to pick it up. Although a fairly light piece of equipment, it&#8217;s just awkward enough that you needed to borrow a truck to take it home. We took the opportunity to pick up a few things from the apartment.<br />
Like the heater&#8230;<br />
&#8230; the TV &#8230;<br />
&#8230; the VCR, DVD player, Playstation, movies, books, CDs, CD burner, a small cabinet, boxes of who-knows-what, and anything else we could pack in the back of the truck.<br />
I should point out that this is a *Japanese* truck. One that could fit in the bed of most large American pick-up trucks. So there wasn&#8217;t that much room for us to store stuff. Not that it was a big deal of any kind. It was weird to sit in because it was so small. You literally felt like the steel of the cab wrapped right around you to conserve space.<br />
Chris arrived just as we were finishing up, and we quickly packed the remainder. Kaz and I drove over in the truck while Chris biked. Due to rush hour traffic, Chris arrived before we did. A quick unpacking, and Chris and Kaz whipped off to take the truck back before they&#8217;d run out of time.<br />
Jen and I waited around, either drawing (in Jen&#8217;s case) or writing (in mine). It took a while, but they eventually returned to the apartment. They ran into Jen on her way back from coffee run (now that we&#8217;re in the Tokyo area, we&#8217;re actually able to find Georgia Max coffee again &#8212; the southern part of Japan seems to be devoid of it).<br />
With that, we were off to dinner at a nearby restaurant. We went for something called okonomiyaki, which is basically food that comes in a bowl, is mixed together, then cooked on a grill that&#8217;s built into the table. It&#8217;s sort of like a Japanese omelette or fritatta. It&#8217;s very tasty. We also had some grilled beef and pork, along with noodle and gyoza.<br />
Tony (yep, the Monkey Man) finally appeared around 22:00, after repeated attempts to try and get a hold of him. The five of us sat around, ate a little, before heading back to Kaz and Chris&#8217; apartment. We stopped first into a 24-hour drug/grocery store to pick up snacks and various things for around the house (they&#8217;re still moving in, so don&#8217;t have a lot of things). Jen bought three more Georgia Max coffees, and had downed two of them before we&#8217;d walked the block and a half to the apartment. She was still wired when we went to bed three hours later.<br />
Upon returning was the Great Soul Calibur II Matchup. Chris and Jen had been talking about this for a long time. Chris is very good at this game, as is Jen. Chris has a sort of &#8220;home field&#8221; advantage because this is a Playstation 2, whereas Jen plays on a GameCube. Doesn&#8217;t sound like it should matter, but it does. Jen won only a single game. Chris thoroughly trashed her in all the others. I just looked over at Jen, smiled, and said:<br />
&#8220;Now you know how I feel when I play you.&#8221;<br />
We called an end to Jen&#8217;s repeated &#8220;just one more!&#8221; requests, turning to the movie &#8220;Zatoichi&#8221;, a Japanese film about a blind master samurai and how he changes the lives of others. It&#8217;s a fairly violent film, but intermixed with comedy and some rather good rhythm (Stomp-like performances appear at various points in the movie). The ending&#8217;s a little disjointed, in my opinion, but it&#8217;s still a good film.<br />
And with that, we went to bed. Tomorrow is light: sleeping in, laundry, and the Fourth Party for Chris and Kaz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2004 23:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[osaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/02/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;. The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;.<br />
The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from our hotel to the Osaka Aquarium, our first destination of the day.<br />
<span id="more-340"></span>The problem was that Jen&#8217;s stomach was beginning to rebel. It doesn&#8217;t appreciate the Japanese diet the same way mine does. Mind you, mine&#8217;s been tempered with age, and isn&#8217;t wholly dependant on low-fat, unsweetened milk (which Jen&#8217;s seems to be). So the lack of milk and high fish content (which Jen&#8217;s not a particular fan of) really didn&#8217;t create an ideal situation.<br />
So we were a little later leaving than I had planned.<br />
We arrived at the aquarium about five minutes ahead of my prediction (noon), despite all the trains and transfers we&#8217;d had to take. Overall, not such a bad thing. Why were we going to an aquarium on the opposite side of the planet? Simply put: because Osaka Aquarium is one of the largest in the world, and features a whale shark, which I&#8217;ve never seen.<br />
Jen got screwed on the entrance fee. According to their fee schedule, she is still a child, which meant a mere 900 yen fee (rather than the 2000 yen adult fee). However, even armed with her passport (as proof of age), the clerks simply didn&#8217;t believe that she was 15. If only we had those guys from the izakaya (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]]) for assistance.<br />
We headed into the aquarium, going up a long escalator into the main building&#8217;s 7th floor, where we were introduced to the Japan Forest, at the heart of the building. This started us on a slow spiral all the way down to the 4th floor, taking us through the Aleutian Islands, Monterey Bay, Gulf of Panama, Ecuadorian Rain Forest, Antarctica, Tasman Sea, Great Barrier Reef, Pacific Ocean, Seto Inland Sea, Kelp Forest, Coast of Chile, Cook Strait, and the Japan Deeps.<br />
Each portion of the trip represented one part of the Ring of Fire, of which Japan is part. (The Ring of Fire is a geological name for the ring around the Pacific Ocean, characterized by tectonic and volcanic activity.) It also is arranged in a way that is supposed to representative of the Gaia theory, which states the world is in fact a living organism from which the life we see sprouts, and returns to upon death.<br />
At the top, the aquarium is interesting, but not particularly thrilling. Monterey Bay was a bit of a laugh, having been to Monterey myself (see 18 July 1998) and having seen the Monterey Bay Aquarium (which I would quite willingly put on the same scale as the Osaka Aquarium for size and quality). As you spiral down, you&#8217;re given a deeper look into some parts, and completely exposed to others for the first time.<br />
At the core of the aquarium is the Pacific Ocean exhibit. This massive tank, sealed in by 30cm-thick acrylic walls, contains 5,400 tons of water and a huge number of aquatic species, including tuna, sun fish, manta rays, oscars, a couple kinds of sharks, especially the whale shark (a species that grows to 12m in length; this one was only about 6m).<br />
We were treated to many different views from several different levels of all the environments, before finally reaching the Japan Deeps, a small, dark tank with the largest, most creepy-looking crabs you&#8217;ve ever seen. It was like something out of &#8220;Alien&#8221;. Down an escalator, and we were at the jellyfish. We heard a lot of &#8220;kawaii&#8221; (Japanese for &#8220;how cute!&#8221;).<br />
Leaving the aquarium, we headed over to the Tempozan Marketplace for food and shopping. The latter was scarce, but the former wasn&#8217;t hard to find in good quantity. Jen inhaled not only her lunch, but half of mine (I wasn&#8217;t keen on eating all the rice) and was still hungry. Apparently, the sauce is the key.<br />
After calling a draw on a seriously insane air hockey game, featuring two paddles per player and three pucks at any given time, we decided to give the Tempozan Giant Ferris Wheel a whirl. This is apparently the world&#8217;s largest giant ferris where (as opposed to the world&#8217;s largest miniature ferris wheel, I can only suppose), and runs to a height of about 100m. The view from up there is quite something.<br />
We headed back to the JR Loop line (via subway) and hopped over to the other side of the city to check out Osaka Castle. This structure dates back to the 16th century, when it was built by Toyotomi Hideyoshi (a warlord who unified Japan) as his stronghold showpiece. After he died, his forces lost to the Tokugawa Shogunate, and it became a Shogun&#8217;s residence until the capital was moved to Edo (now Tokyo). The main building was destroyed by fire in the 17th century and left abandoned until the 20th century, when Osaka chose to rebuild the tower and reopen the castle for all to see. The existing structure is now concrete (hence not original), but the appearance is believed to be correct.<br />
The JR Loop line stops right at the castle grounds. However, it is not a short walk. It&#8217;s well over a kilometre to reach the tower itself. But it&#8217;s a walk work taking, since the view from there is quite good, and the tower itself is very beautiful (not as nice, perhaps, as Himeji Castle supposedly is, but I won&#8217;t be seeing that on this trip).<br />
We returned to the train to try some shopping. I had hoped to go to Dotombori, one of the major shopping and food districts in Osaka, but Jen&#8217;s energy level was so low (and we&#8217;d spent a lot of money over the last couple of days in various bits of non-JR transportation) that even considering going there was not really much of a consideration. Something else that will have to wait for the next time I come this way, I suppose.<br />
We ended up hitting part of Kita, a shopping area next to Osaka Station. There wasn&#8217;t much there. We thought of doing dinner, but due to a miscommunication, it wasn&#8217;t dinner that was of interest, but was just a thought. So it was back to Kyoto.<br />
We ate at Kyoto Station, partaking of gyoza (for Jen) and ramen (for myself) at one of the ramen shops on the 10th floor. (The station is big.) Following dinner, we headed back to the hotel. Jen really wanted to rest and draw. Being so early, I went back out.<br />
I walked down Kurasame St. to the Kyoto Tower, a rather unassuming edifice just north of Kyoto Station. It&#8217;s not particularly tall, but offered a decent view of downtown at night (although unlike the World Trade Center at Hamamatsucho in Tokyo, the interior lights are far too bright), and of the lights out at Kiyomizudera Shrine (which look very nice at night).<br />
I walked around the station again afterwards, taking some more pictures (but at night) before heading back to the hotel.<br />
On my way back, I popped into the Family Mart (a convenience store) to grab a snack. That&#8217;s when it hit me &#8212; I should find some milk for Jen. She&#8217;s desperately needed milk for a couple of days now, and most of the stuff we find just doesn&#8217;t cut the mustard. But at the Family Mart, I found something that apparently will do for now.<br />
The whole milk thing is just one of a few things that have not been ideal. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not complaining. Just that travelling with Jen has, at times, been a bit more of a challenge than I would have hoped for. We&#8217;ve had to cut short some things because, somehow, this 31 year-old can out pace his 15 year-old cousin. Osaka was a good example of this. I just hope that the milk we&#8217;ve found helps restore her energy so we can handle things like Nikko, Kamakura, and the various Tokyo excursions.<br />
[flickr]tag:osaka+japan+april+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+april+2004+&#8221;2&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">340</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Nishi Honganji Temple</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 23:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/01/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we experienced what can only be the most terrifying thing I&#8217;ve ever experienced. The earthquake hit around 7:30, and shook the entire room. Jen and I leapt from bed, and I dragged her into one of the doorways &#8212; supposedly the safest place to be during an earthquake. The rumbling continued for a good &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Nishi Honganji Temple"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, we experienced what can only be the most terrifying thing I&#8217;ve ever experienced. The earthquake hit around 7:30, and shook the entire room. Jen and I leapt from bed, and I dragged her into one of the doorways &#8212; supposedly the safest place to be during an earthquake. The rumbling continued for a good 30 seconds (not that I was timing, but it was certainly a long shake) before things settled down a bit. I don&#8217;t know how often Kyoto gets an earthquake, but apparently even our modest little ryokan can handle the stress.<br />
April fool! Had you going, didn&#8217;t I? No, there wasn&#8217;t an earthquake. Quite the opposite, actually. It would have taken an earthquake to get Jen out of bed.<br />
<span id="more-339"></span>Breakfast showed up at the regular time, which was still far too early for Jen. She was quite tired with the events of the last couple of days, and certainly with all the hiking we did yesterday. Add to that the prospect of fish, tofu, and non-western foods for the first meal of the day really didn&#8217;t jump start her any. Still she did her best to try and eat the things put before her.<br />
However, Jen was so tired that she practically begged to go back to sleep. I remembered (if only vaguely) what it was like to be 15, travelling abroad, and always being tired (see [[Behind the Iron Curtain: My Trip to the Soviet Union, Touring Odessa]]). So I let her go back to sleep, and took the opportunity to go wandering to yet more temples, specifically the Higashi Honganji Shrine, located about two blocks north of the JR Kyoto Station.<br />
I walked from the hotel, partly to kill time, but also so I could see what else was on the way down from the hotel. It&#8217;s a bit of a hike, and I wasn&#8217;t in any huge rush. There wasn&#8217;t much to see, outside of watching people, so I was content to speed my arrival at the temple.<br />
It&#8217;s an old temple, originally built in 1602 (it&#8217;s a split from the Nishi Honganji temple, which is about a kilometre to the west). The temple was rebuilt in 1895, during the Meiji Reformation, and those buildings are the ones we see today. Among the massive structures is the largest single wooden structure in the world, the Founder&#8217;s Hall. It&#8217;s size is hard to put into words, other than &#8220;massive&#8221;. The amount of time, effort, skill, and lives it took to build something of this size is just mind-boggling. The details are intricate, and the layout gorgeous. I just wish I could have seen a service here.<br />
Continuing south, I arrived at the JR Kyoto Station. I took a quick detour over to the Kyoto Central Post Office, partly so I could mail some postcards home, but also so I could get some more money from my bank account. I love the post office in Japan &#8212; it just makes so much sense.<br />
The JR Kyoto Station building is immense. It&#8217;s really hard to understand just how large this thing is until you&#8217;re standing in it. The main area is a concourse for passengers and some shops. A few restaurants and food stands are in a space on the second level, set towards the northern end of the main area. From the main floor all the way up to the ceiling (about 11 floors up) is open space. Huge amounts of open space. It&#8217;s enough to make an agoraphobic freak out.<br />
I snapped pictures from the south side of the main space, riding up several flights of the escalator to get the right angle. At the top, I took the Sky Walk (a bridge running under the ceiling out to the north side of the main space). I could feel my knees beginning to quake as I reached the top of the esclator (I have a mild fear of unsafe heights that I regularly try to challenge). But the Sky Walk is so strongly built that there is no real way to see how far down it is.<br />
Finally prying myself away from the architecture of the station building, I returned to awaken Jen from her slumber. Awake barely 20 minutes, I had timed my return quite well. It was time for the adventure of the day: Mt. Hiei.<br />
The northeast corner of Kyoto has been known as the &#8220;Devil&#8217;s Gate&#8221;, a fear that it would let in demons to destroy the city. The gate is guarded, however, by Enryaku-ji, a temple that at its height had over 3,000 buildings and spanned the entire mountain area. Today, it&#8217;s a little smaller, but is so important to Bhuddism in Japan (the temple area is regarded as the Mother of all Japanese Bhuddism) that it is now a UNESCO World Cultural Asset.<br />
This is what Jen and I wanted to see (although when we left this morning, we thought there was an actual &#8220;Demon Gate&#8221;, as we&#8217;d misunderstood the text in the travel guide), and set out to find it.<br />
The first step was to take a subway to the Kaisan Sanjo station, where we switched to the Kaisan Railway. Reaching the end of that line, we then switched to the Eizan Railway, and took a single-car train to Yase-Yuen, at the base of Mt. Hiei, a picturesque little area. Then it was onto a cable car, a single-car train pulled up by a cable, and finally a rope-way &#8212; what North Americans would call a cable car &#8212; to the top of the mountain.<br />
This was when we had our first bout of confusion. The ticket machine bore no English instructions, and the staff were unable to help. A sign on the wall seemed to indicate that for 1,640 yen, we could get round-trip tickets up on the cable car and ropeway. But for 1,700 yen, we&#8217;d get something else. But it was the something else I couldn&#8217;t understand. Figuring that it was something we&#8217;d probably need, we got the extra value package.<br />
The cable car departed 15 minutes later. It&#8217;s an odd vehicle, clearly for use on mountains. The grade is at least 15%, if not much more, and requires a vehicle built such that the floor is stepped, like bleachers, as it runs up the curves on the side of the mountain. The single track bulges only right at the middle of the run, when the two cars pass one another (one up, one down), strung together like the counterweights on a grandfather clock.<br />
At the top of the cable car, we switched to the ropeway, transportation I&#8217;m more familiar with. Another five minutes, and we were at the top. We were so glad we&#8217;d decided not to hike the trail.<br />
At the top, we walked around the Mt. Hiei Gardens, which we weren&#8217;t too particuarly interested in. We passed by a sign leading us to Enryaku-ji, but didn&#8217;t realize at first that was what we were looking for. (Doh.) Instead, we ended up at the north entrance to the Gardens.<br />
We figured out that our extra value package included access to the gardens. We felt it best to give it a whirl and see what we could find. Unfortunately, we were far too early in the season (Mt. Hiei can get quite cold &#8212; there&#8217;s even a (really lame) ski hill up there) for the gardens &#8212; there were only just beginning to flower.<br />
The view from the top of the mountain is amazing. You can see Kyoto (despite all the haze) and Otsu, a largish city that sits on the eastern side of Mt. Hiei, on the shores of a large lake. But otherwise, there wasn&#8217;t much up there worth looking at.<br />
Jen decided we needed to take a bus to get to what we wanted to find. When one finally showed up, we hopped on, and almost by fluke, ended up at the To-Do (or East Area) of Enryaku-ji. After paying the modest fee (assumedly to help maintain the grounds and provide for the monks who live and work there), we entered to take a look.<br />
Unlike the other shrines we&#8217;d seen over the last couple of days, To-Do was almost completely deserted of tourists. It was gloriously delightful. And a bit chilly. When we&#8217;d left downtown Kyoto, it was almost 19 degrees. It was barely 10 on the mountaintop, and with the breeze, Jen was a bit cold. I was lucky enough to have long sleeves, but it wasn&#8217;t helping much.<br />
We toured the complex, looking at the Dai Ko-Do, the Konpon Chu-Do (the Centra Main Hall, originally built in 788), and the Monju-ro. But by that time, Jen was heading towards hypothermia, and even I was a little too chilly for comfort. We decided to head home.<br />
As we were mostly on the &#8220;other side&#8221; of the mountain, we thought we&#8217;d take the cable car on that side down to the bottom, a but to the JR Otsu Station, the train back to Kyoto, and then subway back home. This proved a little more difficult when we thought more about cost (the travel portion of this day pretty much blew the bank on our regular travel patterns) and convenience. So we thought about the bus.<br />
We hiked almost a kilometre trying to figure out our travel options. The bus was the next, and almost last, choice. We were so cold and tired that we were willing to take the next bus, no matter where it went. As it stands, back up to the top of the mountain. This wasn&#8217;t so bad, as we could then use the rest of our round-trip ticket to get back down the mountain, and then take the reverse route back to our hotel.<br />
We rested only long enough to prepare for our next shot out. Again, back to Teramachi to find a sweatshirt Jen has seen last night, but hadn&#8217;t purchased at the time. When we got there, we were dismayed to find out that the store was sold out. We would spend another half-hour trying to find it at any other stores. Jen would end up settling for a t-shirt.<br />
Dinner was much needed, so we wanted towards the river area, and found a restaurant called Katsukura. It looked interesting because it looked like it had breaded pork, and because it offered something we hadn&#8217;t seen anywhere else: English menus.<br />
(Okay, yes, there is a certain appeal t having to negotiate with your server to try and get something you might like to eat. I actually find that a lot of fun. But after last night&#8217;s rather disappointing tempura, I felt it better to make sure we were going to get something good.)<br />
Katsukura&#8217;s speciality is pork, in various preparations (but usually breaded). Dinner there usually consists of pork, rice, miso soup, pickles (although we didn&#8217;t get any), and oolong tea. Simple, yet tasty. Really tasty. Really, really, really tasty. Katsukura cooks a mean pork cutlet, I have to say, and their prawns are over eight inches in length. The sauces they provide for dipping really accentuate the flavours.<br />
Wrapping up dinner, we patrolled the arcades again (third night in a row) for anything new. Jen attempted to win a prize with one of the games, but unfortunately had to give up after she ran out of coins.<br />
We returned to the hotel, deciding that we both needed to relax for the night. It&#8217;s been a long couple of days, and with all the fresh mountain air, we could use the chance to rest.<br />
Tomorrow: Osaka.<br />
[flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+april+2004+&#8221;1&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">339</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Kiyomizu Temple</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2004 23:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/31/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was up long before I&#8217;d planned to be up. I&#8217;d wanted to try and sleep a bit more to get rest for the long day of walking ahead, but my body said it was time to rise, and so it did. Besides, the racket of Kyoto on the move outside the window pretty much &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Kiyomizu Temple"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was up long before I&#8217;d planned to be up. I&#8217;d wanted to try and sleep a bit more to get rest for the long day of walking ahead, but my body said it was time to rise, and so it did.<br />
Besides, the racket of Kyoto on the move outside the window pretty much precluded any additional sleep.<br />
<span id="more-338"></span>I took a much needed shower and changed into something a little more comfortable. As Jen took her turn to use the bathroom, our breakfast showed up. Like last night (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto]]), we had a dish that we cooked at our tables (short, personal-sized platforms for our eating enjoyment). Unlike the luscious duck of last night, this morning featured three large cubes of unflavoured tofu.<br />
Oh joy.<br />
Tofu is not really one of those foods I particularly enjoy on its own. It&#8217;s bland and the texture is not particularly appealing. Fortunately, that was offset by the other foods, including sweet scrambled egg, pickles, some potatoey thing, rice, and my personal favourite, miso soup (a *good* use of tofu).<br />
Jen had some difficulties eating her breakfast. But she did a far better job than I ever did at her age.<br />
Bags in hand, we went off in search of our daily adventure. Today, it was shrines, specifically the Higashiyama area on the eastern side of Kyoto. The walk, about six or seven kilometres long, takes you to several of the most popular shrines in the city. It&#8217;s not within walking distance from the ryokan, so we had to take a subway part of the way.<br />
We got off at Gojo station on the Karasuma line (about a kilometre down from the hotel), and walked over to Higashiyama-ku, the area of the city we were going to be exploring. The walk took about 20 minutes. We walked until Gojo St. (Gojo-dori) effectively ended at what turned out to be Nishi-Otani Mausoleum, a rather interesting, albeit somewhat quiet, little place. Realizing this wasn&#8217;t the start of the walk, we exited and suddenly found ourselves in the middle of a massive graveyard.<br />
A pathway wound us through the cemetary, eventually bringing us out at the exit to the Kiyomizu Temple. This was the start of our excursion. Walking up a large flight of stairs through a massive temple gate, we found ourselves at the admissions booth (it seems all the shrines have an entrance fee, presumably to offset the costs of maintenance), and entered the complex.<br />
Kiyomizu is one of the most beloved temples in all of Japan. This is mostly due to one of the bodhisattvas(images of Bhudda) that is enshrined here. It attracts huge numbers of people, even during the middle of the week. (There are many large parking lots for bus tours, assumedly solely for the purpose of bringing people to this area.)<br />
We walked around the grounds (the entrance and exit are situated along a path that takes you through the temple grounds so you can experience most of the site), and came back out almost exactly where we&#8217;d come in from the cemetary path. From there, it was down into Teapot Lane, the main path from the central road arteries to the temple.<br />
Teapot Lane is so named for the countless stores that sell, well, teapots. And tea cups, and sake cups, and fans, and curios of almost all types. We found a replacement mug for Jen (having lost hers the day before in a taxi mishap), and a new handkerchief with Hello Kitty. I almost bought a dozen gorgeous teacup sets, each time reminding myself that I don&#8217;t have that much money to play with (although the thought was very tempting).<br />
We found a gift for Nana in one of the stores. Mike and Brenda had told us to find something very nice for Nana that she could put on her wall. It&#8217;s a Japanese fan, hand-painted, and mounted in a wooden frame with a glass cover. To make sure it was good, I fired a note off to Brenda (it was about 20:00 Calgary time) through my keitai (Japanese cell phone that also does email). About 20 minutes later, I had my response: go for it.<br />
I love modern technology. I just wish we could have phones (and services) just as good as the ones here back in Canada.<br />
We wandered down Teapot Lane until we reached the turn for the alley towards the next temple. By this point, however, we needed lunch, so continued a little further. Finding a small noodle shop that offered tempura udon, we broke for a meal, followed by a dessert of gelato and fresh cream wrapped in a soft tortilla-like cone. Very tasty, though very fattening, I&#8217;m sure.<br />
Returning to the alley, we headed off in search of the Ryozen Kannon Temple. Due to a somewhat vague map, ended up at the Yasaka Pagoda by mistake. Luckily, someone had enough foresight to put up maps to help out misguided tourists such as ourselves. The signs might be only in Japanese, but the pictures are universal.<br />
By the time we reached Maruyama Park (a wonderful public space filled full of cherry trees), I heard a lot of &#8220;are we there yet&#8221; from Jen. I could hardly blame her &#8212; even my feet were beginning to hurt a bit, but I really wanted to see the shrines. Over the next three days, we have to do the Imperial Palace (and hopefully, a couple of other shrines), Mt. Hiei, and Osaka. So I&#8217;m trying to cram in as much as possible, given the circumstances.<br />
We breezed through Maruyama Park, to find ourselves at the gates to Chion-in Temple, a rather impressive structure with huge stone steps that lead up the side of the hill. Getting up was a workout onto itself. Getting down was another challenge. Most people were taking one step at a time. Jen nearly ran down them, almost reminding me of Sen&#8217;s accidental running down of the stairs in Hiraro Miyazaki&#8217;s &#8220;Spirited Away&#8221;, only with a little more control.<br />
Jen said it was all about how you ran down. Apparently, one of her basketball tryouts at school had a competition to run down stairs as fast as you could, something Jen did particularly well. She claimed that running down was the hard part &#8212; it was the easiest time to trip. Going up stairs is easy.<br />
As if the gods had heard Jen&#8217;s little challenge themselves, she suddenly slipped jogging up a short flight of steps on our way out, slamming the top of her shin (just below the knee) into one of the stone steps. We both had a good laugh at Jen&#8217;s misfortune, mostly because of the timing.<br />
Little did we know, however, that Jen&#8217;s injury was more than a simple bruise. When we stopped briefly at Shoren-in Temple (the next temple along the walk), Jen realized that she had cut herself, and was bleeding (thankfully, not too badly). This is not unknown to Jen, who has several scars of various interesting origins all over her body. It seems that being accident-prone runs on the Tisdale side of the family.<br />
We arrived at the Heian Shrine area, much to Jen&#8217;s delight. We took a short break to watch a baseball team practice amongst themselves before we went into the shrine area. Admittledly, I&#8217;ve seen better. The shrine at Narita (see [[My Trip to Japan, Daihonzan Naritasan Shinshoji Temple]]) comes immediately to mind as a good example.<br />
Nevertheless, we (or rather, I) took pictures of the courtyard. The shrine buildings are scaled-down versions of the first Imperial Palace built in 794 AD (though the shrine was built in 1895). Although very nice-looking, aren&#8217;t particularly special. We (or rather, I encouraged Jen to join me as I) entered the shrine&#8217;s gardens for a look-see.<br />
Listed as being &#8220;outstanding&#8221;, I expected a bit from the gardens. I was less than impressed with the layout, the rear, between the shrine&#8217;s rear wall and the outer wall, was almost non-existant, and while the east side was quite nice, it was a far cry from the Hama-Rikyu Gardens I saw in Tokyo last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park]]).<br />
We headed back to the entrance to the Heian area, expecting to take the #5 bus to Kyoto Station. But due to a lack of instructions (or clarity at the bus stop), I thought it better to take the subway. Our feet were sore, but the distance short. We quickly got our tickets (accidentally leaving behind a half-finished bottle of Coke), and headed to Kyoto Station.<br />
The reason for going there was to check out a manga store (&#8220;manga&#8221; refers to serial Japanese comics and all the associated toys and cartoon shows/movies) that we thought to exist there. Turns out, however, that the manga store was in fact a shop dedicated to Tezuka Productions, the company that creates Mighty Atom (known as &#8220;Astroboy&#8221; in North America). Jen was a little disappointed in the result.<br />
We tried, instead, to hit the Yen Shop across from the station, thinking that it was a 100 Yen Shop, the Japanese equivalent of a dollar store. It wasn&#8217;t. So we thought to try a comic store also in the building. It was a library, not a store. A comic *library*? Only in Japan&#8230;<br />
We arrived back at the hotel to take a bit of a break and rest up a bit. Jen needed a shower, and I was pretty tired, myself. We lazed around the room for a while before deciding that a run back over to the Tenamachi area was in order, as was a run out to dinner.<br />
Stopping at the front desk to drop off the key, the clerk we were getting to know fairly well (he used to live in Vancouver) suggested we go to a restaurant called &#8220;Uneme&#8221;, not far from the hotel. We were hungry, but were interested in first hitting the clothing stores and comic book shops on Tenamachi Road.<br />
Comics in hand (clothing stores will have to wait), we found Uneme, right where the clerk said it would be. While not the most outrageously good food I&#8217;ve ever had, it was interesting. The meal included an appetizer of gobo (shredded carrot, beef, and a Japanese root combined with soy sauce and sugar) and fish eggs (not my favourite thing on their own), followed my grilled meats and vegetables on a skewer. Jen then had tempura, and I had sashimi.<br />
And more sake. For both of us. This is something that, admittedly, concerns me a bit. Jen&#8217;s developed a taste for this stuff. In itself, I&#8217;m not worried. Jen seems to have a great deal of control (she doesn&#8217;t like having too much), and the alcohol doesn&#8217;t have a lot of effect. Still, I wonder how badly Aunt Brenda&#8217;s going to give me heck when we get back.<br />
Back to Tenamachi. (Seeing a pattern here?) Most of the stores were closed by now, so there wasn&#8217;t much for us to do except video games. Then it was back to the hote, first stopping at the Lawson&#8217;s for snacks.<br />
But now it is time for rest. It&#8217;s been a long day&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+march+2004+&#8221;31&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">338</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2004 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiroshima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miyajima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/30/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We woke before 8:00 this morning, expecting breakfast. At least, that was the time they put on the reservation notice I got from the guest house reservation service. We didn&#8217;t eat until about 8:30, though, which was fine. Breakfast was mostly western: scrambled eggs, toast, orange juice, and the like. Nothing particularly fancy. Following breakfast, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We woke before 8:00 this morning, expecting breakfast. At least, that was the time they put on the reservation notice I got from the guest house reservation service. We didn&#8217;t eat until about 8:30, though, which was fine.<br />
Breakfast was mostly western: scrambled eggs, toast, orange juice, and the like. Nothing particularly fancy.<br />
<span id="more-337"></span>Following breakfast, Jen and I decided to do a quick hike up the mountain to the ropeway station, just to see what was up there. The walk was short, as we were most of the way up to the station from the ryokan, anyway. The ropeway (what North Americans would call a cable car) runs up to the top of Mt. Meisen, so tourists (and the faithful) can visit the shrines there.<br />
We returned to Momijiso to gather our bags and check out. We also purchased a small wad of postcards to mail back at our first opportunity. The house matron was exceedingly kind, as always, and we thanked her graciously for the stay. (Even though we did pay for it.) Her son appeared just as we were walking down the hill, and gave us a lift (and near-terrifying speeds) down to the ferry dock.<br />
But we didn&#8217;t leave right away. Even in the rain that had started overnight, Miyajima is too beautiful a place to leave so quickly. Besides, I had promised Jen a chance to run through all the stores she wanted &#8230; even if they all seemed to carry the same thing, over and over and over.<br />
We finally boarded the ferry at 12:25, quite a bit later than I had hoped for. I wanted to be in Kyoto early enough that we could get to the ryokan there and still have dinner. Fortunately, the ferry ride is short, the walk to the JR Miyajimaguichi station short, and the train ride to JR Hiroshima much shorter than the streetcar. (Although the JR train was near sauna in temperature.)<br />
Once at the station, we waited for our shinkansen to Shin-Osaka to come up on the board. However, the train I wanted wasn&#8217;t running. This posed a minor problem for connections, since we couldn&#8217;t take Nozomi trains, and the Kodamas were too awkward for getting to Kyoto. A slightly later Hikaru Rail Star soon solved the problem.<br />
Jen and I were separated on the train due to crowded seating. Not a huge deal, since we would be easily reunited once we got to Shin-Osaka, the end of that train&#8217;s run. We both snoozed a bit. At Shin-Osaka, we merely walked down the platform on the same track to board the next train, which took us to Kyoto.<br />
Once there, we found our way to the taxis (a little awkward, but not impossible). Having only a vague idea where we were going, and not speaking any Japanese, you&#8217;d think that perhaps it would be a little difficult to tell the driver where we were going, eh? Luckily, the guest house reservation service sent me the address of our new ryokan, not only in English but also in Japanese, which the driver understood completely.<br />
The drive was a little harrowing, even moreso than the drive on Miyajima. The taxi driver was all over the road, taking whatever spaces he could find to rush us through rush hour traffic. Luckily, taxis in Japan go on just distance and not also time.<br />
After what seemed an eternity, we finally arrived at our new ryokan, and we hastily exited the car. Unfortunately, a little too hasty, as Jen accidentally left behind a bag of souvenirs she&#8217;d bought in Miyajima, including a coffee mug, and a handkerchief for Nana. We don&#8217;t think she lost anything else. (We feared her wallet was in the bag, but thankfully, she had it in her pants.)<br />
The clerk who met us at the door spoke decent English, and ushered us to the tea area once I&#8217;d filled out the guest form. There, we were presented with traditional Japanese cakes (small, very sweet bite-sized cakes of what tasted like compressed sugar) and small bowls of heavy green tea. I think this might be a tradition for ryokans.<br />
We&#8217;re staying at the Hotel Matsui, which is a ryokan hotel. It&#8217;s more traditional Japanese than a regular hotel, but not like the inn-feel of Momijiso. We were shown to our room by the clerk and two small women in kimonos, who showed us a lot of things we didn&#8217;t understand. They asked us when we wanted dinner (18:00) and when we&#8217;d like breakfast (8:30).<br />
Jen immediately had a bath to wash off the sweat and grime of our day&#8217;s journey. I studied the guides for Kyoto and Osaka, trying to figure out what we needed to see over the next few days.<br />
Dinner arrived shortly after 18:00, on four separate trays (two for Jen and I to eat off of, another with rice and pickles, and a fourth with dessert and soup). We had more sushi, some different foods I can&#8217;t even begin to describe because there&#8217;s no North American equivalent, and something that was just amazing.<br />
We each got a little iron pot that sat on a little iron stand, under which looked like a little candle. This was a pot of broth in which we would cook slices of duck meat, green onions, daikon radish, and clear noodles. Once the broth was boiling, in when the ingredients. The resulting dish was absolutely delicious.<br />
After dinner, we went wandering around our area of Kyoto. This included a large covered pedestrian mall, a few side streets, and part of the Gion district, which is supposedly the old Geisha quarter (although it doesn&#8217;t look old, by any means). The streets that had cherry blossoms (which are currently in bloom) sometimes had lights that shone into the trees. We&#8217;d seen something like that not far from Momijiso, but was done with red lights, making the pink flowers glow in the darkness.<br />
We soon found ourselves quite tired (the events of the last few days were more draining than we&#8217;d like to admit) and found our way back to the hotel to get some much needed rest.<br />
Tomorrow: Kyoto and shrines!<br />
As a side note, today is the day Therese is due to give birth (see [[Flying to Montreal to visit friends]]). Due to the time difference and the fact that I doubt we&#8217;ll hear anything right away, I suspect that I&#8217;ll not know for a few days. I only hope that the birth is easy, and that their new family gets off to a good start.<br />
[flickr]tag:miyajima+march+2004+&#8221;30&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kyoto+march+2004+&#8221;30&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">337</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
