<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>taxis &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/taxis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-5</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1199</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.   Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?   So, where to start?   &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.  <br />
Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?  <br />
So, where to start?  <br />
<span id="more-1199"></span>We didn&#8217;t want to stick around the hotel any longer &#8212; the breakfasts here are so darned expensive considering the quality you get. So we opted to head off to a place Alex wanted to see: Alice&#8217;s Teacup, a teahouse up on 64th. Sadly, despite the published opening time at 8:00, the place wasn&#8217;t opening until 10:00. So we adjourned to the French restaurant we spotted along the way.  <br />
By the time we got back to the hotel, Mom was trying to check in. (Such began the longest check-in process I have ever experienced at a hotel.) We gathered together, chatted, and almost immediately put Mi Pequeña Niña to bed. It was nap time, and she was getting a little cranky. She didn&#8217;t wake up again until we stirred her until just after noon, at which point we all headed out for lunch.  <br />
My bright idea? Finding an eatery at Grand Central Terminal.  <br />
Yes, it&#8217;s the train thing. Suck it up. I haven&#8217;t seen a real train in months.  <br />
We found Michael Jordan&#8217;s (I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s related to the basketball player) where we endulged in some seriously tasty edibles. (I think MPN got the best of all of us &#8212; her macaroni and cheese was fantastic). While we were there, we were entertained by a lightshow that was going on in the main concourse, which kept MPN completely fascinated.  <br />
We strolled a bit, but ended up back at the hotel before long, about in time for MPN to crash again. Which was about the time Alex and I started planning our night out. It&#8217;s part of the reason Mom came down &#8212; to keep an eye on MPN while Alex and I tried to paint the town &#8230; well, maybe not red so much as pink.  <br />
We walked to Times Square (again) and started our task at finding a place to see a movie, which was a lot harder than it seems. There are two movie theatres in the area (Regal and AMC), and you have to figure out which movie that you want to see is at which theatre. Which was about when Alex made it clear to me that she needed to eat dinner. That led us to some diner just south of Times Square with the driest chicken I ever ate. (But, admittedly, I&#8217;ve had worse.)<br />
The movie, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was Bedtime Stories. Overall, a well done movie. And I&#8217;m still giggling at Russell Brand&#8217;s rendition of Sleep Panic Disorder. Then we hit the Virgin Megastore for more movies. I had a serious need for a movie fix.  <br />
This morning started a little different, and much more slowly than the previous mornings. We headed off to the Waldorf Astoria (the next block south) for breakfast, and then returned for MPN to have another nap. By the time she awoke, it was time for luch, which was at Au Bon Pain a couple of blocks away. We hopped a cab and about 25 minutes later we were at the Cloisters Museum, a branch of the Met up at the north end of Manhattan island.  <br />
Barely 2 minutes after arriving, Alex realised in a panic that the little backpack that she uses to carry MPN&#8217;s stuff (and her wallet) were in the bag, and the bag was still in the taxi, now departed from the Cloisters. That sent me to a phone to cancel the credit card, and list a missing bag with the Taxi and Limosine Commission. That said, I was also told that it&#8217;ll be a cold day in hell before we get this stuff back, due to the way that the taxis run in this city. Which, I have to admit, is a little odd.  <br />
The Cloisters, for the record, is one of New York City&#8217;s unspoken gems. It&#8217;s out of the way, admittedly, which is why, but it is gorgeous. It was like the churches I saw in England, Scotland, and Ireland (although most of it came from France). Absolutely wonderful! I can see why Mark has said that he wants to hold his wedding there. (Well, when he gets around to getting married, that is.)  <br />
The driver of the hired car we took on the way back really didn&#8217;t listen to me and ended up taking us through Times Square. The hard way. (Believe me, there are easier ways.) He apologised for the mistake, and didn&#8217;t charge us what he should have charged us if he&#8217;d had a meter running.  <br />
Dinner was at a place called Bobby Van&#8217;s, a steakhouse on 54th between Lexington and Park Ave. We were perhaps a bit underdressed, but the meal was fantastic. I&#8217;m going to have such a steak hangover in the morning. And I&#8217;m going to revel in it as much as possible.  <br />
But until then, I&#8217;m exhausted, and looking forward to going home. (That&#8217;s Costa Rica, in case you&#8217;re not sure.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#039;s Mañana Time!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-manana-time</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1008</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s Mañana Time!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of shape only makes things go more slowly. (And no, totally slacking off doesn&#8217;t cause the reverse.)<br />
For us up-tight North Americans, this is the single hardest thing to contend with. Uncertainty is the name of our game, so unknown things aren&#8217;t a problem. It&#8217;s the ability to do simple little things.<br />
Like call each other. Hard to do when you have no phone.<br />
<span id="more-1008"></span>For those of you old enough to remember, it&#8217;s like when you were in high school, and couldn&#8217;t use the phone to call your friends (your sister/brother/parents were hogging it or you were grounded) and had to wait until <em>the following day</em> to talk about anything. Oh, the days of yore!<br />
When &#8212; like us &#8212; you&#8217;ve become accustomed to always-on internet access and cellular phones, it&#8217;s really hard to go back to having nothing. Literally nothing. Jason and I have to &#8220;borrow&#8221; internet from unsecured sites around our respective complexes; Mark is left high and dry. Planning requires an intricate set of where we&#8217;re going and when, and plans in the event we don&#8217;t exactly meet up as planned.<br />
(It also doesn&#8217;t help that we&#8217;re wholly reliant on taxis for now &#8212; we haven&#8217;t been able to figure out the bus system &#8212; which are notoriously unreliable for being available in all places, or being anywhere near punctual. It&#8217;s especially bad if you&#8217;re out late, such as we were Monday night when we tried to catch a taxi after going to the grocery store. It was almost an hour before we could find one.)<br />
At the office, we were struggling to get anything to work, stealing internet from an adjacent office (given, we were told the password). With Lee here, we had carte blanche to purchase a wireless router (yes, Clay, it&#8217;s a D-Link) and a printer. The router allows us to use an existing connection (which only started working properly this morning), and the printer is WiFi-enabled so we can put it wherever it makes sense to put it.<br />
And the speed at which it takes to get them done. We&#8217;re used to &#8220;right away&#8221;. Here, it&#8217;s &#8220;mañana&#8221;, which requires a lot of grains of salt. There&#8217;s just so many things that we would like to have happen now, so we don&#8217;t have to worry about them for long periods of time. But no, it don&#8217;t work that way.<br />
Take Mark, for example. He&#8217;s been in his condo since Monday afternoon. He still doesn&#8217;t have air conditioning installed (despite being told it would be done the day he moved in) and his dryer doesn&#8217;t work yet. It&#8217;s happening, just really slowly.<br />
It&#8217;s not uncommon for someone&#8217;s email system to fill because there just isn&#8217;t a rush to empty it.<br />
Collectively, we&#8217;ve got a whack of things we need done, and we&#8217;ve no idea how fast/easy these will happen. And believe me, this is causing us concern. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>How do we open a bank account? It&#8217;s not as easy as walking into a bank with a few bucks in your hand.</li>
<li>How do we purchase a car? Apparently, it&#8217;s like buying a house in North America, complete with lawyers.</li>
<li>How do we get a driver&#8217;s license? And get one of those fancy &#8220;medical&#8221; certificates?</li>
<li>How do we get the insurance? And handle the annual mechanical inspection?</li>
<li>How do we get cell phones? More importantly, how do we get the number for any phone? Unless you&#8217;re a permanent resident, you can&#8217;t get a number (although you can get the phone).</li>
<li>What health care will we get?</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there&#8217;s the visa process. This is really an entirely separate topic, which I&#8217;m not sure I can really do justice. The whole process is a living nightmare, which Jason and Jen have been trying to wrangle to the ground. Sadly, the consulate keeps giving us new information which amounts to &#8220;oh, by the way, you need to do this too, which I realise totally throws off everything you were already doing&#8221;. More on that later, though.<br />
So this is live in Costa Rica. No, I&#8217;m not complaining. I&#8217;m not changing my mind. But a lot of people wanted to know how it&#8217;s going. Now you know.<br />
Which begs the question: If knowing is half the battle, what the heck is the other half?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shifty Taxis in Beijing</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/shifty-taxis-in-beijing/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=shifty-taxis-in-beijing</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/shifty-taxis-in-beijing/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 15:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/01/shifty-taxis-in-beijing/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[So Amy and I decided to take a taxi back from the Summer Palace to our hotel. Partly because the walk around the Palace grounds (which are huge) wore us out, and partly because we couldn&#8217;t figure out how to get back to the subway station we&#8217;d taken the taxi from in the first place. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/shifty-taxis-in-beijing/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Shifty Taxis in Beijing"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So Amy and I decided to take a taxi back from the Summer Palace to our hotel. Partly because the walk around the Palace grounds (which are huge) wore us out, and partly because we couldn&#8217;t figure out how to get back to the subway station we&#8217;d taken the taxi from in the first place.<br />
A warning, which will likely be universally understood by many travellers, some taxi drivers in Beijing are con artists. Well, more like would-be con artists, as to be a proper artist, you have to be accepted for your ability. The a-hole who decided to dupe us really didn&#8217;t come off that way.<br />
<span id="more-558"></span>As we&#8217;d exited the Summer Palace, this guy ran up to us with a card, said &#8220;meter!&#8221; (usually a good thing) and offered us his car. The card said &#8220;1.20&#8221;, which is supposed to be the rate per kilometre. At first, all was well. But by the time we hit the highway, I happened to notice that the fare was already 36 yuan, rather than a much lower (expected) rate. This set off my bullshit alarm, and I started to watch the meter earnestly, commenting to Amy that we were getting hosed.<br />
When we got to the hotel, the fare was 95 yuan for what shouldn&#8217;t have been more than about 60. We knew that by rough calculation. The driver tried to drop us off across the street from the hotel, but we directed him in (though he did try to avoid it). I guess he knew the jig was up when Amy called over one of the attendants who spoke English. (One advantage of a very nice hotel &#8212; staff who speak English quite well.) The driver offered 70. Given that he did get us there quickly, we agreed.<br />
How do you tell if you&#8217;re about to be ripped off? Glance at the meter. It should be in clear view. There will likely be three numbers: the rate (1.20, 1.60, or 1.80), the kilometres driven (which we think was also rigged, so check with your guides), and the time spent waiting (this doesn&#8217;t seem to affect the fare much). Watch the rate &#8212; ours changed from 1.20 to 1.80 pretty much whenever the driver pushed down on the accelerator.<br />
How to avoid? Peg the fare in advance before you leave, and write it down. Or use a taxi from a good hotel &#8212; they might cost a bit more, but they won&#8217;t pull silly buggers (as my dad used to say) with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/shifty-taxis-in-beijing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">558</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
