<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>christmas &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/christmas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 06:08:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Rudolph the red-nosed, genetically-altered, reindeer subspecies</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 06:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3518</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know the song. We&#8217;ve all seen the 1964 Rankin-Bass television special. In our Western culture, we have a story of an underdog, recognized one foggy Christmas Eve for a trait that only he possessed, which saved Christmas as we know it. And thus Rudy the Red-Beaked Reindeer went down in history. But we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Rudolph the red-nosed, genetically-altered, reindeer subspecies"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know the song. We&#8217;ve all seen the 1964 Rankin-Bass television special. In our Western culture, we have a story of an underdog, recognized one foggy Christmas Eve for a trait that only he possessed, which saved Christmas as we know it. And thus <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPCvyJod0WM" target="_blank">Rudy the Red-Beaked Reindeer</a> went down in history.<br />
But we live in an enlightened age. We like to know why things happened, not just how. And if you listen to that story &#8212; even if you take the Bumble and such into account &#8212; there&#8217;s just too darned much that we&#8217;ve missed. Where&#8217;s the reality check, huh? Oh, you&#8217;re going to throw that Santa thing at me? Sure, okay, now you&#8217;re just being dismissive. We have to face facts, folks. There&#8217;s more to this song. Way more.<br />
Rudolph wasn&#8217;t a hero. He was a convenient freak of nature.<br />
<span id="more-3518"></span><br />
Life on Earth is replete with bizarre creations that regularly defy explanation: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platypus" target="_blank">platypus</a>, the <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/mantis_shrimp" target="_blank">mantis shrimp</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aye-aye">aye-aye</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/09/absurd-creature-of-the-week-naked-mole-rat/">naked mole rat</a>, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VGBs-8qlGzM">blob fish</a>, the <a href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/64804/10-intense-facts-about-giant-weta">giant weta</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/10/absurd-creature-goblin-shark/" target="_blank">goblin shark</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/03/absurd-creature-week-water-bear/" target="_blank">tardigrade</a>, and Donald Trump&#8217;s hair, to name but a few. Despite all of these strange things that don&#8217;t really seem to possible, they&#8217;re all a result of evolution: small changes over eons that have brought about the forms we see today. (Well, except maybe Trump&#8217;s hair. The science on that thing makes quantum entanglement look easy.)<br />
And, honestly, reindeer kind of fall into that category, too. Lest we think they&#8217;re just smaller versions of moose, reindeer (specifically <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mountain_reindeer">Rangifer tarandus tarandus</a></em>, though it could be readily argued that Santa&#8217;s &#8220;tiny&#8221; reindeer were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peary_caribou"><em>R. t. pearyi</em></a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Svalbard_reindeer"><em>R. t. platyrhynchus</em></a>) have some rather interesting biological traits of their own. For example, because they live in low-light conditions for a good portion of the year, <a href="http://kids.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/frym.2015.00018" target="_blank">reindeer can see in the ultraviolet</a>. The ability to fly is an admittedly undocumented trait at this point, but then reindeer aren&#8217;t as closely studied as, say, pandas (and we&#8217;re pretty sure they don&#8217;t fly).<br />
So let&#8217;s look at a specific individual. Yes, the one that the song claims was the most famous of all (yet starts by asking if you remember him; honestly, that&#8217;s like asking if you&#8217;ve ever heard of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amitabh_Bachchan">Amitabh Bachchan</a>). Now we can assume that, protuberances aside, Rudolph was a fairly ordinary reindeer. After all, there&#8217;s no mention of any other part of his anatomy, or any psychological ticks that developed by being socially outcast by an unsympathetic and uncaring herd (and if you believe the TV special, Santa to boot).<br />
No, Rudolph was famous for having a glowing nose, and apparently nothing else. (The ability to fly is moderately debatable, as historic records don&#8217;t outright say that the reindeer flew, only that they drove &#8220;To the top of the porch! to the top of the wall!&#8221;. Though there is a note that they &#8220;flew like the down of a thistle&#8221;, it&#8217;s worth noting that such flight is at the discretion of the wind. But I digress&#8230;) So let&#8217;s focus on Rudy&#8217;s shnozz.<br />
Reindeer have, by nature, <a href="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/02430/reindeer-1_2430746b.jpg">a large, wet nose covered with soft hairs</a>. There&#8217;s nothing on there that looks particularly <a href="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-496823.html">like a light bulb</a>. Which, really, is okay, since bioluminescence doesn&#8217;t use incandescence or plasma-based fluorescence in the way we light our homes. In nature, this is usually a result of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bioluminescence">a chemical reaction in a living organism that gives of a burst of light</a>. The kicker here is that most of that colour tends to come in the blue-green spectrum, which is a far cry from red (there are a few fish that produce red light, but last I checked, reindeer weren&#8217;t aquatic &#8230; though I am told that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W-oFqCVNnbM">they&#8217;re better than people</a>).<br />
That doesn&#8217;t rule out a red nose, however. Like I said, reindeer noses are big &#8212; the full width of their snout, easily the size of a human fist, even in the smallest of reindeer subspecies. So what? Well, those noses are full of blood vessels. Ever shine a light through your hand? You bet: it&#8217;ll turn red. Now, would it be the colour of holly, as suggested by <a href="http://kids.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/frym.2015.00018#ref10">Barbara Hazen</a>? That might be a tough one, but perhaps if Rudolph were active, which would increase blood flow, it could happen? I think a bigger question is: was Rudolph capable of producing this light on his own, or did he have an unfortunate infection of bioluminescent bacteria? (It might be possible to dismiss the latter, as that appears to be a largely marine-based scenario.)<br />
It likely means it was the result of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luciferase" target="_blank">luciferase</a> reaction (I love that name), which is not naturally found in mammalian cells. So amongst an <a href="http://www.daclarke.org/Humour/santa.html" target="_blank">unknown subspecies of extremely fast-moving reindeer</a>, we have a further subspecies with bioluminescence.<br />
Wait.<br />
Is it just me, or does this sound like &#8220;Santa&#8221; is pulling an <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Island_of_Doctor_Moreau" target="_blank">Island of Doctor Moreau</a></em>, here? Maybe his herd of reindeer weren&#8217;t just looking down on Rudolph, but were miffed that he was Santa&#8217;s new favourite? Hey, it&#8217;s entirely possible that the Association of Flying Reindeers, Local 25 pressured Rankin-Bass to make Santa look bad (it&#8217;s not like he can fire them or something &#8212; really, what&#8217;s Santa gonna do without his reindeer, anyway?)<br />
Okay, back to the honker. Rudolph supposedly had a nose bright enough to cut through even the thickest fog. Well, therein lies the real question: was it as bright as a lightbulb? The brightest known bioluminescent organism is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pyrophorus_noctilucus"><em>Pyrophorus noctilucus</em></a> (appropriately named the Headlight Elater), which produces roughly 1.5 times the brightness of a heavily overcast day. That thing is a mere 30 mm in size, and the glowing part is only a portion of that. So if you throw that much brightness into something about 0.05 sq metres &#8230; well, it would certainly be more than enough to light up a room. But a sky? The direction in which your heading? And would be it be focused light a headlight, or radiate in all directions?<br />
It&#8217;s considered &#8220;foggy&#8221; when visibility is limited to 1,000 metres, which is quite a distance. Presumably, the fog of &#8220;that&#8221; Christmas (it&#8217;s unstated, and I frankly don&#8217;t feel like diving through historical weather records) was much, much worse. But we&#8217;ll give them the benefit of the doubt (hey, Santa&#8217;s old, how well can the old fart see?), and say that it&#8217;s a couple dozen metres.<br />
I&#8217;ve driven in fog that thick. I was lucky to break 80 km/h (it was a 100 km/h highway) for fear of driving off the road. My headlights were more of a burden than a benefit, making the fog glow rather than showing me where I was going. Mind you, that was white-yellow light, which doesn&#8217;t penetrate as well as <em>red</em> light. And, in theory, you&#8217;d see better.<br />
Except that <em>they&#8217;re flying</em>. And to make it around the world, <em>they&#8217;re flying really, really, really fast</em>. Honestly, the only reason airplanes have lights is because there&#8217;s a heap of rules that say they have to have them for visual contact with other planes. Otherwise, they&#8217;re useless. So what possible use could Rudy&#8217;s nose be once they&#8217;re airborne?<br />
Simple: The nose was a ruse. It was obvious, so people picked on it. But that wasn&#8217;t what made Rudolph truly special. It was the fact that Rudolph had a strong magnetoreception. This isn&#8217;t fiction, folks, <a href="http://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev.ph.46.030184.003101?journalCode=physiol">this stuff&#8217;s been studied for over 30 years</a>! This is how birds migrate. Even large mammals like roe deer can sense differences in field strength, and that&#8217;s a cousin genus to reindeer. So maybe Dr. Santa Moreau went a few steps further, and mixed the gene pool a bit to increase his herd&#8217;s capabilities. Hey, stir the pot enough, and it&#8217;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cousin_marriage#Genetics" target="_blank">possible to get a few biological oddities</a>&#8230;<br />
There&#8217;s also the minor issue of communication. Let&#8217;s assume, for the moment, that the reindeer and Santa are capable of surviving a trip of speeds over 1000 kilometres <em>per second</em> (that&#8217;s escape velocity from the Milky Way galaxy, in case you were wondering; the New Horizons probe moves at a comparatively pokey 16.26 km/s) &#8212; maybe there&#8217;s a previously unknown bow shock effect that protects them and somehow doesn&#8217;t annihilate anything nearby &#8230; like houses &#8212; how the hell does Santa tell Rudolph + Co. where to go, or how do the reindeer tell Santa that they&#8217;ve arrived?<br />
And, for that matter, how did Dr. Santa ever graft the right genes to make reindeer talk? And suddenly, I think we&#8217;re onto something.<br />
The milk and cookies. It&#8217;s not a &#8220;thank you&#8221; to the man in red who comes bounding down your chimney. It&#8217;s a <em>sacrificial offering</em>, people! We&#8217;ve been keeping him away for centuries. I&#8217;ll bet he&#8217;s lactose and gluten intolerant. People who miss that point? Santa went all Dr. Moreau on them, and made them into his reindeer.<br />
So if you happen to hear hooves pounce all over your rooftops tomorrow night, set a big, roaring fire, and lock your doors. You&#8217;d better watch out, you&#8217;d better not make a sound, you&#8217;d better cock your guns &#8212; I&#8217;m telling you why! &#8212; Santa Moreau is coming to town!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3518</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nest: Excellence in Product Design and Customer Service</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/the-nest-excellence-in-product-design-and-customer-service/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-nest-excellence-in-product-design-and-customer-service</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/the-nest-excellence-in-product-design-and-customer-service/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 06:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3201</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve turned into my dad. Really. I&#8217;ve got to be the hardest person on the planet to buy for. My poor wife pestered me for weeks to expand on my Christmas list (she pre-populated it with: &#8220;If you don&#8217;t add anything, you get a vasectomy!&#8221;), and I amounted to two things: sweatpants, and a new &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/the-nest-excellence-in-product-design-and-customer-service/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Nest: Excellence in Product Design and Customer Service"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve turned into my dad. Really. I&#8217;ve got to be the hardest person on the planet to buy for. My poor wife pestered me for weeks to expand on my Christmas list (she pre-populated it with: &#8220;If you don&#8217;t add anything, you get a vasectomy!&#8221;), and I amounted to two things: sweatpants, and a new silicone scraper for the kitchen.<br />
So leave it to my sister to &#8212; yet again &#8212; pull off a miracle. She has a knack for this. I don&#8217;t know where she&#8217;s acquired this skill, but she&#8217;s got it down and I&#8217;m fairly envious of it. (I struggle every year to return the favour. I suck at it.) Last year it was the most comfy sweatshirt I&#8217;ve ever owned. This year? She delivered to me one of the most whiz-bang things I think I&#8217;ve ever been given:<br />
A thermostat.<br />
<span id="more-3201"></span>Not just <em>any</em> thermostat. Oh no, this is not your run-of-the-mill doohickey. This is a <a href="http://www.nest.com/">Nest</a>.<br />
If ye not seen a Nest before, you need really only understand this: it was (originally) designed by the same guy who helped design the iPod product line, and was an Apple BigWig for a few years. If you&#8217;ve owned an iPod, or even seen an iPod, you have an idea of how much the iPod (and its kin) have changed user experience.<br />
That&#8217;s what the Nest is doing for home heating. It&#8217;s a learning thermostat, and in about 7-10 days, it&#8217;ll figure out how we like to have our house heated, and we should (hopefully) start to have a better home heating experience. Either that, or this is really just the first step of SkyNet, and it&#8217;s going to boil us to death in the middle of the night&#8230;<br />
Anyway, the experience starts with installing the thing. This is usually where most people freeze up &#8212; this is electrical and could potentially turn your house into either an oven or an icebox, if you&#8217;re not careful.<br />
The thermostat itself (a little less than the diameter of a softball) is accompanied by a simple booklet, a wiring/seating plate, optional decorative (aka &#8220;hide the crap the old thermostat left behind&#8221;) plate, a rather nice multibit screwdriver, and self-tapping drywall screws &#8212; no anchors needed.<br />
Mounting the plate was a snap. Did I mention that there&#8217;s a built-in bubble level in the bae plate to make sure your Nest is absolutely straight-line level? Brilliant move, that. Wiring? <a href="http://nest.com/works">There&#8217;s an app for that.</a> (Sorta.) It not only ensures that you <em>can</em> use a Nest, but also how the wires should translate from your current thermostat to the Nest.<br />
Installation time? Less than 10 minutes.<br />
Then the little unit booted, in a suitably cute way. Once it was up and running, it prompted me to connect to the internet. No, I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; it&#8217;s got a WiFi connection, so I can control the heat in my home from my iPhone. No, I&#8217;m not joking. I&#8217;m actually <em>giddy</em> about this. Then it asked me a few more questions, and then &#8212; without any prompting &#8212; updated its own software.<br />
And that&#8217;s when I got the first error. E24. There&#8217;s a <a href="http://nest.com/e24">full explanation of that error on their website</a>, too. Now this is where I was really awed. There was the typically cryptic error message that usually drives people bonkers. Someone had the foresight to have the actual thermostat tell me to go to the URL and use the guide.<br />
Again: THE THERMOSTAT HELPED ME INSTALL ITSELF.<br />
I went through the steps &#8230; and didn&#8217;t really get anywhere. The website told me to call Nest. This is usually where I cringe, as I&#8217;m about to talk to low-paid, likely distant people who are utterly disconnected from the company in question, and read from scripts. Every time I get one, I want to hang up. I can&#8217;t handle them anymore.<br />
This person &#8212; and I deeply regret that I no longer remember her name &#8212; was (reasonably) cheerful, and immediately started by asking me for my email address. My email address is the <em>unique identifier used to configure my account, and the Nest unit</em>. Not some idiotic number, or even my name (which is equally pointless), and helped her identify not only the unit (which operates over Wi-Fi, so she could see the unit&#8217;s data, too), but also how to communicate with me later.<br />
And so we started trying to figure out what was going on. Turns out our renovations introduced some rather strange behaviours that the Nest doesn&#8217;t much like. We have R (the power line), G (the fan line), Y (the cooling line), and W (the heating line), which run down to the blower in the basement, which divvies up the lines and figures out what needs to be done &#8212; including telling the boiler to start pumping hot water. In principle, these are mapped 1:1 (though the R became Rh, Y became Y1, and W became W1) on the Nest.<br />
Y turned out to be pointless, since we have no cooling unit to begin with (it rarely ever gets hot enough here to worry about). Rh was moved to Rc (dunno what the difference is). We slowly made progress. The unit started reporting better electrical states (apparently it disliked having a dead Y, which I can now only assume was part of the issue), and the boiler could start and the heat would flow.<br />
Only the blower&#8217;s fan would never turn off.<br />
Eventually, it was determined that we have a &#8220;variable speed&#8221; fan (on, off, and low, instead of just the on/off), which the Nest doesn&#8217;t much like. In other words, technically incompatible.<br />
To get to this point was 1:04. That&#8217;s ONE HOUR and FOUR MINUTES, by the way. I was on hold for about 10 minutes of that; the rest was us discussing what was happening, and trying different things. At no time did the tech show ANY signs of frustration. Not. Once.<br />
I&#8217;m impressed by this &#8212; <em>extremely so</em>. For those of you who&#8217;ve not read this blog extensively (lucky you!), I used to do tech support. I know the types who call in for help. I know the burdens that are placed on you. Nest Labs, you have a <b>fantastic technical support team, if the tech I talked to is representative of the lot. </b><br />
So first we have a simple device. It has no visible buttons, just a dial that spins infinitely in either direction; to select an option, you merely press the front. It has more options than my damn microwave, and is much simpler to operate.<br />
Next, we have a company that recognizes that just because you have a simple device, you might not have a simple situation. HVAC systems are notoriously complex, especially when, like me, you&#8217;ve got some oddities out there. So provide smart, patient people who guide people though the (periodically complex) steps of setting the unit up.<br />
Incidentally, I did get it working. The last instruction had been &#8220;remove the G wire, and plug it into Y1&#8221;. I&#8217;d gotten as far as &#8220;remove the G wire&#8221; and gone no further. That&#8217;s when the tech and I decided that I needed to do some more research on our blower and figure out how to disable the multi-speed option.<br />
But, y&#8217;know, I just <em>had</em> to go back and try putting the G in the Y1. <em><br />
</em><br />
Boom.<br />
It&#8217;s not exactly what we had before. Our old (dumb) thermostat somehow managed to turn the blower fan off completely when the heat wasn&#8217;t on. The Nest, for whatever reason, can&#8217;t. So when the heat&#8217;s off, the blower fan goes to a low setting, barely moving air through the house (I&#8217;m convinced it&#8217;s actually running slower than the old thermostat could on just the &#8220;fan&#8221; setting). Which, really, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ll mind.<br />
Now I just need to stop staring at the thermostat data. It&#8217;s hypnotic&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/the-nest-excellence-in-product-design-and-customer-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3201</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Blitzkrieg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-blitzkrieg</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3199</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas Blitzkrieg"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of sleep than from trying to do too much.<br />
Heck, it even makes me feel a bit young! Ish. Sort of.<br />
Except for the prolonged yawning, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-3199"></span>Tuesday evening, I went on a mission to find &#8220;Santa&#8221; presents for Monkey and Choo Choo, for a party Evans Hunt was holding for all the company&#8217;s children. I failed miserably for them (Alex would later prove to be a much better Santa in this regard), though it wasn&#8217;t a total wash for Christmas as a whole.<br />
Wednesday night was wrapping, notably a batch of presents from my sister that came in sans trimmings and trappings. My folding skills got a dusting off.<br />
Thursday was the Evans Hunt End of the World / Last Pitch party, our annual fest with clients and spouses. I honestly feel like I leave these parties too early, and I miss out on the good stories. I got the backfill the following day, and was moderately relieved to have missed some of the trouble.<br />
Friday was something slightly different, but very exciting (for me). Along with Tamara, Adrian, and Barb, I went to go see <em>The Hobbit: An Expected Journey</em>. It had been 11 years (I&#8217;d thought it only 10 at the time, but I just double-checked) since Tamara, Adrian, myself, and a couple of others had sat and waited for hours in the hallways at the Famous Players Chinook theatre (now Scotiabank Cineplex) to wait for the opening night of <em>The Lord of the Rings: Fellowship of the Ring</em>. A lot has happened in those years since&#8230;<br />
Eleven years later, I still love movies like that: long, and epic.<br />
I passed out nearly as soon as I got home, mostly due to exhaustion. (I&#8217;d also been running around before getting to the theatre, trying to find a Car2Go that I could actually get into &#8212; their system has been having issues for a couple of weeks, now.)<br />
Saturday morning was a blur of surreptitious present wrapping for the afternoon&#8217;s Santa visit, helping/forcing the kids to clean up the basement, making breakfast, and something else that I now forget. Then it was a blur of lunch-making, dressing (notably the kids in their nice dresses), and then loading into the car for the trip down to Evans Hunt for the party.<br />
This was the first office party for kids that I&#8217;ve ever attended, at any company. For reasons I&#8217;m sure someone much smarter than me could explain, Evans Hunt employees have a statistically high number of kids under the age of 10, and I&#8217;m willing to bet at least half are two or younger. At any rate, the fact that all of these kids existed was what led to the scheduling of the party, which we parents were quite happy for.<br />
The sixth floor &#8212; the new part of the office &#8212; was chosen for the venue. The large boardroom was co-opted for gingerbread man decorating and crafts, the main space for what ended up being punch-clown tackling, with a large comfy chair set aside for the Big Man.<br />
The kids rapidly multiplied, until the point where I think there may have been almost more kids than adults &#8230; though there have been more adults acting like kids after a while.<br />
When Santa arrived (Santa was a friend of a friend who does this professionally), the kids went crazy &#8230; and Choo Choo almost never left his side, utterly desperate for, well, not so much a present as just talking to him. Quite the reverse of Monkey, who was terrified of Santa for the first three and a half years of life.<br />
Monkey, interestingly, was the first one called up. She happily hopped up on his lap, talked a bit, got her present, and got down (with a hurried &#8220;thank you&#8221;) before going off to find out what the present was. (For the record, &#8220;Santa&#8221; was brilliant at finding things the kids seem to love.)<br />
Poor Choo Choo then had to endure most of the other kids coming next, one after another. She sat, enthralled, desperately eager to get on his lap. I managed to drag her away after a little while to drink more of her juice, when suddenly Santa produced the present. Choo Choo was off my lap in the blink of an eye, and raced over to Santa as fast as she could. She happily jumped up, and promptly asked for a &#8220;plane&#8221;.<br />
I have no idea where this &#8220;plane&#8221; thing was coming from. It&#8217;s now what she wants for Christmas. She was moderately disappointed at the <em>Stella and Sam</em> book she got instead.<br />
Party over, we headed home so Alex and I could shower and change for the next event of the day, her office Christmas party. Grandma appeared shortly after 5:00, which was about the time I dropped dinner on the table for them, mostly so they could eat and not bother Alex and I long enough that we could get ready for going out.<br />
We were gone just before 6:00, stopped at the hospital for Alex to get the tickets, and at the Ceili&#8217;s at Southland before 6:20. We sat at a table with Sarah, one of Alex&#8217;s regular co-workers, and Casey, who was one of the co-workers until she left to work at the new South hospital. It was the best move, since it was a good chance for us to chat with people we already knew.<br />
We left by 9:00.<br />
But lest ye think we were done &#8230; think again. Our destination? Toys &#8216;R Us. And not one, but two of them &#8212; one less than five minutes from the restaurant, and the other way up in the north. We didn&#8217;t get home until nearly 11:45. I got to bed a half-hour later after taking Grandma home.<br />
Sunday. Today. Yet more stuff.<br />
Mostly me doing my Christmas shopping, notably picking up things for Alex, and picking up the Playmobile toys for the girls that Grandma and I had found on Friday.<br />
And then we went to Zoo Lights.<br />
We&#8217;ve done this many times before, but this year we opted to try something a little differently. We opted to try going by C-Train, now that the new West LRT is open, and happens to run from here out to the Zoo. It seemed like a good idea, and we were &#8212; at least initially &#8212; excited to try out the new route.<br />
For the record, the trip is a minimum of 35 minutes (45 if you happen to <em>just</em> miss the train, which we did on the outbound). And although it was only -3, it somehow felt quite a bit colder, which we all seemed to notice. Thankfully the kids were well-bundled, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad for them.<br />
We got home at 9:00, well after some people&#8217;s bedtimes.<br />
Like mine. Or at least, that&#8217;s what it feels like. &#8216;Cuz after all this, I feel really tired.<br />
Sleep. Need sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Merry Christmas, 2011</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/12/merry-christmas-2011/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=merry-christmas-2011</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/12/merry-christmas-2011/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 06:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2973</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a long silence, I know. This has been a tough year for the Sowrey family. Between kids growing up, new jobs, and pressures from all angles, finding the time to write is a challenge unlike any I&#8217;ve experienced. And frankly, it becomes a lot lower on my priorities, despite how much I miss &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/12/merry-christmas-2011/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Merry Christmas, 2011"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long silence, I know. This has been a tough year for the Sowrey family. Between kids growing up, new jobs, and pressures from all angles, finding the time to write is a challenge unlike any I&#8217;ve experienced. And frankly, it becomes a lot lower on my priorities, despite how much I miss it.<br />
That brings me to today, Christmas Day 2011. Today is another long, hard day in a long line of long, hard days. But not a bad day &#8212; certainly not bad. Just long, and by the end of it my head is spinning and I long for a day where I don&#8217;t have to do anything &#8230; despite knowing full well that were I actually to get such a day, I&#8217;d be bored outta my tree.<br />
Such is the life of the working parent, I suppose&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2973"></span>The last couple of months have been filled in a near-insane level of activity, and almost no break whatsoever. Even when my most recent project delivered and my company closed down for the holidays, the gear just shifted into &#8220;Christmas preparation&#8221;. This went until last night, at about 11:45, when the last present had been stashed under the tree, and I could sit down and relax for a few moments before Alex got home from work (she doesn&#8217;t get off work until 23:30, and not home until midnight).<br />
Barely six hours of sleep &#8230; and the mayhem began.<br />
Today is the first Christmas where Monkey will remember the details, where she was excited about Santa Claus, where she knew exactly what she wanted, and we&#8217;d be in some serious trouble if the present didn&#8217;t come. (For the record, a Dora the Explorer singing guitar.) It was the first Christmas where we had to fend off children from running right to the Christmas tree. It was the first Christmas where I understood why my parents wanted to eat breakfast before a single present was unwrapped.<br />
I think back to those earliest Christmases I can remember, and they are nothing but joyful. Oddly enough, I don&#8217;t remember fights with my sister, though I&#8217;m certain they happened. I remember wonderful things wrapped in colourful paper, hours spent in our basement (the tree was kept far from view while I was young), playing with new toys for hours more. I remember the trips to Mrs. Sinnott&#8217;s apartment for lunch, and afterwards the entire troupe would end up at our house for a massive, and very loud, dinner.  Those years are long since past, never to return. I miss them greatly, but the memories haven&#8217;t faded.<br />
It&#8217;s been 10 years since our last Christmas with dad. That, too, was a very happy Christmas. Although smaller, it was the day my brother-in-law formally proposed to my sister. There wasn&#8217;t a dry eye in the room &#8230; partly because Craig was stringing Cathy along with some rather inventively-labelled gifts. It was a tremendous meal, too. And it was as loud as any dinner I could remember previous.<br />
Ten years later, I&#8217;m starting those same memories with my kids. While I suspect we&#8217;ll not have the same insanity around the dinner table that followed each and every Christmas at Gatestone Avenue, Alex and I have strived to make some traditions we hope to keep going. (Whether or not they get more boisterous remains to be seen.)<br />
Today, while still in the midst of presents, we Skyped with some of the family back east &#8212; technical difficulties prevented full communication, along with small kids eating up parental patience and stamina on both ends. Tempers flared, tears rolled, and a few things were thrown. Mom then reminded me that Cathy and I had done precisely the same thing when we were kids (even I don&#8217;t remember it), and her recommendation was a deep breath and naps for everyone.<br />
Two napped. The ones who needed them most (the extremely tired and the last-shift worker), did not.<br />
Brunch was late in the morning, waiting for Grandma to arrive. Moulded pancakes with fruit salad and maple bacon. A decent meal, if a bit of a struggle (pancake moulds and I have a tepid relationship). Though significantly better than my dinner meal, which was a slow-cooked orange-cranberry turkey breast. The Sahara might be considered more moist. Alex was luckily spared, as she had to work.<br />
That&#8217;s been the strangest part of this Christmas, not having Alex around all the time. She&#8217;s usually out of the house between 15:00 and 23:50 on the days she works, including Christmas Eve and Christmas Day, two of the hardest days of the year to not be at home. It&#8217;s been hard on everyone, but I feel particularly bad for Alex, having to miss the evening events. We had to skimp on Christmas dinner, possibly my single favourite meal of the year, because Alex wouldn&#8217;t be here. (Hence the horridly dry turkey breast.)<br />
It&#8217;s time to start thinking about closing out the year, which we&#8217;ll do from the West Coast, and look towards the events of 2012. I&#8217;m looking forward to a good time.<br />
Happy holidays, everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/12/merry-christmas-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A rainy train</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-rainy-train/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-rainy-train</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-rainy-train/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 05:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2822</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Every year, the City of Vancouver puts on a light show in and around the miniature train in Stanley Park. Last night, after the kids had gone to bed, Allen, Jean, and I discussed the possibility of going. The catch was tickets. Tickets for the ride are best bought in advance, and usually sell out &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-rainy-train/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A rainy train"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every year, the City of Vancouver puts on a light show in and around the miniature train in Stanley Park. Last night, after the kids had gone to bed, Allen, Jean, and I discussed the possibility of going. The catch was tickets. Tickets for the ride are best bought in advance, and usually sell out in November. But that&#8217;s only half the rides &#8212; the other half are sold the day of, and you need to be present at the booth to get them.<br />
Jean very kindly (extremely kindly? suicidally kindly?) went down this morning, in the cold and the rain, to line up and get tickets for the &#8220;best possible&#8221; time for us to ride, around 17:30. That is &#8220;best&#8221; as it&#8217;s early enough that we can still have dinner at a reasonable time, and it&#8217;s late enough that Nikki can join us from her job.<br />
Tonight, I also remembered how miserable Vancouver can be in the winter.<br />
<span id="more-2822"></span>It rained all day, and the temperature never got above 4 degrees. It could be easily argued that, despite being colder, Calgary has much nicer weather. That rain makes a lot of difference. So it was that, in the rain, we all trucked into Vancouver and found our way into Stanley Park, and parked near the miniature train area.<br />
You couldn&#8217;t miss it if you were blinded, locked in a box, and put inside a cargo van. Someone said there were over two million lights, and I could believe it. I&#8217;ve never seen so many lights, and the Calgary Zoo Lights go a long way to make a push for &#8220;most lights&#8221;. If Zoo Lights went for the density seen at Bright Nights, Stanley Park&#8217;s version, over the same area that it uses now, I think the Calgary Zoo could be visible from space.<br />
Despite the rain, we wandered about the lights while waiting our ticketed time. Some of the items, notably a rocking stand of lighted nutcrackers, are old and probably well-predate me. Most of the lights, however, are LED and considerably more recent (not to mention energy efficient &#8212; important when you&#8217;re using two million lights). It&#8217;s a hodge-podge of lights, and worth the trip around while waiting your turn at the train.<br />
[flickr]photo:5289113217[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5289211815[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5289816622[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5289215423[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5289216681[/flickr]<br />
I&#8217;d been on it once many years ago (1999, I think), though I remember little of it now. (There&#8217;s much of 1998-early 2000 that is foggy, for a number of reasons.) I&#8217;m fairly certain, however, that I had gone on a rainless evening, as there was no way I could forget how miserably cold and damp one feels while waiting to get on the train.<br />
I had pushed into the line, dragging Alex and the kids with me, thinking that we had a defined slot at which to board. As it turned out, I&#8217;d misunderstood the purpose of the times &#8212; merely to stagger the arrivals, and not to dictate a specific start time. As such, I got us into line before Nikki had even arrived, and the plan had always been to ride as a family. Alex, the kids, and I ended up jumping out of line on the station platform, waiting for the others to catch up.<br />
They were running three trains that night, so the line went surprisingly quickly. Each of the trains carried upwards of 50 people, and the trains arrived and departed about every five minutes. Although we had to wait nearly a half hour for the others to catch up, it somehow didn&#8217;t seem too awkward. (We were, at least, under shelter.)<br />
The train is small, and you have to be careful getting on. Alex clocked her head rather badly on the car&#8217;s roof, and I felt like a sumo wrestler trying to get on with Choo Choo strapped to my front, and the diaper bag on my back. (Choo Choo would not like the ride much at all, as I think she was rather hungry and not getting what she wanted.) And then we were off, listening to the dulcet tones of Anne Murray.<br />
The lights were strewn about the train&#8217;s route, which is a 10-12 minute course. Some of the areas were decorated with Christmas-themed scenes, some religious and most not (including, no joke, a set from SCTV&#8217;s Great White North, with a track from Bob and Doug&#8217;s album blaring over the speakers as we passed &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t resist a few &#8220;coo-loo-coo-coo-coo-LOO-COO-COO&#8221; refrains, myself).<br />
By far the most impressive part was when we exited the &#8220;national&#8221; tunnel (with black light diagrams of every province) into the &#8220;Niagara&#8221; area (which doesn&#8217;t have anything to do with the Falls) and saw lights draped over every square centimetre of ground, tree, and shrub. That area alone must&#8217;ve taken weeks to set up, and the payoff was fantastic.<br />
Despite the relatively slow speed, the cold, damp air made for a chilly ride, and we were none to upset when we finally reached the end of the line. Carefully disembarking, we hurried back to our cars, and drove off towards Gastown. Part 2 of the evening, notably dinner, was meant to be at the Old Spaghetti Factory.<br />
Sadly, that was the least thought out part of the plan, and we found a 140 minute-long wait instead. Nikki, working near the Gastown area, suggested Vallarta, a nearby Mexican restaurant as a backup. No wait whatsoever, and we were soon eating.<br />
But the kids were going down. Choo Choo had already been extremely upset about waiting to eat while on our way to Gastown, and Monkey was trending into the &#8220;wired from being up too late&#8221; zone. We made an effort to eat quickly so we could head back home.<br />
Back at the Aicken farmstead, the fireplace was stoked, warm clothes were donned, and hot drinks consumed to help warm us up from the penetrating cold we all seemed to feel. Tomorrow is plan-less, save for the Christmas Eve activities.<br />
I&#8217;m excited to be this close to Christmas. Not for the obvious reasons: I know I&#8217;m not getting the things on my list. But I am getting to watch this year&#8217;s festivities through my kids, which is definitely something to look forward to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-rainy-train/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2822</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A visit to the North Pole</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-visit-to-the-north-pole/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-visit-to-the-north-pole</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-visit-to-the-north-pole/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 01:15:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2818</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[During one of her many perusals of the local newspaper, Jean (aka &#8220;Granny&#8221;) came across an ad for &#8220;North Pole, BC&#8220;, billed as a &#8220;gateway&#8221; to the North Pole via Maple Ridge. (Perhaps not the most obvious place to teleport to the top of the world, but just about as likely as, say, Spuzzum.) So &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-visit-to-the-north-pole/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A visit to the North Pole"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During one of her many perusals of the local newspaper, Jean (aka &#8220;Granny&#8221;) came across an ad for &#8220;<a href="http://www.northpolebc.com/">North Pole, BC</a>&#8220;, billed as a &#8220;gateway&#8221; to the North Pole via Maple Ridge. (Perhaps not the most obvious place to teleport to the top of the world, but just about as likely as, say, Spuzzum.)<br />
So Jean arranged for us all (having to buy tickets being a big factor) to visit Santa in his own home, and witness a bit of a behind-the-scenes approach to Christmas.<br />
Even if, y&#8217;know, it&#8217;s above zero, all green, and the only snow to be seen is on the mountains&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2818"></span><a href="http://www.timberlineranch.com">Timberline Ranch</a>, a &#8220;non-denominational Christian&#8221; horse camp for kids runs the event, which is located at the very north of the Maple Ridge District, past the end of the paved roads, and pretty much right at the foot of the coastal mountains. It was about a 45 minute drive, not counting the time we had to wait for a grader to finish smoothing out a section of the aforementioned unpaved road.<br />
It&#8217;s hard to miss the decorative &#8220;North Pole, BC&#8221; sign awaiting all at the gates. The North Pole bus stop awaits just after the parking lot, and almost immediately you&#8217;re met by elves. (The &#8220;elves&#8221; are high school and university students, dressed in appropriately festive and elvish red-and-white stripped tights, with red and green frocks.) They check you in, and then &#8212; much like a bus ride &#8212; you wait for your scheduled departure.<br />
[flickr]photo:5284308365[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284907502[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284909280[/flickr]<br />
They group together several families, and you travel in a group. First stop? The gift shop, oddly enough. That one puzzled me a bit &#8212; you typically exit through a gift shop, not enter. (For the record, we exited a by walking down a path.) Form there, up a pathway, past the &#8220;elf wishing tree&#8221; to the Post Office. (The various buildings were actually bunks used for summer camps, heavily decorated to be something else.) There we all hustled in to await the first pseudo-event.<br />
[flickr]photo:5284909996[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284313823[/flickr]<br />
Monkey, it seems, had far too much for breakfast, and the three helpings of porridge were weighing heavily on her belly, causing her to declare that she was &#8220;bored&#8221; and &#8220;tired&#8221;. (Alex and I quickly declared that one serving of porridge would be enough in the future.)<br />
The elf running the post office first had the kids (ranging in age from only a couple of months up to about age five) find a couple of letters that had been &#8220;misplaced&#8221;. Then the kids got to have their letters &#8220;approved&#8221; for mailing (placed on a scale to determine if they asked for too much), before being trucked back outside and have the letters put in the mail.<br />
The second stop was the Elvern School of Secrets, where the only male elf in the group (which we would later find out was a theatrical student &#8212; a complete non-surprise given his very over-the-top performance) gave the audience a three-step lesson in being an elf. I can&#8217;t tell you about that, though, I&#8217;m sworn to secret. Though I can say that poor grandpa got suckered into reciting the oath while on one knee.<br />
[flickr]photo:5284323475[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284324671[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284964516[/flickr]<br />
Then it was off to one of the elves&#8217; favourite activities: ice fishing. In lieu of frozen water was well-carved styrofoam and magnetic fish. Every kid got a chance.<br />
Next up was the toy workshop, where the slave labour portion of the tour kicked in. (You think Santa makes all these toys himself??) Every kid got the emptied fabric shell of a white bear, and was encouraged to fill it with stuffing, and bring it up to the &#8220;head elf&#8221; to be registered. (The bears were later for sale, wrapped, with the child&#8217;s name already attached.) Then it was into Mrs. Claus&#8217; cabin for storytime.<br />
[flickr]photo:5284982512[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5284385901[/flickr]<br />
Finally, it was time for the Big Man himself. This is where I really have to hand it to the North Pole, BC operation. Considering this is supposedly a first-year operation, it&#8217;s handled as professionally and smoothly as a Disney experience. (Someone&#8217;s done their research!) There are actually two Santas at work, both secreted in cabins such that the kids don&#8217;t know that there&#8217;s two of them, and each family has actual private time with Santa, rather than having to feel like the typical mall assembly-line.<br />
To accomplish this, the group was divided, and two families (including ours) were whisked away to &#8220;Club Eggnog&#8221;, a little play area in the basement of the main ranch building, to play while waiting our turn. Monkey seemed to get more and more excited to see Santa, but I harboured the suspicion this was all bravado. When we&#8217;d gone to the Santa in Chinook Mall a couple of weeks ago, she&#8217;d bailed at the last second and only Choo Choo had sat on Santa&#8217;s lap. Still, Monkey raced up the stairs, and ran ahead of us as we went to see Santa.<br />
But as the door opened, the &#8220;wait a second&#8221; look crossed her face, and suddenly she didn&#8217;t want to go in. (Called it&#8230;) But with a little gentle coaxing, and a promise to hold a hand, we managed to get her to at least enter the cabin. By then, Santa, clearing having seen this dozens of times, helped Monkey into the cabin, and ultimately to sit down with him. From there, she was fine, and freely told Santa her life story (as well as what she wanted for Christmas &#8212; thankfully, Jessie remained on the list).<br />
We did a quick round of pictures, one with just the kids, then with the parents, and finally the grandparents. Monkey waved goodbye, said &#8220;thank you&#8221;, and we headed back outside.<br />
We had lunch in the cafe (on the main floor above Club Eggnog), before heading off for a pony ride, which Monkey had been promised. The sky was darkening quickly (it seems to get darker here in Maple Ridge earlier than it does in Calgary), and we headed home after Monkey had a couple of laps around the riding barn.<br />
Both kids were asleep before we got to central Maple Ridge.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/a-visit-to-the-north-pole/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2818</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-5</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1199</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.   Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?   So, where to start?   &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.  <br />
Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?  <br />
So, where to start?  <br />
<span id="more-1199"></span>We didn&#8217;t want to stick around the hotel any longer &#8212; the breakfasts here are so darned expensive considering the quality you get. So we opted to head off to a place Alex wanted to see: Alice&#8217;s Teacup, a teahouse up on 64th. Sadly, despite the published opening time at 8:00, the place wasn&#8217;t opening until 10:00. So we adjourned to the French restaurant we spotted along the way.  <br />
By the time we got back to the hotel, Mom was trying to check in. (Such began the longest check-in process I have ever experienced at a hotel.) We gathered together, chatted, and almost immediately put Mi Pequeña Niña to bed. It was nap time, and she was getting a little cranky. She didn&#8217;t wake up again until we stirred her until just after noon, at which point we all headed out for lunch.  <br />
My bright idea? Finding an eatery at Grand Central Terminal.  <br />
Yes, it&#8217;s the train thing. Suck it up. I haven&#8217;t seen a real train in months.  <br />
We found Michael Jordan&#8217;s (I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s related to the basketball player) where we endulged in some seriously tasty edibles. (I think MPN got the best of all of us &#8212; her macaroni and cheese was fantastic). While we were there, we were entertained by a lightshow that was going on in the main concourse, which kept MPN completely fascinated.  <br />
We strolled a bit, but ended up back at the hotel before long, about in time for MPN to crash again. Which was about the time Alex and I started planning our night out. It&#8217;s part of the reason Mom came down &#8212; to keep an eye on MPN while Alex and I tried to paint the town &#8230; well, maybe not red so much as pink.  <br />
We walked to Times Square (again) and started our task at finding a place to see a movie, which was a lot harder than it seems. There are two movie theatres in the area (Regal and AMC), and you have to figure out which movie that you want to see is at which theatre. Which was about when Alex made it clear to me that she needed to eat dinner. That led us to some diner just south of Times Square with the driest chicken I ever ate. (But, admittedly, I&#8217;ve had worse.)<br />
The movie, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was Bedtime Stories. Overall, a well done movie. And I&#8217;m still giggling at Russell Brand&#8217;s rendition of Sleep Panic Disorder. Then we hit the Virgin Megastore for more movies. I had a serious need for a movie fix.  <br />
This morning started a little different, and much more slowly than the previous mornings. We headed off to the Waldorf Astoria (the next block south) for breakfast, and then returned for MPN to have another nap. By the time she awoke, it was time for luch, which was at Au Bon Pain a couple of blocks away. We hopped a cab and about 25 minutes later we were at the Cloisters Museum, a branch of the Met up at the north end of Manhattan island.  <br />
Barely 2 minutes after arriving, Alex realised in a panic that the little backpack that she uses to carry MPN&#8217;s stuff (and her wallet) were in the bag, and the bag was still in the taxi, now departed from the Cloisters. That sent me to a phone to cancel the credit card, and list a missing bag with the Taxi and Limosine Commission. That said, I was also told that it&#8217;ll be a cold day in hell before we get this stuff back, due to the way that the taxis run in this city. Which, I have to admit, is a little odd.  <br />
The Cloisters, for the record, is one of New York City&#8217;s unspoken gems. It&#8217;s out of the way, admittedly, which is why, but it is gorgeous. It was like the churches I saw in England, Scotland, and Ireland (although most of it came from France). Absolutely wonderful! I can see why Mark has said that he wants to hold his wedding there. (Well, when he gets around to getting married, that is.)  <br />
The driver of the hired car we took on the way back really didn&#8217;t listen to me and ended up taking us through Times Square. The hard way. (Believe me, there are easier ways.) He apologised for the mistake, and didn&#8217;t charge us what he should have charged us if he&#8217;d had a meter running.  <br />
Dinner was at a place called Bobby Van&#8217;s, a steakhouse on 54th between Lexington and Park Ave. We were perhaps a bit underdressed, but the meal was fantastic. I&#8217;m going to have such a steak hangover in the morning. And I&#8217;m going to revel in it as much as possible.  <br />
But until then, I&#8217;m exhausted, and looking forward to going home. (That&#8217;s Costa Rica, in case you&#8217;re not sure.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 02:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1196</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Merry Ho Ho, everyone!   Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Merry Ho Ho, everyone!  <br />
Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For those of you keeping track, I&#8217;m at 12 coffees since I started.)  <br />
Then it was back for present opening. &#8216;Cuz it just ain&#8217;t Christmas without presents.  <br />
<span id="more-1196"></span>Due to our travel plans, Alex and I opted not to actually get each other presents. Instead, we went for the &#8220;Aw, Honey, You Shouldn&#8217;t Have!&#8221; move where we buy what we want for ourselves, and then thank the other for being so thoughtful. (Yes, it borders heavily on the extremely lame, but we neither need or want much, and it&#8217;s just easier to do it this way rather than try to bring it all, or remember what the other wants and try to purchase it when you&#8217;re rarely alone). Alex already did her book run earlier in the week. I might never get a chance to do mine, and I&#8217;m okay with that. Lately, I&#8217;ve been realising that I haven&#8217;t cared as much about me as I have about Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña.  <br />
The scavenger hunt wasn&#8217;t long &#8212; the presents were easy to find for Megan (that&#8217;s the point) and we didn&#8217;t have a chance to wrap anything. There will be wrapped presents back in Costa Rica, but for now she&#8217;ll do without. She found her new books in her stocking, her new shirts, and Yorkie (the name we gave to the stuffed dog). Then came much playing with all of them while we tried to find some sort of Christmas movie on TV. The best we could do was <em>Bad Santa</em>. Not exactly a kid-friendly movie.  <br />
We chatted with Cathy, Craig, and their kids (well, Tori &#8212; Natalee the newborn babe seems to be asleep every time we see her) &#8212; and my mom &#8212; while they were having breakfast, awaiting the time we could call Allen. Sadly, we had problems lining up our time with Allen, so we eventually had to give up and start working on our day. Bundling up, it was time for our Christmas Day excursion to the Central Park Zoo.  <br />
New York City never slows down, never stops. Even Christmas Day, traffic is bustling, people are everywhere, stops (some) are open, and it&#8217;s almost business as usual. It&#8217;s truly my kind of town! (No, I doubt I&#8217;ll ever get a chance to live here.) We walked from our hotel at 51st and Lexington to Central Park, watching all the people and wondering if we bundled up Megan well enough for the brisker-than-it-first-felt weather. In the end she seemed fine, and didn&#8217;t complain about the cold. (She would later complain about missing a nap.)  <br />
The Central Park Zoo isn&#8217;t what I thought it would be. Again, damn you Hollywood!, my vision wasn&#8217;t what it was. No attention-hogging lions, no wise-cracking zebras, no hypochondriatic giraffes, and no pushy hippos. Mind you, I could swear one of the penguins looked like he was up to something. (Mind you, it could have been a &#8220;her&#8221; &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to tell.)  <br />
Don&#8217;t get me wrong, the Central Park Zoo is really a wonderful place on Christmas Day. Not only does the clock chime Christmas Carols, but it&#8217;s not really busy, and easy to get around. It doesn&#8217;t hurt that the place is miniscule &#8212; literally the smallest zoo I&#8217;ve ever been to. (I&#8217;ve been to petting zoos that were larger.) Good use of the space, I should add.  <br />
By the time we were leaving, MPN was rapidly approaching meltdown due to lack of sleep. It was a near-race to get back to the hotel and get her down. Along the way, I ended up having to carry her (it calms her down), and before long I had a little bobble head baby &#8212; she was literally falling asleep and trying to sit in my arms. I leaned her forward into my chest and that was that &#8212; she went deadweight. Alex and I took the opportunity to go into the Oxford Cafe for lunch, putting her back into her stroller to sleep.  <br />
I had turkey. My only turkey of the day, as it would turn out. Alex indulged in perhaps the largest tuna salad bagel I&#8217;ve ever seen. It was far from gourmet, but given the circumstances, I was hardly one to argue.  <br />
Although MPN woke up briefly on the way back to the room, it was a tenuous consciousness, and it wasn&#8217;t long before she was back down and passed out. We tried to figure out where to go for dinner. While New York City truly is a wondrous place for food, Christmas Day is a little more limited. While (almost) every hotel restaurant is open, not all of them are easy to get into, have availability, or even turkey for that matter. We ended up going with San Martin, a nearby Italian restaurant.  <br />
Seafood risotto and fusilli primavera. Not exactly traditional, but then this trip has been anything but &#8212; so why stop with dinner? I wouldn&#8217;t go so far as to recommend the place, however. It&#8217;s okay, but I wouldn&#8217;t call it &#8220;great&#8221;.  <br />
MPN and I tried to check out Rockefeller Center while Alex endulged in a long-overdue bath. I think about half of New York came out for it, and I had the briefest glimpse what Times Square on New Year&#8217;s Eve must be like. It was a roundabout trip before we headed back and got the wee one to bed.  <br />
Speaking of which, it&#8217;s our turn to do the same. Mom arrives tomorrow, and we&#8217;re both in need of some serious ZZZs. I hope you all had a Merry Christmas. (And for those of you back in Canada, enjoy the Boxing Week sales!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-2</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 03:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1194</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Pequeña Niña if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My dogs are barkin&#8217;. It&#8217;s been a day on my feet. A good day, to be sure, but a lot of walking, and a lot of standing. The same was true for Alex, and it would be for Mi Pequeña Niña if she hadn&#8217;t slept for a solid hour or so while we were walking about. (Considering that was her only nap of the day, that&#8217;s not a bad thing, either.)<br />
The way started out as a rough plan to go to the Empire State Building, and check out the view of Manhattan. But our plans here are very flexible. Aside from the fact that I&#8217;ve been to New York City twice before, we&#8217;re travelling with a napping toddler, who is apt to change our plans at a moment&#8217;s notice for any number of reasons. So I try not to go too crazy when plans are forced to change.  <br />
(Emphasis on the word &#8220;try&#8221;.)<br />
<span id="more-1194"></span>Following a decent breakfast, we dressed for our run out to the CitiGroup building, and hop the E train eastwards to the 7th Ave station, where we switched to a northbound B train to 81st St. The stop, for those of you who don&#8217;t know, for the American Museum of Natural History. I&#8217;d seen it once before from the outside, but had really wanted to visit it since seeing &#8220;A Night At the Museum&#8221;.  <br />
A couple of things about the New York Subway system:<br />
  </p>
<ol>
<li>Accessibility. Not everyone has two capable feet. Some people require wheels, from those in wheelchairs to parents who try to get around with strollers. I&#8217;m amazed that not only are many stations on the system not equipped with ramps and elevators, in order to get in or out of the system, you need a station attendant to unlock the &#8220;service&#8221; gates (or trip the alarm on your way out).  </li>
<li>Not every person riding the subway is from the United States of America. So asking for a ZIP code when you want to use a credit card to purchase tickets is really short-sighted. (A note for those of you in our boat: punch in &#8220;99999&#8221;, &#8216;cuz it&#8217;s not posted anywhere.)</li>
<li>Allow people to purchase more than one ticket at a time, or at least suggest how you can use the same Metrocard for more than one person. Take a few lessons from the London Underground, who have this down to an artform.  </li>
<li>There is no better place to find amateur musicians. Why most of these people don&#8217;t have music on iTunes for sale is beyond me.  </li>
</ol>
<p>  <br />
The main entrance to the AMNH is made up of three small revolving doors. Not suitable for all strollers, certainly not ours. I had to go in through the planetarium entrance and work my way back to the main entrance. Which wasn&#8217;t easy due to malfunctioning elevators (and a near total lack of signage for alternatives). I&#8217;m certain that Alex (who went in through the main entrance) was wondering where Mi Pequeña Niña and I were.  <br />
When we did finally meet up in the main entrance hall, I was supremely disappointed. That massive entranceway in &#8220;A Night At The Museum&#8221;? About a third of that size. No statue of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback. No round front desk. There is a dinosaur &#8212; three, actually. But it&#8217;s just not as impressive. (Other things that seemed to be missing: Dioramas of railway builders and Roman legions, Civil war soldiers, and an Egyptian wing with a golden plaque that brings things together at night. But I digress.)<br />
Our first stop was at a temporary exhibit &#8212; a butterfly garden. It is with supreme irony that we flew five hours from Costa Rica to visit a butterfly garden with specimens from Costa Rica. (And in greater numbers than we&#8217;ve experienced before.) MPN was enthralled with all the butterflies, with them fluttering all about. The guides there (all volunteers) were all really well-educated about butterflies, too.  <br />
We moved on from there, moving to the 1st floor, in search of the Spitzer Hall of Human Evolution. (Alex would have a PhD in Anthropology by now if she&#8217;d known about anthropology before going into university.) To get there, we went through the Hall of Biodiversity, the Environment of New York State (featuring exhibits that hadn&#8217;t been dusted in at least 40 years &#8212; and looked about that dated), before passing a café on the south-west side.  <br />
It gave us a chance for a quick bite (I eschewed the $10.50 sandwiches), before we entered the Spitzer Hall. That was about when MPN finally passed out. Alex read every letter of every sign in the hall. I scanned many of them, reading more into the things that interested me more (e.g. the various branches of evolution that led to homo sapiens, and especially those branches that turned out to be dead-ends. (I still want to know where Neanderthals came from, and why they died out.)  <br />
While Alex continued to review evolution, I strayed along, eventually finding my way into another &#8220;hall&#8221; (the Arthur Ross Hall) dedicated wholly to meteorites. In the centre of the room was a particularly large specimen, Ahnighito (so dubbed by the Inuit of Greeland), is effectively a massive chunk of iron clocking in at a serious 34 tons. (That&#8217;s Imperial tons, by the way &#8212; some 68,000+ pounds.) It doesn&#8217;t look like it weighs 34 tons when you first see it. But when you touch it, you suddenly feel the weight of its mass and the distance it&#8217;s travelled.  I also ducked into the hall of minerals next door (at one point, I was a budding geologist) before returning to Alex and we continued our excursion around the museum.  <br />
The Hall of North American Mammals, the Hall of North American Tourists (otherwise known as  the gift shop), and finally the exit back to the subway to return to the hotel.  <br />
This being Christmas Eve, we planned to hit a Christmas service. I suggested St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, a particualrly wonderful example of gothic architecture just across the street from Rockefeller Center. But when we arrived, we found that we weren&#8217;t the only ones with the idea. Most of Manhattan gets this idea. Tickets for the event were apparently sold out by Labor Day.  <br />
Fortunately, there&#8217;s a non-denominational church nearby (though I think its roots are in the Anglican church) called St. Bart&#8217;s. We popped in there to find plenty of seating. The only problem with the service, sadly, was MPN, who would have none of this sitting still crap. Alex and I ended up having to take turns keeping her pinned down (or occupied) as not to disturb the entire church. Murdo&#8217;s talk of hearing MPN&#8217;s &#8220;music&#8221; was not echoed here.  <br />
When we left, it was raining. Yes, raining. It&#8217;s Christmas in New York, and it&#8217;s raining. The chill we first felt at landing is now gone, and I find the weather much warmer. Why didn&#8217;t we stay at home in Costa Rica?, you&#8217;re asking, I&#8217;m sure.  <br />
Alex made a desperate last-dash to a nearby CVS (drugstore) for some Christmasy things, such as a string of lights (very important), some decorations (right out of the classic &#8220;Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer&#8221; TV special), and the only tradition that we&#8217;ve had every year thus far &#8212; Turtles (the chocolate kind).  <br />
And on that note, it&#8217;s now time for us to go to bed. So to all of you, Merry Christmas to all, and to all a good night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1194</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
