<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>halloween &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/halloween/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 17:40:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A first &#034;real&#034; Hallowe&#039;en</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/a-first-real-halloween/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-first-real-halloween</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/a-first-real-halloween/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 17:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halloween]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today was Hallowe&#8217;en here in Calgary, and your first real Hallowe&#8217;en, kids. Yes, Monkey, you could easily argue that you had your first Hallowe&#8217;en two years ago when we lived in Costa Rica. (It could be further argued that you were in Calgary for your very first Hallowe&#8217;en, but clocking in at a mere two &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/a-first-real-halloween/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A first &#34;real&#34; Hallowe&#039;en"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was Hallowe&#8217;en here in Calgary, and your first real Hallowe&#8217;en, kids. Yes, Monkey, you could easily argue that <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/11/halloween-in-costa-rica/">you had your first Hallowe&#8217;en two years ago when we lived in Costa Rica</a>. (It could be further argued that you were in Calgary for your very first Hallowe&#8217;en, but clocking in at a mere two months drastically limited your ability to say &#8220;trick or treat&#8221; &#8230; or pretty much anything, really.)<br />
That &#8220;first&#8221; Hallowe&#8217;en was largely missed by myself (sadly &#8212; traffic was not daddy&#8217;s friend that night), and your experience was limited to what the mothers at Avalon could put together. From what I understand, fun was had by all. But it wasn&#8217;t the same as going door-to-door, saying &#8220;trick or treat&#8221;, and loading yourself so full of candy that you don&#8217;t know what to do with yourself.<br />
I gotta say, you made me proud tonight.<br />
<span id="more-2789"></span>We sort of started for Hallowe&#8217;en a few weeks ago when we went to the Calgary Corn Maze. We bought a pumpkin that was destined to be the one that sat out in front of our house tonight. However, while at the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market on Saturday, Mommy and I decided to buy a couple of more. After you kicked another pumpkin, Monkey, we ended up with three. (In the end, no matter the appropriateness of your actions, four pumpkins proved correct.)<br />
Mommy was on the prowl for you, as well, and found a cowgirl princess costume. For Choo Choo &#8212; no, Mommy didn&#8217;t forget you &#8212; there was a pumpkin outfit. Sadly, Choo Choo, you didn&#8217;t get to do much tonight. You were in the stroller, thoroughly pissed off at the utter lack of attention you were getting towards getting to sleep. (You&#8217;re not sleeping right now. You&#8217;ll sleep at night &#8230; mostly &#8230; but napping during the day is driving poor Mommy insane. We can only hope you grow out of this.)<br />
We carved up the pumpkins this morning after breakfast. Since we had four, it made sense to carve &#8220;self portraits&#8221; into them. That was Mommy&#8217;s idea. But instead of actual pictures, we went with something more symbolic &#8212; a monkey for Monkey, a choo choo for Choo Choo, knitting needles and yarn for Mommy, and (of course) an Apple for me.<br />
[flickr]photo:5134855938[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5134260485[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5134861756[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5134264055[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5134265501[/flickr]<br />
Then we trucked off to Westbrook Mall so you could trick-or-treat there for the first time. You practiced your &#8220;trick or treat&#8221; very well, and we soon unleashed you to the unsuspecting store clerks. You needed the odd reminder, but generally were very good about saying both &#8220;trick or treat&#8221;, and &#8220;thank you&#8221; when you received your candy. And considering you were one of the few kids (young kids, at that &#8212; I was surprised at the number of older kids) who travelled on their own, you showed no shyness, and seemed to be respectful of lineups.<br />
[flickr]photo:5134268555[/flickr]<br />
Choo Choo, you would have loved trick-or-treating. But you were wetting your diaper. Sorry, but that&#8217;s just the honest truth.<br />
We had pizza with Nana and Grandma, who watched the house and gave out candy to the total of 14 (possibly 13, there may be still some debate) kids who came to our door. Then the four of us, Choo Choo in the stroller (and crying) headed out to the second house down the block, where you rang the doorbell, and said your first evening, in-the-dark, wearing-warm-clothes-under-your-costume (a very Canadian thing to do) &#8220;trick or treat&#8221;.<br />
You literally ran away from that house exclaiming, and I kid you not:</p>
<blockquote><p>Let&#8217;s get more candy!</p></blockquote>
<p>That scene was repeated another 10 or so times down one side of our little crescent street before Mommy and Choo Choo headed home, and you and I tackled the other side. Many times, you would turn just as we&#8217;d turned up a walkway, and said forcefully:</p>
<blockquote><p>I&#8217;m going by myself. You stay right there!</p></blockquote>
<p>A couple of times you forgot to say &#8220;thank you&#8221; (I had to chastise you for that), and a couple of times you walked right into people&#8217;s houses (I had to laugh every time you did). You didn&#8217;t say much to the nice people who gave you candy, but you were generally polite.<br />
Next year, with luck, both you and Choo Choo will be able to go, since Choo Choo should be walking by then. We might not get far with the both of you, but it should make for a very cute evening. We&#8217;ll have to start thinking of costumes that would for the both of you.<br />
Given the fact that you went out with just a small basket, you did surprisingly well. And that so few kids came to our house only means that Mommy and I won&#8217;t be raiding your supply this year.  Though if I can make one suggestion for next year: learn how to do an inventory.<br />
[flickr]photo:5134286415[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/a-first-real-halloween/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2789</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halloween in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/halloween-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=halloween-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/halloween-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 03:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halloween]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8230;doesn&#8217;t really exist. Not in the way we gringos are used to seeing it, that is. Where we come from, decorations can rise to the level of an artform, and the single evening has evolved to the point where the only thing people really want to do is scare the crap out of each other. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/halloween-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Halloween in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;doesn&#8217;t really exist. Not in the way we gringos are used to seeing it, that is. Where we come from, decorations can rise to the level of an artform, and the single evening has evolved to the point where the only thing people really want to do is scare the crap out of each other.  <br />
All in good fun, of course.  <br />
In Costa Rica, 31 October is known better as (El) Noche de las Brujas (Witches&#8217; Night). While that sounds quite a bit cooler than &#8220;Halloween&#8221; (I still prefer the more archaic &#8220;All Hallows&#8217; Eve&#8221;), it&#8217;s not really observed here, which is a shame.  <br />
<span id="more-1152"></span>Now, I have to say that I didn&#8217;t really get to experience what was done all that much. Friday evening seemed to be a confluence of a variety of things, including payday (which for some reason that I haven&#8217;t figured out yet seems to wreak havoc on traffic) and the end of the month. A normal 30-minute commute turned into a near-hour and a half on the road. A bit much, if you ask me.  <br />
Anyway, by the time I got home, the bulk of the event was already over. One of the mother&#8217;s at our complex arranged a bit of a near-parade for the children here (there&#8217;s a lot more under the age of 5 than I expected), around the lago that sits in the middle of our collected group of condo buildings. Tiki torches lit the way, and a few &#8220;stations&#8221; doled out candies.  <br />
The parade had long since ended by 19:00, and the remaining kids were on the grass just outside of our building, eating candy and/or staring at the parents as if to say: &#8220;Alright, now what I am supposed to in this outfit?&#8221;<br />
The costumes were pretty simple, considering most of the kids were pretty young. The most elaborate was a young girl (she couldn&#8217;t have been much more than six months older than Mi Pequeña Niña) in traditional Spanish flamenco attire. Alex had found a little fairy princess outfit for MPN that gave her little wings, a tutu, and a magic wand.  <br />
Had MPN been in Calgary, she&#8217;d have been in a parka.  <br />
Okay, yes, mild exaggeration.  <br />
Most of the other kids looked like they were having fun, though I think the parents were getting more of a kick out of it than their children. Another amusing point &#8212; almost all of the others were Spanish-speakers, largely Argentinian (we think &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of them in the complex). Alex and MPN were the only gringos in the group.  <br />
Out on the streets, there wasn&#8217;t a costume to be seen anywhere. In Calgary, you&#8217;d drive home 40% slower, keeping a wary eye for Spiderman, the current pop stars, pirates, and the like, any of whom might dive in front of your car at any moment. In a way, I miss that.<br />
I also missed the pumpkin. I couldn&#8217;t find one here (and I did look). They don&#8217;t really have them in Costa Rica. Though you could use a squash &#8230; but it just ain&#8217;t the same (or size). Not like the monster pumpkins we could get back in Ontario, anyway.<br />
Well, that&#8217;s another changed event down here. Can&#8217;t wait to see how Christmas fares, now that nearly every place we go not only has their Christmas display out, but decorations too. Lights and music can&#8217;t be far behind&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/halloween-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1152</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
