<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>yekaterinburg &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/yekaterinburg/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 13:20:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A little story about Ekaterinburg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 13:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trans-siberian railway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yekaterinburg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/13/a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ekaterinburg (Soviet name, a much harsher &#8220;Sverdlovsk&#8221;) is a wonderful little place to spend an afternoon. Assuming you can find your hotel, that is. After doing our little thing at the post office to try and catch up on postings, Amy and I did about the only thing we had time for: a walking tour. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A little story about Ekaterinburg"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ekaterinburg (Soviet name, a much harsher &#8220;Sverdlovsk&#8221;) is a wonderful little place to spend an afternoon. Assuming you can find your hotel, that is.<br />
After doing our little thing at the post office to try and catch up on postings, Amy and I did about the only thing we had time for: a walking tour. Fortunately, our Lonely Planet book on the Trans Siberian Railway has a walking tour laid out pretty well. It was just a matter for us to walk it.<br />
<span id="more-538"></span><a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03564.JPG" alt="The river in downtown Ekaterinburg" width="300" /></a><br />
Starting off at the river downtown (actually, the result of a dam that you don&#8217;t even realize is a dam), you head east to a traffic circle, then north to a memorial to soldiers killed in the Afghan conflict. Then you&#8217;re supposed to head a bit west and then north to find a park. Sadly, I took us north, forgetting the west. Result: we walked too far, and missed the park. Amy got us back on track, and soon were sauntering through a rather picturesque little set of trees.<br />
On the opposite side is the site where the Russian Royal Family was murdered on 16 July 1917. The house where their brutal execution took place was actually levelled by Boris Yeltsin (then governor of the area) back in the 70s. It now sports a small iron cross, a marble cross (erected when the Romanov remains &#8212; or, more specifically, what are believed to be the remains) were sent to St. Petersburg for final burial. There is also a rather large church there, now, too (in addition to a much smaller wooden one). Supposedly, the Romanov family are considered saints. Personally, they were ignorant buffoons who didn&#8217;t see the tide coming in until it was too late&#8230;<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03561.JPG" alt="The iron cross marking the site of the Russian Royal family's murder" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03562.JPG" alt="A marble tablet at the same site. I have no idea what it says." width="300" /></a><br />
Then it was a hasty retreat back to downtown for a bite to eat before running back to the station to catch our train to Krasnoyarsk. But you already know how that went&#8230;<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03563.JPG" alt="I love Sverdlovsk" width="300" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-story-about-ekaterinburg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">538</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The language barrier</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/the-language-barrier/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-language-barrier</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/the-language-barrier/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2005 10:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yekaterinburg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/12/the-language-barrier/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, we finally hit the wall. It took us a while. Kazan is far enough away from Moscow that you&#8217;ll be hard-pressed to find much English. The most we saw was on the sign at the kremlin. Since English is the official language of the UN, all UNESCO sites have to have signs in English. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/the-language-barrier/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The language barrier"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, we finally hit the wall. It took us a while.<br />
Kazan is far enough away from Moscow that you&#8217;ll be hard-pressed to find much English. The most we saw was on the sign at the kremlin. Since English is the official language of the UN, all UNESCO sites have to have signs in English. After that, we were on our own.<br />
<span id="more-536"></span>Ordering was fun. We&#8217;ve figured out that digging a few key words out of our Russian phrase books helps, as does pointing. Knowing brand names helps, too. And every McDonald&#8217;s seems to have one person who knows English pretty darn well.<br />
As I&#8217;ve already written, Ekaterinburg was fun just finding our hotel. But the fun continued even afterwards. No hot water. After 20 hours on a train and lugging heavy bags around, we needed showers. Cold water doesn&#8217;t make for a good shower. Bleh. The building, for some reason, was also quite cool. Initially, it felt great because we were so hot. Not so much after we cooled down. It seemed heat and hot water weren&#8217;t wholly necessary. We managed to have warm water this morning, though. A few words out of our dictionaries and a few from the attendant&#8217;s managed to solve that problem.<br />
Without question, though, the best experience was ordering dinner last night. The restaurant &#8212; Troli Bali &#8212; had no English at all, and our server knew less English than we do Russian. We managed to order beer (that much we&#8217;ve picked up) before trying to decipher the menus. It took 20 minutes just to order a pork chop. Food just tastes better when you have to work for it.<br />
This is one of the great things about traveling &#8212; having to adapt to the challenges put before you. Language is only one of them, though it&#8217;s one of the toughest. Russian we&#8217;re not exactly getting the hang of, but it&#8217;s getting easier. By the time we&#8217;re comfortable with it, we&#8217;ll be switching to Mongolian, and then Chinese.<br />
Home is just too far away!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/the-language-barrier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">536</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding the Academy of Geology Hotel</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2005 09:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trans-siberian railway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yekaterinburg]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/12/finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the Lonely Planet books fall a little short&#8230;So here&#8217;s the description of the Academy of Geology Hotel here in Ekaterinburg, as provided in the Lonely Planet Trans-Siberian Railway book: Bldg 6, prosp Lenina 54 Singles/doubles with breakfast $26/30. This is the best budget option with smart, spacious rooms in a quite complex tucked away &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finding the Academy of Geology Hotel"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When the Lonely Planet books fall a little short&#8230;So here&#8217;s the description of the Academy of Geology Hotel here in Ekaterinburg, as provided in the Lonely Planet Trans-Siberian Railway book:</p>
<blockquote><p>Bldg 6, prosp Lenina 54<br />
Singles/doubles with breakfast $26/30. This is the best budget option with smart, spacious rooms in a quite complex tucked away off the main road.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah. So let me tell you how we found the place. First of all, we found Lenina Prospekt &#8212; that wasn&#8217;t hard. We walked all the way down to #54 (buildings aren&#8217;t individually numbered here, they go in groups). When you get into cases where buildings are in groups, they&#8217;re numbered something like 54/6 &#8212; such as the building holding our hotel.<br />
Admittedly, I don&#8217;t know what exactly Amy was looking for, but I guess I expected something a little more &#8230; less apartment-y, which is what the 54 block looked like. We found 54/5, but couldn&#8217;t find 54/6. So we started walking around. A kind gentleman, about early 40s, asked us a question. We replied, sheepishly:</p>
<blockquote><p>ya neh gavaroo pa-rooskie</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah, you guessed it: &#8220;I don&#8217;t speak Russian.&#8221;<br />
This didn&#8217;t stop him, or us, and we proceeded to point, speak slowly (in both languages) until he dug out a map. Turns out that a building in the &#8220;courtyard&#8221; was the one we wanted. The side we could see was partly boarded up and covered in grafitti. We walked around to the other side and found the &#8220;Academy of Geology&#8221; sign, which we could barely read thanks to a Russian trend to use words similar to those in English, but with different spelling. The woman inside was totally unintelligable, and suggested (though her thick, steel bar window) that we should walk around the building. To the graffiti side, it seemed.<br />
Luckily, a boy about 15 years old spoke up &#8212; speaking just enough English to understand that we couldn&#8217;t find the place. Back to the old woman. Conversation, back around to the <em>side</em> (west side, to be specific) of the building to a very unmarked and handle-less door. Pressing a little black buzzer above the door called the attendant, upon which we found out, that yes, this was the place.<br />
For the record, the hotel is fairly nice, but certainly nothing special. So a word of warning to those of you looking for the hotel &#8212; it&#8217;s not clearly marked in the Lonely Planet books, and may require some assistance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/finding-the-academy-of-geology-hotel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">535</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
