<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ontario &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/ontario/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 22:27:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>20 years from Ontario</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=20-years-from-ontario</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two decades ago today, I did something immensely stupid: I left home. Literally and figuratively. Twenty years ago, I was still sleeping in my room on Gatestone Avenue in Oakville. While I had lived on my own at university, and while I was on my co-op work terms in Ottawa, staying at home was &#8230; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "20 years from Ontario"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two decades ago today, I did something immensely stupid: I left home. Literally and figuratively. Twenty years ago, I was still sleeping in my room on Gatestone Avenue in Oakville. While I had lived on my own at university, and while I was on my co-op work terms in Ottawa, staying at home was &#8230; comfortable. And as my parents didn&#8217;t object, it seemed like a good idea. Literally leaving home wasn&#8217;t the problem &#8212; I&#8217;d already done it a dozen times.<br />
Figuratively leaving home &#8212; notably the familiarity of the Greater Toronto area, but Ontario in general &#8212; was another matter. I&#8217;d not really lived abroad, where going to my parents&#8217; house was something I did in an afternoon. I decided to throw myself into the world without any plan whatsoever.<br />
Twenty years on, it was the smartest move I ever made.<br />
<span id="more-3621"></span><br />
Toronto is often derided as the &#8220;centre of Canada&#8221;. It&#8217;s the largest city, and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_Toronto_Area" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greater Toronto area</a> has around six million people, roughly one sixth the entire population of Canada. It&#8217;s a massive economic base &#8212; most of the banks are headquartered there &#8212; so there&#8217;s a significant amount of perceived power &#8230; and utter disregard for the Rest of Canada.<br />
This is the mentality I grew up with, and the one I carried with me when I moved to Vancouver. Until that point, I&#8217;d only visited Vancouver twice: both times in the prior five months to moving away. I&#8217;d experienced only a brief glimpse of Vancouver and what it would do to me.<br />
So why did I move? In a way: complacency, though I didn&#8217;t really recognize that at the time. I had a job in Toronto, I had my family, I had my friends. What I didn&#8217;t have was &#8230; <em>something</em>. To this day, I genuinely don&#8217;t know what it was that I was missing, nor do I think I&#8217;ve found it in the 20 years since. But I knew that I wasn&#8217;t going to find it in Toronto.<br />
In the span of only a few weeks, I packed up what little I considered as &#8220;my life&#8221;, threw it in a bag and a couple of boxes, packed myself into a cramped Canada 3000 plane, and soon found myself wandering Granville Street asking myself: &#8220;Now what?&#8221;<br />
No plan, no expectations, no worries. And at a mere 25 years old, I had enough education and experience under my belt to know I&#8217;d find a job (though I didn&#8217;t know where), I&#8217;d find a place to live (something I can definitely say would be a problem if I were doing that today), and things would somehow figure themselves out. Oh, the wonderful naiveness of my youth!<br />
Twenty years on, I have a family of my own. I&#8217;ve been many places, I done many things, and yet &#8212; to quote U2 &#8212; I still haven&#8217;t found what I&#8217;m looking for. I&#8217;ve had to create a plan (several, really), and I have to set expectations (both with myself, and with others), and my worries &#8230; well, I think I&#8217;d terrify poor 25 year-old me. Relatedly, to answer the question of &#8220;what would I tell a younger me, if I could&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>You are coming to a lot of mountains. Some you will have to cross over, some you can travel under. But you will always get to the other side, and there will always be loved ones there for you.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah, I know, it&#8217;s  wishy-washy. Why not tell myself the truth? Because I love my life. For all the hell I periodically go through, I can&#8217;t imagine it any other way. It&#8217;s a classic science-fiction trope: one little change in the past could dramatically alter your future. Could be for the better, could be for the worse. I like what I have, and I&#8217;d like of like to keep it that way.<br />
Actually, slight correction: I like what I have, but there are many days when I long for things of the last. People I miss, places I&#8217;ve been, or in the case of earlier today, when I didn&#8217;t have to cook or clean the dishes in the carefree days of my youth. Right now, Monkey and Choo Choo are playing in the room next to me with their LEGOs, and I miss those days. Responsibility weighs heavily.<br />
And while we&#8217;re at it, exactly <em>who</em> left me have my own kids, anyway? I mean, my wife is a fairly significant part, but anyone who truly knows me will wonder what reasonable agency allowed me to reproduce. It&#8217;s been a decade of that, and I still have this strange feeling that some strange agent will appear at my door, saying I broke some kind of law.<br />
Until that day, I&#8217;ll just take the things I could have told my younger self &#8230; and tell them to my kids. They haven&#8217;t had their futures yet (barring the presence of time loops that haven&#8217;t made themselves present), so hopefully I can impart some of that wisdom so their mountains aren&#8217;t so tall, the snow drifts aren&#8217;t so deep, and that they know what&#8217;s waiting for them on the other side before they even start climbing.<br />
If they listen, that is. They&#8217;re definitely my kids: know-it-alls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things I have missed about summer in Ontario</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/07/things-i-have-missed-about-summer-in-ontario/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=things-i-have-missed-about-summer-in-ontario</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/07/things-i-have-missed-about-summer-in-ontario/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 17:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m currently in Ontario, taking the opportunity to visit with my family. It&#8217;s always a strange feeling to come back here: it&#8217;s where I was born and grew up, but I&#8217;ve been gone for over 15 years. A lot has changed. You really can&#8217;t go home again. That&#8217;s not to say that I entirely like &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/07/things-i-have-missed-about-summer-in-ontario/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Things I have missed about summer in Ontario"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m currently in Ontario, taking the opportunity to visit with my family. It&#8217;s always a strange feeling to come back here: it&#8217;s where I was born and grew up, but I&#8217;ve been gone for over 15 years. A lot has changed. You really can&#8217;t go home again.<br />
That&#8217;s not to say that I entirely like or dislike the way things currently are. I&#8217;m a bit indifferent, I guess. This is now some place for me to go to, to visit, but not where I feel particularly rooted. That&#8217;s what change does to you, I suppose.<br />
That said, there are some things that I do miss.<br />
<span id="more-3504"></span><br />
One of the first things I missed was my family. A bit of a well, duuuuh! for some of you, I&#8217;m sure. These are people who know me well, who I can&#8217;t deceive in the slightest. There are no walls, no barriers. Openness and honesty is the only option, and painful it may periodically be, it&#8217;s always necessary and cathartic. There&#8217;s no blame or regret. I&#8217;m thankful for it each time, and especially this time.<br />
Next are my friends, whom I miss their company, and frequently miss getting to see when I&#8217;m out: too much going on, and not enough time. I worry that this visit will be no different, but with luck things will work in my favour.<br />
Then comes a weird one: bugs. Specifically cicadas and crickets. Alberta has mosquitoes, about the only bug other than bees, wasps, and houseflies that make any sound. Southern Ontario gets cicadas, and this seems to be a high year of their cycle: loud buzzing everywhere.<br />
This drives some people nuts. For me, though, it&#8217;s the sound of summer. The sound of being in my parent&#8217;s backyard, swinging on the swingset, playing in my sandpile, or swimming in the pool (yes, I had a pool growing up).<br />
In the evenings, after the sun went down, there were the crickets. I think I may miss the crickets more. Their chirps were my summertime lullaby, my reassurance that all was well with the world. I&#8217;ve never heard a single chirp in Alberta, I don&#8217;t even know if they exist out that way.<br />
The crickets came out on the warm nights, which were always my favourite ones to drive around at 2am from a friend&#8217;s place, taking the long way to enjoy the soft draft that came through the open windows as you cruised down some empty road.<br />
And, at least when I lived here, three warm nights (coming from hot, muggy days) usually netted a whip-cracking thunderstorm that would rattle windows, and light up the darkest curtains for hours on end. I so dearly mIss watching the bolts from the kitchen window with my mom. The mornings after were always damp and crisp.<br />
If I had to into Toronto during the day, I took a GO Train. Thirty-five years on, you&#8217;ll still hear the conductor asking you to &#8220;stand clear of the doors, please&#8221;. There&#8217;s something wonderfully sane that it&#8217;s still done by a real person, and not a recording.<br />
And since this is <i>me</i> that we&#8217;re discussing, let&#8217;s also mention the things I don&#8217;t miss:<br />
First up is that hot mugginess I mentioned earlier. Being near the Great Lakes led to a lot of humidity. Combine that with 35C temperatures, and it gets pretty uncomfortable pretty quick. I&#8217;ve been damp with sweat since I stepped off the plane a few days ago. The only time I&#8217;ve been less comfortable was Hong Kong.<br />
And I would be remiss not to mention the traffic. Dear God, the traffic! (I took the GO Train not just because it was a train.) I genuinely do not understand people who drive when they have a choice to <i>not.</i><br />
Especially on Hwy 400 northbound on a long weekend. Which I currently am (but I&#8217;m not actually driving).<br />
So those of you in Calgary who complaint about the Deerfoot? Try Yonge and the 401 sometime, and then try to convince me that the Anderson road interchange is the worst thing ever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/07/things-i-have-missed-about-summer-in-ontario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3504</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Hazy Burlington</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-hazy-burlington</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 13:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our last day in Calgary &#8212; yesterday &#8212; was filled mostly by me repacking all of our bags so we could fly out, and then the actual travel here to Burlington, Ontario. We&#8217;re here to visit with family (today is Alex&#8217;s family reunion) before we leave for Costa Rica. Or face the long-distance wrath of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "In Hazy Burlington"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our last day in Calgary &#8212; yesterday &#8212; was filled mostly by me repacking all of our bags so we could fly out, and then the actual travel here to Burlington, Ontario. We&#8217;re here to visit with family (today is Alex&#8217;s family reunion) before we leave for Costa Rica.<br />
Or face the long-distance wrath of scorned relations&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-1022"></span>We have four large pieces of luggage, including  Alex&#8217;s large Air Canada bag and my backpack. In principle, I think we were supposed to be charged for taking more than one bag each (Air Canada&#8217;s policy dings you for each additional bag these days). But I was a bit of a dink yesterday. Air  Canada&#8217;s so-called efficient process has you check-in at kiosks first, and then you get into a line to talk to an agent. Why? Seriously? It&#8217;s really silly to have to check-in twice &#8212; which is effectively what that process is. At any rate, I ended up bypassing it because of flying with an infant, and managed to  actually check in at a clerk&#8217;s desk before the line suddenly exploded with about 100 people.  <br />
The flight out wasn&#8217;t too bad. I find they&#8217;re slowly getting better again, but they&#8217;re still only reaching back up to the point where WestJet has always been.  Air Canada will never return to its former glory &#8212; domestically-speaking &#8212; but at least I&#8217;ll be able to  likely  fly them again without  all my bitching about their service level.<br />
The new Toronto Pearson terminal is massive. Huge.  Totally forgot how big it is.  Getting out was surprisingly easy, although Avis had run out of the small car we had reserved, and &#8220;upgraded&#8221; us to a Chrysler 300. This is not an upgrade in my world. This is cruel and  inhuman torture. It&#8217;s a boat.  I feel like I should be looking at a radar display to make sure I&#8217;m not going to run aground. It&#8217;s way more car than we need. And no,  Mr. Desk Clerk,  despite what your fancy chart says, a Nissan Versa actually does have a bigger trunk. Or at least it fit our bags better.<br />
It&#8217;s humid, stick, and hazy here.  But it smells  just like I remember as a kid. I always loved summer in Ontario. Except for the heat and humidity, that is. Forty degrees with the humidex. Ugh.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting my Birth Certificate shouldn&#039;t be this hard</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 19:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One part of moving to any other country is the act of applying for a work visa. It&#8217;s pretty much a requirement where treaties (e.g. the European Union) aren&#8217;t there to ease the situation. A necessary evil, if you will. Because in most cases, the process is not really well documented and you&#8217;re going to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Getting my Birth Certificate shouldn&#039;t be this hard"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One part of moving to any other country is the act of applying for a work visa. It&#8217;s pretty much a requirement where treaties (e.g. the European Union) aren&#8217;t there to ease the situation. A necessary evil, if you will. Because in most cases, the process is not really well documented and you&#8217;re going to spend a lot of time trying to figure out exactly what you need.<br />
And believe me, we are far from actually getting this one sorted out. Jason&#8217;s been a massive force in getting us some iota closer to having it done, but the reality is that we&#8217;re going to be flying by the seats of our pants until documentation is actually done.<br />
<span id="more-995"></span>One thing we need for an application is a birth certificate. But not the one you put in your wallet. You need the big one. Where you were born, your birth weight and time, who your parents are and where they were born, the name of the hospital and the doctor who delivered you. Might as well ask for my life history, while you&#8217;re at it.<br />
I don&#8217;t have this form. Nor does my mother. No problem, though, in this day-and-age, you need only sign onto a website and order one. Right?<br />
Service Ontario has a pretty slick system, I&#8217;ll give them that. But here&#8217;s my #1 major fault with it. I already have a birth certificate. I&#8217;m on record. I have a card in my wallet with a number on it that (I presume) uniquely identifies me.<br />
But it doesn&#8217;t mean sqwat. I have to fill out the form as if I&#8217;m a new birth. I have no idea how much I weighed when I was born. No idea who the doctor was (Mom remembered, though &#8212; proves you aren&#8217;t going senile!). I even had to provide a guarantor. What the heck??<br />
Ordered, though. Should get it in about five days. Then we have to get eight passport pictures, marriage certificate, and a few other things to get our visas sorted out. Yeesh. I foresee a lot of flying in my future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Middle Ontario wedding</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-middle-ontario-wedding</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 04:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/07/08/a-middle-ontario-wedding/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My friend Kathryn got married this weekend. A truly wonderful event that forced my hand to leave the comfort of my familiar Cowtown (and miss the opening of the Calgary Stampede) to visit rural Ontario and experience the joyous event. I gotta say, probably the most relaxful weekend I&#8217;ve had in &#8230; well, a really &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Middle Ontario wedding"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/kathryn-and-andreas-wedding/">My friend Kathryn got married this weekend.</a> A truly wonderful event that forced my hand to leave the comfort of my familiar Cowtown (and miss the opening of the Calgary Stampede) to visit rural Ontario and experience the joyous event.<br />
I gotta say, probably the most relaxful weekend I&#8217;ve had in &#8230; well, a really long time.<br />
<span id="more-766"></span>It started with a fairly hectic departure on Thursday afternoon. Alex drove me to the airport, I had to run out to a flight, which although I made with a bit of time to spare, ended up being late no thanks to the caterers. (In other words, less food on the plane than there should have been.)<br />
And although I flew Air Canada &#8212; [[Air Canada sucks|perhaps my least favourite airline]] &#8212; I had a really good experience. I was pleasantly surprised. Still, I&#8217;ll fly WestJet because I like it. Arrived in Toronto, checked into the airport Sheraton, and had a good night&#8217;s sleep.<br />
The following day, I picked up my rental car, and proceeded to drive out to Beaverton. The Ford Focus has been a decent car, though I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d run out and buy one. It&#8217;s okay, but far from perfect.<br />
The drive took my through stomping grounds not trampled in many years. I turned north in Whitby (having accidentally gone as far as Oshawa) up Highway 12.<br />
As soon as I felt I was out of the urban area, I turned off the air conditioning, rolled down the windows, and turned my iPod to play nothing but <em>The Tragically Hip</em>. It&#8217;s been years since I did this. I&#8217;d been thinking of it for a couple of weeks, and it was a thoroughly liberating experience to blare over 15 years&#8217; of music as I blasted through the plains of rural Ontario. How I missed the experience.<br />
Along the way, I found a few abandoned rail lines (I need to figure out which they were), back roads, and small towns I&#8217;d never been to (or through). <a href="http://www.beavertononlakesimcoe.com/">Beaverton </a>itself is a rather interesting little place, and the sort of place you would buy a small cottage for weekend (or summer) escapes. This is where Andrea&#8217;s parents have retired to, though they&#8217;re not even in Beaverton proper, prefering more remote locations.<br />
I actually got lost finding the place. Well, not lost per se, but I definitely overshot  where I needed to be by 15 clicks or so. Rather embarrassing for someone  who would normally pride themselves on knowing where they were and where they were going. (See, hon, I&#8217;m saying I was wrong. Take note of this!)<br />
Imaging driving up a corduroy road. Weeds standing shoulder high. No ferris wheel rusting off in the distance, but there&#8217;s not much else. Suddenly, there&#8217;s a break in the bush at the side of the road. The path is full of stones turned white from age and abuse. It looks like danger to go down it. At the end is a clearing with a gorgeous brick farmhouse, manicured lawns, and enough clear cut grass to park cars.<br />
This is where all the fun took place. And it was only as I came into the  yard that I realised something I had not thought of before:<br />
Would I know anyone there?<br />
It dawned on me that aside from Kathryn&#8217;s family &#8212; who barely recognised me in the 12-odd years since I last saw them &#8212; I didn&#8217;t know anyone. I was one of the oldest friends Kathryn had there. If not the oldest. I feel old just <em>thinking </em>about it! But as I talked with Maureen &#8212; Kathryn&#8217;s mom &#8212; I spied the names of Gerry and Sam, mutual friends whom I&#8217;d met through Chris years ago. (Gerry and I had done a trans-Canada trip back in 1997, and I went their <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/gerry-and-sam/">wedding in 2001</a>.)<br />
At least I wasn&#8217;t alone.<br />
Although I was uncomfortable in the heat (not as bad as [[Je suis en Paris, Jour Trois!|Paris last summer]]), the ceremony was wonderful, the food excellent, and I had a great time catching up with my old friends. It had been a very long time since I&#8217;d had a good chat with Gerry and Sam. Just made me remember why I like them so much.<br />
The night carried on and soon dinner was over, the dancing begun, and the mosquitoes were out in swarms. We lathered up with repellent to prevent severe blood loss, but even that wasn&#8217;t enough for some.<br />
I met up with Marika, Kathryn&#8217;s friend for many years [[Kathryn comes for a visit|whom had stayed at Chris&#8217; and my apartment back in 2001]]. She in turn pointed out Bryce, whom I&#8217;d met the night of the Camelot show.<br />
Insert singing dolls here.<br />
I had to leave around 22:00, as I still had 90 minutes to drive. I wasn&#8217;t going back towards the airport, but up to Huntsville to hang out with my family for the rest of the weekend. (I figured I had to make the most of the time.)<br />
I said goodbye to Gerry and Sam, which seemed such a shame &#8212; I rarely get to see or chat to them and leaving so soon just seemed so wrong. I was sorry to say goodbye to Kathryn as well, since I&#8217;d barely had a chance to talk to her. I wasn&#8217;t the furthest away to come (Marika beat me &#8212; she came from Vancouver), but it&#8217;s still hard to see someone only a short while.<br />
The drive up to Huntsville was punctuated by road signs I could barely read, drivers who seemed to not know where they were going, and the need for high beams so I could see in the intense black of the northern Ontario night. At the end, Craig was waiting for me with a beer.<br />
In a weird way, it was sort of home. In a very confused, fast-paced, intense, and long-distance way, that is.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603438536698, tag: 2007+july[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">766</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Up at the cottage</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=up-at-the-cottage</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 03:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/07/08/up-at-the-cottage/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, I had the chance to go stay with my sister and brother-in-law&#8217;s cottage near Huntsville, ON. It&#8217;s been a long time since I was last there, and it was good to see my family one last time before it expands again by one. I really need to get out there more often. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Up at the cottage"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, I had the chance to go stay with my sister and brother-in-law&#8217;s cottage near Huntsville, ON. It&#8217;s been a long time since I was last there, and it was good to see my family one last time before it expands again by one.<br />
I really need to get out there more often.<br />
<span id="more-767"></span>Aside from the additional sleep (the beds are comfy, and there&#8217;s no distractions &#8212; except for stomping toddlers, and flushing toilets), it&#8217;s good to get away from cities to remember what it&#8217;s like to be &#8220;away from it all&#8221;.<br />
The cottage country mentality in Ontario is a tough one to understand if you&#8217;ve never lived there. Everyone wants to get away from Toronto on a regular basis. For some, it&#8217;s just living outside of Toronto. For others, it&#8217;s getting away from the Golden Horseshoe, to experience something unique and different.<br />
About three hours is your limit for effectiveness. Less than that, and you&#8217;re not far enough away. Toronto extends (almost) from its shores on Lake Ontario all the way to Barrie. If you can&#8217;t pass Barrie, you&#8217;re at risk of being a subdivision. Everything else needs to be further.<br />
That puts you in the Muskokas. That&#8217;s three hours (ish) away. It&#8217;s a long haul, without being truly annoying. Well, if you&#8217;re on your own, anyway. With bawling toddler, that might be another issue. For me, no biggie.<br />
Besides, I got to be with my family. I don&#8217;t see them nearly enough, and being with Cathy, Mom, Craig, and Tori was a great time. I wished Alex could have been with us, but Alex isn&#8217;t really in a state to fly that far &#8212; it&#8217;s a tough slog when you&#8217;re 35 weeks pregnant. Heck, it&#8217;s almost a tough slog for me!<br />
It&#8217;s almost time for me to head back to Alberta, but I thought I&#8217;d toss in a few pictures of the weekend just past&#8230;<br />
[flickr]set:72157603442812417,tag:2007[/flickr][flickr]set:72157603438559316,tag:2007[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day of Visitation</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/day-of-visitation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=day-of-visitation</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/day-of-visitation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 01:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/12/28/day-of-visitation/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alex slept better in a king-size hotel bed. Not so much for myself. I was tired. Grumpy. Irritable. That&#8217;s why I was particularly annoyed with the complete and utter disappearance of my deodorant (which I know I had with me) and two T-shirts. They&#8217;ve totally disappeared. I have no idea what the heck has happened &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/day-of-visitation/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Day of Visitation"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex slept better in a king-size hotel bed. Not so much for myself. I was tired. Grumpy. Irritable.<br />
That&#8217;s why I was particularly annoyed with the complete and utter disappearance of my deodorant (which I <em>know</em> I had with me) and two T-shirts. They&#8217;ve totally disappeared. I have no idea what the heck has happened to them.<br />
<span id="more-593"></span>Breakfast was very simple: cereal and a bagel. I&#8217;d have killed for a slice of process cheese, if that&#8217;s all I could have gotten. Breads aren&#8217;t what I really like, but I&#8217;ll take it if that&#8217;s all there is. We retreated to bed for a bit more sleep, which really didn&#8217;t help. The shower did, though.<br />
The missing items weren&#8217;t at Janice&#8217;s, and a quick sanity check proved they had in fact gone MIA. This mystery is going to bug me for a long time to come.<br />
We drove down to St. Thomas after picking up Janice and ate at the Beanery, a lovely little bistro that serves a decent BBQ pulled pork sandwich. Now don&#8217;t get me wrong, it&#8217;s nothing compared to the authentic versions you get in the True South, but for a small town in Southern Ontario, it wasn&#8217;t bad.<br />
This was my first ever exposure to the Railway Capital of Canada. Once upon a time, St. Thomas was the most active hub in Canada for rail, sporting no less than eight separate rail lines. Today that&#8217;s dropped to only CN, CP, and maybe the GEXR. NYC is gone, L&amp;PS is little more than a tourist railroad, and CASO is now a mere memory. Maps still mark where most of the rails were, though only a few there can remember the glory days.<br />
I&#8217;m convinced beyond doubt that I was born about four decades too late. I could imagine being out in winter on a snowy night, listening to the slow moans and whistles of steam trains on the various lines as they moved around in the dark. All I saw today were a pair of Union Pacific diesels, no doubt burning up time on service with CP. The steam locomotives on the Port Stanley railway are locked up for the winter.<br />
After lunch, we dropped Janice off at the Presbyterian church and went off quickly to visit Alex&#8217;s grandmother&#8217;s grave &#8212; also the site where her grandfather will be buried on Friday. Sadly, I will not see the funeral, as I need to head home to ensure that the Rolex redesign continues on schedule. Work has a nasty habit of wreaking havoc on my life.<br />
We attended the afternoon visitation. I recognized Kinella and Dugald, Janice&#8217;s sister and brother. The last time I&#8217;d seen them was our wedding reception in Oakville in September last year. The six of us (including Dugald&#8217;s wife) met about fifty or so people who came in to pay respects to Kenneth Campbell, a man I never met and whom I regret never knowing. He seemed like quite the man, and I&#8217;m sure he had many stories to tell. Such are the twists of fate in life.<br />
After the reception, Alex and I did a bit of touring around town before heading off to London so I could catch a train. I need to be on a plane tomorrow morning at 7:00. Originally, the funeral was scheduled for today, and this wasn&#8217;t a problem. The changing of times threw me off and all I&#8217;ve been able to do is attend the visitation. Once again, I miss the chance to meet more of Alex&#8217;s family.<br />
Dinner was at a place called J. Dee&#8217;s Market Grill. The &#8220;Market Grill&#8221; refers to the Covent Market Garden across the street. The Grill serves little more than hamburgers. Very good ones, I should add. But the selection is, shall we say, light?<br />
Timing was tight, but I made the train. As you&#8217;ve already seen in the previous rant, the internet access doesn&#8217;t seem to work properly. Someone else has theirs working, though, so I&#8217;ll have to try again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/day-of-visitation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">593</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Merry Old London (Ontario)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-merry-old-london-ontario</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 03:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/12/27/in-merry-old-london-ontario/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We arrived last night, around 20:00 local time. A quick run through the airport, and we were tracking through the back country out to Janice&#8217;s place in Kintore. The house was cool (old farm houses tend to lack a lot of insulation or it mostly needs to be replaced) so Alex was a little chilly &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "In Merry Old London (Ontario)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We arrived last night, around 20:00 local time. A quick run through the airport, and we were tracking through the back country out to Janice&#8217;s place in Kintore.<br />
The house was cool (old farm houses tend to lack a lot of insulation or it mostly needs to be replaced) so Alex was a little chilly most of the time. We watched <em><a href="http://us.imdb.com/title/tt0479647/">Bon Cop Bad Cop</a></em> until around midnight or so (22:00 our time) before we were tired enough to go to sleep. I&#8217;d picked it up during what will be my last bout of Boxing Day sales. They&#8217;re hardly sales, since most of the prices (for the things I wanted) were still steep.<br />
<span id="more-591"></span>The cool house required several layers of blankets for warmth. I slept reasonably well. Alex didn&#8217;t, though more due to an inability to breathe. Janice&#8217;s house, in addition to being older, is much more humid (Ontario weather), dusty (due to age and size), and has two cats Alex&#8217;s immune system is unfamiliar with. End result: up much of the night.<br />
After giving up on trying to start Janice&#8217;s car, we got a lift from her neighbour back to the airport to pick up a rental car: a Dodge Calibur. We hadn&#8217;t asked for the Calibur &#8212; that&#8217;s what we were given. That&#8217;s what Enterprise defines as a &#8220;small car&#8221;. It&#8217;s certainly not the smallest thing on the roads, but it made for a comfortable ride out to Oakville. We figured it was a good chance to visit with family.<br />
Our first stop was at Burlington Mall to get Alex&#8217;s cousin Tara&#8217;s new baby a present. Then it was a 20 minute stop at Tara&#8217;s house before proceeding to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s. Tori was not in a mood to see us at all, and regularly ran away from both Alex and I. Turmoil is wreaking havoc with her, due to Craig working for the last several weeks in Windsor and Tori starting in day care so Cathy can go back to work.<br />
Our visit was too short, as always. We came in, chatted with Cathy and Craig, headed over to Mom&#8217;s for dinner for almost three hours, then were back on the road by 19:30 heading to London. Alex seems far more comfortable with driving in Southern Ontario than I am. Maybe I&#8217;ve become less tolerant of long-distance drives?<br />
Stopping briefly at Janice&#8217;s house again, we dropped off cat food and a new electric heating pad before heading off to the Quality Suites hotel in south London for the night. Alex needs her rest, and a room free of airborne irritants is important. Tomorrow, we join the rest of Alex&#8217;s family in St. Thomas for visitation. At some point, I&#8217;ve got to get back to Oakville for my flight home. Not sure yet how I&#8217;m going to do that&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting my niece for the first time</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/05/23/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spent most of last week in Critical Mass&#8217; Toronto office. I was there primarily to support our technical team, which hasn&#8217;t had the level of support from me that it&#8217;s been needing. So I went out to try and reestablish my presence other than &#8220;that guy in Calgary&#8221;. The trip was successful, though I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Meeting my niece for the first time"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent most of last week in Critical Mass&#8217; Toronto office. I was there primarily to support our technical team, which hasn&#8217;t had the level of support from me that it&#8217;s been needing. So I went out to try and reestablish my presence other than &#8220;that guy in Calgary&#8221;.<br />
The trip was successful, though I have yet to type up all my findings. That&#8217;s going to take a bit longer, as I&#8217;m sure to be put on the spot for a variety of must-do activities for this week. C&#8217;est la vie, though.<br />
<span id="more-437"></span>I didn&#8217;t return to Calgary with Paul on Thursday, though. I stuck around for the weekend, as I&#8217;d already planned to be in Oakville for the weekend. Back in January, my family expanded by one with the birth of my niece. Since then, Alex and I had tried to figure out when the best time was to go out and visit. As such planning tends to go, it was arduous, difficult, and ultimately it came down to picking a weekend and going. It would be barely over a week since returning from the UK and Ireland.<br />
Turns out it was the best thing for me. Returning from the UK wasn&#8217;t easy for me. As I discovered last year, it&#8217;s very easy to get into the travel groove. The constant stimulation is amazing, almost addictive. Coming down is ugly, often fettered with depression. The last thing I wanted to be dealing with is wishing I were somewhere else, when I need to concentrate on the here-and-now. So changing quickly from Calgary to Toronto actually turned out to be a benefit. Get some travel in me, but set me up for being home.<br />
Then there was seeing my neice for the first time. Cathy and Craig met me at the train station (literally next door to Mom&#8217;s condo) pushing around their daughter in a carriage to help her sleep. Small, adorable, and looking more like her father than her mother. It wasn&#8217;t until we got into the condo and she woke up that she first saw me.<br />
And immediately smiled.<br />
Now it could be argued that a child of her age (barely four months) does not have the ability to fully discern who she&#8217;s seeing or how specifically to react. I&#8217;m sure hundreds of reports have been written about the mental processes of a newborn, and that most of them strongly doubt the ability to recognize things definitively. But there&#8217;s also a case for the potential for genetic memory &#8212; that it&#8217;s possible to recognize features through genetic programming.<br />
It&#8217;s a thought.<br />
Meeting my niece gave me pause. Partly because I&#8217;ve never really been comfortable around babies, but because this is a new life in my family. Unlike all the other babies I&#8217;ve been around, she&#8217;s related to me. Not through marriage, but by blood. Genetically similar. It&#8217;s a different thing to see a cute baby, and then see a baby you&#8217;re related to. (And Mom thinks she looks like I did at her age. Cathy doubts it. I&#8217;m undecided.) But it&#8217;s a cool effect, too. You feel a certain amount of attachment to her.<br />
I held her only once while there &#8212; she still depends greatly on Cathy for support. And I tried to comfort her when they drove us out to the airport &#8212; she doesn&#8217;t like her car seat very much &#8212; but I&#8217;m not the fatherly type just yet. I felt bad, though. All that pain, and no way for me to remove it.<br />
Parenthood. The next great adventure. I wonder what it has in store for me, when it finally happens. I know I&#8217;ll never be ready for it, and it will change my life. I guess if nothing else, I worry mostly about failing at it. Only time will tell, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 04:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/12/31/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day. So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day.<br />
So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 on the morning of 23 December, catching the end of a nasty two-day snowstorm. There&#8217;s poetic justice in this, somewhere.<br />
<span id="more-480"></span>Due to the weather, Cathy (wisely) opted not to come and get me at the airport. Instead, I took a limo (for the extra five dollars, it was worth the comfort) out to Oakville. Since Cathy had to go into work, and I didn&#8217;t have a key to her house, I went to Mom&#8217;s place instead. Cathy had already called her to let her know I was coming, before I called her to let her know I was coming.<br />
I made myself a light breakfast, and then let the red eye flight catch up with me, passing out in Mom&#8217;s bed with my jacket over my head to block out light and sound. Mom and I hung out for a while, then went and ran some errands, concluding with a very lousy lunch at the Tim Horton&#8217;s at the former Trafalgar Village (I have no idea what it&#8217;s called now). The place used to be a Burger King years ago, and was pretty lousy then, too.<br />
I eventually ended up at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s, dumping my things off before the four of us congregated at Mom&#8217;s again for dinner. Ribs, one of my favourites.<br />
During dinner, I decided it was time to let my family know that things were about to change for me. I stated: &#8220;Official annoucement time!&#8221; and declared that they not make any plans for 27 August 2005. This is the day Alex and I will be married. No-one was particularly surprised, and everyone seemed happy about it. This, of course, made me feel happy about it, because I was getting more than a little anxious about the whole thing. Blessings are what I needed most. The happiness I already had.<br />
&#8216;Twas the day before Christmas, and I had a few things left to do, most of which was buying a couple of last-minute presents (most notably for Craig, whom I was having trouble finding). This brought Cathy and I to Oakville Place, barely a kilometre from their house.<br />
Since Oakville Place was first built, I&#8217;d hated it. Originally, I disliked it because of the 100-odd stores in the mall, over 80 of them were dedicated to women&#8217;s fashions. For a teenaged boy, this was about as interesting as &#8230; well, a mall full of stores that had no interest to me. In later years, I came to revile it due to its marked resemblance to a two-storey strip mall. It was meant to look bright and wonderful, but its design left much to be desired.<br />
Recently, Oakville Place underwent a significant overhaul, culminating with a complete change of food courts (the old one is gone, a new, larger one is on the second floor in the new &#8220;wing&#8221;), several new stores (including &#8212; GASP! &#8212; an HMV), and a few other changes. The pit in the centre under the clock has been gone many a-year, but following it are the two fountains that used to exist at either end of the main section under the stairs. The stores are actually nicer than I remember (with a few exceptions), and it feels more like a mall than an oversized women&#8217;s fashion store.<br />
Dinner that night was not at Mom&#8217;s or at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s. For this, we would travel across town to Mark and Darla&#8217;s. This was the first time that I would see Mark and Darla&#8217;s home (completed; I saw it over a year ago &#8212; see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion]]). I hadn&#8217;t really seen them since Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding.<br />
Mark had invited us over for Christmas Eve dinner, which would be roast beef and yorkshire pudding (which Cathy would make, following the time-honoure recipe that came with the roast pans Dad bought in the States eons ago). This, I looked forward to. I *love* roast beef, especially when prepared by those passionate about it.<br />
Mark and Darla&#8217;s home is quite beautiful. Very tastefully decorated, and already full of the smells of dinner. We were a bit late in arriving, which meant that dinner was well on the way to being ready. Also in attendance were Julie and Dave, whom I hadn&#8217;t seen for almost as long as the last time I saw Mark and Darla. We settled into conversation before we were called to the dinner.<br />
The first round was a smashing corn chowder. That was followed by the roast beef, onions and parsnips, yorkshires, mashed potatoes, and peas. Dessert was a mousse cake from &#8220;La Petit Gateau&#8221;, which is either a really neat little pastry shop, or an in-joke about a supermarket that I never got filled in on. Either way, all was very tasty. Mark went all out.<br />
Even moreso when Cathy, Mom, and I recognized what Mark wore around his neck. When Mark was first going to Appleby College, it was Dad who had taught Mark how to tie a tie. When we were cleaning out Dad&#8217;s things after his death, Cathy had given Mark one of Dad&#8217;s trademark paisley ties. It was this tie that Mark wore over dinner. Given how the meal turned out, I would hedge to bet that Dad had shown up just to give a little advice.<br />
Following dinner was a game &#8212; Scene It. This neat little game includes a DVD that you use as part of the questions. Mark had played it before, but the rest of us had not. We split into four teams: Mark, Darla and Julie (Dave had gone to bed, a victim of a 38-hour day), Cathy and Craig, and Mom and myself. Owing to a series of fortunate rolls and good questions, Mom and I finished the game when the others were about half-way through. (I hate to say it, but they were up against a movie geek. I really wonder how Chris, Stuart, and I would fare against each other.) The others finished neck-in-neck.<br />
Cathy, Craig, and I would stay up a bit late that night, talking about generally nothing (Cathy blaring loud music) before we all went to bed.<br />
Mom arrived around 9:00 the next morning for Christmas day. Her only stipulation was that she wanted to be home before 13:00 to make the turkey. This would not be a problem. A new tradition was started with present unwrapping. In previous years, &#8220;Santa&#8221; (which was usually me) would hand out a present to each person, who would then unwrap it in turn. This year, Cathy and Craig instituted the &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; rule. Basically, they said &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; and everyone unwrapped. The 1-2-3s got progressively faster as the unwrapping progressed.<br />
Interestingly enough, most of the presents I got weren&#8217;t just for me &#8212; they were also for Alex. They included a picnic backpack (as opposed to a basket), a picnic blanket with inflatable headrests, a flashlight, and walkie-talkies. It wouldn&#8217;t be the only time I would regret Alex not being able to come out to Ontario. (She was at her father&#8217;s place in Ruskin.)<br />
Breakfast was a mom-saver: bread, eggs, cream cheese, and a lot of maple syrup. It cooked while we unwrapped. Mimosas washed it down well.<br />
Mom left just before 11:00 for home, while Cathy, Craig, and I wandered around the house. Hamilton Dave (formerly Scarborough Dave) arrived not long afterwards. He was joining us for dinner that night. The last time I&#8217;d seen him was at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding (see [[Cathy and Craig&#8217;s Wedding]]).<br />
The gifts kept coming. Dave received a clock from Cathy and Craig for his boat. In exchange, Cathy and Craig received heated cups for their car. This precipitated a test, where Craig took the remote thermometer, some hot water, and placed the mug in his car to see what would happen. (It works, for the record, but keeps the temperature rather than raise it.) Julie and Dave stopped by for a beer before heading onto other parts for the day.<br />
Dinner was at Mom&#8217;s. It seemed odd to be having dinner there, though I can&#8217;t really tell you why. Maybe because it&#8217;s not the house on Gatestone, where I&#8217;d had so many Christmas dinners before. Hopefully, Christmas dinner will be at our place next year!<br />
We got back and played Possumopoly (a parody of Monopoly based on the <em>Red Green</em> TV show). Craig is plain evil. We played until Dave pretty much passed out from all the beer.<br />
Boxing day was all about the board games. Cathy, Craig, and I played from noon almost all the way through until we went to bed. (It takes a long time to place the Ontario Trivia game.) More visitors passed through, including Mark and Darla. Walkie talkies were tested as Craig went out for supplies at the local convenience store. Pizza was our only other interruption.<br />
The next day, Mom and I went out for Greek for lunch. We then did a little shopping (including presents for Chris and Kaz &#8212; books on Canada, a subtle hint for him to move back). The party that night was the fifth (and hopefully final) wedding party for the two of them (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]] and [[Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba]]). I was literally the token white guy. Therese and Stuart couldn&#8217;t make it as they&#8217;d only arrived in town 10 minutes before the party started, and wanted to visit with family. Gerry was also in the area, but lines were crossed and our paths weren&#8217;t. I would miss out on Gerry&#8217;s presence this time around (Chris would catch up with him a couple days later).<br />
Oddly enough, none of these absences really bothered me &#8212; it gave me a lot of time to chat with Chris and Kaz. And joke with Kaz about being so cold. And I did get a chance to talk with Gerry the next morning.<br />
Chris, Kaz, and I met up with Stuart and Therese for dim sum the next morning. I picked up Chris and Kaz from Chris&#8217; parents&#8217; place, a rental while they wait for their new house to be built. It&#8217;s weird not seeing them in the house I knew. Weirder still was seeing Aidan, Therese and Stuart&#8217;s daughter. It&#8217;s still hard to believe my friends are reproducing. She&#8217;s a doctor (in psychiatry) and he&#8217;s an art director for a major ad firm. We&#8217;ve somehow all grown up. It&#8217;s kind of creepy, actually.<br />
Therese looked like herself again, assumedly due to the lack of a parasitic organism inside her. Stuart looked tired, but the new &#8216;do helped. Kaz wanted to smuggle Aidan back to Japan. We ate and talked for a long time. But eventually we had to part ways. I had to go home. I dropped Chris and Kaz at Clarkson station, not knowing when I&#8217;d see them next.<br />
I thought I&#8217;d done a great packing job, only to realize that I&#8217;d forgotten a few things. I had to steal a duffel bag from Craig to get it all home. Steak and Caesar salad &#8212; a Sowrey favourite &#8212; was my last supper before the flight. Despite a full, uncomfortable flight, Alex was waiting for me when I got back.<br />
I realized how much I&#8217;d missed her for the last few days. It was a realization that she is <em>The One</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">480</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
