<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>canadian club &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/canadian-club/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 04:15:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Spaghetti with Santa</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/spaghetti-with-santa/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=spaghetti-with-santa</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/spaghetti-with-santa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 04:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re a little slow on the draw &#8217;round here, folks &#8212; sorry about that! It&#8217;s been a little busy as of late, and trying to stay on top of news is more than a little challenging. Needless to say, gonna keep this one short. On Saturday, we went off to have Spaghetti with Santa. This &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/spaghetti-with-santa/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Spaghetti with Santa"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re a little slow on the draw &#8217;round here, folks &#8212; sorry about that! It&#8217;s been a little busy as of late, and trying to stay on top of news is more than a little challenging.<br />
Needless to say, gonna keep this one short.<br />
<span id="more-1174"></span>On Saturday, we went off to have Spaghetti with Santa. This was a charity event that was held at Big Mike&#8217;s, a guest house operation over in Escazu. The idea was to come out, have a simple lunch, take a photo of your kids sitting with Santa, with all the proceeds going to a local children&#8217;s fund.<br />
Despite the fact that this event seemed to be set up by gringos for gringos, the directions were in Spanish. Not being particularly familiar with the area, it took us a while to realise that Big Mike&#8217;s was actually inside a guarded neighbourhood. Our suspicions were confirmed when we saw actual signs that read &#8220;Spaghetti with Santa&#8221;.<br />
And this, dear reader, is where we hit the stereotypical part of parenting: Wanting to have a photo of your child with Santa, but only to have your child emit sounds of pure terror and desperately wanting to run away screaming from the big, creepy guy in the red suit. First attempt: Total wash.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t until after lunch that we tried again, which was met with inventiveness from Alex, myself, and Santa as we jostled to keep Mi Pequeña Niña calm long enough to take the picture. As it stands, the picture was hurried, Alex was cut partially out, and MPN looks towards Santa with a sort of &#8220;WHO THE HELL IS THIS GUY?!&#8221; kind of look.<br />
Success comes in small amounts.<br />
That evening, we had a second Christmas event. Though this one would be sans bebe, as we left our darling wonder in the hands of Mark, my co-worker and commuting buddy. Mark is still gloriously single, but shows an adeptness to children that I wish I had. MPN laughs constantly around Mark, because Mark has no compunction about being silly around children. It was only on (American) Thanksgiving a mere two weeks ago that he held his first baby &#8212; ours.<br />
That said, we loaded him up with pizza, Coca Lite, while Alex and I went off in search of the annual Canadian Club Christmas party, held this year at the Crowne Plaza to the north of La Sabana. Believe me, a far harder task than it sounds, as we found out (while driving) that the roads were diverted due to Christmas decoration, and that the entrance to the Crowne Plaza is anything but obvious. Such is life.<br />
There we met up with Meranda, one of Alex&#8217;s new friends, whom she met through the Costa Rica Parents website. Meranda seems to know everyone and everything, and is one of those people you keep on speed dial &#8216;cuz chances are she knows how to get you out of a tight spot. Or at least tell you what store to go to when you need molasses. (And no, I&#8217;m not kidding about the molasses.)<br />
The party was a dressier (and larger) version of the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/">Thanksgiving dinner</a> the Canadian Club held back in October. It was a chance to meet a few new people. Most of the people at our table were French Canadian (or at least were fluent in French). Alex and I were by far the newest arrivals to Costa Rica.<br />
Dinner was regrettably a dip from the October meal. By the time we finally got to approach the buffet, the turkey had been wiped out. The single slice of pork was okay, but far from completed my desire for turkey. I knew we should have bought one in the stores when we had the chance. Butterball or not, I&#8217;m having some issues not having turkey&#8230;<br />
There was a power outage while we were gone. It was obvious to us as we approached our complex, and we were met with an enveloping blackness that surrounded everything. It was more than a little creepy. The gate was wide open, and the magnetic locks on the building doors were not working. Poor Mark was left in a pitch-black room, with only his cell phone for light. (We hadn&#8217;t figured on a blackout, so had neglected to tell him where the candles are.)<br />
We might yet have more Christmas activities, but for now we&#8217;re mostly aiming towards New York City, which we fly to in under two weeks&#8217; time. It should be fun.<br />
And it better have turkey!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/spaghetti-with-santa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1174</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen. Thanksgiving &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thanksgiving in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen.<br />
Thanksgiving &#8212; for Canadians, anyway &#8212; comes on the second Monday of October. Officially, that&#8217;s today, but many Canadians tend to have the feast on the Sunday owing to a need to travel. And since Thanksgiving isn&#8217;t observed in Costa Rica (in fact, it&#8217;s barely known outside the expat community), it&#8217;s not even a blip on the radar.<br />
Which begs, of course, the question: How does one get their turkey fix?<br />
<span id="more-1134"></span>Well, luckily for us, there&#8217;s a whack of people who have that exact same problem, and are significantly better organised than we are at this point. They&#8217;re the <a href="http://www.canadianclubcr.com/">Canadian Club of Costa Rica</a>, a collection of former Canucks who want to preserve some of the feelings of home down here in the tropics. We&#8217;d first heard about them not long after first arriving, but hadn&#8217;t moved on anything due to the other aspects of trying to live here &#8230; like getting internet and a phone.<br />
I digress&#8230;<br />
Alex, though one of the other mothers in her playgroup, found out that the Canadian Club (why does this always <a href="http://www.canadianclubwhisky.com/">make me think of whisky</a>?) was holding a Thanksgiving &#8220;dinner&#8221; (more like a lunch) at &#8212; of all places &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/">Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo</a>, our (well, my) favourite bar in Santa Ana.<br />
The opportunity to sit down with other expats, chat, and have some turkey was rather appealing. So we signed up for a pair of seats. On Sunday, just after Mi Pequeña Niña woke up from her morning nap, we headed out to quell our turkey fix.<br />
A large Canadian flag was draped over one of the bushes out in front of the restaurant. Many of the people attending had to drive from much further distances, so it was helpful as a landmark. The restaurant was chosen (I think) mostly because the owner (I believe his name is &#8220;Paul&#8221;) is an expat from Vancouver.<br />
Upon entry, I quickly realised that the Canadian Club&#8217;s primary membership seems to be retirees. I hadn&#8217;t even considered that fact (rather stupidly!). Alex and I were among the youngest there &#8212; our daughter, included. Only two other children (no older than 10), and one couple that I could see that could have been in their late 20s.<br />
[flickr]tag:thanksgiving+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
We were at Table 13. Not the last table in the arrangement, but apparently the unluckiest &#8212; we were served last. We were seated with a man who&#8217;s been in Costa Rica about as long as I have (Steve) and his American friend, Jo. Jo has been here 17 years so seems more Costa Rican than she is American.<br />
It took a while for the MC to get everyone&#8217;s attention as the conversation just kept going. Ten minutes later, they were going over the details of the afternoon&#8217;s events (a funny hat contest, a raffle for a round-trip ticket on Continental, our meals, etc.), and that the Ambassador would be dropping by. It hadn&#8217;t even occurred to me that Canada&#8217;s ambassador to Costa Rica (whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten, and even Google can&#8217;t easily find it &#8212; bad architecture, Canada!) would come to such an affair. Nice guy, though. Flatlander from Saskatchewan.<br />
While we were waiting for things to get moving, we ordered up some beverages. I went with my usual Imperial (kind of hard to pass up on), Alex went with a white wine, Jo went with a Bavaria, and I think Steve only had club soda (Canada Dry Club Soda, to be precise). But we had to get ice &#8212; Alex&#8217;s wine came unchilled, and Jo seemed to like ice in her beer (a common practice here for some). The ice came in a large, red bucket with a pair of toothed metal tongs.<br />
MPN had fun for a while, laughing and giggling, but she didn&#8217;t take too well to being stuck in one place and not being able to walk around on her own. This happens frequently (usually after she&#8217;s finished eating, and especially on airplanes), and can sometimes lead to &#8230; incidents. Such as the one we had yesterday.<br />
Remember the ice bucket? What happens if you leave an uninsulated plastic bucket of ice out in a tropical climate? Right &#8212; you get water. Cold water.<br />
Ice cold water.<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña decided that the bucket would be fun to play with. (She does this with most things put in front of her, including (but not limited to) cutlery, glass bottles, plates, sunglasses, keys, paper, books, tablecloths, flowers &#8230; basically anything she can reach.) Sometimes she plays with those objects with other things in her hand, such as her small plastic feeding spoon. And sometimes, she gets just the right grip&#8230;<br />
Suddenly, I felt a wash of extreme cold in my lap. I thought she&#8217;d spilled her juice. Then I saw the bucket, heard MPN starting to scream (the shock got to her, too), and noticed that my lap was very wet. Ice cold, as it were.<br />
Lunch/dinner was actually pretty good, considering Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo isn&#8217;t exactly known for its Canuck cuisine. (It&#8217;s not known at all, to be frank.) But it was real turkey, with potatoes, stuffing (decent stuffing, at that), creamed beans, and cranberry jelly (which I fed to MPN). Dessert? Alex&#8217;s favourite &#8212; pumpkin pie.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stick around long after the meal was over. MPN was rapidly heading towards naptime, and the wetness of my shorts was finally getting to me.<br />
Sadly, not enough to induce turkey coma, but certainly better than if we&#8217;d gone with no turkey at all. I think we&#8217;re going to have to figure out how to get a turkey for Christmas, though &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to go another holiday without turkey. I honestly miss it too much, and there&#8217;s just such potential down here. With luck, we&#8217;ll be able to invite a few people over to make it worthwhile.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1134</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
