<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>red deer &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/red-deer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 15:04:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Red Eye Greyhound</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=red-eye-greyhound</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 15:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So when you last left me, dear reader, I was sitting in the Denny&#8217;s in Red Deer (the only place I could find that was open sufficiently late), biding my time before heading down to the Greyhound station to find my 3:00 (am) bus for Edmonton. I honestly wish I could spin a yarn of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Red Eye Greyhound"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So when you last left me, dear reader, I was sitting in the Denny&#8217;s in Red Deer (the only place I could find that was open sufficiently late), biding my time before heading down to the Greyhound station to find my 3:00 (am) bus for Edmonton.<br />
I honestly wish I could spin a yarn of difficulty, with a late, packed bus, screaming kids, barfing drunk people, a tired and beligerent driver, getting lost in who-knows-where Alberta before the engine gives out and stranding us in -15 C weather. I wish I could tell you that, because it would be a lot more interesting than what happened.<br />
I got on the bus at 3:07 (the bus was a wee bit late), and I got off just after 6:00 (I didn&#8217;t look at the clock). I had two seats to myself. No-one made a sound save for the driver, who was very nice about announcing arrivals, and drove very well (so far as I could tell, anyway &#8212; I was trying to get some sleep, which I think I managed). I arrived with my head attached.<br />
The worst part of this segment of the trip has been trying to find a decent place in Edmonton for breakfast. Your run-of-the-mill diner is hard to come by, though that&#8217;s likely due to the fact that it&#8217;s the downtown core, and not the funkier parts of town.<br />
But I sit here, in the Three Bananas Cafe (eating a breakfast sandwich), looking out on the Edmonton City Centre building in his purplish glow, watching the signs at the top of the CN building tracing out the company&#8217;s logo over and over.<br />
Yeah. Boring.<br />
Sorry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/red-eye-greyhound/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3228</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A musical evening in Red Deer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-musical-evening-in-red-deer</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A musical evening in Red Deer"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And I had good reason, y&#8217;know!<br />
Back in July, during the Calgary Stampede, the Tragically Hip played the Calgary Roundup, <em>the</em> outdoor concert of the year. I had wanted to go, but I totally messed up where the tickets were sold (stupid me, I thought it was Ticketmaster), and by the time I&#8217;d realised it &#8230; it was too late. Sold out, and I was out of luck.<br />
This is what brought me to Red Deer.<br />
<span id="more-3226"></span>I&#8217;ve been listening to the Tragically Hip since their <em>Road Apples</em> album, back in my last year(s) of high school. I was immediately hooked, and remained that way ever since. The only thing I hadn&#8217;t done is gone to a lot of their concerts. There was usually a reason, I assure you. My own idiocy aside, it was either bad timing (I wasn&#8217;t around/available), or was without someone to go with (while I may see a movie solo, a concert is an entirely different matter).<br />
So when the Hip announced Red Deer, I was quick to jump on getting tickets, this being the closest the Hip would come to Calgary this go around. Even with a presale code, the best I could do was 10th row on the floor (which, as it turns out, was still pretty darned good). My accomplice was a fellow former-Ontarioan, Scott &#8212; one of a few hundred Scotts that I seem to know.<br />
We left Calgary shortly before 15:00 for our just-over-an-hour jaunt north. (Alex and the kids had left nearly 90 minutes earlier for their trip to Alberta Beach &#8212; we meet up tomorrow in Edmonton. More on that in a moment&#8230;) The worst problem we had beyond some less-than-savoury other drivers was some fog that reduced visibility to about 200 metres or so. Once we were past Olds, it seemed to clear up.<br />
We arrived in Red Deer just after 16:00, and ran a couple of errands before holing up at the Toad and Turtle for a couple of hours of beer, nachos, and random conversation about &#8230; well, pretty much what you&#8217;d expect from a pair of geek programmer fathers who don&#8217;t get out enough. (If you are one, you&#8217;re nodding in agreement. If you&#8217;re not one, you probably don&#8217;t really want to know.)<br />
Westerner Park (an oddly named place, IMO) lay a mere click away, and we quickly found a place to park the car. We were soon accosted by another concert-goer &#8212; originally from Hamilton &#8212; who swore he was going to start a chant so the Hip would play <em>Wheat Kings</em>. He was rather pleased to hear that both Scott and I originally hail from Ontario.<br />
The concert venue is the two-tiered arena, primarily for the Red Deer Rebels, the local CHL team. So, as you can imagine, it&#8217;s not a big place. Which was completely fine with me. And so we waited for the opening act, to start at 20:00.<br />
Opening was a band called The Arkells, out of Hamilton. Until the concert had been announced, I hadn&#8217;t heard of the Arkells. The announcement, of course, drove both Scott and I to check out their music. Within 10 minutes, I&#8217;d bought both of their albums and put them onto heavy rotation. This was not for any form of preparation, this was solely because the albums were that good. I cannot think, in my musical history, of any band that has turned out albums so strong that I&#8217;m compelled to buy and listen constantly for nearly two weeks. Several of their songs are still on my frequently-listened playlists. (Side note: I swear some of their songs must be written for people who work in marketing&#8230;)<br />
Live? I was pretty much floored. Not only did the Arkells come out with a bang, they <em>refused</em> to let up. They got everyone on their feet, and they got the entire audience going. In terms of what an opening act should do, they did it far better than any opening act I&#8217;ve ever seen. It&#8217;s just a shame that their set was so short. I pray that they come to Calgary in the near future as a solo act, or with an opening act of their own.<br />
The intermission was short, filled with roadies racing across the stage to clean off the Arkell&#8217;s equipment, and make sure the Hip&#8217;s equipment was good to go. Shortly before 21:00, some fifteen and a half years since the last time I&#8217;d seen them, the Tragically Hip took stage to a roar. And they kept roaring for two-odd hours.<br />
It was sort of like listening to my own Tragically Hip playlist, which is a kind of &#8220;best of&#8221;. But live and loud, complete with Gord Downie&#8217;s interjections and rants, for which he is famous (though none as legendary as the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gjSyZslQp0w">Killer Whale Tank</a>, or of July&#8217;s Roundup concert, which should approach <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1N4AQGON5_o">the same level of epicness</a>, if you ask me).<br />
The encore was five songs, including <em>Wheat Kings</em>. I could hear the audience over the band. We were in the 10th row.<br />
Following the concert, Scott dropped me off where I now am, at the Denny&#8217;s on Gaetz, before he headed back to Calgary. Why am I still here? Well, remember how I said I&#8217;m meeting Alex and the kids in Edmonton? Well, I have to get there. Right now, they&#8217;re in Alberta Beach (google it, folks) visiting a friend. In a little over two hours, with luck, I&#8217;ll be boarding a Greyhound bus for Edmonton, arriving at 6:00.<br />
Yes, that&#8217;s 6:00 in the morning. Look at the datestamp folks, it&#8217;s after midnight.<br />
This is what&#8217;s led me to sitting in a back booth at the Denny&#8217;s, using their wifi, to &#8230; um &#8230; well, kill time. Then I can walk (yes, walk) to the Greyhound station, and try get a couple of hours sleep before arriving in Edmonton, for a short vacation and some fun.<br />
But for now, I&#8217;ve got the Hip and the Arkells on repeat in my head. &#8216;Cuz they&#8217;re a lot better than listening to some of the shmucks in this place&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A bullet train in Calgary?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-bullet-train-in-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 22:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/09/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train from here to Fort McMurray. Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks. Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A bullet train in Calgary?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/calgary/story/2008/01/09/10year-plan.html">Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train</a> from here to Fort McMurray.<br />
Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks.<br />
<span id="more-887"></span>Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train in Alberta is insane. Completely. Why, you ask?</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is going to pay the $3-4 billion to build a dedicated grade-separated, high-speed rail network? Don&#8217;t look to either <a href="http://www.cp.ca/">CP</a> or <a href="http://www.cn.ca">CN</a>.</li>
<li>Similarly, who runs it? If it&#8217;s VIA, expect the service to have constant problems, since budgets to run high-speed are much higher than regular trains, and <a href="http://www.viarail.ca">VIA</a>&#8216;s got enough budgetary problems as it is.</li>
<li>Do we honestly think there would be enough use of the trains to make them even remotely cost-effective? <a href="http://www.westjet.com">WestJet</a> is pretty darn cheap, y&#8217;know&#8230;</li>
<li>The provincial government was looking to shore up the existing lines up north to help move heavy equipment by train. CN passed on the work (they own the lines) after realising the cost to build up the service wasn&#8217;t worth the revenue. Take that as a subtle hint for new lines.</li>
<li>It hits -40 in many places, with a lot of snow. I don&#8217;t know of many (read: any) high-speed lines that regularly go through such conditions. Hokkaido in Japan is the nearest, and even that&#8217;s not as severe.</li>
</ul>
<p>Politically, it strikes me as odd that anyone would stand up behind this as a good idea, since it&#8217;ll likely be a government that owns it, and it would probably become a white elephant. Very cool, and I&#8217;d ride it just for the sake of riding it &#8212; but governments have been voted out of office for stuff like this.<br />
All of that said, it&#8217;s totally the green option. Run the train often enough, and you have less cars (less automobile pollution) and less planes (less aviation pollution). It&#8217;s also a nicer way to travel long distances. And Canada&#8217;s full of that distance thing.<br />
Mind you, the bullet train wasn&#8217;t the only &#8220;odd&#8221; thing in that report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Building a ring road in Calgary. Um&#8230; <a href="http://content.calgary.ca/CCA/City+Hall/Office+of+the+Mayor/Press+Room/Archive/2006/February+2006/NE+Ring+Road.htm">aren&#8217;t we doing that already</a>?</li>
<li>Where is the mention of expanding Calgary Transit? For the love of Pete, people &#8212; why are you trying to link together cities when [[Calgary Transit Sucks|we can&#8217;t even sort ourselves out]]?</li>
<li>A covered skywalk or monorail between the Telus Convention Centre and the Stampede facilities. What, the C-Train isn&#8217;t good enough for you already? (See previous note about public transit.)</li>
<li>An international aerospace hub. If there was a way to eloquently describe my blank stare at this one, I would. But I&#8217;m simply not that good a writer.</li>
</ul>
<p>I offer one thought to the people who came up with this: Let&#8217;s blueprint something for success, please? Around my office, we ask people to set SMART goals. It&#8217;s an acronym, with the &#8220;R&#8221; standing for &#8220;realistic&#8221;. Which these blueprints really seem to be missing.<br />
If you want success, you needn&#8217;t look further than our own front door. We have three overloaded hospitals, our transit system is not keeping pace with the need, ambulances are running short on availability regularly, and if you haven&#8217;t thought about our water supply availability, you might want to consider that soon, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">887</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
