<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>music &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/music/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 05:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>My Hip Stories</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-hip-stories</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 05:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3529</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In two days, I&#8217;m going to see The Tragically Hip play at the Saddledome. I will freely admit that, somewhat stereotypically Canadian of me, The Hip is my favourite band. So I will also state that I&#8217;m excited to see them play. However, I&#8217;m also somewhat dreading it, too. It&#8217;ll be the last time I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Hip Stories"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In two days, I&#8217;m going to see The Tragically Hip play at the Saddledome. I will freely admit that, somewhat stereotypically Canadian of me, The Hip is my favourite band. So I will also state that I&#8217;m excited to see them play. However, I&#8217;m also somewhat dreading it, too. It&#8217;ll be the last time I see them live, in person. It&#8217;s their final tour.<br />
Not all Canadians care. I don&#8217;t know how many do (I&#8217;ll optimistically suggest 40%), but a few of us are more passionate. But it&#8217;s not because we&#8217;re that passionate about the band per se, it&#8217;s more about how The Tragically Hip have affected our lives (past and/or present), to the point where we have defined stories that involve or revolve around them.<br />
Here&#8217;s mine&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3529"></span></p>
<h2>My First Hip</h2>
<p>I can&#8217;t tell you the date, but I can definitely tell you the year: 1991. And I can tell you the place: Dave Begg&#8217;s parents&#8217; house, where he was hosting a classic &#8220;high school house party&#8221;. I believe it was later in the year, as I do recall university being a factor, and all of us had graduated high school in spring of that year. We were energetic, naive, enjoying our first years beyond the households we&#8217;d been nurtured within, defining ourselves as individuals &#8230; well, when you&#8217;re fresh to university, you think freely, right?<br />
Anyway, this particular party, I was admiring Dave&#8217;s capacity to down copious amounts of beer with the only apparent effect being the colour of his cheeks. (Though nearly all of us were 19 and legally allowed to drink, I would not start drinking for another four years.) We were all chatting, laughing, not really reminiscing high school yet (we wouldn&#8217;t yet learn how sublime high school was compared to the pressures and stress of the Real World<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> beyond), and vaguely listening to the CD playing loudly in the stereo.<br />
I&#8217;m attracted to music. Today, in the present, I will freely admit that music can distract me so much that I find it difficult to have conversations with people right in front of me when there&#8217;s music I wish to listen to. But even then, in my youthful ability to do a thousand things at once, I found myself paying close attention to the song I heard: <em>Cordelia</em>.<br />
By that point, like anyone who listened to rock on the radio, we knew of The Hip. <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em>,<em> Blow At High Dough</em>, and <em>38 Years Old</em> were already well-known from The Hip&#8217;s second album. By the time of the party, <em>Little Bones</em>, <em>Twist My Arm</em>, and <em>Three Pistols</em> had all received sufficient CanCon airtime to enter into our &#8220;oh yeah, I&#8217;ve heard that before&#8221; catalogues. <em>Cordelia </em>hit me rather suddenly:</p>
<blockquote><p>Angst on the planks, spitting from a bridge<br />
Just to see how far down it really is</p></blockquote>
<p>Those are the opening lines. They don&#8217;t seem like much, but having read Margaret Atwood&#8217;s <em>Cat&#8217;s Eye</em> earlier in the year (for one of my high school English classes), the scene of the novel&#8217;s protagonist standing on a bridge with her friend Cordelia, acting out that very motion, suddenly rang with me. (For the record, I&#8217;ve always believed that <em>Cordelia</em> references <em>Cat&#8217;s Eye</em>; I also suspect I&#8217;m the only person who believes that.)<br />
I paid much closer attention to the album after that, since no-one bothered to replace it with anything else, so it just kept playing. Though it was nascent, it was that night I became a fan of The Tragically Hip.</p>
<h2>Midnight Release</h2>
<p>By the time <em>Fully Completely</em> came to existence barely a year later, The Hip had gone from being merely known to more of a household name. So much so that, for the first time that I&#8217;d ever heard of it, their album would be released for sale at midnight on 6 October 1992.<br />
I was attending the University of Waterloo. Just a block to the east of the campus, at 150 University Drive (where it meets Phillip Street), was an HMV (I think it&#8217;s now a Burger King). It was a store I knew well, but generally didn&#8217;t frequent (CDs started at $20 back in those days, and university students generally were on tight budgets). But that night, easily a hundred like-minded people joined the line to be among the first in Canada to get their hands on the new Hip album.<br />
Twenty-four years on, it&#8217;s hard to remember details, but I do remember the store being smart enough to have stacks of the discs ready to roll, and the cashiers ready to roll them out as quickly as possible. The album was playing over the speakers, which gave us the sample of what we were about to listen to as soon as we could get back to our respective holes in the wall.<br />
At the time, I was living at the University&#8217;s Columbia Lake Townhouses, a student &#8220;community&#8221; on the northwest corner of the University&#8217;s land, a series of buildings that generally felt like they&#8217;d been assembled <em>by </em>students, with all the attention to detail one would expect. Though my memory is a bit faded, I&#8217;m fairly certain I walked (I don&#8217;t recall having a car at the time, but I&#8217;ve been known to be wrong before.) It was 2.5 km straight-line distance to my stereo.<br />
It was a $500 special my dad had helped me buy some years earlier, when I worked for his company as a general labourer (I supplied the hard-earned cash, he supplied the bargaining experience). He&#8217;d taken me to a discount stereo place on Dundas St. at the edge of Toronto. It was a Fisher. Nothing fancy, but it had more than enough oomph to overpower most of the stereos in Village 1 the year before.<br />
My roommates were asleep when I got back. Roger, Brian, and Ed were great guys, but were studious. They weren&#8217;t partiers, something I was thankful for. But it also meant that I had to listen to my new purchase on headphones, rather than disturb them with <em>Fully Completely</em>. From beginning to end, it was an album that helped me rethink of how I viewed Canadian music. Like <em>Road Apples</em> before it, there were a few hits, but there were many songs that went well beyond a mere guitar hook or melody. These were things I wouldn&#8217;t yet appreciate for years to come, but it was here I learned more about the strength of a lyric.<br />
Skip ahead 22 years. I&#8217;m married, with kids, living a few thousand kilometres away in the foothills of the Rockies. And The Tragically Hip were touring again, playing <em>Fully Completely</em> in its entirety, front to back (despite the album being pressed in one order, and the liner notes suggesting a different one), and for a few moments I felt that moment back in my sparse university room, listening on headphones, to something new.</p>
<h2>Another Roadside Attraction</h2>
<p>It was 1997. I&#8217;d left university (I&#8217;d not actually <em>graduated</em> yet, though my mother would usher me though that stage), and was working in downtown Toronto at a small software company. My friend Gerry Dessureau had gotten me the interview, and I was willing to subject myself to some rather poor startup habits in an effort to make a mark in my career-to-be.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if was Gerry, or our co-worker and friend Mike Klinowski who had first mentioned it, but <em>Another Roadside Attraction</em> was coming. And the lineup sounded pretty darned good.<br />
The 1990s had seen the rise of the music festival: Lollapalooza, Lilith Fair, Ozzfest, Warped Tour, Edgefest (a Toronto-area event), and the Woodstock revival. (Interesting fact: The Tragically Hip were lauded for their appearance at Woodstock &#8217;99.) Whether these tours became a factor in their decision to run their tour that year (<em>Trouble at the Henhouse</em> came out the previous year, followed by their live album, <em>Live Between Us</em>, earlier in &#8217;97), or that they just wanted to have fun with a bunch of friends, I don&#8217;t know. But tour they did, and they brought some really big names with them, starting with supporting and promoting Canadian indie band Wilco and indie sensation Ron Sexsmith, and Canadian Ashley MacIssac (who was still riding high on his <em>Hi<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> How Are You Today?</em> album). Along for the ride were also Sheryl Crow (her self-titled second album also released in 1996), and Los Lobos (who, really, needed no introduction). But the headliners were still The Tragically Hip.<br />
The date was set for Sunday, 3 August 1997. The location was Molson Park in Barrie, a large festival space next to the Molson brewery. I picked up Mike at the Kipling Station in far-west Toronto, then swung north to pick up Gerry in Brampton. We drove up the 400 that morning in anticipation of a great day in the sun, to experience &#8230; whatever there was to experience. I&#8217;d never been to an event such as this, and though there had been many like it by this point, it was unknown to me.<br />
Even in 1997, the approach to Barrie was slow on the 400, and we were diverted to Veterans Drive to the west to sneak in through the north end of the facility. (It&#8217;s worth noting that Molson&#8217;s closed in Barrie, and sold all the land. Where we saw the Hip is now a shopping mall.) We parked, and braced ourselves for whatever was to come.<br />
The more unknown acts, notably Van Allen Belt, Change of Heart, and the Mutton Birds were on early. So we diverted to the beer garden and the merchandise stalls. It would be Ron Sexsmith that drew us out to the massive greenspace where some 35,000 of new-found friends would gather together over the course of the next few hours. I don&#8217;t quite remember the order of performers, though I know that Ashley MacIssac, Los Lobos, Sheryl Crow, and the Hip were the last four. I remember being front-and-nearly-centre for MacIssac, who elicited a mosh pit for playing a (fiddle!) cover of the Bee Gee&#8217;s <em>Stayin&#8217; Alive</em>.<br />
And I remember someone landing on my head.<br />
Remember, it was the 90s. People crowd-surfed. And as was always the case, you had to keep an eye out for people headed towards the front of the crowd. Sadly, I didn&#8217;t see this guy coming, and I ended up creating the dreaded &#8220;hole&#8221;. My head cranked to the right. Before I could blink, Gerry had grabbed me and hauled me out of the pack to make sure nothing was broken. Lucky, owing largely to my youth (and possible intoxication), I was fine (I wouldn&#8217;t even have the sore neck later). But the events kept me away from the front. Mike, however, was at the front fence; we wouldn&#8217;t see him again until nearly midnight.<br />
I still remember the moment The Hip took the stage. It was the first time I&#8217;d seen them live, a moment I&#8217;d been (unknowingly) waiting to happen for years. If you <a href="http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-tragically-hip/1997/molson-park-barrie-on-canada-6bdc560e.html" target="_blank">believe the internet</a>, the first Hip song I heard live was <em>Springtime in Vienna</em>. Though, to be fair, I don&#8217;t remember. I do remember hearing the audience overpower them, singing <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em>, and I remember Ashley MacIssac joining them for a song (history records this as <em>Wheat Kings</em>). I remember witnessing Gord Downie&#8217;s presence on the stage, how he both fed and drew energy from the audience. I remember thinking that he must&#8217;ve been high on something, because I couldn&#8217;t understand how someone could be so acutely strange on stage without being deliberate; I would learn later that to witness Canada&#8217;s Poet Musician in the act is an experience in and of itself. And I remember the thunderous applause for the Sons of Kingston, Ontario.<br />
And I remember looking for nearly an hour to find Mike, who&#8217;d been pressed so hard into the fence that he&#8217;d not been able to escape, the lucky bastard. We waited another hour before the traffic died down enough that we could leave. It was a long, quiet trip back into town. Downtown Toronto was silent at 3am Monday morning, save for the woman in a taxi next to us who flashed her breasts at a rather stunned Mike, who neglected to alert Gerry or I to the spectacle. Gerry stayed at Mike&#8217;s that night, whereas I would return to Oakville; all of us still had work in a few hours.</p>
<h2>Road Trip to Red Deer</h2>
<p>In 2013, the tour supporting <em>Now For Plan A</em> would not come to Calgary until July; their route would only come as close as Red Deer, about 90 minutes north of Calgary. And in the prairies, 90 minutes is just a long commute, not remotely a barrier for my friend Scott and I.<br />
But a mere concert this was not, if just because of the date: 22 January 2013, just three days before Alex&#8217;s birthday. So when Alex decided that she wanted to go to Edmonton, there was a problem to resolve. One does not tell one&#8217;s wife that you will not be present for their desires.<br />
Options included both Scott and I driving (not ideal, as then both Alex and I would be driving to Edmonton and back), Alex dropping us off for the concert and waiting (also not ideal, since Scott wouldn&#8217;t have a way back, and it meant an overnight in Red Deer), or (in the final version), Scott would drive me to Red Deer, and then I would bus to Edmonton after the concert.<br />
Scott and I left early from work. Alex and the kids would leave roughly the same time, but would go directly to Edmonton (they would meet with one of Alex&#8217;s friends that evening). Scott and I went to the Toad n&#8217; Turtle, a pub at the south end of Red Deer, a short hop from Westerner Park, where the concert would unfold that night. We ate, we drank, we whiled away the hours until it was time.<br />
The last time I&#8217;d been in a &#8220;small town&#8221; venue was when I&#8217;d been fortunate enough to see David Bowie in Kelowna. (The two cities are fairly similar in size.) It was a large hockey arena, appropriate for its two Canadian guests that evening: The Hip, and their opening act, The Arkells.<br />
Until a few days earlier, I hadn&#8217;t really known of The Arkells. I might have heard a song or two of theirs on the radio, but it would have likely been by chance and I wouldn&#8217;t have known it. But since we knew they were the opening act, both Scott and I listened to them in advance to see if they were worth seeing. In roughly the same amount of time since we&#8217;d started listening, both of us had each bought both of The Arkells&#8217; albums, and were anxious to see them perform.<br />
Well-placed on the floor towards the front, we were left in awe of The Hip&#8217;s choice to prime the audience. The Arkells came out punching, and didn&#8217;t let up for the entire hour of their set. They engaged directly with the audience. They played the songs that Scott and I had come to know only days earlier (such as already-mainstays <em>Whistleblower</em> and <em>The Boss Is Coming</em>), and dropped epic covers from not only Motown, but also The Clash&#8217;s <em>Rock The Casbah</em>.<br />
I might not remember all that was said that night, but I do remember commenting to Scott during the lull between acts that The Hip had a hell of an act to have to follow.<br />
The Tragically Hip did not disappoint. Not even remotely.<br />
They played more from their recent albums than from their back catalogue, including the rather curious <em>Man Machine Poem</em>, a literal poem set to music. To watch Gord Downie perform it on stage was like a grand operatic drama woven amongst the guitars and drums of modern rock.<br />
Selfishly, my favourite moment was hearing <em>My Music At Work</em>, which had been a personal theme of mine for years, stemming from my career in digital marketing. I found the words echoed very much in mind:</p>
<blockquote><p>Everything is bleak<br />
It&#8217;s the middle of the night<br />
You&#8217;re all alone and<br />
The dummies might be right<br />
You feel like a jerk<br />
My music at work</p></blockquote>
<p>Following the final song of the encore, <em>Blow At High Dough</em>, Scott dropped me off at the Denny&#8217;s on 50th Ave so I could wait in relative comfort until my bus. Despite all my grand foresight, one thing I had not picked up on until much too late was that the buses didn&#8217;t run as frequently as I&#8217;d liked. The earliest bus was 3am. Like so many years before, I would find myself up to a very early hour, catch glimpses of sleep, before needing to be awake in a distant city.<br />
Others would come into the Denny&#8217;s as I sat and read. I overheard their conversations. More than a few were commenting on the concert. It was strongly believed that The Hip were staying at the Sheraton just down the road, and wouldn&#8217;t it be cool to see them there? <em>It would</em>, I nodded to myself, <em>but I wouldn&#8217;t want to be a pest.</em> So I sat and drank my coffee, ate my snack, and packed up for the cold walk to the bus station.</p>
<h2>Canada Day</h2>
<p>In June of that same year, I caught wind of plans for a Canada Day concert in London, England, which would feature The Tragically Hip. At the time, I could only smile to myself and think of how fun that would be &#8230; and how much I wanted to go back to London. But without even having to question, I knew that getting time away from my family (which included three- and five-year olds) was only a pipe dream. The wistfulness only got worse as The Arkells were added, followed by The Sheepdogs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Then they added Jann Arden to the line-up.<br />
I have to admit, I&#8217;m not a ardent Arden fan. I feel kind of bad for having to say that, especially given that I live in her hometown. I&#8217;ve been to one of her concerts, and she is a brilliant performer. Her ability to deliver cracking stand-up comedy amidst heart-wrenching songs is an admirable talent. But her music doesn&#8217;t resonate with me as much as it does my wife. Mind you, that might not be a fair comparison; I&#8217;m not sure that I love The Hip as much as Alex loves Jann Arden. It&#8217;s almost stalker-ish.<br />
So when Alex joked that we should go to London for Canada Day, the laughter was short and nervous, filled with a thick dose of &#8220;why not?&#8221;.<br />
The kids were &#8220;why not&#8221;, of course. We weren&#8217;t comfortable with the idea of taking them to England. Then we turned uncharacteristically selfish (at least insofar as our offspring are concerned) and started wondering how we might be able to steal away for a few days and leave them in the hands of family who live in town. And, rather suddenly, we had booked airfare to England and found as cheap a hotel as we could while remaining inside Zone 1 of the Underground.<br />
It was a wonderfully refreshing experience to fly with only Alex at my side, and not having to worry about children on a plane. (We would worry about them in other ways, of course, but entertaining children on an eight-hour flight was something were just weren&#8217;t ready for.) We weren&#8217;t in First Class, but for our first parents-only getaway, it might as well have been a private berth on a luxury steamship.<br />
In the days leading up to Canada Day, we took advantage of being childless in London: we toured. We walked the streets in the rain, went to the Tower of London, and Tower Bridge. We saw <em>Spamalot</em> on a whim. I finally got to visit St. Paul&#8217;s Cathedral, something I&#8217;d longed to do since my first visit to London many years earlier.<br />
As a boy, my father participated in a choir. He was known as &#8220;The Deacon&#8221; to his friends; he loved to belt out Christmas carols. One year, he had travelled to London, and performed at St. Paul&#8217;s. This was a source of personal pride for him. I wanted to know what it was like.<br />
St. Paul&#8217;s is an impressive building, both for architecture and for art. And it that had been all that I had seen, then perhaps the moment would have passed as little more than a tick on my London To Do list. But as I rounded a pillar (cursing again the limitation that prevented me from taking pictures inside), a choir started to sing. I looked over, to see a small group of kids, boys and girls, directly under massive dome. I froze. As their voices wafted and echoed across the stone interior, I could almost hear my father&#8217;s voice. It&#8217;s rare for me to cry in public.<br />
On the day before the concert, we were invited to join Alex&#8217;s friend&#8217;s family in Cambridge, where she had obtained her law degree. I nearly had another brush with my father&#8217;s ghost, in the form of King&#8217;s College Chapel, the home of my father&#8217;s favourite choir. Thankfully (I suppose), the Chapel was closed for a private function, so the waterworks were kept at bay. Instead, Alex&#8217;s friend Kirstie took us on a guided tour of the millennia-old university.<br />
Kirstie and her family would meet us the following morning in Trafalgar Square for Canada Day. Though not a Bank Holiday in London, it was a chance to get some Canadiana for them; Kirstie had spent some of her childhood in Calgary (it&#8217;s how she and Alex know each other). We got in line for the pancakes and waffles, walked past the Blackberry booth (Blackberry was a sponsor of the event), and sat down to watch the street hockey tournament. Kirstie wouldn&#8217;t stay the entire day, she had to retrieve her youngest from daycare; her husband Grenville would stay for the concert.<br />
The first band up was one I&#8217;d never heard of before: Northern Cree, a First Nations Pow-Wow and Round Dance singing group. It&#8217;s a bit of a shame that as Canadians, we didn&#8217;t know who they were, or could recognize that we&#8217;d probably heard them perform many times before but didn&#8217;t know. And I wonder how exotic they seemed to the British, who certainly don&#8217;t come across such music.<br />
The Arkells came next, and unloaded their vibe across the Square, and onto the streets beyond. Where Northern Cree might have attracted attention, The Arkells became a full-on beacon for what was to come, and the crowds started to grow. That was when I ran into my friend Terri, who had moved to England some years earlier, and had acquired an accent to boot. It wasn&#8217;t easy to chat up while also trying to listen to music. I think I did it rather poorly, to be honest.<br />
I lost Alex (and Terri) for the duration of Jann Arden&#8217;s set, even though Jann had stripped her performance down considerably, coming only with two other musicians and playing acoustically. As The Sheepdogs started to play, we opted to take our leave for a bit and get a break from the crowds. Though I did want to see The Sheepdogs play, even I felt like a break might be good.<br />
We got only as far as Parliament Square Garden, across from the Palace of Westminster. Alex opted to call it an evening and head back to our room, and leave me to wind up the show. I will admit a certain amount of conflict within me: should I stay with my wife, or go see what would likely be a brilliant outdoor concert? (There&#8217;s a Clash song that echoes the sentiment&#8230;)<br />
But Alex encouraged me to go. We had come all this way, and she wasn&#8217;t going to have any part in me missing The Hip in London. So I wound my way back to Trafalgar Square, dove back into the crowds, and as politely as a Canadian can, worked my way within a couple of people of the front fence. No mosh pits would land people on my head this time.<br />
From my position at Stage Left, I could see the band approach on the stairs, following George Stroumboulopoulos. Strombo, as he&#8217;s known in shorthand, is Canada&#8217;s music geek. He hosts a show on CBC Radio 2, playing pretty much what he likes, saying whatever comes to mind. He&#8217;s known for being a terrific interviewer, and does his research. Although he&#8217;s appeared on CNN (a point that still puzzles me), I suspect that non-Canucks in the audience that night hadn&#8217;t a clue who he was. But everyone knew who he was introducing.<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5_1RoiSQHaY" target="_blank">They opened with <em>At Transformation</em></a>, a leading track from <em>Now For Plan A,</em> and followed with <em>Grace, Too</em>. The one-two punch got people excited. And we all waited for Gord Downie to unleash himself, demonstrating to Britain that their former colony had talents they couldn&#8217;t have imagined.<br />
Though the set was fairly close to the one I&#8217;d seen in Red Deer only a few months earlier, the crowd was decidedly more energetic, likely further enthused by the day and the location. Canadian flags were everywhere, either in the traditional form, or emblazoned on hats or shirts. Everyone in the audience knew the words. The only thing saving the band from being overpowered during the chorus of <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em> (which wrapped <em>Nautical Disaster</em>) was the size of the audio system; had I been further back, I suspect the audience might have won.<br />
There was no real encore. Instead, The Hip did a song I&#8217;d never heard them play before: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YNyzFCaDA84" target="_blank"><em>O Canada</em></a>. If there were a moment to give me real chills, despite the hot summer evening, I&#8217;d struggle to think of one.<br />
With the concert over, the Square started to empty. In hopes of finding Terri and apologizing for our rather aborted discussion, I raced back to the steps before The National Gallery where I had last seen her. However, amongst tens of thousands of people, it&#8217;s exceptionally hard to find just one. So I was quite surprised to suddenly find myself talking to Grenville, whom I&#8217;d lost track of several hours earlier.<br />
We moved to The Chandos, a nearby pub, to quaff a pair of pints before having to go our respective ways. We discussed the concert in quite some detail. I was curious to hear Gren&#8217;s thoughts, especially being a Brit, and Brit&#8217;s take their music seriously. I mean, this is the home of more legends of rock and influences to nearly every genre of music I know. It&#8217;s not a place you walk into and expect to be respected; you have to earn that right. And Gren is probably as good a representation of that knowledge as I can think of. Suffice to say, I expected reservation.<br />
What I got was: &#8220;They&#8217;re really good!&#8221; he exclaimed between sips of a bitter, &#8220;I&#8217;ll need to listen to more of them!&#8221;</p>
<h2>The stories to come&#8230;</h2>
<p>Like any good book, there&#8217;s always room for more. The question that dogs us is: how much more? Since Gord Downie announced his cancer diagnosis, we&#8217;ve all breathed softly, already expecting the worst. Though he has endured treatment, the inevitability of the disease hangs over everything like a looming storm.<br />
I have at least two more stories to add. The first one will be on Monday, when The Hip play here in Calgary, the first of two shows. I&#8217;ll be in the 8th row with Alex &#8212; her first Hip concert. I&#8217;m simultaneously excited to see them again, and I&#8217;m dreading the finality of it. I hate to see them leave.<br />
The second, and possibly last, will be on 20 August, when The Hip play what might be their final concert. Ever. They&#8217;re playing at home in Kingston, which CBC is livecasting to those of us unable to be there.<br />
We don&#8217;t know what to expect. We don&#8217;t know what to think. In the end, though, we&#8217;ll always have our stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3529</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A musical evening in Red Deer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-musical-evening-in-red-deer</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3226</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A musical evening in Red Deer"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And I had good reason, y&#8217;know!<br />
Back in July, during the Calgary Stampede, the Tragically Hip played the Calgary Roundup, <em>the</em> outdoor concert of the year. I had wanted to go, but I totally messed up where the tickets were sold (stupid me, I thought it was Ticketmaster), and by the time I&#8217;d realised it &#8230; it was too late. Sold out, and I was out of luck.<br />
This is what brought me to Red Deer.<br />
<span id="more-3226"></span>I&#8217;ve been listening to the Tragically Hip since their <em>Road Apples</em> album, back in my last year(s) of high school. I was immediately hooked, and remained that way ever since. The only thing I hadn&#8217;t done is gone to a lot of their concerts. There was usually a reason, I assure you. My own idiocy aside, it was either bad timing (I wasn&#8217;t around/available), or was without someone to go with (while I may see a movie solo, a concert is an entirely different matter).<br />
So when the Hip announced Red Deer, I was quick to jump on getting tickets, this being the closest the Hip would come to Calgary this go around. Even with a presale code, the best I could do was 10th row on the floor (which, as it turns out, was still pretty darned good). My accomplice was a fellow former-Ontarioan, Scott &#8212; one of a few hundred Scotts that I seem to know.<br />
We left Calgary shortly before 15:00 for our just-over-an-hour jaunt north. (Alex and the kids had left nearly 90 minutes earlier for their trip to Alberta Beach &#8212; we meet up tomorrow in Edmonton. More on that in a moment&#8230;) The worst problem we had beyond some less-than-savoury other drivers was some fog that reduced visibility to about 200 metres or so. Once we were past Olds, it seemed to clear up.<br />
We arrived in Red Deer just after 16:00, and ran a couple of errands before holing up at the Toad and Turtle for a couple of hours of beer, nachos, and random conversation about &#8230; well, pretty much what you&#8217;d expect from a pair of geek programmer fathers who don&#8217;t get out enough. (If you are one, you&#8217;re nodding in agreement. If you&#8217;re not one, you probably don&#8217;t really want to know.)<br />
Westerner Park (an oddly named place, IMO) lay a mere click away, and we quickly found a place to park the car. We were soon accosted by another concert-goer &#8212; originally from Hamilton &#8212; who swore he was going to start a chant so the Hip would play <em>Wheat Kings</em>. He was rather pleased to hear that both Scott and I originally hail from Ontario.<br />
The concert venue is the two-tiered arena, primarily for the Red Deer Rebels, the local CHL team. So, as you can imagine, it&#8217;s not a big place. Which was completely fine with me. And so we waited for the opening act, to start at 20:00.<br />
Opening was a band called The Arkells, out of Hamilton. Until the concert had been announced, I hadn&#8217;t heard of the Arkells. The announcement, of course, drove both Scott and I to check out their music. Within 10 minutes, I&#8217;d bought both of their albums and put them onto heavy rotation. This was not for any form of preparation, this was solely because the albums were that good. I cannot think, in my musical history, of any band that has turned out albums so strong that I&#8217;m compelled to buy and listen constantly for nearly two weeks. Several of their songs are still on my frequently-listened playlists. (Side note: I swear some of their songs must be written for people who work in marketing&#8230;)<br />
Live? I was pretty much floored. Not only did the Arkells come out with a bang, they <em>refused</em> to let up. They got everyone on their feet, and they got the entire audience going. In terms of what an opening act should do, they did it far better than any opening act I&#8217;ve ever seen. It&#8217;s just a shame that their set was so short. I pray that they come to Calgary in the near future as a solo act, or with an opening act of their own.<br />
The intermission was short, filled with roadies racing across the stage to clean off the Arkell&#8217;s equipment, and make sure the Hip&#8217;s equipment was good to go. Shortly before 21:00, some fifteen and a half years since the last time I&#8217;d seen them, the Tragically Hip took stage to a roar. And they kept roaring for two-odd hours.<br />
It was sort of like listening to my own Tragically Hip playlist, which is a kind of &#8220;best of&#8221;. But live and loud, complete with Gord Downie&#8217;s interjections and rants, for which he is famous (though none as legendary as the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gjSyZslQp0w">Killer Whale Tank</a>, or of July&#8217;s Roundup concert, which should approach <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1N4AQGON5_o">the same level of epicness</a>, if you ask me).<br />
The encore was five songs, including <em>Wheat Kings</em>. I could hear the audience over the band. We were in the 10th row.<br />
Following the concert, Scott dropped me off where I now am, at the Denny&#8217;s on Gaetz, before he headed back to Calgary. Why am I still here? Well, remember how I said I&#8217;m meeting Alex and the kids in Edmonton? Well, I have to get there. Right now, they&#8217;re in Alberta Beach (google it, folks) visiting a friend. In a little over two hours, with luck, I&#8217;ll be boarding a Greyhound bus for Edmonton, arriving at 6:00.<br />
Yes, that&#8217;s 6:00 in the morning. Look at the datestamp folks, it&#8217;s after midnight.<br />
This is what&#8217;s led me to sitting in a back booth at the Denny&#8217;s, using their wifi, to &#8230; um &#8230; well, kill time. Then I can walk (yes, walk) to the Greyhound station, and try get a couple of hours sleep before arriving in Edmonton, for a short vacation and some fun.<br />
But for now, I&#8217;ve got the Hip and the Arkells on repeat in my head. &#8216;Cuz they&#8217;re a lot better than listening to some of the shmucks in this place&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TV is dead. Long live the internet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3076</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TV is dead. Long live the internet!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial that changed the direction of the UHF antenna&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve lost you, haven&#8217;t I? I shudder to think how few of you have an <em>inkling</em> of what I&#8217;m talking about. Yeah, that&#8217;s how old I am. I remember when there were only a handful of channels, when almost all of the content was on ABC, NBC, CBS, CBC, CTV, Global, and a few independent stations (such as the awesome CityTV and the the extremely nacent Fox). I remember the introduction of cable. I remember having to wait for the summer reruns because I missed that crucial episode of <em>The A Team</em> that everyone was talking about in class the next morning. I remember when the season debuts were a big thing. I remember when missing a live televised event was significant, because it was gone forever.<br />
It seems somehow just as bizarre a concept as the Spanish Inquisition.<br />
<span id="more-3076"></span>Up until a few years ago, this model was still fairly static. Despite the massive influx of cable, the ridiculous proliferation of specialty channels (seriously, I cannot fathom how some of them make any money), Youtube, Torrents, and the like, the concept of &#8220;television&#8221; hadn&#8217;t really changed. You still relied on the networks. Waiting for the most recent <em>Survivor</em> was still a big thing. And people watched the evening news.<br />
In the last 24-30 months, however, I&#8217;ve seen a massive shift in service. The <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/research/2010/01/the-itunes-effect-and-the-futu.html">iTunes Effect</a> completely altered the way that we consume music (despite the music industry continually trying to roll the clock back as if nothing ever happened), and it&#8217;s echoed into the way we consume video. And I choose that word very carefully: <em>video.</em> Not &#8220;television&#8221;, not &#8220;movies&#8221;. The length of a given item, or its relevance to a related group of videos (say, a television series of yore, or a trilogy of films) is largely irrelevant. Thanks to devices such as DVRs, tablets, Boxees, Apple TVs, and so forth, we can consume video on our own terms, and not at those of the telecommunications companies to whom we enslaved ourselves for over five decades.<br />
A month and a half ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/upstairs-reno-the-fun-begins/">my family moved out of our home</a> so the kitchen renovation could begin in earnest. When we did that, we took our living room video display (I now loathe to call it a &#8220;TV set&#8221;) and the Apple TV so we could watch, well, <em>something</em>. For three weeks, all we had were whatever videos were on the Apple TV &#8212; we had no network connection to speak of, so no new videos during that time.<br />
When we got back into our home, the living room was far from any suitable state to be able to hook our video displays back up to the television display boxes. No TV. (In fact, hardly any video at all.) At the end of a month and a half, it&#8217;s hard for us to really &#8220;miss&#8221; television at all.<br />
We had Telus Optik. It was a decent service, and the only real complaint I had with it was that we had about 180 channels more than we watched. There were four on any form of rotation: Discovery (for my <em>MythBusters</em> fix), Treehouse (for the kids&#8217; shows), whatever channel showed <em>Greys Anatomy</em>, and one or two other channels were in the mix for a few things. But that was it. No kidding. No joke. We paid $80 to watch less than a half dozen things.<br />
Yesterday, I pulled the plug (not <em>completely</em>, mind you &#8212; I rather stupidly signed up for a three year contract, thinking this blog post was still quite a ways away; the account is in &#8220;suspension&#8221; for $5/month, though it counts towards the contract term), and we started onto a new path: internet-only content.<br />
We are far from the first to do this. I have several friends who cut their cable a while ago, and have sufficed quite well off of whatever they could glean from the internet. iTunes has been a major source of material, as has the ubiquitous YouTube. Many have turned to the less-legal Torrents to acquire television shows and movies, while others have looked to online services such as Netflix.<br />
My problem with the internet aspect until recently was twofold: fragmentation, and accessibility. There&#8217;s a lot of different venues in which to find the content one might want to watch &#8212; think of it as having two constantly criss-cross a typical urban mega-strip mall on an erratic shopping spree, rather than being able to go to a single store and finding all that you need. And then it&#8217;s an issue where you go to a given store expecting to find the very shirt your American friend told you about, but despite it being an American clothier, that specific shirt isn&#8217;t available in Canada. (Canada remains, frustratingly, a digital backwater when it comes to internet content.)<br />
So what&#8217;s changed? Aside from the realization that we just don&#8217;t watch regular television anymore, it was the introduction of a &#8220;content aggregator&#8221; (not sure what else to call it), some handy (but legally grey-area) tools, and the ability to be a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing. Allow me to introduce our new media setup&#8230;</p>
<h2>The Device</h2>
<p>Ultimately, you need a unit to actually serve content (the stuff &#8212; literally &#8212; doesn&#8217;t fly through the air, anymore). The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_TV#Apple_TV_First_Generation">Apple TV (version 1)</a> had been a decent first attempt, but it failed in a number of ways, not the least of which was a strong tie to iTunes and not a lot of expandability (even the <a href="http://firecore.com/atvflash">aTV Flash</a> hack offered little more). It meant that it was hard for us to use different media sources, or even watch DVDs through a single device.<br />
Enter the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_Mini">mid-2010 Apple Mac Mini, model A1347 (non-server)</a>. Slightly taller than the Apple TV, this is a complete computer, and can run any software we need. Furthermore, it has full support for 1080p video, complete audio support, and because it&#8217;s a full computer, it can be used by Monkey and Choo Choo as they grow up and need to use computers in their school (while Mommy and I get to help/watch). Even more key for this specific release of the Mac Mini, however, is that this is the last one that came with a SuperDrive built-in &#8212; the next release was without an optical drive, making it hard to watch those reams of physical media we&#8217;ve been accumulating.<br />
The Mac Mini is limited to 320 GB, which seems like a lot, but it&#8217;ll fill up quickly with the media we hope to deliver through it. So instead, I&#8217;m going to be attaching it to a terabyte drive (ideally a RAIDed one, with a secondary backup for real redundancy) that will store all the music, movies, photos, and various videos that our family will use. Our network is gigabit (thanks to Telus), so network speed shouldn&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<h2>The Software</h2>
<p>Operating system aside, the complete list is still pending, but I&#8217;m looking at:</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Duh. We have a significant amount of content in iTunes, and there is zero reason not to use iTunes to access it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plexapp.com/">Plex Server</a><br />
This is the aggregation tool. It offers a significant amount of functionality for linking disparate pieces of content (including iTunes) into a single interface, and offers a variety of &#8220;channels&#8221; for watching online content. Because it works full-screen, it&#8217;s a suitable replacement for the venerable Front Row. It also includes a player that can play software copies of DVDs&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://thelittleappfactory.com/ripit/">RipIt</a><br />
Boy, it didn&#8217;t take long to get back into that legal black hole, didn&#8217;t it? Yes, I am using a piece of software to extract the content from media I have purchased and am placing it in a non-public system for my own personal entertainment, digital lock provisions be damned. Big Media pushing bullshit like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">SOPA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_Canada">C-11</a> can <a href="http://www.freshnewsound.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/johnny_cash.jpg">suck my balls</a>. I don&#8217;t like physical media, it&#8217;s too prone to damage by jam-covered fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, we will install what&#8217;s needed, when it&#8217;s needed. Right now, I&#8217;m not sure what that is, but I&#8217;m sure we can adapt when the time comes.</p>
<h2>The Services</h2>
<p>The hardware and software alone will not solve our problems. It&#8217;s not really any different than buying a &#8220;regular&#8221; television set. The problem is that you still need to have content provided from <em>somewhere</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Again, duh. Our existing library is one thing, but iTunes still has an extensive (and lovely) collection of media from which to select. We&#8217;ve used iTunes for quite some time, and plan to keep using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://goo.gl/EY0O4">The Service I Can&#8217;t Really Talk About</a><br />
Okay, this is another one of those &#8220;grey area&#8221; items. Technically, Canadians can&#8217;t see American content (think Hulu, American versions of Netflix and iTunes, and Comedy Network) because some dumbass decided that we&#8217;re not allowed to see it. So our IP blocks are scanned and summarily blocked. This service makes you look like an American &#8212; a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing &#8212; and away you go. It&#8217;s not illegal, but I&#8217;m sure that some moron lawyer will cry foul (because he&#8217;s paid to do so) and it&#8217;ll get yanked. Hence, I refuse to name it. Like Plex, it also provides a number of channels, so we should be able to watch &#8230; well, pretty much anything we want, really.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.netflix.ca">Netflix</a> (the American verison!)<br />
My biggest gripe with Netflix is that the Canadian content is so wildly different than the American content &#8230; despite it running off the same system. So thanks to the aforementioned service, we get the added benefit of a larger library.</li>
</ul>
<div>Okay, what about live television? Say I want to watch the hockey game, or even the Olympics? Well, this is where the Mac Mini comes to the rescue again. Because it&#8217;s a full computer, it has a full browser (and various necessary plugins) so that we can visit a website and watch live feeds. Perfect? Probably not, but at least it&#8217;s better than channel surfing.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>The Result</h2>
<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know yet. From everything I&#8217;ve read and from everything everyone who&#8217;s already gone down this road has told me, this seems like a solid path. But I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that it won&#8217;t be a bed of roses (and, really, when you think about it, is a &#8220;bed of roses&#8221; all that appealing? Think of the thorns!) and this could fail. I doubt it will fail entirely, since we get content no matter what, it&#8217;s just the depth at which we get it.<br />
So what of actual &#8220;television&#8221;? We&#8217;re in the shift now, and already it&#8217;s showing. Advertisers are trying to find new ways to market to people who are willingly skipping commercials. Big Media is slow to adapt (surprise, surprise!), but is at least starting to recognise the revenue potential, so it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll fight against it. But the transition from network model (which provides funding and marketing for television shows) is at risk, given a more fragmented market.<br />
For us, this can only be a win-win. People want to make video, and we want to consume it. The question of <em>how</em> remains, and its only a matter of time before these bits of technology-in-infancy are replaced by more robust and &#8220;complete&#8221; systems that hide the mess of aggregation, bringing about a true &#8220;on demand&#8221; environment that has been promised for the better part of 20 years.<br />
As for our specific experience, we&#8217;ll keep you posted. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve got a Mac Mini to set up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copyrights are the new Colonialism</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2512</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Copyrights are the new Colonialism"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the name of Queen/King and country. Colonies were born out of determination, slavery, and blood extracted from those too weak to defend themselves from British will.<br />
In time, a phrase was born: The sun never sets on the British Empire. Great Britain&#8217;s influence extended far beyond its native shores, its power unquestionable. A few thrived under the colonial system, but the majority &#8212; the people living under colonial rule &#8212; were marginalised as being little more than the ignorant masses; significant numbers suffered horribly.<br />
It&#8217;s really no wonder that the Empire collapsed under its own weight.<br />
<span id="more-2512"></span>Flash forward now to our present, a world where corporations, not governments, run the world. Oh, sure, we see the laws passed by governments in the interests of its people, but it&#8217;s not the governments creating them. It&#8217;s lobbyists, working on behalf of the corporations. It&#8217;s the corporations funding political careers through donations (legal or otherwise). It&#8217;s the corporations funding large-scale advertising campaigns placing candidates more friendly to their needs into office.<br />
It is these corporations directing the current colonialism: copyrights. Think of these not as the legalese that they are &#8212; instead, think of them as land claims, which were a significant part of the British Empire. A land claim meant you had title to earn money from people who worked your land, and the power to treat them however (un)fairly you wished. If anyone tried to take your land, you were obliged to defend it with as deadly force as you could muster.<br />
Copyrights have been with us &#8212; and have been a controversial topic &#8212; ever since Thag copied Zog&#8217;s cave painting, and Zog hit Thag over the head with a rock. Interestingly, that form of retribution hasn&#8217;t changed much in the roughly 45,000 years since. It&#8217;s been a battle for recognition of ownership, of artistry, and for &#8220;what&#8217;s right&#8221;.<br />
One of the biggest problems is that copyright enforcement hasn&#8217;t been particularly consistent over the years, either. Zog was lucky enough to avoid a complex judicial system. Until the early 1990s, we had to rely mostly on physical presence (namely, you had to buy an actual piece of art). Software copyrights existed, but were poorly enforced, even within large law-abiding corporations. The advance of technology broke the physical barrier, gave people the ability to access materials on their behalf &#8230; and shortly afterwards, gave corporations the ability to know who was breaking their rules.<br />
We saw the first signs of the new colonialism at the turn of the 21st century, when one of the corporations &#8212; the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recording_Industry_Association_of_America">Recording Industry Association of America</a> (RIAA) &#8212; launched what would be come the first of many public and painful lawsuits. Metallica brought the battle into the public eye when they effectively offended the then-denizens of the internet, decrying the &#8220;fair use&#8221; belief held by many (the legality of said perspective notwithstanding). It was the first shot fired in the new independence, the first time that people showed to the world that they wanted things on their terms, not someone else&#8217;s.<br />
The weapon wielded by groups like the RIAA and the MPAA (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_Picture_Association_of_America">Motion Picture Assocation of America</a>) was not a battle axe or a howitzer, but the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Millennium_Copyright_Act">Digital Millennium Copyright Act</a> &#8212; the DCMA. This law, enacted in the United States of America, implemented two of the treaties agreed upon by WIPO (World Intellectual Property Organization) in 1996. This is how we came to know DRM (Digital Rights Management). They used it <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/11/movie-ticket-prices-and-acts-of-piracy/">to guilt us to not copy</a>, and then <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">slaughter us when we did</a>. The corporations had found legitimacy for their battle through governments.<br />
In theory, this should have worked entirely to the corporation&#8217;s wishes. Within their own borders, the laws were clear, and things went (mostly) according to plan. But they weren&#8217;t so effective in the international reality. Not all countries recognised, or even seemed to care, about other country&#8217;s laws &#8212; and certainly not about the ones that enforced copyrights. Governments were engaged again to help enforce the corporations&#8217; will.<br />
When you have to go up to the biggest kid in the schoolyard and ask for your toy back, all you can do is whine. I imagine &#8220;aw, come on!&#8221; was heard a lot when the United States asked China not to copy software, movies, or CDs. But China opted to give only a token of acceptance &#8212; sort of like giving back only one of the wheels from the Tonka truck. China can do that, because it owns a huge portion of the United States debt, and provides the United States with cheap imports.<br />
Where were the WIPO and the World Trade Organization (WTO) in all of this? Someone&#8217;s got to run world court, right?<br />
But the rules started changing. In the last two years, Canada had to improve its own copyright legislation, also based on DCMA, and driven by the industry &#8212; the corporations &#8212; and not by the people whom the government should represent. The sledgehammer just fell on <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/4697/125/">Costa Rica: fix your copyrights, or the United States will stop importing sugar</a> (note that coffee and bananas were excluded from the ban).  Lo siento, Costa Rica, but CAFTA/TLC won&#8217;t help you here &#8212; remember, the United States wrote the core of it to benefit themselves.<br />
Costa Rica and Canada are not alone. Dozens of countries are now working on ACTA &#8212; the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2010/01/actas-shameful-secret.ars">Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement &#8212; a virtually secret pact</a> designed to do only one thing: enforce a DCMA-like mandate worldwide. Governments don&#8217;t want to talk about it. The corporations? They&#8217;re smiling like buddhist cows.<br />
Colonialism was best defined when the powerful centre took after its weaker neighbours and opponents. You either fought them, or you joined them.  The colonists in all of this are us, the people. We&#8217;re the ones being handed the royal decrees without benefit of democracy, the ones getting taxation without representation. We&#8217;ll be the ones held in stockades, heads put on pikes, and held up as terrorists to the state (covering for the corporation).<br />
Now lest anyone thing I&#8217;m against copyrights, I&#8217;m not. I respect the creativity needed to make something new, and the need for that artist is duly compensated for their efforts. But I&#8217;m against the inappropriate use of copyrights (and patents, for that matter). When copyrights are flaunted by corporations and not by the artist, it becomes a debate of what&#8217;s more important &#8212; stockholder dividends, or protecting the artist&#8217;s needs?<br />
&#8216;Cuz from what I&#8217;m seeing, another war for independence is coming. But this one will cross nearly every border, involve almost everyone, and probably install a new form of class structure in the process. Suddenly, that remote cabin in the mountains looks a lot more appealing&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Music industry&#039;s future: Creators and Performers</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 20:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1316</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The music industry is falling apart. Not in the way your under-maintained 1991 economy car with rust spots is leaving a breadcrumb trail of broken parts, but in the way your high school clique drifted apart as everyone got older and started looking for new direction. This is the order of things, both natural and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Music industry&#039;s future: Creators and Performers"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The music industry is falling apart. Not in the way your under-maintained 1991 economy car with rust spots is leaving a breadcrumb trail of broken parts, but in the way your high school clique drifted apart as everyone got older and started looking for new direction. This is the order of things, both natural and man-made &#8212; everything trends towards its own destruction.<br />
Sadly, the music industry hasn&#8217;t quite figured this out yet. They&#8217;ve been fighting blindly to retain the status quo, and failing miserably. RIAA take note: <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">suing your core audience for using your content</a>, thus alienating them and their sphere of influence from future purchases is not good business acumen. Where did you get your MBAs, from Sally Struthers&#8217; International Correspondance School?<br />
It&#8217;s high time you accepted that you are no longer in control of your own future. Your audience is.<br />
<span id="more-1316"></span>This is the way it&#8217;s always been, actually. The audience &#8212; those who support your business &#8212; will ultimately shape it. If they decide that something is no longer worth time (and especially money), are you going to keep that part of your business running? I think not. No businesses are that stupid. (Okay, <em>almost</em> no businesses.)<br />
They way I see it, we&#8217;re going to see two classes of artists emerge from the Old School of Music: Creators and Performers. Together, they will help retain the creativity we&#8217;ve come to expect from our music industry, but will bring more depth and more options. Music might even take on more importance in terms of its creation and distribution, and the music industry will continue to thrive if it figures out where the revenue stream will be. (Subtle hint: pay attention to the rest of this article.)<br />
Okay, first the Creators. These are the people you&#8217;re already familiar with: the artists and bands who create the music, record albums, and play concerts. In the future, they might continue doing these very things. But some of them might change. Like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/">The Beatles in their Studio era</a>, some Creators might decide only to focus on recording music (whole albums might even go away), and spend the time and effort to get them absolutely right.<br />
Oh, and a note to The Beatles, while we&#8217;re talking about you. (I love you guys, I do. You created beautiful music and you will likely forever remain as the most adept composers and performers in the rock genre.) You and/or your Estates need to get the hell off your high horses. You&#8217;re good (still), but <a href="http://tech.yahoo.com/blogs/patterson/43724">saying that your music is worth more than those sold for $0.99</a> on iTunes is the height of arrogance.<br />
There&#8217;s a reason the $0.99 price point works well. First, it&#8217;s psychological &#8212; it&#8217;s less than a dollar (or pound, or euro &#8212; you get my point). Most people don&#8217;t think twice about something that costs less than a dollar. Doesn&#8217;t matter if it&#8217;s exactly one dollar (hence one teeny, weeny cent more) &#8212; that decimal point will immediately turn buyers away. Also consider economies of scale &#8212; the less something costs, the more likely you are to sell that item. In an era where piracy is being held up as the industry&#8217;s single largest threat, you should really consider that you&#8217;ll not only increase sales but decrease piracy if one of the factors for theft (the cost) is reduced.<br />
Not that I haven&#8217;t <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/11/movie-ticket-prices-and-acts-of-piracy/">already ranted about those very concepts before</a>. Not once. Nuh uh.<br />
&#8220;Okay,&#8221; you say, &#8220;if Creators are only making albums, how do they make any money? All the big money is in concerts these days!&#8221;<br />
Yep. That&#8217;s where the Performers come in. Not every Creator will want to perform. Some of them, like The Beatles, will want to only create music. But then there are people who aren&#8217;t as interested (or even capable) of creating music &#8212; they&#8217;d rather perform. Want some examples? Look at most of the pop artists out there &#8212; they don&#8217;t write their own stuff.<br />
The catch here is that the rules change a bit. Think &#8220;cover bands&#8221;. There are bands out there &#8212; you&#8217;ve seen them &#8212; who play the dingy bars and office parties of the world who don&#8217;t have an original note to their credit, but can play <em>Baba O&#8217;Riley</em> better than The Who. The Performers excel at creating a show, a spectacle of music that can come from one or many different Creators (even themselves, if they also create).<br />
Yeah, I know that happens already. But this is the difference: They don&#8217;t ride for free. Right now, artists only receive royalties when a song of theirs is recorded by another artist &#8212; not when it&#8217;s played live in concert. Music becomes licensed for use, and any Performer can apply to use a given piece of work in a performance. The copyright laws already support such a model, just that this loophole exists.<br />
A Creator could do very well if a license fee is paid for each song that&#8217;s played on a concert tour. The fees could easily be set per venue, where a small venue might garner only $20, but a large venue could net thousands. Per showing.<br />
Yes, this could create a chaos where there are dozens of Britney Spears clones running amok. But similarly, it could also create multiple Cirque du Soleils. And since the prices of live shows would likely rise as a necessary result (since you&#8217;re paying for an experience), Performers would be competing to create high-quality shows to gain the most audience (and hence, most profit).<br />
The music industry? Who do you think orchestrates contract negotiations between Creators and Performers, who helps organise the album sales, who helps set up concerts and takes a slice of those profits? No, the profits won&#8217;t be as large as they used to be, and artists will likely end up with control (if not complete, then certainly partial) of their own work, but the music industry can certainly support the efforts. The key thing is that it will still be smaller than it is now. That much is inevitable.<br />
This model is, in my opinion, already emerging. It will have arrived when we finally see something new: a successful Performer who plays only music made by someone else. Quite literally, a Top 10 cover band. They&#8217;re definitely coming, though. It&#8217;s just a matter of when.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Beatles is better: British Invasion, or Studio?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 04:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1317</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The other day, as Mark was driving us to work, we were treated to Ob-La-Di, Ob-La-Da on Radio Dos as we were inching our way through the daily Lindora grind. I&#8217;ve heard this song at least 100 times (iTunes reports a mere 43, but I&#8217;ve reset the counters a couple of times). I was humming &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Which Beatles is better: British Invasion, or Studio?"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The other day, as <a href="http://www.facebook.com/people/Mark-Fallai/538501445">Mark</a> was driving us to work, we were treated to <em>Ob-La-Di, Ob-La-Da </em>on <a href="http://www.radiodos.com/">Radio Dos</a> as we were inching our way through the daily Lindora grind. I&#8217;ve heard this song at least 100 times (iTunes reports a mere 43, but I&#8217;ve reset the counters a couple of times). I was humming along when I thought of something:  <br />
I&#8217;m listening to The Beatles. Studio-era Beatles.<br />
I started to wonder &#8212; which I did aloud, as I often do when commuting with Mark &#8212; which of The Beatles&#8217; incarnations were more popular? Depending on whom you ask, Studio-era gets more airplay. But does that make them more interesting?<br />
Allow me to dig a little deeper on this one&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-1317"></span>First off, let&#8217;s make sure we&#8217;re all speaking-dy the same lingua-dy. I refer to basically only two eras of The Beatles: the British Invasion, and Studio. (I&#8217;m sure you could break it down further, but we&#8217;re only talking a mere decade of existence, so let&#8217;s dispense with splitting hairs on this one.) I consider these two very important for one simple reason: the latter is when they got all weird.<br />
For the record, I love Studio Beatles. But not everyone dug the sitar at first.<br />
British Invasion Beatles changed the face of rock music as we know it. The Fab Four stormed the world and captured a lot of attention with with catchy music, a few snappy covers, and some very well-played marketing (the movies ring any bells?) that solidified their popularity.  <br />
Studio Beatles  (is it just me, or is this starting to sound like &#8220;Malibu Barbie&#8221;?) took their popularity, and used it to allow them the freedom to do things they couldn&#8217;t have done without their existing fame. (Well, that, plus a visit to India and a number of drug-related issues.) They created music that was, by definition, experimental &#8212; it hadn&#8217;t been done before.  <br />
The breakpoint album for all of this is <em>Revolver</em>  (1966). Prior to this album are songs such as <em>Help!</em>, <em>Paperback Writer</em>, <em>I Want To Hold Your Hand</em>, <em>She Loves You</em>, <em>A Hard Day&#8217;s Night</em>, <em>Nowhere Man</em>, and <em>Drive My Car</em>. After <em>Revolver</em> are <em>With A Little Help</em>, <em>I Am The Walrus</em>, <em>Strawberry Fields Forever</em>, <em>All You Need Is Love</em>, <em>Helter Skelter</em>, <em>Ob-La-Di, Ob-La-Da</em>, <em>Revolution</em>, and <em>Let It Be</em>.   <em>Revolver</em>  itself is a transitionary album, including <em>Taxman</em>, <em>Eleanor Rigby</em>, <em>Yellow Submarine</em>, and <em>Good Day Sunshine</em>.  <br />
I know what you&#8217;re thinking: What&#8217;s the difference?  <br />
Listen to the music. Not just the words, but the instruments (aside from the sitar, there&#8217;s much more orchestral arrangements and alternative devices like the mellotron), the layers of sound (<em>A Day In The Life</em>, as a perfect example), the vocals (<em>Helter Skelter</em>, <em>I Am The Walrus</em>), and even how it was all put together (if you listen to <em>Strawberry Fields Forever</em>, you can here where the song slows down &#8212; that was done by hand, slowing the mixing tape with a finger).<br />
Prior to <em>Revolver</em>, the music is more recognisable. But after India, some new elements played into <em>Revolver</em>, and after The Beatles gave up touring, they put all their energy into what was next.   And that next album was <em>Sgt. Pepper&#8217;s Lonely Hearts Club Band</em>. An album that, according to some, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Wilson#Smile.2C_group_tension.2C_and_Brother_Records">caused Brian Wilson to give up on <em>Smile</em></a> and sink deeper into mental illness &#8212; he believed that The Beatles had beaten him to what he had been trying to create.  <br />
And yet, I think, the Studio Beatles get more airplay. Not the weird stuff per se &#8212; you&#8217;re more likely to hear <em>Hey Jude</em>, <em>Hello Goodbye</em>, <em>When I&#8217;m Sixty-Four</em>, or <em>Come Together</em>. But it seems to be more of the latter.<br />
So what do you think? British Invasion, or Studio? Which do you choose, and why?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My 10 favourite cover songs</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/my-10-favourite-cover-songs/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-10-favourite-cover-songs</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/my-10-favourite-cover-songs/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 04:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1229</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the annals of music, there will always the be homage to the giants that came before, who created the sound, and inspired the ones yet to come. That usually lends to things like the ubiquitous cover track &#8212; a performer&#8217;s version of a previous performer&#8217;s work.   As we all know, the vast majority &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/my-10-favourite-cover-songs/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My 10 favourite cover songs"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the annals of music, there will always the be homage to the giants that came before, who created the sound, and inspired the ones yet to come. That usually lends to things like the ubiquitous cover track &#8212; a performer&#8217;s version of a previous performer&#8217;s work.  <br />
As we all know, the vast majority of said covers are &#8230; well, crap. People don&#8217;t spend the time to consider the message or the music that went into the piece, and are quite happy to churn out a version that doesn&#8217;t sound much different than the original, or sounds so substantially worse that you really have to imagine what on earth they were thinking.  <br />
<span id="more-1229"></span>But there are the gems &#8212; the music that was reinvisioned (sort of like when Tim Burton reinvisioned <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133152/"><em>Planet of the Apes</em></a>, but with more positive results) and create &#8212; in effect &#8212; a new piece of music that can stand alone from the original.  <br />
Now there are a number of really good covers out there, and I&#8217;m not going to compile a list of all of them (this is the internet folks, it&#8217;s already been done many times over). These are just my Top 10.  </p>
<ol>
<li><em>Hard to Handle </em>&#8211; The Black Crowes.  <br />
Otis Redding probably has the record for most-covered songs. I count this one because The Black Crowes really make this their own song, and it was a wild hit on its own. It still remains a hard-driving song, the sort of thing you blare out your car windows in the heat of summer.<br />
  </li>
<li><em>I Heard It Through The Grapevine  </em>&#8211; Creedence Clearwater Revival<br />
CCR had a complete knack for taking well-known songs and taking them into near-opus form. Not only with <em>Grapevine</em>, but also  <em>Suzie Q</em> and  <em>I Put A Spell On You</em>.  <br />
  </li>
<li><em>Walk This Way </em>&#8211; Run DMC and Aerosmith<br />
It could be claimed this isn&#8217;t a cover because Aerosmith is actually playing in the song itself. But a cover it is, and a defining cover because it was the first to blend rap (hip-hop) and rock &#8216;n roll, and do it very successfully. (Hey, it revitalised Aerosmith&#8217;s career&#8230;)<br />
  </li>
<li><em>Run Run Away </em>&#8211; Great Big Sea<br />
Most non-Canucks have never heard this version. It was what brought Great Big Sea to my attention. Slade&#8217;s original version was much more hard-driving rock, with synth bagpipes for laughs. Great Big Sea ran with the celtic aspect, and made it into a song you&#8217;d swear had always been played in east coast kitchens.<br />
  </li>
<li><em>Respect </em>&#8211; Aretha Franklin.<br />
Remember the original? Idon&#8217;t either. Another Otis Redding original. But no-one can out-do Aretha Franklin for presence in performance. That, and she spun the song from being male-focused to female-focused. That&#8217;s a great twist on an original!<br />
  </li>
<li><em>Knockin&#8217; On Heaven&#8217;s Door </em>&#8211; Guns N&#8217; Roses   (also consider <em>Live and Let Die</em>, but not <em>Sympathy for the Devil</em>)<br />
I got nothing against Guns &#8216;n Roses, especially when they can what was previously a fairly laid-back Bob Dylan piece of gold (made famous later by Eric Clapton, another amazing version of this song), and then chew it up, spit all over it, use it to snort a few lines of coke, and still have it sound great. I also like G&#8217;n&#8217;R&#8217;s run on <em>Live and Let Die</em> for the same reason.  <br />
  </li>
<li><em>Higher Ground </em>&#8211; Red Hot Chili Peppers<br />
Stevie Wonder wrote a complex song that is hard to play &#8230; so Red Hot Chili Peppers turned it into a wicked base-line and leapt all over it with a lot more crunch. They even gave a nod to Stevie towards the end of the song.<br />
  </li>
<li><em>Light My Fire </em>&#8211; Shirley Bassey<br />
The Doors, big-band style. Shirley Bassey has a voice like no other, and she gives this her all. It&#8217;s especially fun in the remixes that were released in the early 2000s.  <br />
  </li>
<li><em>Hurt </em>&#8211; Johnny Cash<br />
This is a song I don&#8217;t actually own. Because it actually hurts to listen to it. You can&#8217;t watch the video without crying, unless you&#8217;re dead. This isn&#8217;t a cover &#8212; it&#8217;s a lament. You feel every inch of Johnny Cash&#8217;s life, and every drop of his pain.  <br />
  </li>
<li><em>With A Little Help (From My Friends)</em> &#8211; Joe Cocker<br />
For years, I kid you not, I thought this was a song Joe Cocker wrote. It wasn&#8217;t until one day, listening to The Beatles original, that I had the realisation that Joe Cocker had covered it. This is my prototype for a cover song &#8212; take the original, and make it your own. To this day, I don&#8217;t think anyone does it better than Joe did in 1969.  </li>
</ol>
<p>Okay, so those are my picks. What do you folks think?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/my-10-favourite-cover-songs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Network Connection</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-network-connection</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 18:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1148</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something.   For me, it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Network Connection"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something.  <br />
For me, it&#8217;s music.  <br />
<span id="more-1148"></span>Feel free to sing along. I&#8217;m sure <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSFLZ-MzIhM">you know the tune</a>&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Where are there so many drops in our network<br />
Out into the internet?<br />
Our network is simple, really quite basic,<br />
But which I daily reset.<br />
So we&#8217;ve been told by our service provider<br />
We&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me.  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Who said that ATM was a good system?<br />
Bandwidth gets shared too far.<br />
All it takes is just one jerk to tie up the router<br />
And then you can&#8217;t send your TAR.  <br />
What&#8217;s so amazing &#8217;bout tech that&#8217;s so aging<br />
When fibre was just meant to be?<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me.  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">It&#8217;s down whenever it rains,<br />
I think it&#8217;s going to be tragic&#8230;
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">We&#8217;ve been promised fibre for over a month now,<br />
I hope it comes any day.<br />
Then we&#8217;ll surf the internet without an outage,<br />
And upload without delay.<br />
We&#8217;ll have our own servers and not be dependent<br />
On our Calgary family.  <br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me!  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">La, la la lee la da do, la aw crap, the friggin&#8217; thing&#8217;s out again&#8230;</p>
<p>With apologies to Paul Williams, Kenneth Ascher, and Kermit the Frog.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kids&#039; music kinda sucks, but there is good stuff out there!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/kids-music-kinda-sucks-but-there-is-good-stuff-out-ther/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=kids-music-kinda-sucks-but-there-is-good-stuff-out-ther</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/kids-music-kinda-sucks-but-there-is-good-stuff-out-ther/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 18:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1090</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I remember kids music when I was young. A lot of it was Disney (or published by Disney), available on vinyl 45s that we played on our Mickey Mouse record player &#8212; you remember, the one where Mickey&#8217;s arm is the arm for playing the record, and his forefinger contained the stylus?   You don&#8217;t &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/kids-music-kinda-sucks-but-there-is-good-stuff-out-ther/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Kids&#039; music kinda sucks, but there is good stuff out there!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember kids music when I was young. A lot of it was Disney (or published by Disney), available on vinyl 45s that we played on our <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R-Fh6AiMyDM">Mickey Mouse record player</a> &#8212; you remember, the one where Mickey&#8217;s arm is the arm for playing the record, and his forefinger contained the stylus?  <br />
You <em>don&#8217;t</em> remember&#8230; You don&#8217;t even know what a 45 is?  Frick, I&#8217;m getting too old for this.  <br />
<span id="more-1090"></span>Well, back when I was a kid, it was a lot of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burl_Ives">Burl Ives</a>, singing bears, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raffi_(musician)">Raffi</a>, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharon,_Lois_&amp;_Bram">Sharon, Lois, and Bram</a>. I never really liked those songs much, admittedly. Well, maybe except for Burl Ives &#8212; how can you not love that voice?  <br />
Anyway, I never really liked them because I always felt like I was being patronised. Like some adult was patting me on the head and saying: &#8220;There, there, little boy. We&#8217;ll sing you a nice song to make you happy.&#8221; Well, screw you, Raffi, I don&#8217;t want to listen to your happy song about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Down_by_the_Bay">flipping bays where watermelons grow</a>. I know damn well what my mother will say, and it&#8217;s nothing about polka-dotted whale tales. I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;s even ever seen a whale, polka-dotted or not!<br />
(For the record, I have nothing but the highest respect for Raffi and the work he has done not just in music, but in child advocacy. I just can&#8217;t listen to his music.)<br />
It&#8217;s stuck with me all my life. To this day, I still can&#8217;t listen to most kids&#8217; music. And I really can&#8217;t stand the &#8220;<a href="http://www.scoutsongs.com/lyrics/purplestew.html">Purple Stew</a>&#8221; song. Man, I <em>hated </em>that song when it was sung in school. I spent years &#8212; <strong>YEARS </strong>&#8212; skooching to the corner so no-one would pick me to end up in that damned purple stew. Unlike my other apparently-ignorant classmates, I knew what the stew was for, and I wasn&#8217;t keen on being eaten!  <br />
So naturally, now that I&#8217;m a parent, I&#8217;m worried. I don&#8217;t want to have to listen to kids&#8217; music, the kind that has turned several of my friends insane because their kids want to listen to the same song a million times. If the song isn&#8217;t any good to begin with, you&#8217;re ready to commit sepuku. I&#8217;ve seen the blank stares on their faces, reminicent of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zombie">early-stages of zombification</a>. I like music &#8212; no, I need music! Good music! Without music, there is no hope, no future, no salvation, nothing to carry me through a hard day!  <br />
Luckily, now being at an age where I can appreciate things more for what they are, I&#8217;ve managed to discover a few things.  <br />
First, not everyone writes crappy kids&#8217; music. Witness <a href="http://www.sesamestreet.org/">Sesame Street</a> and <a href="http://muppets.go.com">The Muppets</a>. Jim Henson was more than a visionary when it came to children&#8217;s programming, he (or whomever did the music direction) totally hit the nail on the head when it came to the songs: Make songs that kids like to sing, that parents won&#8217;t yak at.<br />
&lt;rant&gt;<br />
Remember, folks, good parents listen and watch every thing their kid hears and sees (be it music or TV). Parents who plunk their kid in front of a TV, go off to do something else and then <a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;rlz=1C1GGLS_enCR291&amp;q=parent+group+complain+television">bitch about what their kids are watching</a> are <strong>BAD PARENTS</strong>. You&#8217;re being stupid. And yes, I&#8217;m a parent now, so I can say that with a certain amount of certainty. If you&#8217;re not willing to take an interest in your child&#8217;s activities, you&#8217;re not parenting. Just sayin&#8217;.<br />
&lt;/rant&gt;<br />
Anyhoo&#8230;<br />
A few people have figured out to make decent kids&#8217; music. I can listen to The Muppets (even the oft-maligned &#8220;<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwSFSkJvwZ4">Mah Na Mah Na</a>&#8220;) until my ears bleed, and I don&#8217;t go crazy. That&#8217;s important.  <br />
A couple of months ago, I found out I wasn&#8217;t alone. It seemed that someone else had that idea. They created an album called &#8220;<a href="http://www.musicforthekids.com/">For the Kids</a>&#8220;, which took a lot of the songs you knew as a kid, and had them played by people you listen to now. Examples: &#8220;<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vfCq1fqarJE">La La La La Lemon</a>&#8221; by the Barenaked Ladies, &#8220;<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSFLZ-MzIhM">The Rainbow Connection</a>&#8221; by Sarah McLachlan, &#8220;Twinkle Twinkle Little Star&#8221; by Chantal Kreviazuk, and even Tom Waits appears on the album.  But admittedly, even though Sarah McLachlan does a wonderful rendition, I will always hear Kermit the Frog sing &#8220;The Rainbow Connection&#8221;.  <br />
I wonder if the experience of recording &#8220;La La La La Lemon&#8221; inspired the <a href="http://www.bnlmusic.com/default2.asp">Barenaked Ladies</a>, &#8216;cuz earlier this year they released their latest album &#8212; of kids&#8217; music. &#8220;<a href="http://www.bnlmusic.com/snacktime/">Snacktime</a>&#8221; was a total surprise to me, though after listening to it a couple of times, it really makes sense. I mean, these guys are all late-30s children, for crying out loud. As a parent, I don&#8217;t just mind listening to it &#8212; I sing along to it (albeit very badly).  <br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Longs-Lullabies-Curious-George-Johnson/dp/B000CR7RDE">Jack Johnston pumped out the soundtrack to Curious George</a>, which is fantastic! (Still need to pick that one up.) And several other compliation albums with good, listenable music are now <span style="text-decoration: line-through">freely</span> readily available (see the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kids-Too-Various-Artists/dp/B0003JANQE/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-7732828-5102460?ie=UTF8&amp;s=music&amp;qid=1190337394&amp;sr=1-1#purchase">Also Bought section in For The Kids Too</a>).<br />
So, parents out there suffering to annoying music, there is hope! Turn away the garbage, and pull out some new stuff. Sing with your kids because it&#8217;s not annoying! Once you get them interested in (better) music, you can slowly amp them up to more popular music.<br />
And eventually, they&#8217;ll be screaming the lyrics to &#8220;<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v69yX3qZUZQ">Aces High</a>&#8220;. (Just don&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn you&#8230;)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/kids-music-kinda-sucks-but-there-is-good-stuff-out-ther/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1090</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steve Jobs blows it. Again.</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=steve-jobs-blows-it-again</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 16:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1091</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Sigh.  There&#8217;s nothing more frustrating than watching Apple come so close to finally tying the knot, only to leave threads dangling.   I speak, of course, of yesterday&#8217;s Let&#8217;s Rock event where the apparently-not-dead (but much gaunter-looking) Steve Jobs talked at length about iTunes and iPods. And they played Jack Johnson, who is somehow the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Steve Jobs blows it. Again."</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sigh.  There&#8217;s nothing more frustrating than watching Apple come so close to finally tying the knot, only to leave threads dangling.  <br />
I speak, of course, of yesterday&#8217;s <a href="http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/0809dt4bs89/event/index.html">Let&#8217;s Rock</a> event where the <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5047484/steve-jobs-responds-to-accusations-of-dying">apparently-not-dead (but much gaunter-looking) Steve Jobs</a> talked at length about iTunes and iPods. And they played Jack Johnson, who is somehow the most popular male performer on iTunes to this point in history. (Yeah, I don&#8217;t get that either. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, Jack, you&#8217;re a great performer &#8212; just didn&#8217;t see that coming.)  <br />
But why &#8212; oh why! &#8212; does Apple have to continually deny us a complete entertainment experience?  <br />
<span id="more-1091"></span><a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/2007/09/13/the-iphone-is-obsolete/">I blogged about the iPhone shortly after its launch</a> (well, I&#8217;d written the blog entry, just took a couple of months to get posted &#8212; long story) about how I felt that Apple had missed a killer opportunity. Like, as in a killing-the-competition-kind-of-killer.  <br />
I still feel that way. It&#8217;s been over a year and a half, now. And still, Apple plain refuses to pick up that ball.  <br />
Let&#8217;s review. Apple has the following in their product and service lines:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes</a>: a massive database of media (music, video, podcast) that now includes HD video and the ability to get movies without leaving your house</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/mac/">Powerful computers</a> (with ample disk space) to store your collected content from iTunes, and serve it out to&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/appletv/">Apple TV</a> (version 2; version 1 was a dud), which serves beautifully as a device to put your iTunes-served content onto your 50&#8243; HD television. (It&#8217;s even kept under the <a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes section on the website</a>, for crying out loud!)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/macmini/">Mac Mini</a>, which could serve as a node on an internal network to receive content from a central server and sent to Apple TV, providing additional functionality (such as web browsing &#8212; can you say &#8220;interactive television&#8221;?)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/">AirPort Extreme</a> (Wi-Fi, which I&#8217;m getting to)</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Front_Row">Front Row</a>, which allows easy access to any of your content through a simple remote (which is the way it should be &#8212; one device, not 10). And for the love of all things geeky, amp this up, will ya? You downplay it too much. It&#8217;s slick. It&#8217;s nice &#8212; give it more presence!</li>
<li>And of course, the <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> and <a href="http://www.apple.com/ipodtouch/">iPod Touch</a>, both Wi-Fi internet-capable devices that sync with iTunes</li>
</ul>
<p>So, Steve, where is my home entertainment environment?  <br />
You&#8217;ve got all the pieces. They&#8217;re right there. Sure, with enough work I could figure it out on my own &#8212; it&#8217;s not that hard. But you&#8217;re missing a killer market here. You&#8217;re an experience-based company, for Pete&#8217;s sake! You know all about experience, because that&#8217;s what you sell.<br />
Apple makes hardware and software. Big frickin&#8217; deal &#8212; so do all of your competitors. But you spent the time to make them work well, and in a way that users don&#8217;t just love, you turn them into rabid fanboys. (Sorry, Microsoft, but your fanboys don&#8217;t come close.)<br />
And while you&#8217;re at it, how hard would it be to make an app for the iPhone / iPod Touch that would allow you to flip audio/video between nodes in your house? To allow you to &#8212; literally &#8212; carry a tune from your node in your kitchen to your bedroom via your Wi-fi device (iWhatever) without skipping a beat. Video, too &#8212; so my wife can continue to watch her favourite movie in bed without missing anything.  <br />
While I&#8217;m at it, I have a couple of other requests I want to add:</p>
<ul>
<li>Let me rip my DVDs into iTunes. DCMA be damned &#8212; I bought the movie, and I want to use it on my devices. There is no <em>reasonable </em>explanation for why I shouldn&#8217;t be able to do this.  </li>
<li>50&#8243; <a href="http://www.apple.com/displays/">Cinema Display</a>. People would give up vital parts of their anatomy to have one of these. Imagine how an iTunes-served movie would look on one. Just sayin&#8217;.  </li>
</ul>
<p>C&#8217;mon, Steve. Don&#8217;t make me beg. It&#8217;s not a pretty sight.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/steve-jobs-blows-it-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1091</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
