<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>visa &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/visa/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>It&#039;s Mañana Time!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-manana-time</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 23:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1008</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s Mañana Time!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re slowly getting ourselves up-to-speed down here. But the reality is that things are not happening at anywhere near the speed we&#8217;re used to. This was something we were warned about &#8212; you need to relax and allow things to take their time. Things do not happen quickly here, and getting all bent out of shape only makes things go more slowly. (And no, totally slacking off doesn&#8217;t cause the reverse.)<br />
For us up-tight North Americans, this is the single hardest thing to contend with. Uncertainty is the name of our game, so unknown things aren&#8217;t a problem. It&#8217;s the ability to do simple little things.<br />
Like call each other. Hard to do when you have no phone.<br />
<span id="more-1008"></span>For those of you old enough to remember, it&#8217;s like when you were in high school, and couldn&#8217;t use the phone to call your friends (your sister/brother/parents were hogging it or you were grounded) and had to wait until <em>the following day</em> to talk about anything. Oh, the days of yore!<br />
When &#8212; like us &#8212; you&#8217;ve become accustomed to always-on internet access and cellular phones, it&#8217;s really hard to go back to having nothing. Literally nothing. Jason and I have to &#8220;borrow&#8221; internet from unsecured sites around our respective complexes; Mark is left high and dry. Planning requires an intricate set of where we&#8217;re going and when, and plans in the event we don&#8217;t exactly meet up as planned.<br />
(It also doesn&#8217;t help that we&#8217;re wholly reliant on taxis for now &#8212; we haven&#8217;t been able to figure out the bus system &#8212; which are notoriously unreliable for being available in all places, or being anywhere near punctual. It&#8217;s especially bad if you&#8217;re out late, such as we were Monday night when we tried to catch a taxi after going to the grocery store. It was almost an hour before we could find one.)<br />
At the office, we were struggling to get anything to work, stealing internet from an adjacent office (given, we were told the password). With Lee here, we had carte blanche to purchase a wireless router (yes, Clay, it&#8217;s a D-Link) and a printer. The router allows us to use an existing connection (which only started working properly this morning), and the printer is WiFi-enabled so we can put it wherever it makes sense to put it.<br />
And the speed at which it takes to get them done. We&#8217;re used to &#8220;right away&#8221;. Here, it&#8217;s &#8220;mañana&#8221;, which requires a lot of grains of salt. There&#8217;s just so many things that we would like to have happen now, so we don&#8217;t have to worry about them for long periods of time. But no, it don&#8217;t work that way.<br />
Take Mark, for example. He&#8217;s been in his condo since Monday afternoon. He still doesn&#8217;t have air conditioning installed (despite being told it would be done the day he moved in) and his dryer doesn&#8217;t work yet. It&#8217;s happening, just really slowly.<br />
It&#8217;s not uncommon for someone&#8217;s email system to fill because there just isn&#8217;t a rush to empty it.<br />
Collectively, we&#8217;ve got a whack of things we need done, and we&#8217;ve no idea how fast/easy these will happen. And believe me, this is causing us concern. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>How do we open a bank account? It&#8217;s not as easy as walking into a bank with a few bucks in your hand.</li>
<li>How do we purchase a car? Apparently, it&#8217;s like buying a house in North America, complete with lawyers.</li>
<li>How do we get a driver&#8217;s license? And get one of those fancy &#8220;medical&#8221; certificates?</li>
<li>How do we get the insurance? And handle the annual mechanical inspection?</li>
<li>How do we get cell phones? More importantly, how do we get the number for any phone? Unless you&#8217;re a permanent resident, you can&#8217;t get a number (although you can get the phone).</li>
<li>What health care will we get?</li>
</ul>
<p>And then there&#8217;s the visa process. This is really an entirely separate topic, which I&#8217;m not sure I can really do justice. The whole process is a living nightmare, which Jason and Jen have been trying to wrangle to the ground. Sadly, the consulate keeps giving us new information which amounts to &#8220;oh, by the way, you need to do this too, which I realise totally throws off everything you were already doing&#8221;. More on that later, though.<br />
So this is live in Costa Rica. No, I&#8217;m not complaining. I&#8217;m not changing my mind. But a lot of people wanted to know how it&#8217;s going. Now you know.<br />
Which begs the question: If knowing is half the battle, what the heck is the other half?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/its-manana-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting my Birth Certificate shouldn&#039;t be this hard</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 19:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=995</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[One part of moving to any other country is the act of applying for a work visa. It&#8217;s pretty much a requirement where treaties (e.g. the European Union) aren&#8217;t there to ease the situation. A necessary evil, if you will. Because in most cases, the process is not really well documented and you&#8217;re going to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Getting my Birth Certificate shouldn&#039;t be this hard"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One part of moving to any other country is the act of applying for a work visa. It&#8217;s pretty much a requirement where treaties (e.g. the European Union) aren&#8217;t there to ease the situation. A necessary evil, if you will. Because in most cases, the process is not really well documented and you&#8217;re going to spend a lot of time trying to figure out exactly what you need.<br />
And believe me, we are far from actually getting this one sorted out. Jason&#8217;s been a massive force in getting us some iota closer to having it done, but the reality is that we&#8217;re going to be flying by the seats of our pants until documentation is actually done.<br />
<span id="more-995"></span>One thing we need for an application is a birth certificate. But not the one you put in your wallet. You need the big one. Where you were born, your birth weight and time, who your parents are and where they were born, the name of the hospital and the doctor who delivered you. Might as well ask for my life history, while you&#8217;re at it.<br />
I don&#8217;t have this form. Nor does my mother. No problem, though, in this day-and-age, you need only sign onto a website and order one. Right?<br />
Service Ontario has a pretty slick system, I&#8217;ll give them that. But here&#8217;s my #1 major fault with it. I already have a birth certificate. I&#8217;m on record. I have a card in my wallet with a number on it that (I presume) uniquely identifies me.<br />
But it doesn&#8217;t mean sqwat. I have to fill out the form as if I&#8217;m a new birth. I have no idea how much I weighed when I was born. No idea who the doctor was (Mom remembered, though &#8212; proves you aren&#8217;t going senile!). I even had to provide a guarantor. What the heck??<br />
Ordered, though. Should get it in about five days. Then we have to get eight passport pictures, marriage certificate, and a few other things to get our visas sorted out. Yeesh. I foresee a lot of flying in my future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/getting-my-birth-certificate-shouldnt-be-this-hard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">995</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>T minus 14 days to Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/t-minus-14-days-to-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=t-minus-14-days-to-costa-rica</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/t-minus-14-days-to-costa-rica/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 03:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=980</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yeah, I&#8217;m back in Calgary, but this is only for the last bit before moving down (semi-)permanently. We have a place to live. That&#8217;s important, because it&#8217;s a place to go to. That would make this move even harder. But let&#8217;s not mistake one key detail: There&#8217;s only two weeks left (10 business days, at &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/t-minus-14-days-to-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "T minus 14 days to Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yeah, I&#8217;m back in Calgary, but this is only for the last bit before moving down (semi-)permanently. We have a place to live. That&#8217;s important, because it&#8217;s a place to go to. That would make this move even harder. But let&#8217;s not mistake one key detail:<br />
There&#8217;s only two weeks left (10 business days, at that). And I&#8217;ve got a lot to do.<br />
Among them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sell my car (and other things &#8212; a post for that is coming soon!)</li>
<li>Arrange for property management (almost done)</li>
<li>Ensure financials are sorted out (notably the bank accounts, and get a wire transfer to Costa Rica for our place)</li>
<li>Get my working visa sorted out</li>
<li>Meet with the tax guy up here (and he hasn&#8217;t set a meeting yet)</li>
<li>Ensure the renovations will be finished (they&#8217;re nowhere near done)</li>
<li>Make sure the movers are arranged (as they&#8217;ll need to clean the house out when I come back for Alex and the Wee One, herein known as Mi Pequeña Niña, or MPN for short)</li>
<li>and probably a million other things I can&#8217;t think of right now</li>
</ul>
<p>Needless to say, I&#8217;ve got a lot on my plate. There&#8217;s a lot to do, and not much time to do it. Let the fun begin&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/t-minus-14-days-to-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">980</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
