<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>copyrights &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/copyrights/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>TV is dead. Long live the internet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TV is dead. Long live the internet!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial that changed the direction of the UHF antenna&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve lost you, haven&#8217;t I? I shudder to think how few of you have an <em>inkling</em> of what I&#8217;m talking about. Yeah, that&#8217;s how old I am. I remember when there were only a handful of channels, when almost all of the content was on ABC, NBC, CBS, CBC, CTV, Global, and a few independent stations (such as the awesome CityTV and the the extremely nacent Fox). I remember the introduction of cable. I remember having to wait for the summer reruns because I missed that crucial episode of <em>The A Team</em> that everyone was talking about in class the next morning. I remember when the season debuts were a big thing. I remember when missing a live televised event was significant, because it was gone forever.<br />
It seems somehow just as bizarre a concept as the Spanish Inquisition.<br />
<span id="more-3076"></span>Up until a few years ago, this model was still fairly static. Despite the massive influx of cable, the ridiculous proliferation of specialty channels (seriously, I cannot fathom how some of them make any money), Youtube, Torrents, and the like, the concept of &#8220;television&#8221; hadn&#8217;t really changed. You still relied on the networks. Waiting for the most recent <em>Survivor</em> was still a big thing. And people watched the evening news.<br />
In the last 24-30 months, however, I&#8217;ve seen a massive shift in service. The <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/research/2010/01/the-itunes-effect-and-the-futu.html">iTunes Effect</a> completely altered the way that we consume music (despite the music industry continually trying to roll the clock back as if nothing ever happened), and it&#8217;s echoed into the way we consume video. And I choose that word very carefully: <em>video.</em> Not &#8220;television&#8221;, not &#8220;movies&#8221;. The length of a given item, or its relevance to a related group of videos (say, a television series of yore, or a trilogy of films) is largely irrelevant. Thanks to devices such as DVRs, tablets, Boxees, Apple TVs, and so forth, we can consume video on our own terms, and not at those of the telecommunications companies to whom we enslaved ourselves for over five decades.<br />
A month and a half ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/upstairs-reno-the-fun-begins/">my family moved out of our home</a> so the kitchen renovation could begin in earnest. When we did that, we took our living room video display (I now loathe to call it a &#8220;TV set&#8221;) and the Apple TV so we could watch, well, <em>something</em>. For three weeks, all we had were whatever videos were on the Apple TV &#8212; we had no network connection to speak of, so no new videos during that time.<br />
When we got back into our home, the living room was far from any suitable state to be able to hook our video displays back up to the television display boxes. No TV. (In fact, hardly any video at all.) At the end of a month and a half, it&#8217;s hard for us to really &#8220;miss&#8221; television at all.<br />
We had Telus Optik. It was a decent service, and the only real complaint I had with it was that we had about 180 channels more than we watched. There were four on any form of rotation: Discovery (for my <em>MythBusters</em> fix), Treehouse (for the kids&#8217; shows), whatever channel showed <em>Greys Anatomy</em>, and one or two other channels were in the mix for a few things. But that was it. No kidding. No joke. We paid $80 to watch less than a half dozen things.<br />
Yesterday, I pulled the plug (not <em>completely</em>, mind you &#8212; I rather stupidly signed up for a three year contract, thinking this blog post was still quite a ways away; the account is in &#8220;suspension&#8221; for $5/month, though it counts towards the contract term), and we started onto a new path: internet-only content.<br />
We are far from the first to do this. I have several friends who cut their cable a while ago, and have sufficed quite well off of whatever they could glean from the internet. iTunes has been a major source of material, as has the ubiquitous YouTube. Many have turned to the less-legal Torrents to acquire television shows and movies, while others have looked to online services such as Netflix.<br />
My problem with the internet aspect until recently was twofold: fragmentation, and accessibility. There&#8217;s a lot of different venues in which to find the content one might want to watch &#8212; think of it as having two constantly criss-cross a typical urban mega-strip mall on an erratic shopping spree, rather than being able to go to a single store and finding all that you need. And then it&#8217;s an issue where you go to a given store expecting to find the very shirt your American friend told you about, but despite it being an American clothier, that specific shirt isn&#8217;t available in Canada. (Canada remains, frustratingly, a digital backwater when it comes to internet content.)<br />
So what&#8217;s changed? Aside from the realization that we just don&#8217;t watch regular television anymore, it was the introduction of a &#8220;content aggregator&#8221; (not sure what else to call it), some handy (but legally grey-area) tools, and the ability to be a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing. Allow me to introduce our new media setup&#8230;</p>
<h2>The Device</h2>
<p>Ultimately, you need a unit to actually serve content (the stuff &#8212; literally &#8212; doesn&#8217;t fly through the air, anymore). The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_TV#Apple_TV_First_Generation">Apple TV (version 1)</a> had been a decent first attempt, but it failed in a number of ways, not the least of which was a strong tie to iTunes and not a lot of expandability (even the <a href="http://firecore.com/atvflash">aTV Flash</a> hack offered little more). It meant that it was hard for us to use different media sources, or even watch DVDs through a single device.<br />
Enter the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_Mini">mid-2010 Apple Mac Mini, model A1347 (non-server)</a>. Slightly taller than the Apple TV, this is a complete computer, and can run any software we need. Furthermore, it has full support for 1080p video, complete audio support, and because it&#8217;s a full computer, it can be used by Monkey and Choo Choo as they grow up and need to use computers in their school (while Mommy and I get to help/watch). Even more key for this specific release of the Mac Mini, however, is that this is the last one that came with a SuperDrive built-in &#8212; the next release was without an optical drive, making it hard to watch those reams of physical media we&#8217;ve been accumulating.<br />
The Mac Mini is limited to 320 GB, which seems like a lot, but it&#8217;ll fill up quickly with the media we hope to deliver through it. So instead, I&#8217;m going to be attaching it to a terabyte drive (ideally a RAIDed one, with a secondary backup for real redundancy) that will store all the music, movies, photos, and various videos that our family will use. Our network is gigabit (thanks to Telus), so network speed shouldn&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<h2>The Software</h2>
<p>Operating system aside, the complete list is still pending, but I&#8217;m looking at:</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Duh. We have a significant amount of content in iTunes, and there is zero reason not to use iTunes to access it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plexapp.com/">Plex Server</a><br />
This is the aggregation tool. It offers a significant amount of functionality for linking disparate pieces of content (including iTunes) into a single interface, and offers a variety of &#8220;channels&#8221; for watching online content. Because it works full-screen, it&#8217;s a suitable replacement for the venerable Front Row. It also includes a player that can play software copies of DVDs&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://thelittleappfactory.com/ripit/">RipIt</a><br />
Boy, it didn&#8217;t take long to get back into that legal black hole, didn&#8217;t it? Yes, I am using a piece of software to extract the content from media I have purchased and am placing it in a non-public system for my own personal entertainment, digital lock provisions be damned. Big Media pushing bullshit like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">SOPA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_Canada">C-11</a> can <a href="http://www.freshnewsound.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/johnny_cash.jpg">suck my balls</a>. I don&#8217;t like physical media, it&#8217;s too prone to damage by jam-covered fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, we will install what&#8217;s needed, when it&#8217;s needed. Right now, I&#8217;m not sure what that is, but I&#8217;m sure we can adapt when the time comes.</p>
<h2>The Services</h2>
<p>The hardware and software alone will not solve our problems. It&#8217;s not really any different than buying a &#8220;regular&#8221; television set. The problem is that you still need to have content provided from <em>somewhere</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Again, duh. Our existing library is one thing, but iTunes still has an extensive (and lovely) collection of media from which to select. We&#8217;ve used iTunes for quite some time, and plan to keep using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://goo.gl/EY0O4">The Service I Can&#8217;t Really Talk About</a><br />
Okay, this is another one of those &#8220;grey area&#8221; items. Technically, Canadians can&#8217;t see American content (think Hulu, American versions of Netflix and iTunes, and Comedy Network) because some dumbass decided that we&#8217;re not allowed to see it. So our IP blocks are scanned and summarily blocked. This service makes you look like an American &#8212; a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing &#8212; and away you go. It&#8217;s not illegal, but I&#8217;m sure that some moron lawyer will cry foul (because he&#8217;s paid to do so) and it&#8217;ll get yanked. Hence, I refuse to name it. Like Plex, it also provides a number of channels, so we should be able to watch &#8230; well, pretty much anything we want, really.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.netflix.ca">Netflix</a> (the American verison!)<br />
My biggest gripe with Netflix is that the Canadian content is so wildly different than the American content &#8230; despite it running off the same system. So thanks to the aforementioned service, we get the added benefit of a larger library.</li>
</ul>
<div>Okay, what about live television? Say I want to watch the hockey game, or even the Olympics? Well, this is where the Mac Mini comes to the rescue again. Because it&#8217;s a full computer, it has a full browser (and various necessary plugins) so that we can visit a website and watch live feeds. Perfect? Probably not, but at least it&#8217;s better than channel surfing.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>The Result</h2>
<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know yet. From everything I&#8217;ve read and from everything everyone who&#8217;s already gone down this road has told me, this seems like a solid path. But I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that it won&#8217;t be a bed of roses (and, really, when you think about it, is a &#8220;bed of roses&#8221; all that appealing? Think of the thorns!) and this could fail. I doubt it will fail entirely, since we get content no matter what, it&#8217;s just the depth at which we get it.<br />
So what of actual &#8220;television&#8221;? We&#8217;re in the shift now, and already it&#8217;s showing. Advertisers are trying to find new ways to market to people who are willingly skipping commercials. Big Media is slow to adapt (surprise, surprise!), but is at least starting to recognise the revenue potential, so it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll fight against it. But the transition from network model (which provides funding and marketing for television shows) is at risk, given a more fragmented market.<br />
For us, this can only be a win-win. People want to make video, and we want to consume it. The question of <em>how</em> remains, and its only a matter of time before these bits of technology-in-infancy are replaced by more robust and &#8220;complete&#8221; systems that hide the mess of aggregation, bringing about a true &#8220;on demand&#8221; environment that has been promised for the better part of 20 years.<br />
As for our specific experience, we&#8217;ll keep you posted. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve got a Mac Mini to set up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada: You&#039;re about to lose your freedom</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 17:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ll keep this one short folks, I promise. Do you use the internet (even watching videos on YouTube and Facebook counts)? Do you use an iPod/iPhone/iWhatever? Do you watch downloaded movies? Are you a student (or thinking of going back to school)? Then you&#8217;d better pay very close attention, because your beloved Federal Government under &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada: You&#039;re about to lose your freedom"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ll keep this one short folks, I promise.<br />
Do you use the internet (even watching videos on YouTube and Facebook counts)? Do you use an iPod/iPhone/iWhatever? Do you watch downloaded movies? Are you a student (or thinking of going back to school)? Then you&#8217;d better pay very close attention, because your beloved Federal Government under Stephen Harper is about to <strong>pull the rug out from under you</strong>.<br />
If you somehow missed the bruhaha over the United States&#8217; failed SOPA bill, you cannot afford to miss Canada&#8217;s attempt at the same thing. We&#8217;re very close to passing bill C-11, a bill sponsored by big media (notably movie studios, the music industry, and publishing giants) who want to <strong>control the way you access your music, TV, and books</strong>. They want this control because they are unable to cope with the digital economy, and want the Government to create laws that heavily restrict your actions, and impose ridiculous punishment.<br />
Now I am no expert on these things, but I read someone who is: <a href="http://www.commonlaw.uottawa.ca/en/michael-geist.html" target="_blank">Professor Michael Geist of the University of Ottawa, the Canada Research Chair of Internet and E-Commerce Law</a>. (I mean, really, could you possibly get anyone better?) He has written some excellent articles on just how <em>bad</em> C-11 is &#8212; and has been very clear on how it could be improved so it&#8217;s not so terrible. (The Government, to no surprise, is not listening.)<br />
I offer you the following from Geist&#8217;s blog. The intros here are my paraphrased summaries of the articles.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6307/125/" target="_blank">Mr. Geist&#8217;s response to the CRIA (Canadian Recording Industry Association)&#8217;s op-ed saying that C-11 isn&#8217;t that bad (as you can guess, it<em> really is</em> that bad)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6033/125/" target="_blank">The politics behind why Canada is keeping digital lock rules that will greatly hamper fair use of video, music, and books. That means: no more funny YouTube videos, and good luck at quoting books or articles for your research papers.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6287/125/" target="_blank">The Canadian music industry threatens critics of C-11, effectively branding them as criminals. It&#8217;s the moronic &#8220;you&#8217;re either with or, or against us&#8221; stance.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6275/125/" target="_blank">Mr. Geist asks ten key questions of the various copyright agreements. The answers aren&#8217;t pretty.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6257/125/" target="_blank">What&#8217;s going on behind closed doors, and how these bills are ending up in our Legislature.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6264/125/" target="_blank">Could YouTube become illegal in Canada?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6243/125/" target="_blank">How US lobbyists are pressuring the US Government to exclude Canada from international agreements because we haven&#8217;t bowed to their demands. Worse still, they refuse to allow for any cultural considerations (remember, we are a multicultural nation!)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And he also visited with <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/strombo/technology-1/soapbox-michael-geist-on-bill-c-11.html" target="_blank">Strombo on the CBC to talk about C-11</a>. It&#8217;s less than two minutes, and it explains just about everything. Even if you don&#8217;t read the above articles, <strong>you really should watch this video</strong>.<br />
In short, our beloved Government is refusing to adopt the perspective that they <strong>represent the Canadian people</strong>. They are preferring to listen to corporations and corporate associations, and worse still &#8212; <em>foreign</em> corporations who have <em>no business</em> dictating our laws.<br />
Okay, so what do you do?<br />
First, <a href="http://openmedia.ca/lockdown" target="_blank">sign up with OpenMedia&#8217;s petition</a>. It only takes a moment, and every single little bit helps. (SOPA died in the United States because the vocal backlash was loud enough.)<br />
Then, can I suggest sending the following text to the Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper (<a href="mailto:stephen.harper@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">stephen.harper@parl.gc.ca</a>), the  Minister of Industry and Minister of State (Agriculture) Hon. Christian Paradis (<a href="mailto:christian.paradis@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">christian.paradis@parl.gc.ca</a>) (he&#8217;s the Minister putting C-11 forth, and hence is responsible for our impending nightmare), Nycole Turmel (<a href="mailto:nycole.turmel@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">nycole.turmel@parl.gc.ca</a>) (she&#8217;s our official, albeit interim, Leader of the Opposition), Hon. Bob Rae (<a href="mailto:bob.rae@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">bob.rae@parl.gc.ca</a>) (our most experienced elder statesman in Parliament), and <a href="http://www.parl.gc.ca/Parlinfo/Compilations/HouseOfCommons/MemberByPostalCode.aspx?Menu=HOC" target="_blank">your Canadian Member of Parliament</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p>Dear Gentlemen and Madams,<br />
I am writing to express my deep concern regarding Bill C-11, now put forth in our Parliament.<br />
While I am very much aware of the need to address copyright laws within Canada to ensure that they meet international agreements, the terms and conditions being put forth in C-11 appear to be overlooking the needs of the Canadian people, both in the present and in the future. These terms go far past those required by international agreement, and introduce unnecessary restriction and overly  punitive  damages.<br />
The proposed conditions are being driven primarily by corporations, and are also heavily influenced by foreign governments and foreign corporations who have no right to comment on Canada&#8217;s laws. The Canadian Federal Government is supposed to stand for its people, yet we are being considered last in this process.<br />
Please stop the blind approval of this damaging legislation and reopen it to Canadian legal experts who have offered wise and just opinion on how C-11 could still address the needs of Canadian law while not imposing unnecessary (and unfair) restrictions on law-abiding Canadians.<br />
Most sincerely,<br />
[Your name here. Please use a real one.]</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why SOPA will (and must) fail</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-sopa-will-and-must-fail</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 04:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why SOPA will (and must) fail"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear reader, is something that you do need to be aware of, as it may very well affect this very website.<br />
The Stop Online Piracy Act is a bill before the Government of the United States of America that proposes &#8212; in a general sense &#8212; a series of rules and penalties in an effort to eradicate online piracy. At a high level, it certainly seems like a reasonable request. In fact, so reasonable that anyone not spending time reviewing the details of the bill might very well have missed some of the more draconian measures being implemented, allowing &#8212; in effect &#8212; individual companies to disable outright any website they believe to be infringing on copyright without right of trial, so long as said website has some dependency on US-based services (which a tremendous percentage of websites have).<br />
In effect, a US company can shut down your otherwise legal operation because they&#8217;ve told their government that you&#8217;re the bad guy.<br />
Sound unfair? It should. But this, dear reader, is also where things get more sinister.<br />
The authors of this bill are members of the American government, but that&#8217;s not who is really driving it. The backers? Big media. Notably, the same companies who have been engaging in a futile, misguided, and often grossly misdirecting effort to have laws enacted to protect their business models. <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/76259944/SOPA-Supporters">Companies represented by the RIAA and MPAA, and a host of old companies who don&#8217;t want to change.</a><br />
They&#8217;re flailing, and failing. They&#8217;re unable to grasp the concept of digital media. They&#8217;re used to their physical world &#8212; one book to one person, one CD in one CD player, one VHS tape showing on one tube-based television set. The new world allows a single copy to be copied, cut, remixed, and displayed on millions of devices simultaneously. The media companies chime: &#8220;Show me the money.&#8221;<br />
But instead of adapting, they cry foul. They cry piracy. They claim that they&#8217;re losing money hand-over-fist, and they will expire without the assistance of new laws. Yet, they&#8217;re not losing money. In fact, many of the music labels are making more than ever, largely in part to Apple, who strong-armed them into making music cheap, and &#8212; to absolutely no surprise to any armchair economist &#8212; removed the barrier to entry, and sold music in such quantities that the music industry was very likely saved from imminent death.<br />
Hence, SOPA. And while the White House chosen to not sign the bill, there is no reason to believe it won&#8217;t be back in some other odious form.<br />
Beyond the American government, I have reason to also fear this bill because of the efforts of my own government. The Canadian government has thrice shown to be spineless in its resistance to these same groups lobbying for ridiculous legislation in Canada that would put our own culture and identity as unwarranted in terms of content ownership. Our politicians, who had in decades previous been those who stand only for its own people, now show to be bowing to massive foreign conglomerates, leaving its own people to suffer as a result.<br />
SOPA, and bills like it must fail. Because they are flawed in their consideration of evolution, because they fail to take digital commerce into account, and because they will unnecessarily bind our children into false agreements and behaviours that will haunt them their entire lives.<br />
If you are an American, please write your congressperson. If you are Canadian, please write your MP. In either case, don&#8217;t let your government become party to Big Media&#8217;s insanity, don&#8217;t let our future be dictated by corporations. Learn more at <a href="http://americancensorship.org/">AmericanCensorship.org</a>.<br />
Content yearns to be free. Not free as in ownership, but free as in freedom, free as in life. Let content live.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copyrights are the new Colonialism</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Copyrights are the new Colonialism"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the name of Queen/King and country. Colonies were born out of determination, slavery, and blood extracted from those too weak to defend themselves from British will.<br />
In time, a phrase was born: The sun never sets on the British Empire. Great Britain&#8217;s influence extended far beyond its native shores, its power unquestionable. A few thrived under the colonial system, but the majority &#8212; the people living under colonial rule &#8212; were marginalised as being little more than the ignorant masses; significant numbers suffered horribly.<br />
It&#8217;s really no wonder that the Empire collapsed under its own weight.<br />
<span id="more-2512"></span>Flash forward now to our present, a world where corporations, not governments, run the world. Oh, sure, we see the laws passed by governments in the interests of its people, but it&#8217;s not the governments creating them. It&#8217;s lobbyists, working on behalf of the corporations. It&#8217;s the corporations funding political careers through donations (legal or otherwise). It&#8217;s the corporations funding large-scale advertising campaigns placing candidates more friendly to their needs into office.<br />
It is these corporations directing the current colonialism: copyrights. Think of these not as the legalese that they are &#8212; instead, think of them as land claims, which were a significant part of the British Empire. A land claim meant you had title to earn money from people who worked your land, and the power to treat them however (un)fairly you wished. If anyone tried to take your land, you were obliged to defend it with as deadly force as you could muster.<br />
Copyrights have been with us &#8212; and have been a controversial topic &#8212; ever since Thag copied Zog&#8217;s cave painting, and Zog hit Thag over the head with a rock. Interestingly, that form of retribution hasn&#8217;t changed much in the roughly 45,000 years since. It&#8217;s been a battle for recognition of ownership, of artistry, and for &#8220;what&#8217;s right&#8221;.<br />
One of the biggest problems is that copyright enforcement hasn&#8217;t been particularly consistent over the years, either. Zog was lucky enough to avoid a complex judicial system. Until the early 1990s, we had to rely mostly on physical presence (namely, you had to buy an actual piece of art). Software copyrights existed, but were poorly enforced, even within large law-abiding corporations. The advance of technology broke the physical barrier, gave people the ability to access materials on their behalf &#8230; and shortly afterwards, gave corporations the ability to know who was breaking their rules.<br />
We saw the first signs of the new colonialism at the turn of the 21st century, when one of the corporations &#8212; the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recording_Industry_Association_of_America">Recording Industry Association of America</a> (RIAA) &#8212; launched what would be come the first of many public and painful lawsuits. Metallica brought the battle into the public eye when they effectively offended the then-denizens of the internet, decrying the &#8220;fair use&#8221; belief held by many (the legality of said perspective notwithstanding). It was the first shot fired in the new independence, the first time that people showed to the world that they wanted things on their terms, not someone else&#8217;s.<br />
The weapon wielded by groups like the RIAA and the MPAA (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_Picture_Association_of_America">Motion Picture Assocation of America</a>) was not a battle axe or a howitzer, but the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Millennium_Copyright_Act">Digital Millennium Copyright Act</a> &#8212; the DCMA. This law, enacted in the United States of America, implemented two of the treaties agreed upon by WIPO (World Intellectual Property Organization) in 1996. This is how we came to know DRM (Digital Rights Management). They used it <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/11/movie-ticket-prices-and-acts-of-piracy/">to guilt us to not copy</a>, and then <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">slaughter us when we did</a>. The corporations had found legitimacy for their battle through governments.<br />
In theory, this should have worked entirely to the corporation&#8217;s wishes. Within their own borders, the laws were clear, and things went (mostly) according to plan. But they weren&#8217;t so effective in the international reality. Not all countries recognised, or even seemed to care, about other country&#8217;s laws &#8212; and certainly not about the ones that enforced copyrights. Governments were engaged again to help enforce the corporations&#8217; will.<br />
When you have to go up to the biggest kid in the schoolyard and ask for your toy back, all you can do is whine. I imagine &#8220;aw, come on!&#8221; was heard a lot when the United States asked China not to copy software, movies, or CDs. But China opted to give only a token of acceptance &#8212; sort of like giving back only one of the wheels from the Tonka truck. China can do that, because it owns a huge portion of the United States debt, and provides the United States with cheap imports.<br />
Where were the WIPO and the World Trade Organization (WTO) in all of this? Someone&#8217;s got to run world court, right?<br />
But the rules started changing. In the last two years, Canada had to improve its own copyright legislation, also based on DCMA, and driven by the industry &#8212; the corporations &#8212; and not by the people whom the government should represent. The sledgehammer just fell on <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/4697/125/">Costa Rica: fix your copyrights, or the United States will stop importing sugar</a> (note that coffee and bananas were excluded from the ban).  Lo siento, Costa Rica, but CAFTA/TLC won&#8217;t help you here &#8212; remember, the United States wrote the core of it to benefit themselves.<br />
Costa Rica and Canada are not alone. Dozens of countries are now working on ACTA &#8212; the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2010/01/actas-shameful-secret.ars">Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement &#8212; a virtually secret pact</a> designed to do only one thing: enforce a DCMA-like mandate worldwide. Governments don&#8217;t want to talk about it. The corporations? They&#8217;re smiling like buddhist cows.<br />
Colonialism was best defined when the powerful centre took after its weaker neighbours and opponents. You either fought them, or you joined them.  The colonists in all of this are us, the people. We&#8217;re the ones being handed the royal decrees without benefit of democracy, the ones getting taxation without representation. We&#8217;ll be the ones held in stockades, heads put on pikes, and held up as terrorists to the state (covering for the corporation).<br />
Now lest anyone thing I&#8217;m against copyrights, I&#8217;m not. I respect the creativity needed to make something new, and the need for that artist is duly compensated for their efforts. But I&#8217;m against the inappropriate use of copyrights (and patents, for that matter). When copyrights are flaunted by corporations and not by the artist, it becomes a debate of what&#8217;s more important &#8212; stockholder dividends, or protecting the artist&#8217;s needs?<br />
&#8216;Cuz from what I&#8217;m seeing, another war for independence is coming. But this one will cross nearly every border, involve almost everyone, and probably install a new form of class structure in the process. Suddenly, that remote cabin in the mountains looks a lot more appealing&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Music industry&#039;s future: Creators and Performers</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 20:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The music industry is falling apart. Not in the way your under-maintained 1991 economy car with rust spots is leaving a breadcrumb trail of broken parts, but in the way your high school clique drifted apart as everyone got older and started looking for new direction. This is the order of things, both natural and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Music industry&#039;s future: Creators and Performers"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The music industry is falling apart. Not in the way your under-maintained 1991 economy car with rust spots is leaving a breadcrumb trail of broken parts, but in the way your high school clique drifted apart as everyone got older and started looking for new direction. This is the order of things, both natural and man-made &#8212; everything trends towards its own destruction.<br />
Sadly, the music industry hasn&#8217;t quite figured this out yet. They&#8217;ve been fighting blindly to retain the status quo, and failing miserably. RIAA take note: <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">suing your core audience for using your content</a>, thus alienating them and their sphere of influence from future purchases is not good business acumen. Where did you get your MBAs, from Sally Struthers&#8217; International Correspondance School?<br />
It&#8217;s high time you accepted that you are no longer in control of your own future. Your audience is.<br />
<span id="more-1316"></span>This is the way it&#8217;s always been, actually. The audience &#8212; those who support your business &#8212; will ultimately shape it. If they decide that something is no longer worth time (and especially money), are you going to keep that part of your business running? I think not. No businesses are that stupid. (Okay, <em>almost</em> no businesses.)<br />
They way I see it, we&#8217;re going to see two classes of artists emerge from the Old School of Music: Creators and Performers. Together, they will help retain the creativity we&#8217;ve come to expect from our music industry, but will bring more depth and more options. Music might even take on more importance in terms of its creation and distribution, and the music industry will continue to thrive if it figures out where the revenue stream will be. (Subtle hint: pay attention to the rest of this article.)<br />
Okay, first the Creators. These are the people you&#8217;re already familiar with: the artists and bands who create the music, record albums, and play concerts. In the future, they might continue doing these very things. But some of them might change. Like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/04/which-beatles-is-better-british-invasion-or-studio/">The Beatles in their Studio era</a>, some Creators might decide only to focus on recording music (whole albums might even go away), and spend the time and effort to get them absolutely right.<br />
Oh, and a note to The Beatles, while we&#8217;re talking about you. (I love you guys, I do. You created beautiful music and you will likely forever remain as the most adept composers and performers in the rock genre.) You and/or your Estates need to get the hell off your high horses. You&#8217;re good (still), but <a href="http://tech.yahoo.com/blogs/patterson/43724">saying that your music is worth more than those sold for $0.99</a> on iTunes is the height of arrogance.<br />
There&#8217;s a reason the $0.99 price point works well. First, it&#8217;s psychological &#8212; it&#8217;s less than a dollar (or pound, or euro &#8212; you get my point). Most people don&#8217;t think twice about something that costs less than a dollar. Doesn&#8217;t matter if it&#8217;s exactly one dollar (hence one teeny, weeny cent more) &#8212; that decimal point will immediately turn buyers away. Also consider economies of scale &#8212; the less something costs, the more likely you are to sell that item. In an era where piracy is being held up as the industry&#8217;s single largest threat, you should really consider that you&#8217;ll not only increase sales but decrease piracy if one of the factors for theft (the cost) is reduced.<br />
Not that I haven&#8217;t <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/11/movie-ticket-prices-and-acts-of-piracy/">already ranted about those very concepts before</a>. Not once. Nuh uh.<br />
&#8220;Okay,&#8221; you say, &#8220;if Creators are only making albums, how do they make any money? All the big money is in concerts these days!&#8221;<br />
Yep. That&#8217;s where the Performers come in. Not every Creator will want to perform. Some of them, like The Beatles, will want to only create music. But then there are people who aren&#8217;t as interested (or even capable) of creating music &#8212; they&#8217;d rather perform. Want some examples? Look at most of the pop artists out there &#8212; they don&#8217;t write their own stuff.<br />
The catch here is that the rules change a bit. Think &#8220;cover bands&#8221;. There are bands out there &#8212; you&#8217;ve seen them &#8212; who play the dingy bars and office parties of the world who don&#8217;t have an original note to their credit, but can play <em>Baba O&#8217;Riley</em> better than The Who. The Performers excel at creating a show, a spectacle of music that can come from one or many different Creators (even themselves, if they also create).<br />
Yeah, I know that happens already. But this is the difference: They don&#8217;t ride for free. Right now, artists only receive royalties when a song of theirs is recorded by another artist &#8212; not when it&#8217;s played live in concert. Music becomes licensed for use, and any Performer can apply to use a given piece of work in a performance. The copyright laws already support such a model, just that this loophole exists.<br />
A Creator could do very well if a license fee is paid for each song that&#8217;s played on a concert tour. The fees could easily be set per venue, where a small venue might garner only $20, but a large venue could net thousands. Per showing.<br />
Yes, this could create a chaos where there are dozens of Britney Spears clones running amok. But similarly, it could also create multiple Cirque du Soleils. And since the prices of live shows would likely rise as a necessary result (since you&#8217;re paying for an experience), Performers would be competing to create high-quality shows to gain the most audience (and hence, most profit).<br />
The music industry? Who do you think orchestrates contract negotiations between Creators and Performers, who helps organise the album sales, who helps set up concerts and takes a slice of those profits? No, the profits won&#8217;t be as large as they used to be, and artists will likely end up with control (if not complete, then certainly partial) of their own work, but the music industry can certainly support the efforts. The key thing is that it will still be smaller than it is now. That much is inevitable.<br />
This model is, in my opinion, already emerging. It will have arrived when we finally see something new: a successful Performer who plays only music made by someone else. Quite literally, a Top 10 cover band. They&#8217;re definitely coming, though. It&#8217;s just a matter of when.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/04/music-industrys-future-creators-and-performers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada, you can blame Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canada-you-can-blame-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 03:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sigh. Well, thanks to the residents of Calgary Centre-North, Canada is now stuck with Jim Prentice again.  And I&#8217;m just too darned tired to rant. Wasted effort at this point.   But I reserve my right to call &#8220;I told ya so!&#8221; when the lawsuits start.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sigh.<br />
Well, thanks to the residents of Calgary Centre-North, Canada is now stuck with Jim Prentice <em>again</em>.  And I&#8217;m just too darned tired to rant. Wasted effort at this point.  <br />
But I reserve my right to call &#8220;I told ya so!&#8221; when the lawsuits start.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/canada-you-can-blame-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Canada: I&#039;m going to break the law</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 20:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/21/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it would appear that short of an Act of God (or, heaven forbid, some actual common sense runs through Parliament), Bill C-61 will forever handcuff Canadians and prevent long-term technological evolution. It&#8217;s one of the worst-written pieces of legislation to hit Canadians in years, as it does not take real-world habits into account at &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dear Canada: I&#039;m going to break the law"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, it would appear that short of an Act of God (or, heaven forbid, some actual common sense runs through Parliament), Bill C-61 will forever handcuff Canadians and prevent long-term technological evolution. It&#8217;s one of the <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/3385/125/">worst-written pieces of legislation to hit Canadians</a> in years, as it does not take real-world habits into account at all (short of the negative views, of course), and penalises everyone for something most of them haven&#8217;t done.<br />
I&#8217;m going to get the Government in on a little secret. I&#8217;m breaking it. I refuse to let your ridiculous industry ass-kissing paperwork prevent me from moving with the evolutionary tide. I&#8217;m breaking the law and doing what I think is right.<br />
<span id="more-1102"></span>Well, I will if/when I return to Canada &#8212; I&#8217;m currently living in Costa Rica.<br />
Here&#8217;s my single major problem: You won&#8217;t let me evolve. DVDs are dead. They are ubiquitous, that I won&#8217;t argue. But they are dead. The whole Blu-Ray/HD-DVD argument was a total non-event because it didn&#8217;t matter who won &#8212; Apple had already beaten them to the punch. Download the movies at half the price, and with all of the quality. It&#8217;s not about physical media anymore &#8212; it&#8217;s about data files.<br />
Maybe you missed the whole MP3 revolution? Why do you think so many music stores are closing, or desperately clawing their way online to weather the storm? I can&#8217;t tell you the last time I bought a CD. But I can tell you where all my music is &#8212; on a networked drive.<br />
Yes, NETWORKED &#8212; already in violation of Bill C-61. It&#8217;s there for two reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>I don&#8217;t want to lose anything. Data files are much more volatile than CDs thanks to hardware failure. Loose a hard drive, and you lose your entire music collection. So my music is on a RAID 1 <acronym title="Network Attached Storage">NAS</acronym> device to ensure that loss doesn&#8217;t happen.</li>
<li>Since my wife and I combined our personal CD collections into a single unit, we want to be able to listen to them from our computers &#8212; both of them. Hey, maybe you didn&#8217;t know that many Canadian households are now have more than one computer? Well, fancy that!</li>
</ol>
<p>And I&#8217;m not stopping there.<br />
The concept of scheduled TV is dying. It ain&#8217;t dead yet, but it&#8217;s not far off. The TiVO was the first stab in the back, the DIY PVR was your sucking chest wound, and the release of TV shows to iTunes and Hulu &#8212; well, there&#8217;s your kill shot. (And I&#8217;m not even counting the illegal forms of distribution through the &#8216;net!) It&#8217;s here, folks, like it or not.<br />
I&#8217;m going to build a PVR. A big one. My friend Doug built his own &#8212; three TV cards so he can record two shows while watching a third, all at the same time. And why not? I don&#8217;t want to sit through 500 channels of shit. Most of what&#8217;s on the air these days is utter garbage, and the good stuff is often on when I&#8217;m either not near a TV (which is normal) or on at a time when I&#8217;m asleep. So I&#8217;m gonna watch what I want <em>when I want</em>.<br />
And now here&#8217;s where I&#8217;m really gonna piss you off&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;m going to put all of it on my home network. Yeah, that&#8217;s right, a network. My televisions (however many I end up having, it doesn&#8217;t matter) will be &#8220;smart&#8221; &#8212; they&#8217;ll have a little computer attached to them (say, like the Apple TV, an off-the-shelf product) that links into my media library.<br />
Oh, did you not notice that both Microsoft Media Center and iTunes were media libraries? How sad that the Government doesn&#8217;t even realise the <em>current</em> state of affairs, let alone plan for the future.<br />
I&#8217;ll be able to watch whatever I want from any TV in the house. All my music, TV shows, movies (yep, even the ones that were on the DVDs that I purchased legally), home movies, internet radio, and so forth, will all be accessible 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, from any computer in my house.<br />
But no, dear Government, I will not be broadcasting that to the world. I do have my limits, and the security of my at home network is paramount. It will be high-speed, but it will also be high-security, for a reason. Firewalled, encrypted, and monitored. Because this is my family&#8217;s stuff, not the public&#8217;s. And last I checked, Canada was still a constitutional monarchy, and not a socialist state.<br />
So, please fine me. Take me to court. I&#8217;ll be more than happy to take such a ridiculous set of legislation to the Supreme Court of Canada and have it struck down. I&#8217;ve got lots on my side, including musicians, artists, prior art, and &#8212; this is the hardest one to have in court, but I feel it&#8217;s the most necessary &#8212; <em>common fucking sense</em>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/dear-canada-im-going-to-break-the-law/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1102</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An open letter to Jim Prentice</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/an-open-letter-to-jim-prentice/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-open-letter-to-jim-prentice</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/an-open-letter-to-jim-prentice/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 15:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear &#8220;Honourable&#8221; Jim Prentice, Allow me to express my sincerest feelings when I say you are responsible for fucking over the Canadian people. This bill you are introducing this morning &#8212; likely as I write this very post &#8212; is not for the benefit of the Canadian people. Not one bit. This is purely to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/an-open-letter-to-jim-prentice/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "An open letter to Jim Prentice"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/technology/story/2008/06/04/tech-prentice.html">&#8220;Honourable&#8221;</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Prentice">Jim Prentice</a>,<br />
Allow me to express my sincerest feelings when I say you are responsible for <em>fucking</em> over the Canadian people. <a href="http://www2.parl.gc.ca/HousePublications/Publication.aspx?DocId=3570473&amp;Mode=1&amp;Language=E">This bill you are introducing this morning</a> &#8212; likely as I write this very post &#8212; is not for the benefit of the Canadian people.<br />
Not one bit.<br />
<span id="more-1000"></span>This is purely to support two things: <a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2007/12/18/mtv-declares-music-i.html">Archaic business models that have not yet woken up to the new economy</a>, and to the United States government. You are blatantly ignoring the wishes of the informed Canadian public, who (thanks to the <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/">grassroots efforts of Michael Geist</a>) have told you that this is a bad idea. You mistakenly believe that it is business that runs this country, and not its citizens.<br />
You claim you wish to find balance between the Canadian people and business. Unless there are 10+ million business involved, Mr. Prentice, I&#8217;m rather certain there will be no balance even considered. And when the courts become clogged with <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">incessant and insipid lawsuits</a> rivalling the ridiculousness going on with the RIAA south of the border, we&#8217;ll know who to thank.<br />
Be rest assured, there are a lot of people in your constituency who are not happy with you. I hope this is your last hurrah in Ottawa, because I&#8217;d be very surprised if you are re-elected after this. You are effectively handcuffing our daily activities for no valid reason. Please explain to me why I am not allowed to put movies I have purchased on my iPod or put them onto my home media server? You can&#8217;t.<br />
There is no valid reason &#8230; except money of course. I dare not suggest anything further on this matter, since I&#8217;m sure it would raise some interesting legal issues. But I truly do wonder what is going through that pin head of yours that thinks this is good for the Canadian people.<br />
And please, let&#8217;s remember that this is about people, not companies nor governments. Laws are meant to support day-to-day civil operation of a society, not hamstring it to the point of revolution. Canada stands (as much as it can, knowing full well yesterday&#8217;s <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2008/06/11/apology-future.html">long-overdue apology for residential schooling</a>) for tolerance, understanding, and balance. Let&#8217;s not make another dumb-ass mistake that lingers for a century. The Digital Copyright Millennium Act made one major fallacy &#8212; it assumed that it understood the new economy. It clearly hasn&#8217;t. Nor do you. As the Minister of Industry, you might want to brush up on that.<br />
Shit like this makes me almost happy to be moving to Costa Rica&#8230;<br />
[Update]<br />
I also have to add a link to an excellent article by fellow Twitterite Matthew Ingram, who <a href="http://www.mathewingram.com/work/2008/06/12/canadian-copyright-bill-good-and-bad/">really nailed some of the key issues with this bill</a>.<br />
[Update Update]<br />
I changed a couple of notes above once I had a chance to read some of <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/3025/125/">Michael Geist&#8217;s review of the new act</a>. Overall, I still hold the same level of seething hate for this act (I still think we&#8217;re getting royally screwed by big business and American interests), I just wanted to make sure I wasn&#8217;t using a fact incorrectly. (Notably, I can copy music to my iPod, but I can&#8217;t copy a movie that I purchased to my home media server.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/an-open-letter-to-jim-prentice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is that irritating whine?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/02/what-is-that-irritating-whine/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-is-that-irritating-whine</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/02/what-is-that-irritating-whine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 22:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/02/28/what-is-that-irritating-whine/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A word to the RIAA: SHUT UP! Who the hell do these people think they are? Why are they telling me what I can do with the material that I&#8217;ve legally paid for? Why should I do anything more than punch the first RIAA rep I come across just to take out my frustration? I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/02/what-is-that-irritating-whine/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What is that irritating whine?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A word to the RIAA:<br />
<em><strong>SHUT UP!</strong></em><br />
<span id="more-663"></span>Who the hell do these people think they are? Why are they telling me what I can do with the material that I&#8217;ve <em>legally</em> paid for? Why should I do anything more than punch the first RIAA rep I come across just to take out my frustration?<br />
I came across an article on Ars Technica that talks about how the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20070228-8948.html">RIAA is claiming that the FAIR USE Act being introduced in the States is effectively the end of all humankind</a>. It bothers me a lot. Why? Because the RIAA is now so full of itself (and the idea of DRM) that it claims the DCMA is responsible for the creation of:</p>
<ul>
<li>iPod</li>
<li>iTunes Store</li>
<li>DVDs</li>
<li>The Holy Roman Church</li>
</ul>
<p>Well, maybe not that last one, but it&#8217;s equally as unlikely (and insipid to suggest) that the DCMA had anything to do with it.<br />
News flash: The DCMA didn&#8217;t create, lend to, or even hint at the dawning of anything beyond a headache. The iPod exists because Apple wanted to dominate the MP3 market. (They switched from MP3 to AAC encoding to avoid licencing fees to Fraunhofer.) The iTunes Store exists because Apple had the foresight to see that selling the <em>experience </em>mattered more than the device that plays the music.<br />
As for DVDs &#8230; c&#8217;mon, gimme a break. It&#8217;s called natural process of development. The DVD was inevitable the moment the first light went on in the mind of the guy who created the LaserDisc. DCMA just made the wrangling over its development (different regions, anyone?) way more complicated than it needed to be. Don&#8217;t even get me started on Blu Ray or HD-DVD.<br />
The DCMA act was brought in by lawyers for the sole purpose of increasing profits for themselves, earned by assisting their clients in suing teenagers and little old ladies who downloaded a few tunes online. That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s done for us &#8212; it&#8217;s made the RIAA into a monster through its own ego.<br />
And no, the FAIR USE Act it&#8217;s not legalizing hacking, ya idjits! It&#8217;s allow the legal schmoes such as myself (we&#8217;re in the <em>majority</em>, last I checked) to use the things that we legally <em>paid</em> for in whatever manner we feel appropriate (provided it doesn&#8217;t violate existing public use stipulations). Ideas that existed with the CD, cassette tape, 45, LP, phonograph, wax recording tube, Gutenburg&#8217;s printing press, and the freaking clay tablet.<br />
Considering all the damage that&#8217;s been done, I&#8217;m almost amazed anyone wants to listen &#8212; let alone be associated &#8212; with the RIAA. So please, shut the hell up and let us get access to the damn media we bought.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/02/what-is-that-irritating-whine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">663</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
