<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>human rights &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/human-rights/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 02:36:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Conservatives win the next Canadian federal election!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 02:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This isn&#8217;t a predictive headline, folks. This is truth. The Conservatives will win the election in October. I, as an Expat, can&#8217;t vote in it, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that I don&#8217;t take at least a sense of interest in it. Or stock in the fact that the Conservatives are finally getting what they wanted &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Conservatives win the next Canadian federal election!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This isn&#8217;t a predictive headline, folks. This is truth. The Conservatives will win the election in October. I, as an Expat, can&#8217;t vote in it, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that I don&#8217;t take at least a sense of interest in it. Or stock in the fact that the Conservatives are finally getting what they wanted the last time: Complete control.<br />
For the last two years, Canada has been living in the most blessed of political states: a minority government. As close to having the car in neutral as it gets. It means the least chance of political scandal (the &#8220;ruling&#8221; party doesn&#8217;t want to make mistakes that&#8217;ll haunt them come election time), and the opposition enjoys a place of perceived power as they get courted by the ruling party to help push through votes.<br />
Well, that&#8217;s all coming to an end now. So brace yourself, Canada &#8212; things are likely to get worse.<br />
<span id="more-1086"></span>Here&#8217;s the reality: The Conservatives are keen on setting the dial back a number of years. Estimates vary between 5 and 50. They want a world that&#8217;s white-bread, heterosexual, and very business-friendly. As opposed to being morally and ethically stalwart.<br />
Now, for the record, I&#8217;m not holding up the Liberals to that standard. As we all know, their 13-year run in office went seriously afoul and rotten towards the end. Not a problem with the Liberals per se, but with a lack of government controls. Things like that make it hard to keep office.<br />
Unlike the Liberals, the Conservatives are also very straight-forward with what they want. They will:</p>
<ul>
<li>Turn a blind eye to the environment, crying an attack on the economy every time</li>
<li>Repeal the same-sex laws</li>
<li>Keep the GST artifically low to make good with the Canadian public, despite a perpetual deficit</li>
<li>Raise an issue with Canadian sovernity over the arctic waters</li>
<li>Claim the Liberals are liars</li>
</ul>
<p>My arguments to these?</p>
<ul>
<li>You can focus on the economy now, or deal with the disaster later when the environment is in serious trouble. We know global warming has started to thaw the arctic, has accelerated the melting of glaciers (and will turn parts of Alberta to desert within 30 years), the abysmal record of the oil sands is ruining massive tracts of northern wilderness, the rise of temperatures is causing more and more issues with farming, and a never-ending dependence on gasoline is ruining air quality across the country. So what&#8217;ll it be, Harper &#8212; deal with the problem while it&#8217;s still manageable, or worry about your next meal ticket.</li>
<li>I hate to say it, but this is coming. There are too many intolerant people in the Conservative party, and I full expect them to dig this corpse out and force a repeal.</li>
<li>News flash, folks &#8212; you might be paying less GST, but you&#8217;re suffering for it when you go to the doctor or have to pay more for your childrens&#8217; education. Where do you think this money was coming from before? Yep, taxes. It&#8217;s a bit of a &#8220;duh&#8221;, but I&#8217;m regularly amazed at how many people complain about both high taxes and difficult medical care. I suggest picking one and sticking with it.</li>
<li>Canada has a place in the arctic &#8212; defending the rights of those who live there, and protecting the delicate environment that&#8217;s rapidly falling apart. And that should be it. This isn&#8217;t the Panama Canal, folks; even thinking of charging a toll for passage is just asking for conflict.</li>
<li>Everyone lies in politics. The trick is identifying it. That&#8217;s your reponsibility as a Canadian citizen, I might add &#8212; not theirs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here&#8217;s my problem with this election: There are no alternatives. Dion is totally the wrong person for the job. He has even less charisma than Harper (yes, it is possible). The Liberal Party chose wrong. They went with a Francophone in the interests of preserving national unity. But a Francophone does not represent the new powerhouse of the West (Alberta outclocks Ontario, folks, by quite a large margin when you look at the per capita). Canadians like money, and Harper comes from a province with stinkloads of it.<br />
It doesn&#8217;t matter what the Liberals should have done &#8212; that&#8217;s old news, now. It&#8217;s how they&#8217;re going to handle this election. The Liberals are going to take a serious hit. The Conservatives have done an excellent job of not pissing anyone off, and have a track record to be envious of. The Liberals? Whine, whine whine. Not smart.<br />
NDP? Please. Don&#8217;t make me laugh. The Bloc also serves no threat &#8230; except to the Liberals. See above.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/conservatives-win-the-next-canadian-federal-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The IOC is living in a dream world</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 19:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I was skipping through my various feeds this morning, I came across the following quote from Jacques Rogge, President of the IOC: Jacques Rogge, the president of the International Olympic Committee, said the Games would &#8220;help the world to understand China, and it will also help China to understand the world.&#8221; I think we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The IOC is living in a dream world"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was skipping through my various feeds this morning, <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/sport/othersports/olympics/2518676/Beijing-Olympics-George-Bush-calls-on-China-to-improve-human-rights-record.html">I came across the following quote</a> from Jacques Rogge, President of the IOC:</p>
<blockquote><p>Jacques Rogge, the president of the International Olympic Committee, said the Games would &#8220;help the world to understand China, and it will also help China to understand the world.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>I think we need to send a team into the IOC&#8217;s fantasy world and extract them, because they&#8217;ve clearly (and totally) misunderstood the situation.<br />
<span id="more-1029"></span>I have two fundamental issues with that quote:</p>
<ol>
<li>The world will not understand China</li>
<li>China has no interest in understanding the world</li>
</ol>
<p>Why won&#8217;t the world understand China? Because the world doesn&#8217;t want to. China is the world&#8217;s   (current) longest-standing culture. Over 5,000 years of history &#8230; a lot of it engaged in conflicts. Not so much war with others, but mostly with themselves. That&#8217;s 5,000 years of political instability, dictatorships (the Emperors weren&#8217;t exactly the nicest of people), insurrections, and various foreign invasions (Mongols, British, and Japanese, to name but a few).<br />
In a country with 1.3 billion people (70% of whom are rural farmers) and a very long history of political upheaval, you can&#8217;t really blame the so-called Communist Party (by textbook definition, China isn&#8217;t communist, nor has there ever been a truly communist government) for being so strong-armed. It could be even viewed (on an optimistic level) that this is more about ensuring the stability of China as a nation than it is about political power.<br />
If you were being optimistic. I could go pessimistic, but that&#8217;s another post&#8230;<br />
Here&#8217;s the problem, though: The world wishes to impose its political views on China. The world wants China to be democratic. The world wants China to end its human rights abuses. <em>The world wants China to change.</em> This isn&#8217;t an act of understanding. This is the world pointing it&#8217;s finger at China.<br />
China, on the other hand, is sort of like a bull. It&#8217;s a big, heavy animal that pretty much does what it wants, when it wants. Everyone needs that bull for various things (bulls are handy things to have on the global ranch), but if you ask that bull to do something it doesn&#8217;t want to do, it&#8217;s not going to do it. It doesn&#8217;t need to, and it&#8217;s quite content to stay the way it is.<br />
More importantly, China doesn&#8217;t want to take direction from outsiders. It has its own view of what it needs to survive, and the views of the rest of the world don&#8217;t really matter. Why? Because even with everything &#8220;bad&#8221; that China does, everyone still buys &#8220;Made In China&#8221; because it&#8217;s cheaper than buying it elsewhere. The money keeps coming, so China has no need to change. (Ain&#8217;t greed grand?)<br />
Hence, there is no need for China to understand the world. Ergo, it won&#8217;t.<br />
So, a note to the IOC: I dunno where the heck you people have been for the last decade, but you really shouldn&#8217;t be surprised with the situation you&#8217;re walking into. China is effectively third-world in terms of its industrialisation, political system, environmental controls, and judicial process. Their economy makes them damn near the most powerful country on Earth (they own a seriously large chunk of the United States&#8217; debt). Hence all the pollution, lack of access to free information, and all their reasons to crack down on perceived freedoms.<br />
Expect protests and expect problems. The Olympics in Beijing have only just started, but you should expect that you&#8217;ll be hearing about these for years to come.<br />
(Incidentally, if my blog isn&#8217;t already blocked in China, this should pretty much prevent it from ever being seen there. Oh well.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/the-ioc-is-living-in-a-dream-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1029</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Same-Sex Marriage is Wrong for Canada</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 05:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/01/why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our world is changing. It changes every day. Sometimes for the better, and sometimes for the worse. Overall, the trend is &#8220;better&#8221;. Or so one would believe over the last few years. Let&#8217;s flip back to the 1960s. Racial integration within the Americas (the United States and Canada, to be specific). Back then, racial integration &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why Same-Sex Marriage is Wrong for Canada"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our world is changing. It changes every day. Sometimes for the better, and sometimes for the worse. Overall, the trend is &#8220;better&#8221;. Or so one would believe over the last few years.<br />
Let&#8217;s flip back to the 1960s. Racial integration within the Americas (the United States and Canada, to be specific). Back then, racial integration was the huge topic. We&#8217;d gotten past the days of Rosa Parks, who&#8217;d single-handedly kicked off the turning point in equality. Now we were dealing with another shocking problem: love between the races. How could a white girl marry a black man? (Or a white man a Chinese woman, etc.)<br />
It&#8217;s amazing how people react to open-mindedness. There were those who supported the movement. And there were those who vehemently objected. (Interestingly enough, the objectors were in every case far more violent than the supporters. Draw your own conclusions.) Eventually, reason prevailed.<br />
&#8220;What reason?!&#8221; cries the Moral Right. &#8220;There ain&#8217;t no reason a white woman should marry anything but a white man.&#8221;<br />
It&#8217;s the idea of racial purity. Whites should stick with whites, blacks with black, asians with asians, and so forth. It&#8217;s the idea that you dilute the race when you intermix. Or at least that&#8217;s what I assume it to be. It&#8217;s sometimes hard to get a straight answer from the objectors &#8212; they tend to mumble a bit as they froth at the mouth.<br />
Today, interracial marriage is accepted in the open-minded areas of the Americas (most of Canada, the Blue States, and major cities within the Red States), tolerated in others. In a few cases, you&#8217;d be best to be walking several steps apart from each other as not to lead onto the possibility that there&#8217;s a familial link of any kind. Thankfully, those are few and far between.<br />
So imagine my surprise during the U.S. elections back in November. You&#8217;d think we&#8217;d swung back 40 years. Suddenly, States that seemed to be rolling in reason were rolling back the clock. Laws outright banning same sex marriages. Even the thought of marriage between two men caused people to be physically ill.<br />
In Canada, we were running the other direction. British Columbia, Ontario, New Brunswick, Yukon Territory, Newfoundland, Quebec, and even venerable Saskatchewan realized that there was no reason why homosexuals couldn&#8217;t be married, and made it legal. (Although Nova Scotia had an interesting twist to it &#8230; provincial law required one partner to be the &#8220;wife&#8221; and the other to be the &#8220;husband&#8221;, no matter what the sex was.)<br />
Alberta, being the closest thing Canada has to a Red State, naturally objected, declaring the end of the world if same sex unions were approved. King Ralph even declared that he&#8217;d use the &#8220;Notwithstanding Clause&#8221; to opt out of the Canadian Bill of Rights so he wouldn&#8217;t be forced to accept a homosexual married couple as his neighbour.<br />
I mean, really, how does this guy keep getting reelected?<br />
The Canadian Supreme Court ruled about a month ago that the final decision on Gay Marriage would not sit with them. As far as they were concerned, the law was clear: it&#8217;s a Legislative matter. A political hot potato / buck-passing to dump it on Parliment Hill to resolve. Ultimately, it will require a passage of a Bill to decide whether or not my friends Amy and Sandra can get married.<br />
Yes, I have a particular attachment to this issue. But not just because I have gay friends who want to get married. I have an attachment because I believe in equality.<br />
Yes, this is all about equality. You can sit there and postulate all you want. It&#8217;s about equality. If you live in North America, if you believe in the democratic system, then you must by nature believe in equality. There is no practical difference between the sexes (reproductive systems notwithstanding), nor are there any between the races (reproductive sizes, real or imagined, notwithstanding). So why should there be any between sexual orientations?<br />
The single biggest argument I&#8217;ve heard against gay marriage is that the Bible doesn&#8217;t allow for it. I have two challenges to that. First, show me the exact passage that denies gay marriage. There&#8217;s one about a man lying with another man (or rather forbidding it), but that does not extend to marriage. You can infer all you want, but if you&#8217;re reading the Bible as an instruction manual, you&#8217;ll need to pull the exact quote. As for my second point, just to be really picky, Canada and the United States separated the church and state well over a century ago to prevent interference with the operation of each. In other words, the Bible has nothing to do with it.<br />
Not to mention the fact that marriage is a legal issue, not necessarily a religious one. Sure, there will be those who want a religious ceremony &#8212; that&#8217;s a decision for the specific religious sect, not for the lawmakers. There is secular marriage, where the law does apply. What does the law provide? A legal union of two people in entity. It allows the bonds of family to be formally created and legally binding, for better or for worse. Frankly, if two gay men want to have the same grief that comes with some of the marriages I&#8217;ve seen, I say let &#8217;em go for it!<br />
&#8220;Wait a cotton-pickin&#8217; minute! I don&#8217;t want two fags to marry because someone might think I married a man!&#8221;<br />
That afraid of your own sexuality, eh? I mean, really, how paranoid do you have to be to think that anyone is a) going to think that you married someone of the same sex (unless it&#8217;s really blatantly obvious), or b) even remotely care? Let&#8217;s have a reality check for one moment. The vast majority of people are heterosexual. That means the majority of marriages are heterosexual. That means the majority of people will be thinking you would be married to someone of the *opposite* sex. If anything, it&#8217;ll be homosexuals getting offended because people will think they married someone of the opposite sex.<br />
It&#8217;s equality, people. Get a dose of reality. Get your heads out of the sand and look around. What, really, would change if gays were allow to marry? Absolutely nothing. Your life wouldn&#8217;t change one iota. Not one freaking bit.<br />
It&#8217;s the idea of sexual mixing. The fear that if homosexuality were treated the same as heterosexuality, that it might &#8220;bleed&#8221; into the rest of the pool, and suddenly make that guy standing next to you look just as attractive as that woman on the other side of the bus. This, for some reason, terrifies people. Be a little rational, will you? If the thought of sleeping with a member of the same sex revulses you now, it still will six months, six years, and six decades from now. You&#8217;re set in your ways. Your children will be unaffected, as will their children, so on and so on.<br />
Tolerance will be important. Everyone needs to understand that, like with race, homosexuality isn&#8217;t an underclass. They are the same as everyone else. They have the same rights as you and I on an individual basis. On paper, we are all exactly the same. (Well, except for the Native Indians. They continue to get the shaft from society, but that&#8217;s another rant for another time.) If we are all the same individually, why should we not be the same together?<br />
The vote hasn&#8217;t come yet in Canada, but it&#8217;s coming soon. To all Canadian Members of Parliment: Please be rational. Don&#8217;t think with your gut &#8212; that&#8217;s what&#8217;s caused all this trouble. Think with your head. Think with the law in mind. Remember that the issue is not about religion, it&#8217;s not about sexuality. It&#8217;s about equality. Homosexuals deserve the right to marry as much as anyone else in this country (of legal age, that is).<br />
And this is coming from a guy who&#8217;s getting married himself. I have the right to marry. I want my friends to have that same right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/why-same-sex-marriage-is-wrong-for-canada/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">404</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
