<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>health &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3685</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; not of woman borne! &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. Well, mostly. That &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; <em>not of woman borne!</em> &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. </p>



<p>Well, mostly. That whole anti-K thing and all, as we remind you of every now and then. Which is almost a bizarre parallel to today: almost immediately after you were born, the doctors wanted to whisk you away to the NICU to ensure that the anti-K situation wasn&#8217;t affecting your health. You were isolated. </p>



<p>Ten years later, you&#8217;re isolated again. This time, none of our doing (biological or otherwise), but because of COVID-19. You&#8217;re spending your birthday apart from nearly everyone but your family. </p>



<span id="more-3685"></span>



<p>You had wanted a grand party for today, and had selected a pretty cool venue: Petland. With lots of animals and friends and cake and food and fun and &#8230; it was all cancelled. Everything non-essential is closing, or has already closed. School was cancelled, all classes for the rest of the school year. I hope you might remember this year for the longest summer ever, but who knows what is yet to come with restrictions. I&#8217;m not sure which you lament more, that you won&#8217;t have any friends for your birthday, or that you won&#8217;t have the party. You love your animals.</p>



<p>It seems today will be just the four of us. Mostly the three of you, I suppose, since I&#8217;m trapped in the basement, working from home. I hadn&#8217;t planned it this way, of course, and this is the World&#8217;s Lamest Excuse on a day like this while we&#8217;re all in this situation (I <em>am</em> in the house, after all), but this is the last card in my hand after playing all the others&#8230;</p>



<p>My vacation time this year was planned for next week, March break, as we were going to go Saltspring Island. And with today being a school day, you were <em>originally</em> going to go to school. (Admittedly, that changed, too, but by then my vacation time was all gone.) I was going to see you as much as possible today as I could. That was the plan. </p>



<p>Only three days ago, Sunday the 16th, the Government cancelled all classes. School out for summer. International travel was effectively banned. Albertans were <em>strongly </em>encouraged to not partake of any non-essential travel, effectively forcing a cancellation of vacation. The day after, my office went into full &#8220;work from home&#8221; mode, and I became one of the most needed people in the office to ensure that this was going to work. </p>



<p>Two days later, I&#8217;m in the basement, wishing I could have avoided this. I am sorry, Choo Choo. I wish this situation were different, very different. I wish I was with you the entire day, not just a part of it. I wish we could have your party, I wish we could go to the coast and see seals and whales and fairy doors. I hope that, somehow, we still manage to make today a good day for you, given the limitations on what we can &#8212; what we should responsibly &#8212; do. </p>



<p>One day, I hope, we will make this up for you. Maybe you&#8217;re 11th will be more memorable for the things we couldn&#8217;t do this year. Or, maybe, many years from now, you&#8217;ll reminisce on today: &#8220;Lemme tell you about my 10th birthday, when the whole world was on quarantine&#8230;&#8221;</p>



<p>Now that&#8217;ll be a story.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New year, renewed hope</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/new-year-renewed-hope/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-year-renewed-hope</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/new-year-renewed-hope/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 05:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3399</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I blinked, and 2013 kind of vanished on me. It&#8217;s a blur, a seemingly endless stream of activity that rarely relented long enough for me to appreciate any of it. I have pictures to prove it, sure, but I have to struggle sometimes to remember the date, or what else might have happened. I&#8217;m fairly &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/new-year-renewed-hope/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New year, renewed hope"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I blinked, and 2013 kind of vanished on me. It&#8217;s a blur, a seemingly endless stream of activity that rarely relented long enough for me to appreciate any of it. I have pictures to prove it, sure, but I have to struggle sometimes to remember the date, or what else might have happened.<br />
I&#8217;m fairly certain this isn&#8217;t (solely) a result of age. It&#8217;s parenthood. It&#8217;s a rigorous schedule that keeps the family machine moving at quite a pace. Between work schedules (which alternate such that Alex and I resemble &#8220;ships passing in the night&#8221;), school schedules, various after school activities, and the family activities, there&#8217;s very little time for much else.<br />
Like, say, writing a blog.<br />
<span id="more-3399"></span><br />
This brings me to a few revelations of the last year. The first one, which is more of an evolution than a revelation, is that I miss my kids terribly every day. I&#8217;ve always missed them, but they&#8217;re no longer babies &#8212; they&#8217;re little people with clear thoughts, (mostly) clear emotions, and they&#8217;re capable of expressing themselves. They no longer say &#8220;don&#8217;t go&#8221; when I head off to work because they want me around &#8212; they <em>sound</em> sad, they hold me longer, and it sounds more like begging than just mere missive.<br />
And especially, Choo Choo. She&#8217;s still three. It seems like she&#8217;s been three for years, now, which I absolutely adore. Back before Monkey was even born, I&#8217;d told Alex that I was mostly looking forwards to the age of three, because it&#8217;s enough that a kid can talk clearly, but they&#8217;re just constantly happy, and silly, and fun, and dancing, and making up stories, and everything I thought parenthood would be. (Yes, I&#8217;ve since had the rude awakening.) My last child is growing up, and she&#8217;s no longer the wee babe I held in my arms. She&#8217;s still small, yes, but if she&#8217;s like Monkey, she&#8217;ll be growing quickly. Too quickly.<br />
The next one, and likely the most painful one to realize, is that I&#8217;m not particularly happy. I love my wife, I love my kids, and that&#8217;s a lot, don&#8217;t get me wrong. But I feel like I never see my friends (especially my far-flung ones; the internet is therein a live-saver), and it&#8217;s hard to make new friends, given the aforementioned schedule. There&#8217;s also little down time from the moment I wake up until the moment I go to sleep. Every day I see notes from people I know on Twitter or Facebook &#8212; people I know with families &#8212; who talk about the hobbies they have or the games they play, and I think: How the hell do they do it? I look at my house, it&#8217;s frequently a mess, and I feel like I&#8217;m barely above water. I don&#8217;t travel, which I used to love and miss dearly, which makes me feel confined to Calgary. And then I look at my lowly little blog, which used to get so much attention, and I&#8217;ve barely made a post a month over the last year. Maybe I need to find new happiness? I don&#8217;t know.<br />
My health ain&#8217;t what it used to be. As little as a few years ago, I was still largely invulnerable, or so it seemed. Then I got a hernia. Then appendicitis. Illnesses seem to be getting worse. And then this year, my heart palpitations sent me to a cardiologist. I&#8217;m fine, for the record &#8212; I&#8217;m actually <em>normal</em> in that sense &#8212; but the doctor did say I was exhausted, been drinking too much caffeine, and not getting enough sleep.<br />
The last one was a recognition that I can no longer do any kind of freelance work. I&#8217;ve tried, repeatedly, over the years to make it work. The realities of my &#8220;day job&#8221; almost always interfere, and I usually end up disappointing others. But now, with my home life weighing in more than my job, taking on any kind of work &#8212; even pro bono &#8212; is stressful beyond comprehension. I don&#8217;t like to disappoint, especially with a friend, and the only way is to formally and completely renounce freelancing. Regardless of how much my family could use the extra income, it&#8217;s just not tenable, especially when related to my happiness problem.<br />
So this will be a year of some change in that regard. I need to change <em>something</em>. &#8216;Cuz going on as it&#8217;s currently going isn&#8217;t good for my happiness, my health, or my family.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/new-year-renewed-hope/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3399</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2012, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2012-a-year-in-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3208</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2012, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an unfulfilled burning need to travel, it&#8217;s truly a wonder I got out of bed in the morning.<br />
So it wasn&#8217;t with any reservation that 2012 walked out of my life on Monday night, yet it still managed to leave me rather depressed. Sadly, 2013 woke me up looking already a lot like 2012, so I&#8217;m not sure if I&#8217;m able to look at this new year with much hope yet. Instead, I suppose I shall have to try harder to make things work more my way.<br />
This not to say that I &#8220;didn&#8217;t like&#8221; 2012. It&#8217;s hard not to like an entire year in one&#8217;s life, especially one that brings so many new things to learn and experience. I just wish it hadn&#8217;t been so darned painful&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3208"></span><br />
Like I said, 2012 was a busy, busy year. So there&#8217;s no way to know if I&#8217;m going to miss anything, because I did a pretty lousy job of documenting it. I can only hope that through extracting details from Twitter, Facebook, Flickr, and my blog, that I can stir enough memories to get this all straight.</p>
<ul>
<li>Experienced our first New Year&#8217;s Tea not at the Banff Springs</li>
<li>Learned that my youngest, Choo Choo (no more than 2), was a lot smarter than I thought she was &#8230; and she only got smarter (and more defiant)</li>
<li>Saw far too few friends for far too short a time</li>
<li>Worked a lot, but not painfully so &#8212; I still had a (family) life outside of it. YAY FOR BALANCE!</li>
<li>Developed a vicious cold that led to &#8212; no word of a lie &#8212; pulled rib muscles. Owie.
<ul>
<li>Had my first chest x-ray, taken by &#8212; drum roll, please &#8212; my wife, Alex!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Discovered that Monkey loves shrimp, especially at dim sum</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t go to dim sum nearly enough</li>
<li>Had some fairly steep automobile expenses (block heater for the Jetta, and a new car for Alex)</li>
<li>Renewed a mortgage for the first time ever (instead of selling the house)</li>
<li>Continued hating, loathing, and despising having to deal with the Facebook API</li>
<li>Went through the agony, grief, despair, anger, bargaining, and acceptance of a major home renovation, as we redid our kitchen (and subsequently, floors and bathrooms)
<ul>
<li>I do so love our kitchen, though&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Found my cooking skills steadily improving
<ul>
<li>Need to watch more cooking shows, and figure out some different techniques</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Broke my little toe. Why do the little bones always hurt more?</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time ranting about how badly our Federal Government seems to want to drive Canadians to be not Canadian (specifically through bills C-11 and C-30, the ever-present Big Telco lobbies, revisiting the abortion laws, and Rob Anders)</li>
<li>Disposed of my giant water jug container of coins (6,400+ of &#8217;em)</li>
<li>Realized that building a &#8220;mobile&#8221; site is a pointless exercise, and that the design needs to adapt for all devices &lt;&#8211; my professional epiphany of the year</li>
<li>Lived (very basically) out of my contractor&#8217;s rental home for a month while our home was being torn apart</li>
<li>Celebrated Choo Choo&#8217;s 2nd Birthday</li>
<li>Cancelled TV at home, and went to internet-only for video content (still a work-in-progress)</li>
<li>Saw the original cast of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em> on stage</li>
<li>Had my first ambulance ride, my first shot of morphine, and my first (and thankfully last) bout of appendicitis
<ul>
<li>Also had a sponge bath; nowhere near as much fun as it sounds</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw <em>Avenue Q</em>. Hurt myself laughing.</li>
<li>Tried not to laugh when Monkey decided to cut Choo Choo&#8217;s hair. I failed.</li>
<li>Learned that I cannot work from home, without breaking my children&#8217;s hearts</li>
<li>Showed my children the &#8220;hole in the sun&#8221; as Venus transited our star &#8212; I think Monkey started to understand heliocentrism&#8230;</li>
<li>Exited the year wondering how RIM/Blackberry is still a going concern, and why Microsoft hadn&#8217;t fired Ballmer</li>
<li>Went to Fairmont Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Oakville</li>
<li>Went to Banff</li>
<li>Aaaaand that&#8217;s it, folks. Depressingly boring year for travel.</li>
<li>Turned 40. Or as I like to call it, &#8220;4, with an extraneous zero&#8221;.</li>
<li>Watched in real-time (delayed by 7 minutes) as Curiosity landed on the surface of Mars using the single most insane landing procedure ever conceived</li>
<li>Monkey became a 5 year old. I&#8217;ve been a parent for over <em>five years</em> now. And the world has not fallen apart (entirely). Who knew?</li>
<li>Tried to stop drinking coffee. Boy that was dumb.</li>
<li>Reminisced about being with the CBC TV 50th Anniversary project 10 years ago</li>
<li>Took Monkey to her first day of kindergarten; oddly, I didn&#8217;t cry</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that our family cannot operate without a second car</li>
<li>Made jam for the first time, and I shall do it again!</li>
<li>Made tomato sauce and tomato paste from scratch; there&#8217;s a reason they&#8217;re cheaper to buy in cans, sadly.</li>
<li>Made a &#8220;perfect&#8221; prime rib. Now I need to make it again.</li>
<li>Figured out how to make gluten-free stuffing for turkey (just need to tone down the spices a bit, as I discovered at Christmas)</li>
<li>Used a roto-tiller for the first time. Sadly, it had very dull blades, so using it hurt. A lot.</li>
<li>Felt my gut in my stomach as a man stood on the edge of the stratosphere. Then he jumped.</li>
<li>Somehow acquired strep</li>
<li>Got taken down, not by the strep, but by the stupid antibiotics I took to get rid of the strep. Go figure.</li>
<li>Had a very long night of trying to get my frozen, snow-bound car out of the airport parking lot.</li>
<li>Had a vicious cold knock me down for two days (minor flu?)</li>
<li>Got a re-learning of high school physics when I tried to vacuum up a box of baking soda. (Try it yourself, if you dare.)</li>
<li>Rode the new West LRT on the first day! Love that I take a train to work, now.</li>
<li>I saw <em>The Hobbit</em>. Yes, I liked it.</li>
<li>Had a minor outpatient surgery that didn&#8217;t exactly jingle my bells; made for an uncomfortable Christmas</li>
<li>Got an iPad mini for Christmas from my company. Had to admit that the Mini is actually a good idea.</li>
<li>Got (and installed) a Nest thermostat. I can&#8217;t stop fiddling with it.</li>
<li>Finally went sledding for the first time in two years.</li>
</ul>
<p>That brings me to the end of the year. So: busy, interesting, painful, trying, educational, somewhat wistful, and definitely productive. We&#8217;ll see what 2013 brings.<br />
I just hope it means no more trips to hospitals&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3208</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 2.5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-2-5</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3121</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 2.5"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), and not far away, flooding is so bad that highways are being washed out.<br />
<span id="more-3121"></span>Yesterday started looking like it might rain, though it didn&#8217;t. That allowed us to bolt up the side of the mountain for a chance for you two to go in the bouncy castles. Sadly, only one of the three was set up, as they were all very wet (the one you were in was still a bit damp). It was so wet, and the clouds threatening a downpour so badly that we couldn&#8217;t decide whether or not to buy a day pass. Thankfully, the two attendants decided to let you two bounce anyway, as they didn&#8217;t get the other two castles set up until much later.<br />
We went for a snack afterwards: hot chocolate for both of you, along with (shared) slices of banana bread and devil&#8217;s food chocolate cake. After our snack, we all headed back to the S7 house for our lunch: Grandpa&#8217;s chili.<br />
Choo Choo went for a nap, Monkey went out with Mommy and Tia Nicole. It was quiet around the house for a little while.<br />
I attempted to make dinner. With a mostly-frozen chicken. The stupid heat-proof dish shattered, the chicken hadn&#8217;t thawed as expected, and I was thoroughly disgusted with my lousy attempt. We ended up having to order from a new restaurant nearby (that happens to make a fire roasted chicken with fries that is strongly reminiscent of those from a chain named for Alps-bound edifices).<br />
Post-dinner was our hot springs soak. Monkey, you&#8217;re getting better at swimming, but you&#8217;re still somewhat hopeless without a floatation device. We need to practice on your doggy paddle. And, I should also add, you finally took to the hot pool (which was significantly hotter than when Mommy and I had gone the night before). Choo Choo, on the other hand, could have just stayed there for hours.<br />
Sadly, that trip also put both of you well past your bedtimes; Monkey, you didn&#8217;t get to bed until nearly 22:00, which is dangerous for your overnight rest (as it stands, it wasn&#8217;t that good). But I can safely say Choo Choo had it worse.<br />
Laryngotracheobronchitis, to be exact. You picked it up yesterday morning, the wheezing very prominent. We had hoped it would pass, but it just got worse. So bad that a couple of times you woke up screaming &#8212; which wasn&#8217;t actually screaming, as you couldn&#8217;t really do much other than gasp and emit a raspy squeak. At 4:00, Mommy and I packed you into the car, and we were off to the hospital &#8230; nearly 30 kilometres away.<br />
The trip to Invermere was a bit difficult. I was anxious to get you there quickly, Choo Choo, but with dawn only just starting to dawn, it was still very dark, and light patches of fog randomly appeared. In any urban setting, I might not think twice about it &#8212; on Highway 93/95, which has a constant animal warning, I was more than a little worried about going too quickly.<br />
Ironically, I nearly hit the damn deer sitting in the middle of an Invermere street, less than 100 metres from the hospital, because I&#8217;d stopped watching for them.<br />
Invermere Hospital is small. Really small. The outer doors were locked, and we had to get buzzed in. Then we were met by the entire hospital night staff: Two Registered Nurses and a Practicing Nurse. A grand total of 12 emergency beds, and 8 overnight beds. We were the only ones there, so we had the entire hospital focused on you, Choo Choo. A far cry from the busy-ness of the Calgary hospitals.<br />
The Practicing Nurse almost immediately said &#8220;croup&#8221;, which is a nasty condition that stems from an infection of your vocal chords. Sadly, in small kids, it causes a tight constriction, leading to the wheezing and barking cough. That led to a phone call to the admitting desk &#8212; at some other remote location &#8212; and another call to the on-call doctor.<br />
In the meantime, we were whisked away to Bed #4 &#8212; as unoccupied as every other bed &#8212; where you got to lay down with a warm blanket. You were scared, Choo Choo, and I don&#8217;t blame you. There were two very nice ladies fawning over you, and you were somewhere you didn&#8217;t recognise at all. Then, to make things worse, you had some drops to drink (an oral steroid to help with your larynx), and then they put a mask over your face to help give you some ventalin to help you breathe.<br />
You really didn&#8217;t like that mask. It didn&#8217;t matter that it was painted to look a bit like a doggy, you just didn&#8217;t want it there, you didn&#8217;t want the mist, you just wanted it off. You cried. And I don&#8217;t blame you one bit. You were given a box of apple juice and two Digestive cookies for when you got it off, and stickers to put on while the mist did its work.<br />
When the doctor arrived, a very nice man I might add, he proceeded to do a quick check, and then took you and Mommy for a quick stroll outside to let the cool air help you breathe.<br />
I asked the nurses about the hospital, and learned how small it was, that we were in the &#8220;shoulder&#8221; season, between the high points of winter (dislocated shoulders and broken bones from the ski hills) and summer (not detailed, but I presume similar given the tendency for people to switch from one seasonal downhill activity to another).<br />
Finally, we left, thanking everyone for all their help. You munched on ice chips and your other cookie until we were back in Fairy-mont. We all went right back to bed &#8212; I curled up with you until you were asleep again &#8212; and managed to get some more rest.<br />
Breakfast was late, activities were (sadly) largely aborted. We managed to get in a short swim before eating lunch. Choo Choo went back down for a nap (in an effort to try get back to regular sleep patterns), and Monkey and I went for a (short) craft session, making Wiggly Worms.<br />
Monkey, you&#8217;ve been making cupcakes with Granny, and watching Wall-E. That&#8217;s where we are right now. Mommy just got back from a much-needed massage. Grandpa and Tia Nicole are in Invermere. The afternoon and evening are ahead of us; we shall see what comes.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appendix to Appendicitis</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/appendix-to-appendicitis/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=appendix-to-appendicitis</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/appendix-to-appendicitis/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 02:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3096</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ll presume you&#8217;ve read my previous post, which is how I got &#8230; well, to this post. If you haven&#8217;t read the previous one, you should &#8212; this is kind of Part 2. We&#8217;ll wait&#8230; Now when we last chatted, you left me lying on a bed in Rockyview General Hospital&#8217;s Day Surgery ward, waiting &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/appendix-to-appendicitis/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Appendix to Appendicitis"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ll presume you&#8217;ve <a title="The gall of it all" href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/05/the-gall-of-it-all/">read my previous post</a>, which is how I got &#8230; well, to this post. If you haven&#8217;t read the previous one, you should &#8212; this is kind of Part 2.<br />
We&#8217;ll wait&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3096"></span>Now when we last chatted, you left me lying on a bed in Rockyview General Hospital&#8217;s Day Surgery ward, waiting for my turn for an emergency operation. (The term &#8220;emergency&#8221; being highly subjective, of course. One person&#8217;s emergency is another person&#8217;s &#8220;hurry up and wait&#8221;.) The assessment had been long done, the papers were signed, and all I had to do was &#8230; well, lie there.<br />
You&#8217;re probably wondering how I wrote that entry while waiting. It wasn&#8217;t easy. I was on a lot of morphine. It took me a while so it didn&#8217;t sound totally incoherent. (I&#8217;m leaving it in its morphine-addled state for posterity.) As for the mechanism of how I wrote it &#8212; thank the wonders of modern technology. An iPhone 4 with the WordPress app, and access to the hospital&#8217;s WiFi (courtesy of my wonderful wife, Alex, who happens to work there). The rest you&#8217;ve already read.<br />
Somewhere around 14:15, Alex finally appeared (she&#8217;d planned to be there earlier, but chaos reigned once again around the house), early for her evening shift so she could come by and check on me. I had just been given my instructions to drop the trousers as the call to go to the OR would come &#8220;any minute&#8221;, so I had to be pants-less.<br />
I didn&#8217;t have the apprehension I had for my <a title="My first surgery" href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/">first surgery, which was just over a year ago for my hernia</a>. I was terrified of that one. Having had that experience, I was less worried for this one, though I still wasn&#8217;t really looking forward to it. So when they came for me a few minutes after Alex appeared, I wasn&#8217;t sweating bullets &#8230; although in hindsight, that could have also been due to the morphine.<br />
I should also note that until writing this blog entry (which is just before I posted it; I don&#8217;t normally write blogs over long periods of time), I didn&#8217;t really understand how much danger I was in. I downplayed the appendicitis a lot more than I should have. It&#8217;s a serious thing, and treating it lightly in any way can quite easily lead to death. Point of note, there.<br />
I waited for only a moment in the OR holding area before the nurse appeared to wheel me around to OR 12, where I was met by the anesthesiologist, and eventually the surgeon. The standard &#8220;what&#8217;s your name, birthdate, and what procedure are you having done&#8221; questions were posed (it&#8217;s a sanity check more than anything else), before I was brought into the OR itself. OR 12 is a lot smaller than the OR I&#8217;d been in before, and looked less TV-friendly. I repeated the answers again to the two other nurses in the room, adding &#8220;my appendix hates me, and I&#8217;m not particularly fond of it at the moment, either&#8221; before scootching over onto the surgical table.<br />
The last thing I remember clearly was asking the anesthesiologist if I was getting the same drugs I got the last surgery (she seemed to have the record handy), since I knew those drugs wouldn&#8217;t, y&#8217;know, kill me or anything. Also, I&#8217;d found the recovery to be fairly easy. She replied that while the base drug was the same, the actual mix was usually left to the preferences of the individual.<br />
An aside&#8230; I&#8217;m trying to understand this whole &#8220;preference&#8221; thing. I&#8217;ve never really understood how the medical industry has such a wide variance in the execution of a medical practice. Different drugs because of a personal opinion, even when documentation shows otherwise; or Doctor A doing a procedure totally different than Doctor B, even if the result is the same. Are standards that loose? I know this is kind of a rhetorical question, because the same nonsense exists in my field &#8212; standards are at best guidelines, and open to interpretation. Anyway&#8230;<br />
I fought recovery tooth and nail. I simply couldn&#8217;t snap out of it. Whatever drugs that anesthesiologist used are going down in my books as &#8220;awful, not to be repeated&#8221;. I had to be on an oxygen supply for three hours before anyone would let me take that idiotic hose off my nose. My belly was sore, but the pain in the lower right quadrant was (thankfully) gone. About a half hour after gaining most of my consciousness, I was wheeled up to Unit 83 to begin my stay.<br />
The reason for the stay is due to the seriousness of appendicitis. The appendix, depending on whom you ask, is a leftover (but still somewhat functional) part of your digestive tract, meaning that it&#8217;s still got some really nasty stuff in it. While functioning normally, it&#8217;s not usually a problem. But when something goes wrong &#8230; it goes wrong in a really, really bad way. Most of the problem is that its in an area with a (literal, but being used mostly for effect) shitload of bacteria. And they just love it when things get necrotic, like when appendicitis sets in. Leave it too long, and the appendix starts to fill with pus, bursts, and then you&#8217;ve got a major problem on your hand &#8212; lots of bad stuff now floating around in the most sensitive part of your body.<br />
Antibiotics are a key part of this fight. I&#8217;d already started to receive them as part of treatment and preparation, but I was to stay on them (and am still taking them) as part of the cleanup. While some appendicitis cases are cleaned up entirely with antibiotics, surgery is still a very common practice. But even with removal, there&#8217;s usually some nastiness left behind.<br />
By about 18:00, <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/sowrey/status/198202776889720833">I was feeling somewhat stable again</a>. News had been light on the surgery, and all I had known was that the appendectomy had gone well, and that the offending piece was &#8220;pus-y&#8221;. I was in a room with a older woman going through a very rough bout of recent diabetes diagnosis, migraines, and what appeared to be a rebellious intestine. For all that I was in discomfort, she easily put me in my place.<br />
An hour later, I was already doing my first post-operative walkabout, having felt that lying down for the better part of two days was already too much. It had gone far better than I had expected, and was glad to see that my abdominal muscles had been left largely unaffected. (Incidentally, if you&#8217;re ever offered a choice between a laparoscopy vs. a regular surgery, get the laparoscopy. The holes hurt, yes, but the recovery is mind-bogglingly easier.)<br />
Then came the sponge bath. This was unexpected, and not particularly desired, either. The reason is the iodine wash, which isn&#8217;t even really iodine &#8212; it&#8217;s an orange-coloured antiseptic whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten &#8212; apparently becomes itchy if left on too long. I didn&#8217;t remember this from last year, but I&#8217;d also been discharged the same day, and washed myself. Staying at the hospital, this puts the responsibility in the hands of the Nurse&#8217;s Assistant.<br />
This was Divya, a nice young woman who announced herself as she drew the curtain around my bed, explaining what she had to do. I suddenly felt rather sad that this had to be part of her job, to remove the antiseptic, to have to deal with people&#8217;s private parts and various injuries. How numb must you become to such things? And also, a recognition that I had pretty much shed any remaining humility as this was done, for I (apparently) no longer had anything to hide.<br />
By 20:00, I was eating. Toast, mind you, and dry at that. But it was food. I&#8217;d sufficed off of saline drips for nearly 24 hours, and enough was enough. Just a little earlier, I&#8217;d been fortunate to receive some ice chips; the sound I made from that first spoonful was so orgasmic that every nurse who came in related the story to me. It was honest, though &#8212; my mouth felt absolutely awful, and having something in my mouth, especially some form of liquid, was the most gratifying sensation.<br />
I had refused morphine since coming out of surgery (not for any sort of &#8220;heroism&#8221; &#8212; the last batch had made me feel like my beard was made of electricity, and it totally buggers up my sense of time), so I had to struggle to get to sleep on my own, along with assistance from my old friend, Tylenol 3.<br />
But rest came fitfully, at best. Aside from having my blood pressure taken regularly, I also had to get up to go to the bathroom fairly often (that stupid pee bottle didn&#8217;t agree with me one bit), and I couldn&#8217;t seem to get just warm enough to get restful (seriously, why are hospitals <em>cold</em>?). I finally &#8220;woke up&#8221; for the day at 6:30 &#8212; the time Choo Choo normally comes in to wake me up &#8212; and gave up trying to get any more rest.<br />
The surgeon, Dr. Artan Reso, came in that morning and gave me the real shpeal on what had happened. Terms like &#8220;perforated&#8221; and &#8220;muscousy&#8221; had been tossed around the night before. Dr. Reso was more specific: perforated, no; but it had been very close to bursting. So close, it sounded, that I was a lucky man to have it removed when I did. Had it burst, very likely I would still be in the hospital, very likely fighting for my life. He seemed oddly cheerful about the whole thing, almost like an Albanian Dr. Julius Hibbert&#8230;<br />
Apparently due to my recovery rate, and the ever-present need for beds, I was to be discharged. But before I was kicked to the curb, I got a highly appreciated breakfast, a visit from the two surgical residents I&#8217;d seen the day before, and my friend Dan, who arrived about 15 minutes before Alex appeared with the kids.<br />
What I currently have to show for all of this are three holes in my belly. The largest is my belly button (where the camera was inserted), one about ten centimetres to the left, and third about six centimetres below the belly button. The dressings are clear transparent plastic, and adhere so tightly that it looks sort of like I&#8217;ve been shot three times, and the bleeding is just starting. It&#8217;s mildly creepy. (Monkey&#8217;s since asked that I not lift my shirt again. I can&#8217;t blame her.)<br />
The pain is easier than my hernia, no question. That one was hell to sit upright with. This is much easier, but I&#8217;m still getting wicked sharp pains. Lying down is still, by far, the easiest thing to do.<br />
And so recovery goes on. Sadly, this also impacts a few things: work (my boss actually called my wife, ordering me away from my phone and my computer &#8212; no lie!), being Monkey&#8217;s soccer coach (there&#8217;s three of us, but I still feel bad about it), any form of exercise (I&#8217;m doing laps around our new kitchen island, but &#8230; well, it&#8217;s boring), and my appetite is pretty low (okay, not really a bad thing, I might lose a couple of pounds from all this). But life should return to normal soon enough.<br />
Y&#8217;know, if by &#8220;normal&#8221;, I mean &#8220;randomly chaotic&#8221;. Which I do.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/appendix-to-appendicitis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The gall of it all</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/the-gall-of-it-all/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-gall-of-it-all</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/the-gall-of-it-all/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 13:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3086</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yesterday morning, I woke up unusually hungry. I honestly can&#8217;t think of the last time I actually woke up hungry. Also dead tired, but that&#8217;s another matter. Breakfast was small, one egg and coffee, which I hoped would be enough. By 9:30, though, the pains were back, and I tried to eat again. Nothing fancy, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/the-gall-of-it-all/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The gall of it all"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday morning, I woke up unusually hungry. I honestly can&#8217;t think of the last time I actually woke up hungry. Also dead tired, but that&#8217;s another matter. Breakfast was small, one egg and coffee, which I hoped would be enough.<br />
By 9:30, though, the pains were back, and I tried to eat again. Nothing fancy, just a rice cake with some peanut butter. It only kind of worked. A half hour later, hunger had turned to real pain.<br />
Things only went downhill from there.<br />
<span id="more-3086"></span><br />
By noon, the pain had become that I had to stop working (I was working from home) and go lie down &#8212; I simply couldn&#8217;t concentrate. But lying down did nothing. There wasn&#8217;t a single position that in anyway abated the pain.<br />
Alex gave me Ovol. Nothing. She got me ginger ale. Nothing. I, for laughs, induced vomiting. Nothing at all. Acetaminophen had no effect, either. I figured it was time to call Alberta HealthLink and get an opinion. The call was short, but clear: get to a hospital ASAFP.<br />
That was the hard part. Alex had an appointment, and had to work, so I was supposed to be the parent at home. One car. No easy way to pick up and run. I thought I&#8217;d just hold out until Alex was back, and go then.<br />
My body, however, had other ideas. The pain was worsening. On a scale of 1-10 (1 effectively being nothing; 10 being the most unimaginable pain), I was around a 7. And climbing. I started to get light-headed and found it hard to breathe. I couldn&#8217;t walk or stand without hot pokers in my belly. I had no choice. Instead of calling a taxi, though, I called 911.<br />
Thankfully, the kids did t register that Daddy was in trouble, and our awesome neighbour Amber appeared moments later to take them to her place. The ambulance arrived as the kids were crossing the lawn.<br />
Three techs (one was a student) unloaded a barrage of questions. I hoped it might all be resolved there. But I found myself on the stretcher in the ambulance (I walked out myself), turning into a human pincushion. I got morphine and suddenly all was right with the world.<br />
Despite a quick check-in, I sat in the waiting room for over two hours before a doc could talk to me. Pokes, prods, IVs, and blood and urine tests later, it was inconclusive. Either a problem with my pancreas, or it was my appendix. The resident nearly pushed his hand through to my kidney to get a sense of things.<br />
I went home. I had crackers, apple sauce, and ginger ale. I didn&#8217;t feel much better.<br />
The first Tylenol3 was at roughly 1am, along with a Gravol. It kind o helped. But by 4:00, it was clear that my abdomen needed additional attention. Back to Rockyview.<br />
More pokes. More prods. But the answer seems, well, textbook (according to the doc who saw me: appendicitis. So textbook, in fact, that I&#8217;m bypassing more tests.<br />
So, for now, I&#8217;m waiting for surgery. We&#8217;ll see how it goes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/05/the-gall-of-it-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3086</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the mend</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/on-the-mend/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=on-the-mend</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/on-the-mend/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 23:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2916</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s pick up where we left off, dear reader. As you already know, I came home in a fair amount of discomfort. Thankfully, I also came home drugged up and bearing a temporary stash of drugs to maintain the druggy state. They delivered in their promised one-two punch: lessening of pain, and increasing drowsiness. I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/on-the-mend/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On the mend"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s pick up where we left off, dear reader. As you already know, I came home in a fair amount of discomfort. Thankfully, I also came home drugged up and bearing a temporary stash of drugs to maintain the druggy state. They delivered in their promised one-two punch: lessening of pain, and increasing drowsiness.<br />
I should point out that until Friday, I had not really known pain. My previous experiences had been limited to bonks of the head (one of which has left a noticeable scar) plus a few nasty scrapes. And with one exception (which led to stitches in my nose), every injury was resolved with a simple bandage.<br />
Now I understand why &#8220;keeping up on your meds&#8221; is so key during recovery.<br />
<span id="more-2916"></span><br />
Because this was Day Surgery, I was kicked out of the hospital at the first earliest convenience, which happened to coincide with when Alex could conveniently return to pick me up. As a result, I was the last patient to leave Day Surgery (there was one other, remaining overnight).<br />
I suppose recovering at home is far more preferable to staying in the hospital. There&#8217;s no nurses getting you up every few hours, no roommate in severe coughing fits, no all-room pages, and so forth. It&#8217;s your own bed, your own bathroom, your own environment. There&#8217;s a comfort to that. It also makes me wonder just how far a) our medical technology has progressed, allowing people to go home almost immediately after surgery, or b) how little our healthcare system can support overnighters, and therefore force us out as soon as possible (the &#8220;revolving door medicine&#8221; issue). I suspect it&#8217;s a bit of both.<br />
I passed out in bed not long after getting home, hugging Monkey and Choo Choo (Monkey being especially doting on her poor, owie&#8217;d daddy), and downing 8-10 unsalted Premium Plus crackers and a popsicle &#8212; the only real food I&#8217;d had in almost 24 hours. I waited long enough to pop another Percocet tablet, and laid down.<br />
Now I would like to say that I had envisioned having a good sleep after that. Why, I have no idea. In retrospect, it was such a naive belief as to compare it to the relative innocence of my kids. I was up four times that night, either due to the meds having worn off, the need to pee (my water intake must be pushing my hydration point well past the &#8220;safe&#8221; limit), or simply because my lower back felt like it was doing to implode. Nausea was also a common factor, which I&#8217;m not sure should be attributed to the anesthesia, the meds, the pain, or a weird combination of all three. The only time I did get sick did seem to help much more than should be allowed for the minute volume of ejecta.<br />
Getting in and out of bed was just short of hell. There was no easy way to achieve a vertical stance. Swinging my legs out left me in a partial-vertical/mostly-horizontal state that required either an overhead handle to pull myself up (which we sadly are lacking in our bedroom ceiling), or stomach muscles capable of pulling my upper half into at least a sitting position. Given the broken nature of my muscles, I had to resort to a completely haphazard form of rolling to my left, a partial clockwise rotation to force my feet of the edge of the bed, then pushing myself to sitting (all the while breathing sharply from the pain), and then pushing myself up to standing (thankfully, we have a high bed). The act of climbing back in bed made only slightly more simple as a result of lifting my feet (Alex helping with my left leg, as the aforementioned broken muscles were not cooperating) and sliding in.<br />
Suffice to say, Alex and I were up frequently throughout that first night. I could not be more thankful to have someone with me &#8212; I shudder to think of how awkward and difficult this would have been if I were still single.<br />
The next morning &#8212; which I take only as the point at where the ambient light in my room was more than the nightly minimum &#8212; I ached myself up to quickly down a Tylenol 3 (for which Alex had so graciously filled a prescription) and try to move around a bit.<br />
One of the things in the literature you&#8217;re handed before being discharged from surgery is about the absolute need to get back to &#8220;normal activities&#8221; (with a few notable exceptions) as quickly as possible, provided you don&#8217;t push yourself. (In other words, if you do physical labour, you&#8217;re going to be a while; programmers shouldn&#8217;t have too much trouble.) In short: walking. The key is to walk as soon as possible so your body doesn&#8217;t try to heal itself &#8220;badly&#8221;.<br />
Problem: it was snowing. Again. We&#8217;ve seen more freshly-fallen snow in April than we have in the previous three months, combined. The thought of slipping on said new snow pretty much kiboshed my external sojourns, and left me doing laps around our kitchen island until the ache was something akin to a burning ember crammed midway between my hip and my [Insert your own preference for terminology to male reproductive apparatus here] and pressed down on with a 10 lb weight. That&#8217;s what&#8217;s kept me, for the most part, in a prone position in bed, watching a marathon of Anthony Bourdain&#8217;s <em>No Reservations</em>.<br />
My food, at least on Day 1, was kept to crackers, water, ginger ale (to combat nausea), half a can of chicken soup, a peanut butter and honey sandwich, and a fairly steady stream of pills. Hardly fulfilling, but in the interests of keeping my stool generation to a minimum (remember: groin injury + cut abdominal muscles) seemed prudent. Not to mention anything heavier might bring on more nausea.<br />
Last night, I slept with more pillows, and considerably more soundly. Having not taken any other medication during the night, I woke up notably more pained than I had several hours earlier. A top-up of Percocet seemed to help, as would a fresh ibuprofen intake a couple of hours later. A couple of cups of strong coffee also did wonders, and was a welcome change from water and ginger ale.<br />
I&#8217;m also finding that I&#8217;m not as much of a wimp as I had thought &#8212; this isn&#8217;t nearly as painful as I had imagined. I&#8217;m finding that I&#8217;m also listening to my body more clearly &#8212; when it tells me not to do something, I&#8217;m damn well listening. It means I don&#8217;t sit on the floor (it&#8217;s painful to get up), I don&#8217;t lean strongly to grab something (I go over to it), and picking up anything heavier than my laptop is a strong &#8220;no&#8221;.<br />
Today was better than yesterday, but still tiring. I&#8217;m not going to try to go into the office tomorrow, even though this is a launch week for a project, and I need to ramp up on my next major project. Timing is everything, and there is never a good time for surgery. Hopefully, though, Tuesday will be my luckier day.<br />
Until then, I&#8217;m staying on top of the meds, and snoozing when needed. Which, it also seems, is right now&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/on-the-mend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2916</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My first surgery</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-first-surgery</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 18:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, I finally got my hernia repaired. (&#8220;Repair&#8221;, incidentally, is what the surgery is called.) It&#8217;s a short job that uses, believe it or not, part of a screen door. It wasn&#8217;t a procedure that I was particularly looking forward to &#8212; the thought of surgery was more than a little frightening &#8212; but I&#8217;m &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My first surgery"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I finally got my hernia repaired. (&#8220;Repair&#8221;, incidentally, is what the surgery is called.) It&#8217;s a short job that uses, believe it or not, part of a screen door.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t a procedure that I was particularly looking forward to &#8212; the thought of surgery was more than a little frightening &#8212; but I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;ll be glad to have had.<br />
Y&#8217;know, once all this pain subsides&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2915"></span><br />
I called Rockyview General Hospital on Thursday afternoon to get my scheduled time. Surgery was at 12:15, and I needed to be there for 9:15. Basically, an entire workday having my bowels forced back into place.<br />
No, really. That&#8217;s the procedure. Hernias form as a result of a break in the intestinal wall. Eventually, part of the intestine works its way through, causing the discomfort. Hernias don&#8217;t heal on their own &#8212; you either use a pad to keep things in place, or you get surgery to patch the hole.<br />
The patch literally looks like a piece of screening from a screen door. It gets inserted and the muscles weave into it, creating the barrier. The screen is permanent. Does that make me a cyborg, I wonder?<br />
Alex met me at Admissions. She started at Rockyview two weeks ago, returning to work after over three and a half years of kids and Costa Rica. It was actually weird to see her in scrubs again. She boasted about having Vietnamese for lunch with iced coffee. My nearly 12-hour empty stomach growled, and my head was going into full-tilt caffeine withdrawal.<br />
We scooted over to Day Surgery, where I began my long waiting process with about a dozen others, and their friends/spouses (Alex had to back to work). I sat and read Cryptonomicon until my name was called, about an hour later.<br />
The nurse took me to a change area, where I doffed my skivvies for hospital-issue attire. It was a little tight, and severely lacking on the fashionable approach, but the pant and extra top would at least keep me from freezing while I continued to wait.<br />
My headache was approaching epic levels. Suddenly, those six daily cups of coffee really didn&#8217;t seem like such a great idea. I couldn&#8217;t read my book any longer &#8212; my head hurt so much I couldn&#8217;t focus. I resorted to rubbing my head and the back of my neck to help ease the pain and pass the time.<br />
When my name was finally called, I was ushered to a toilet, removed the pajama bottoms and the cloak (keeping the ever-open gown on, of course), and trundled off to the operating area on a gurney. Once there, I rolled over on my side and declared I would nap while waiting for the doctor to show up.<br />
A kindly nurse appeared and asked if I would like another warmed blanket, which was greeted with enthusiasm (seriously, why are hospitals always so darn cold??). A couple of minutes later, Dr. Steve Martin appeared. (Once again, I lamented the fact that he does not have an arrow through his head.). He talked to me for about two minutes, marked on my left groin with a ballpoint pen where he&#8217;d make the incision, then headed off to get ready to cut me open.<br />
Barely 30 seconds later, the nurse appeared to deal with all the paperwork and formalities. While she was chatting, Alex appeared (having snuck away just long enough for a quick chat). The nurse vanished, replaced almost immediately (it was starting to look like a surgical assembly line) with whom I felt was the single most important person I would meet that day &#8212; the anesthesiologist.<br />
I had a choice: local, or general. There are pros and cons to both (which he outlined fairly well without horrid detail), and I tried to state my local and general fears. In my world, I&#8217;d prefer to lose feeling due to my own actions, however ill-enacted they may be.<br />
Alex said &#8220;see you later&#8221; as the nurse reappeared to take me into the operating room. It was intimidating, and for once TV and movies lived up to the promise: featureless, two massive lights over the table, machines that went &#8220;BING&#8221;, and people in surgical gowns. The nurse had told me that I was to announce myself and what procedure I was to have. It came out like this:<br />
&#8220;My name is Geoff, and I&#8217;m having a left hernia. No, strike that. I <em>have</em> a left hernia and I want to get rid of it.&#8221;<br />
I moved to the operating table and was set upon by the nurse and the anesthesiologist (who immediately asked if I&#8217;d made any decision yet), my arms put onto rests at the side. My right arm got the blood pressure cuff, the left arm &#8212; notably my hand &#8212; turned into a pincushion as the anesthesiologist struggled to find a vein.<br />
Have I mentioned how much I hate needles?<br />
Finally, a decision on my pain-killing was made. I&#8217;d asked all sorts of questions about risks (e.g. not waking up again), but in the end, the real decision was alertness. With a local, I&#8217;d be awake and wondering what was going on &#8212; I&#8217;m too curious for my own good. And with that, an oxygen mask was put over my mouth and nose, and an intense burning burst into my hand.</p>
<blockquote><p>Daisy, Daisy, give me your answer, do&#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>It was like if you were watching a movie, and there&#8217;s a cut to a different scene. There was no fade to black &#8212; the memory just stopped.<br />
&#8220;Take a couple of deep breaths, please,&#8221; said a voice next to me. I was in recovery, absolutely no sense of passed time. &#8220;Deep breaths, please. You need to up your oxygen. We&#8217;ll get a mask if we need to.&#8221; It almost sounded like a threat.<br />
I dunno if it&#8217;s me or the machine, but I&#8217;m always under the limit. I was breathing pretty shallow, and my oxygen level was clocking in at 89. A couple of deep breaths later, it was 99. All was well.<br />
I was trucked back to Day Surgery to complete my recovery before discharge. I needed anti-nauseant and was given Percosets to dull the pain. The only thing I needed to do before I could leave was pee &#8212; something that required me to drink a fair amount of liquid in advance. The nursing staff kept my in good shape, and immediately called Alex to let her know I was okay.<br />
&#8220;Hi, Diagnostic Imaging? Can I speak with Alex the x-ray tech? Hi, this is Day Surgery. Your husband is alive. Feel free to come by whenever.&#8221;<br />
Alex was there barely two minutes later.<br />
I &#8220;power napped&#8221; (nurse&#8217;s words) for the next couple of hours. I had to get another round of anti-nauseant, which dragged things out a bit. When Alex&#8217;s shift was over, I wasn&#8217;t quite ready to go home, so she ducked home to feed the kids. I resumed napping.<br />
I finally left the hospital around 7, and went home. It was good to get home, although I was a little afraid of being tackled by Monkey. Thankfully, she was extremely careful, a gentle cuteness that I&#8217;d never witnessed before.<br />
It&#8217;s been Gravol and T3s since, and moving around is difficult. Recovery takes a few days, but hopefully I&#8217;ll be moving around more easily soon. And eating. And coffee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/my-first-surgery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2915</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An argument for wired city council</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=an-argument-for-wired-city-council</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 03:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2905</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As little as a hundred years ago, North Americans lived (generally) in towns and (much smaller) cities, where it was possible to know your elected representatives personally, meet with them, and have a person-to-person chat. In the years following, our representatives have been accused more and more of being &#8220;disconnected&#8221; and &#8220;out of touch&#8221; from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "An argument for wired city council"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As little as a hundred years ago, North Americans lived (generally) in towns and (much smaller) cities, where it was possible to know your elected representatives personally, meet with them, and have a person-to-person chat. In the years following, our representatives have been accused more and more of being &#8220;disconnected&#8221; and &#8220;out of touch&#8221; from their constituents, as the towns and cities grow, and the number of people in a given district rise well past the point of &#8220;manageable&#8221; by a single person.<br />
The biggest problem is not really the number of people &#8212; it&#8217;s the time councillors need to connect with them all, while still doing the job for which they were elected. In a physical sense, it&#8217;s nearly impossible. Some have turned to the internet to help bridge the gap, using technology to connect.<br />
Allow me to show you an example, which I experienced today&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2905"></span>While waiting for one of my software commits to complete, I took a few minutes to read my news feeds. One article, which caught me more than a little off-guard, was a note about <a href="http://enenews.com/recent-radioactivy-testing-vancouver-canada-shows-iodine-131-rainwater-almost-100-times-above-drinking-water-limit">radioactive particles from the Japanese Fukushima reactor appearing in Vancouver&#8217;s water supply</a>. It was surprising as no-one had really expected that to happen, and moreso because the levels were a lot higher than I would have imagined.<br />
My first thought was how that would affect the water supply in Vancouver, especially towards children (it&#8217;s already an issue in parts of Japan, and BC has already had a scare that led to a run on iodine tablets). My second thought was: the rain on this side of the Rocky Mountains often comes in from the Vancouver area.<br />
Now I &#8212; as a regular, ordinary citizen of Canada&#8217;s fourth largest city &#8212; would likely have to spend quite some time to find out where to start to see if that problem had arrived here. But I&#8217;m not &#8220;regular&#8221; &#8212; I&#8217;m highly connected. And not in the &#8220;I know people way&#8221;, I mean by the internet. And I follow my ward&#8217;s alderman, <a href="http://twitter.com/aldjohnmar">John Mar</a>, on Twitter. Who better to find out if Calgary&#8217;s at risk than one of Calgary&#8217;s tooth-and-nail fighters?<br />
I started with the simple question:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-I-know-you_re-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2906" title="Twitter _ Geoff Sowrey_ @aldjohnmar I know you_re ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-I-know-you_re-....jpg" alt="" width="617" height="334" /></a><br />
Knowing that John&#8217;s a busy guy (he regularly tweets his activities; which I gotta say, it&#8217;s a very handy way of knowing what your elected representative is up to without having to call them on a regular basis), I didn&#8217;t expect an immediate response. Heck, I&#8217;d have been happy with a simple &#8220;yes/no&#8221; answer. I got John&#8217;s response just a few minutes later:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-I-don_t-know-but-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2909" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey I don_t know, but ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-I-don_t-know-but-....jpg" alt="" width="617" height="268" /></a><br />
Okay, first off, in any service-based organisation &#8212; public or private &#8212; immediate (or at least near-immediate) response &#8212; even if it&#8217;s &#8220;we&#8217;ll get back to you&#8221; &#8212; is necessary to instill confidence. Lack of response breeds doubt, and especially with government, makes people think things are being done behind closed doors. In an era where we demand transparency, acknowledgement of a request is <em>the</em> killer app.<br />
It took a little while &#8212; still less time than it would have taken me, I&#8217;m sure &#8212; but I got my answer:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Pleased-to-Report-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2911" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey Pleased to Report, ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Pleased-to-Report-....jpg" alt="" width="613" height="303" /></a><br />
There you go &#8212; we were safe. And you feel a lot more secure with an answer from a public figure than you do from a city bureaucrat. But John&#8217;s answer got me to thinking: a) Iodine 131 is probably not regularly tested for in water supplies (why would it be?), and b) that&#8217;s a fairly recent test. Which led me to wonder if it might be an ongoing test for the foreseeable future:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-That_s-a-relie-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2907" title="Twitter _ Geoff Sowrey_ @aldjohnmar That_s a relie ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-Geoff-Sowrey_-@aldjohnmar-That_s-a-relie-....jpg" alt="" width="615" height="266" /></a><br />
John&#8217;s response, interestingly enough, I mostly expected:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-As-I-understand-it-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2908" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey As I understand it ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-As-I-understand-it-....jpg" alt="" width="611" height="266" /></a><br />
Now, it&#8217;s very easy to dismiss that as &#8220;well, that&#8217;s not answer&#8221; &#8230; and you&#8217;d be right, especially if you&#8217;re concerned about this sort of thing (which I am). But, where John does not fail, he followed up (unprompted) with this:<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Just-heard-back-fr-....jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2910" title="Twitter _ John Mar_ @sowrey Just heard back fr ..." src="http://www.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Twitter-_-John-Mar_-@sowrey-Just-heard-back-fr-....jpg" alt="" width="610" height="299" /></a><br />
So, net result, at least so far as Calgary&#8217;s water is concerned: we&#8217;re okay. But that&#8217;s actually the lesser part of the story. The more important, I think, is that I got an answer to a pressing question over Twitter (not waiting on phones), and directly from my elected official.<br />
As an interesting aside, <a href="http://twitter.com/aldjohnmar/status/11837858318913536">John actually left Twitter early last December</a>, after he received a fair amount of abuse from people who didn&#8217;t think he was tweeting enough. It was a loss for us who followed, since he had been a valuable source of information on the regular goings-on in city council.  Thankfully, John returned to Twitter about two months later.<br />
It&#8217;s a tough gig, being a public figure on Twitter. There are a lot of demands from the informed and uninformed alike, and people&#8217;s patience online is about a tenth of what it is in person (and politeness can sink to a hundredth or less). Somehow, people seem to forget that Twitter is an outlet, not a full-time job. John, so far, has done an admirable job of balancing the act, and remains (in my view) the best of Calgary&#8217;s city council in using Twitter is a communications tool.<br />
So go on, ask me if I feel my councillor is out of touch. I dare ya.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/04/an-argument-for-wired-city-council/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2905</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
