<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>british columbia &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/british-columbia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 05:12:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 05:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kids, You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours. We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230; We started &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kids,<br />
You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours.<br />
We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3119"></span>We started early, all of us up before 7:00 this morning. I&#8217;d packed for our trip last night (and we&#8217;ve since determined that Daddy sucks at remembering certain important things), but we still had some last-minute things that had to be done at the last minute (turning off computers, internet, turning down the hot water heater, to name a few), and the packing of the last few things. I then packed the car &#8212; in the rain, I might add.<br />
Then we bolted to Sunterra for breakfast. This is our Saturday tradition. Every Saturday, we&#8217;re there when they open at 8:00 to have a good, hot breakfast that will usually keep us going for a few hours. (Well, most of us. Mommy&#8217;s current diet means she has to bring her breakfast with her, and it&#8217;s just never enough.) After breakfast, we did a tiny bit of shopping, and we headed out to North Glenmore Park.<br />
Today was the Race for Pace. This was a charitable event to raise funds for the Pacekids Program, which helps disabled kids. Amber, our next-door neighbour, informed us of the event, and it seemed like it would be a lot of fun. Y&#8217;know, in the rain.<br />
I joke, I joke! It didn&#8217;t rain &#8230; that much. It did rain, but nothing like when we woke up, which was a fair pounding. The rain had let up during breakfast. That said, the park was very wet, the ground very soggy, and we all got reasonably damp. Except in spirits. Once the two of you got your superhero capes, you were off like gangbusters. We did the 1 km Superhero race (Mommy and Monkey completed it; Choo Choo and I cheated a bit, only because you&#8217;re a bit of a slow walker, still, Choo Choo), which ended in a crowd of cheers, and medals on your necks.<br />
You played games and won prizes, too! The best was a &#8220;game&#8221; that originally started as an inflatable pool filled with shredded paper, in which were buried toys for kids to find. But it quickly evolved to a game where the kids threw around clumps of shredded paper (both in/out of the pool, and at each other), and pretty much ignored all the toys that were supposed to be &#8220;won&#8221;.<br />
After some slices of the 100th Anniversary Calgary Stampede cake, we headed back to the car, buckled in, and headed back to Sunterra (which, in our defence, was on the way out of the city) to get Choo Choo some diapers (which we&#8217;d forgotten to buy when we were there), hooked up the in-car DVD player (Kiki&#8217;s Delivery Service was the first movie up), and then hit the road.<br />
It rained.<br />
It rained off and on pretty much the rest of the day, really. It&#8217;s raining right now. It&#8217;ll be raining tomorrow. I really hope it stops raining.<br />
Anyway, we stopped in Canmore, rather than our usual habit, which is Banff. Mommy found a nice restaurant she could eat at, which turned out to be a wonderful place with good food, and colouring books. You two and I had grilled cheese sandwiches (mine also had ham, salami, and dill pickles, mind you) while Mommy had a spinach salad.<br />
We tried to find a playground afterwards, but it didn&#8217;t work out so well &#8212; the nearest one was further away than we&#8217;d planned. But we did find a toy store to stop at for short while.<br />
Finding Nemo was the next movie up, which carried us through Banff National Park, and well into Kootenay National Park. Choo Choo, you finally fell asleep as we approached Highway 93, and stayed asleep for about an hour, waking up at the Lodge, where we&#8217;ve often stopped for a short break. (In this case, it was a rather urgent potty break.)<br />
The rest of the trip went as it usually did &#8212; not anywhere near as fast as we&#8217;d like it to go. But soon we were out of the mountains, much to Choo Choo&#8217;s relief (your ears were apparently hurting), and turning south towards what Choo Choo had started to call &#8220;Fairy-mont&#8221;. (My spelling, of course.)<br />
After the obligatory stop in Invermere for groceries, we blasted to Fairy-mont, and checked in at the Mountainside Villas, barely minutes before Grandpa, Granny, and Tia Nicole arrived. We got the keys to our &#8220;new&#8221; house for this year, S7. Normally, we&#8217;re in B6, but it wasn&#8217;t available this week (this week being a traded week, since the timeshare schedule this year put us into Monkey&#8217;s first week of Kindergarten). S7 and B6 are similar, but there are notable differences. For this week, however, I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll be fine.<br />
The both of you ran amok around the house, running up and down stairs, jumping on beds (you&#8217;re still mystified at the Murphy bed; you have no idea where the bed keeps disappearing to). We had dinner (though both of you failed to eat much), you read some stories, and after a significant amount of struggle, we got you both to bed, both still far too excited to be here, and both passing out within minutes of hitting the pillow.<br />
Mommy and I made a run to the hot springs afterwards, and put some more thought into what we&#8217;ll do this week.<br />
Y&#8217;know, if it ever stops raining.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3119</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Believe</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-believe</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Canada, I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I Believe"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Canada,<br />
I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter Olympics (having lived there a couple of years, I know how finicky the weather can be).<br />
And I wasn&#8217;t alone. Thanks to media mainstays, such as The Guardian and the Denver Post, and CTV&#8217;s frequently slipshod and amateurish approach, there was little reason for me to think otherwise.<br />
I find myself, now at the end, relieved to be wrong, and fiercely proud to be a repatriated Canadian.<br />
<span id="more-2626"></span>The <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/">Own The Podium</a> program had me enraged. It was meant to increase the chances of medal wins &#8212; to the point where we had the most medals. Not only was it arrogance beyond our Canadian norm, I found that the program sponsored only those who were in medal contention &#8212; and abandoned the rest. Considering we&#8217;re a socialist country, it seems a very un-Canadian setup. (And can someone tell me, please, why on earth the <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/Funding/detailsw.aspx?id=8">Men&#8217;s Hockey team received Own The Podium funding</a>? It just seems odd to support millionaires who already have significant amounts of training and coaching resources.)<br />
Then came the the death of Georgian luger Nodar Kumaritashvili mere hours before the cauldron was lit.  (And no, Tom Clark, CTV <em>did not need</em> to show footage of the fatal run to &#8220;tell the full story&#8221;. That was utter <em>pandering</em> to sensationalist news coverage. You want to be better than CBC? You&#8217;d better <em>act</em> like you are, first.) The pall cast over the opening felt almost suffocating.<br />
The opening ceremonies themselves were filled with a host of flubs: lip syncing (seriously, we are unable to trust our biggest performers to perform in public?), slight delays (starting even with the snowboarder not coming down on cue), and mechanical failures (erectile dysfunction, anyone?). Problems seemed to continue past the hutzpah, with broken ice resurfacing machines, and an ill-timed rampage by ill-tempted and extremely short-sighted rioters. The press ate us alive.<br />
Our lauded best, held on pedestals for months, were put to the test. But the gold we were promised didn&#8217;t come. Our speedskaters failed to place, and our former moguls world champion could only garner a silver. And admit it, Canada, for a little while, you doubted, too. Had we put too much pressure on our athletes? Did we expect too much? Maybe where I failed was not to recognise it as a beginning of something bigger.<br />
The next day &#8212; less than 24 hours after our first disappointment &#8212; things started to change. Someone I&#8217;d never heard of, suddenly appeared on top. After almost 34 years of waiting, Alexandre Bilodeau had won Canada&#8217;s first gold medal at home. For a moment, the country stood and cheered! We would walk away with something, at least. We would feel like we&#8217;ve achieved. Maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; it was enough to take away our collective dread. Or at least mine.<br />
But the medals were still slow to come. It was two days before another gold from Maelle Ricker. Five days into the games, we had a mere five medals. Our hubris was an embarrassment. Our medals, though appreciated, would stand more as an example of an effort not carried to fruition.<br />
And then something happened that we didn&#8217;t expect. It caught me by surprise, as I know it caught many others. A word that is rarely used in Canada, because of the imagery of our neighbours to the south that it usually invokes: Patriotism. Not a fevered adherence to dogma, but a feeling of national pride the likes of which have not been since I was barely two months old. We all suddenly noticed that you can&#8217;t spell &#8220;Canada&#8221; without &#8220;can&#8221;. And we did.<br />
For me, it was the evening of the men&#8217;s skeleton finals, 19 February. Canada had already won another gold in speed skating, but it was Jon Montgomery&#8217;s victory that seemed to spark something in me. He is not your typical Canadian &#8212; he is brasher, bolder, more outspoken, and not afraid to do things in public that the rest of us would feel the urge to poo-poo as &#8220;not proper&#8221;. His primal scream of victory was the first cry, followed shortly after by a tremendous leap to the top of the podium at the sliding centre; he carried the entire nation with him in that moment. This time, I didn&#8217;t look back down. I &#8212; like you, Canada &#8212; looked forward.<br />
I started to believe.<br />
(And yes, I even started to like that &#8220;<em>I Believe</em>&#8221; song. Probably because after watching enough coverage, you don&#8217;t really have much choice.)<br />
We started the second week with seven medals. Forecasts still placed us well into the 20s. Even with all of our victories in preliminary curling and hockey, it just didn&#8217;t seem possible. But funny thing about believing &#8212; you worry less about failing, and you don&#8217;t want to get left behind.<br />
Our games started with difficult stories:  the disappointment of silver, the struggle in speed skating, and seemingly random disqualifications. The stories had changed. The commentators seemed to take on the energy not just of the crowds, but of the athletes themselves. The stories covered the brotherly dedication, the triumphant (and periodically beer-fuelled) victory marches, impromptu parades, double medals, first wins in new sports, and the sweetheart skaters who not only stole the gold but also the hearts of millions.<br />
But no story could exceed that of Joannie Rochette.<br />
I&#8217;m no figure skater &#8212; I can&#8217;t even skate, really. Growing up, though, I watched a lot of figure skating as a result of watching TV with my mom, a former skater herself, and still an adamant lover of the sport. So, in some small way, I am periodically attracted to it. It was with great fortune that I caught her performance, only days after learning her mother had suddenly died.<br />
I couldn&#8217;t tell you how well she actually skated &#8212; I&#8217;m no judge &#8212; but I can tell you that on that night, Joannie embodied the strength and courage of an Olympian, producing her best possible performance, allowing herself tears only after she was done, to the sound of a thunderous standing ovation. Her medal may have only been a bronze, but as a local paper emblazoned on its headline: it was as good as gold to us.<br />
Most of us Canadians never made it to the games, though I know more than a few who were there, who witnessed gold first-hand. The closest I ever got was my home in southwest Calgary, where I subjected my family to my growing obsession, cheering on my country in its quest for gold, to the point where Alex and I taught the Monkey to chant: &#8220;CA-NA-DA!&#8221; as loudly as she could. We all watched, we all cheered, we all hoped, and we all cried.<br />
And we achieved. We achieved records the likes of which exceeded our expectations. Even with Own The Podium&#8217;s lofty goals, most of us never expected to set a record for the most number of gold medals won in a Winter Olympics. We might not have owned the entire podium, but we took the step that mattered the most to us: the top.<br />
The top was capped with our national games: curling and hockey. Men&#8217;s curling gold, a three-time victory for the women&#8217;s hockey team, and a rematch against our oldest nemesis, the United States. It was joked many times by many people that the men&#8217;s hockey final would effectively close the entire country for the three hours the game would be played. I suspect the joke was not far off. The game would prove to be something special, especially to those born after the early 1970s &#8212; it would become my generation&#8217;s Summit Series, the game that we watched with extreme anticipation, desperately wanting that gold back in our hands.<br />
Vancouver did something to Canada that few would have predicted, even with our previous experience with Calgary and Montreal. For a few weeks,  Vancouver brought together our country &#8212; six timezones and a hugely diverse culture (yes, Canada, we are not just one group; we thrive in our multiculturalism, even if we can&#8217;t always recognise it). Not just in representation, but in anticipation and celebration.  We broke out of our Canadian mould &#8212; we stopped thinking we&#8217;d stop short, that we&#8217;d choke right at the key moments &#8212; and we started to live the dream.<br />
The media has suggested that maybe we&#8217;ll break out from our mould permanently, and be more like our cousins to the south. But we won&#8217;t. That&#8217;s not us. That&#8217;s not <em>Canadian</em>. These games are over, and we&#8217;ll return to our Canadian ways. But we won&#8217;t shrink away, we won&#8217;t forget what happened. We&#8217;ve gotten stronger; we&#8217;ve learned. We&#8217;ve learned how to perform, that success isn&#8217;t just a dream &#8212; it&#8217;s a reality. That we can compete head-to-head with the best the world has to show us, and not be just &#8220;that nice country&#8221;. We&#8217;re now <em>that</em> country: a tough competitor, a fierce opponent. The ones everyone else has to beat.<br />
And it would be nice if we could get our legends back. Mr. Orser, are there not Canadians you can train? Can our curling coaches consider teaching our up-and-comers, rather than guide our competitors? And can we please treat all our athletes with some form of equality? If nothing else, these games proved that underdogs can achieve what no-one expects.<br />
We&#8217;ll freely admit we had things that didn&#8217;t go perfectly. Massive events aren&#8217;t perfect &#8212; the best you can hope for is to mitigate the troubles. So, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14414668">yes Mr. Kiszla, we had a few problems</a> &#8212; I assure you that your lauded Denver games will have their own headaches that will made you cringe. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2010/feb/15/vancouver-winter-olympics-2010">And Mr. Donegan? I&#8217;ve heard better whining</a> from my two-year old when her cereal ends up a bit soggy. Rather than suggesting you return to the golf courses you seem to understand so much better, I suggest you join London&#8217;s Olympic Committee and become personally responsible for London&#8217;s success. Because we&#8217;ll be watching. Closely.<br />
Oh, and one more thing, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14398658">Mr. Kiszla, about the trash talk</a>? After listening to American bragging for so long, you have no idea how wonderful it is to say: <a href="http://media3.hockeycanada.ca/digital_asset/7/1/6/6/3/image_17ee18aea2c8fd14b8ba92026a8b7525.jpg?cache=305395">It&#8217;s still our game</a>. I believe it will remain that way for a long time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My favourite trains (so far)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/my-favourite-trains-so-far/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-favourite-trains-so-far</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/my-favourite-trains-so-far/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 01:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cbc 50]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CN 6060]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edinburgh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irkutsk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mongolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moscow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nova scotia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shanghai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[st. petersburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trans-siberian railway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulaan baatar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via rail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I rarely remember my dreams. I have to wake up in the middle of them to remember what they were about, and quite often I&#8217;m so tired that by the time I can get my mental faculties together to try and remember the dream, I already forgot what it was. Which is probably good, since &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/my-favourite-trains-so-far/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My favourite trains (so far)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I rarely remember my dreams. I have to wake up in the middle of them to remember what they were about, and quite often I&#8217;m so tired that by the time I can get my mental faculties together to try and remember the dream, I already forgot what it was. Which is probably good, since most of the dreams I remember make very little sense.<br />
This morning&#8217;s dream was an exception. I was talking with someone I know (admittedly, can&#8217;t remember who it was) about trains. (Believe it or not, this is not an unknown conversation.) They asked me what my favourite train trips were, and I had said something like &#8220;whoa, that&#8217;s a tough one, let me think&#8221;. Then I started rhyming them off.<br />
Oddly enough, that was about when I woke up &#8230; and I kept rhyming. So I figured, heck, that just sounds like a blog post!<br />
<span id="more-2234"></span>Now these are in rough order of enjoyability and preference (if I had the opportunity to ride again). Though I should state that I would probably ride any of these again in a heartbeat, anyway. Some of these no longer run, however, so their appearance here is strictly archival.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>VIA Rail Canadian Vancouver &#8211; Halifax</strong> (<a href="http://viarail.ca">VIA Rail</a> charter, not currently possible under regular scheduling)<br />
This will likely forever remain my favourite. I had the chance at a unique contract with the CBC, which ended up running <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/cbc-television-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/">coast-to-coast across Canada on a VIA Rail train</a> made entirely of the 1940s Pullman stainless steel cars. There is just no better way to see Canada.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/trans-siberian-railway/"><strong>Trans-Siberian Railway</strong></a><strong> Moscow &#8211; Irkutsk</strong> (<a href="http://www.eng.rzd.ru/">Rossiyskie Zheleznye Dorogi</a>)<br />
It&#8217;s hard to imagine that you can spend 5 days on a constantly-moving train running across a single country, and see almost nothing but vast openness and endless tracts of birch trees. There&#8217;s something magic, mystical, even mysterious about the journey.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2005/05/crossing-the-mongolia-china-border-by-train/"><strong>Trans-Mongolian Railway Ulaan Baatar &#8211; Bejing</strong></a> (<a href="http://www.mtz.mn/">Mongolyn TÃ¶mÃ¶r Zam</a>, <a href="http://www.china-mor.gov.cn/">China Railways</a>)<br />
The trip from Russia to Ulaan Baatar is okay. But the trip from Ulaan Bataar to Bejing is something else. First, the intense desolation of the Gobi Desert. Next, a rail gauge change in Inner Mongolia, followed by an overnight trip into the heart of China, passing through the Great Wall itself as you descend via switchback before finally arriving in Beijing. It&#8217;s a helluva trip.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2005/06/the-shanghai-maglev-train/"><strong>Shanghai MagLev</strong></a> (<a href="http://www.smtdc.com/en/">Shanghai MagLev Transportation Development Corp.</a>)<br />
Pure. Blinding. Speed. This train doesn&#8217;t go far &#8212; from the Pudong area near central Shanghai out to Pudong International Airport, the trip is a mere 30 km. But it travels the distance in just over seven minutes at speeds of up to 431 km/h.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2002/08/bc-rail-cariboo-prospector/"><strong>The Cariboo Prospector</strong></a> (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BC_Rail">BC Rail</a>, discontinued)<br />
Before BC Rail was bought by CN, they ran a passenger service between Prince George and Vancouver. It was an all-day trip, leaving early in the morning, and arriving well after dinner. But there was never a more fantastic trip through the Fraser Canyon, with more spectacular views of places you can&#8217;t get to by car. The service, sadly, no longer runs on BC Rail. <a href="http://www.rockymountaineer.com/routes_and_packages/rainforest_to_gold_rush">A similar trip is available through the Rocky Mountaineer.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2002/10/via-rail-bras-dor-halifax-sydney/"><strong>The Bras D&#8217;or Halifax &#8211; Sydney</strong></a><strong> &#8211; Halifax</strong> (<a href="http://viarail.ca">VIA Rail</a>, discontinued)<br />
VIA Rail ran a slightly odd service (meant to promote tourism, but allowed for no stopover time) between Halifax, Nova Scotia and Sydney, Cape Breton. The trip ran along the shores of Bras D&#8217;or Lake, and in the fall ranks as one of the most beautiful trips I&#8217;ve seen. (The fact that I also got to ride in the cab just made it that much better.) Sadly, due to line maintenance issues, VIA Rail no longer runs this service.</li>
<li><strong>Nozomi Shinkansen </strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T%C5%8Dkaid%C5%8D_Main_Line"><strong>Tokaido Line, Tokyo &#8211; Osaka</strong></a> (<a href="http://www.westjr.co.jp/english/global.html">JR West</a>)<br />
The famous Bullet Train. This is the longest line, running from capital Tokyo to Osaka. The Nozomi-class trains have the fewest stops, hence run the fastest along the line, too.   <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/shinkansen/">Riding a Shinkansen is an experience</a>, not just from the scenery, but from watching the sheer efficiency and pride in which the Japanese operate the service. Even riding in standard class makes you feel important.</li>
<li><a href="http://rrsites.com/royalhudson/"><strong>Royal Hudson</strong></a><strong> Vancouver &#8211; Squamish &#8211; Vancouver</strong> (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BC_Rail">BC Rail</a>, no longer in scheduled operation)<br />
Before BC Rail had to take Hudson <a href="http://www.wcra.org/hudson/story.htm">CP 2860</a> out of service (in need of a refit), I was fortunate enough to ride the train from Vancouver to Squamish and back. (And visited the <a href="http://wcra.org">West Coast Railway Association</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.wcra.org/heritage/">Railway Heritage Park</a> while I was at it.) The line running up the coast is full of wonderful twists and curves, and the view is fantastic. CP 2860 is now leased to the WCRA, who will hopefully run this service periodically with flair.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.absteamtrain.com/"><strong>Alberta Prairie Steam Tours</strong></a><strong> w/ </strong><a href="http://6060.org"><strong>CN 6060</strong></a> (APST, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2001/08/steam-frain-cn-6060-stettler-big-valley/">I got to ride in the caboose</a>, which regular folks don&#8217;t)<br />
Although it&#8217;s been a long time since I last helped out, I used to <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/cn-6060/">work on CN 6060 as an apprentice mechanic</a>. After one such helping-out, I was offered a trip on its scheduled run &#8212; a mere 35 mile run to Big Valley and back. But I got to ride with my mentor, Don, in the caboose. Right next to CN 6060 on the way down, but at the end of the train on the way back. Very memorable, especially considering that I rode on a train pulled by CN 6060 when I was a young boy.</li>
<li><strong>Inverness &#8211; Edinburgh</strong> (<a href="http://www.scotrail.co.uk/">First ScotRail</a>)<br />
This is a regularly-schedule service (multiple times a day, no less) between two of the three largest cities in Scotland. This service &#8212; a five-hour jaunt &#8212; <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2426316987/in/set-72157604778761863/">runs through the Scottish highlands</a> (you&#8217;ll see snow on those rolling mountains), through small villages, and across fantastic landscapes before coming down to the sea, and finally crossing the massive Fourth Bridge. Inverness itself is an excellent place to visit (very near Loch Ness!), and Edinburgh remains one of my favourite cities. It&#8217;s worth the trip, especially if you have a rail pass.</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Arrow_(Russian_train)"><strong>Krazny Strelya (&#8220;Red Arrow&#8221;)</strong></a><strong> St. Petersburg &#8211; Moscow</strong> (<a href="http://www.eng.rzd.ru/">Rossiyskie Zheleznye Dorogi</a>)<br />
Curiously, I didn&#8217;t actually see much of this train. It was <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2005/05/russian-trains/">an overnight journey from St. Petersburg to Moscow</a>. But I do remember it being an extremely nice train (apparently one of the two nicest on Russian railways), and it was the start of my St. Petersburg to Hong Kong overland odyssey. So it has a special place in my memory.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.viarail.ca/en/trains/ontario-and-quebec/toronto-montreal"><strong>Montreal &#8211; Toronto</strong></a> (<a href="http://viarail.ca">VIA Rail</a>)<br />
This might sound extremely pedestrian, but I like this train. It&#8217;s a regular service (several times daily) that runs between two of Canada&#8217;s largest cities. It&#8217;s a 5-6 hour trip, which you can do faster if you fly. But you can&#8217;t do it more comfortably. And you don&#8217;t get to see the landscape that is the St. Lawrence Seaway region. It&#8217;s some of Canada&#8217;s oldest rail, and still some of the nicest.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are the notable ones. There&#8217;s a host of other trains as well, such as commuter lines (GO Train, West Coast Express, BART, AMT, to name a few), local trains (such as most of Japan Rail, China&#8217;s Z1 line between Beijing and Tianjin, and certainly with the regional UK trains), and long distance trains within China, and the London &#8211; Glasgow/Edinburgh lines in the UK.<br />
Since that covers most of my train-riding experiences, yes, you can assume that I generally quite line trains.<br />
Are there ones I don&#8217;t like? Well, the one that comes most to mind is the section of the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2005/05/the-last-russian-stop/">Trans-Siberian between Urkutsk and Ulan Ude</a>. That is pretty darn lousy&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/my-favourite-trains-so-far/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving in Ruskin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-in-ruskin</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 03:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abbotsford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maple ridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/10/09/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had a quick jaunt out to Ruskin (a section of Maple Ridge, BC) for the Thanksgiving weekend. It was a trip I wasn&#8217;t sure I was going to be able to take at first. Reason: Too much work, and too tight deadlines to allow it. Deadlines changed. Whether they changed for the better remains &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thanksgiving in Ruskin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a quick jaunt out to Ruskin (a section of Maple Ridge, BC) for the Thanksgiving weekend. It was a trip I wasn&#8217;t sure I was going to be able to take at first. Reason: Too much work, and too tight deadlines to allow it.<br />
Deadlines changed. Whether they changed for the better remains to be seen&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-476"></span>The flight to Abbotsford was easy. That&#8217;s why I like flying there instead of Vancouver. Alex was already on the coast, having spent a week visiting friends in Victoria and Vancouver. Borrowing a car, she was picking me up at the airport before heading over to Ruskin. It had been only a week, but I was so happy to see her again.<br />
Jean had dropped her car off at the airport, which we were to pick up. As Alex was driving a borrowed car to another location, we were a mini-caravan for a little while. Sandra&#8217;s car (which Alex was driving) was going to her parents&#8217; place, also in Abbotsford, so the trip was quick and easy.<br />
After dropping off the car, we stopped briefly at the farm to drop off our things before going to Maple Ridge to get the turkey. I honestly can&#8217;t remember what the heck we did for dinner, though.<br />
The next day, we visited with Joel and Michelle. For all the times we&#8217;ve been to Ruskin already, I felt bad for never dropping by. So we planned it this time. It wasn&#8217;t anything grand or whiz-bang, but it was a great chance for them to meet Alex, and a chance for us to catch up &#8230; in their hot tub. (It reminded me to get ours cleaned and running again.)<br />
We picked up dinner at Bruce&#8217;s Market, which really amounted to lentil soup with cubed ham. Dirt simple, but surprisingly tasty. We picked up Allen and Jean from the airport, returning to sample our home-cooked meal. There were no leftovers.<br />
We had Thanksgiving dinner on the Monday. Alex was on pie detail. I made cranberry sauce and worked on some of the vegetables. Meanwhile, the household was invaded by various family members all ready for dinner. We even got Audrey to come over (Frank was a given &#8212; he loves turkey). Dinner was at 15:00.<br />
Dropping Nichole off at the bus stop, Allen took Alex and I back to the airport for our short flight back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">476</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Three Valley Gap to Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2004 04:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelstoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/08/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No rooster, just the sounds of patrons leaving their rooms. I think I prefered the rooster. The Chateau&#8217;s name is a little misleading. One is brought to think of the Canadian Pacific (now Fairmont) hotels, with the old world grandeur and luxury. Make no mistake, folks, this ain&#8217;t the Banff Springs. It&#8217;s a 1950&#8217;s motor &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Three Valley Gap to Calgary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No rooster, just the sounds of patrons leaving their rooms. I think I prefered the rooster.<br />
The Chateau&#8217;s name is a little misleading. One is brought to think of the Canadian Pacific (now Fairmont) hotels, with the old world grandeur and luxury. Make no mistake, folks, this ain&#8217;t the Banff Springs. It&#8217;s a 1950&#8217;s motor lodge with a fancy roof. But it&#8217;s comfortable, and the grounds a nicely kitchy. Besides, it&#8217;s a family business, and run very well.<br />
<span id="more-386"></span>Cleaned up, checked out, and darn hungry, we made a break for the restaurant adjacent to the hotel. It&#8217;s tacked onto a gift shop, in which we spent a bit of time after eating. Hitting the road, we actually double-backed on our route for a while. We weren&#8217;t going right home. We were going to the Enchanted Forest.<br />
Some of you have probably seen this before. A pair of green castle tower peaks at the west end of the parking lot, followed by a candy cane house, windmill, and castle walls. It seems kitchy and the sort of thing to avoid. Until today, that has always been my opinion of it. Alex had been here years before with her father. And she desperately wanted to go back. I figured that, if nothing else, it would be good for a laugh.<br />
The Enchanted Forest was built by Ernest and Doris Needham as a place for Doris to put her collection of hand-made cement fairy tale sculptures. Using only hand tools, Ernest and Doris created many of the paths in use today, and the candy cane house in which they lived. When the Trans Canada was pushed through in the late 50s, people began to stop and take a look. Finally, on 1 July 1960, the Enchanted Forest opened to the public despite a lack of a phone line (put through in 1980) and electricity (1981). By 1970, over one million visitors had walked the forest.<br />
The Needhams have long since left the Forest, but the dream continues with its current owners. They&#8217;ve expanded the forest, keeping to the Needham&#8217;s vision, and even added a nature trail free of fairy trappings.<br />
So what is the vision? Every fairy tale you remember (and a few you don&#8217;t). They&#8217;re all there. Even stories that aren&#8217;t fairy tales, but exercises of the imagination (Peter Pan, Winnie the Pooh, and Alice in Wonderland, to name a few). Yes, it&#8217;s meant more for kids, but even the young at heart can have a lot of fun.<br />
Especially when there&#8217;s hardly anyone else there. For the first hour or so, Alex and I were almost alone in the park.<br />
We walked through the castle (with its dungeon, including a motion-activated skeleton in the dark, which caught Alex off-guard), and then into the forest to look at all the exhibits. They&#8217;re spaced apart, enough that you feel like you&#8217;re moving from piece to piece. While the sculptures and &#8220;buildings&#8221; are artificial, everything else is real. The forest is virtually untouched, kept intact without plantings of any kind, and with as few trees removed as possible. Paths allow visitors to walk around without damaging any of the surrounding forest.<br />
Partway through, we found the nature trail, and decided to walk its length. We weren&#8217;t in a rush, and I had lost all sense of time (hence, felt no need to rush). By the time we&#8217;d returned back to the fairy world, a few other families had arrived with their children. One couple asked us if the trail would be suitable for their two small children. Alex and I suggested they skip the trail this time.<br />
Finishing the loop through the park (and gift shop) in about two hours, we hit the road (with me driving) for Revelstoke. Among other things, we needed gas, badly. We arrived at the Petro-Canada on fumes. It was when I was trying to pay for gas that I realized that my credit card was missing. First, panic set in as I worried about the card being misused. Then it hit me, slowly at first &#8212; the card was still at the Milestone&#8217;s in Kamloops.<br />
Doh!<br />
I would later call the Bank of Montreal and report the card lost. &#8216;Cuz I sure as hell ain&#8217;t going back to Kamloops for a lousy hunk o&#8217; plastic.<br />
I coaxed Alex to go into Revelstoke (I&#8217;d never been in the town before) to look at the Railway Musem there. They have a Mikado that I&#8217;d always wanted to see. Ernie spoke highly of it. However, with the loss of my credit card, I was suddenly not so much in a generous mood. Although the cost was minimal (only $6), I cheaped out and suggested we not go instead. I settled for a photo of a passing coal train.<br />
That was a bit of a mistake on my part. The direction of the light sent me to the opposite side of the tracks from Alex&#8217;s car to get the photo. And if you&#8217;ve seen a coal train on CP&#8217;s Shuswap Subdivision, you know how long they are &#8212; a mile, at least! And since it was leaving the Revelstoke yard, it wasn&#8217;t moving particularly quickly.<br />
One advantage of having to wait like that, you see a few things. No, I didn&#8217;t magically find my credit card. I found another 7-11! Once the train had moved on, we made another stop to refill our Slurpee addiction before continuing to Golden.<br />
Rogers Pass is an impressive place, although I had never really given it appropriate credit. Having seen the Rogers Pass Interpretive Centre on our way out (I hadn&#8217;t been driving at the time), I suggested we pull in for a gander. Luckily, our Parks Canada pass warranted us free entry.<br />
If you don&#8217;t learn something new every day, you aren&#8217;t trying hard enough. Today was definitely a learning day. When the Canadian Pacific had first come across Rogers Pass, it had to build an impressive set of bridges and snow sheds (31 of them in total) to keep the rail line clear of avalanches and the inevitably deep snow fall. In 1916, some of the difficulty crossing the mountain was solved by the construction of the Connaught Tunnel.<br />
Rogers Pass continued to be trouble, however, until 1980, when CP built the longest railway tunnel in Canada &#8212; the MacDonald Tunnel, over 25 kilometres under the mountain that gives the tunnel its name. The original rail line across the pass no longer exists, most of it having disappeared with the construction of the Trans Canada Highway. Only a few relics of show sheds and some of the old rail bed still exists. One day, I&#8217;m going to have go back and take a closer look.<br />
Smitty&#8217;s fed us lunch in Golden. It was obvious this particular restaurant had been there for a long time, not only from the décor and construction, but also due to the quality of food. They were obviously comfortable with feeding truckers. I&#8217;m comfortable in knowing that I&#8217;ll never be a trucker, if for no other reason than I&#8217;d have a tough time trying to eat at a lot of the places they seem to frequent.<br />
Alex took over driving for the remaining portion into Calgary, starting with a quick burst into Golden for, you guessed it, another Slurpee. (Hey, when you don&#8217;t get &#8217;em when you want &#8217;em, you build up a craving that takes a few days to kill off.)<br />
Field soon appeared in view, and the end of BC was coming up quickly. Before we tackled the Big Hill, Alex suggested a detour: Takakkaw Falls. I&#8217;d seen the sign for it a dozen times, but had never been there. So without further consideration, in we went.<br />
The road out to the falls is about 14 kilometres long. It winds all over the place (how they build those roads is beyond me), and includes the most insane switchback that I&#8217;ve ever seen. It&#8217;s so tight that signs suggest that RVs back up and down the middle portion because there is simply no way for them to actually turn around.<br />
The falls are a bit of a hike from the parking lot. We had to make a quick stop at the toilets before we went off, though. Due to the CUPE strike with Parks Canada, the toilets weren&#8217;t in the best state (Alex ended up having to use the men&#8217;s room).<br />
Takakkaw Falls are very high &#8212; about 254 metres tall. During the summer melt, it&#8217;s apparently a torrent that soaks anything around it. At this time of the year it&#8217;s a comparable trickle, though still quite exciting to see. I need to go back there late spring next year!<br />
Alex wanted to stay the night. We had the tent and sleeping bags, and certainly there would be available campsites. But I wanted to get home. The trip was great, but I wanted to bring it to a close. Besides, I wanted clean clothes, and didn&#8217;t feel like having to get up super-early to back up and get back to Calgary so I could go to work. I&#8217;m tired enough in the day as it is without having to do all that.<br />
Aside from a brief stop at the Spiral Tunnel lookout on the Big Hill, we didn&#8217;t stop again until we were back in Calgary. The trip back was without a doubt the worst part of the trip we&#8217;d had. Perhaps a little sympathetic with our mood about returning home, the skies had opened up and dumped a collossal storm upon the Alberta plains just east of the mountains. When we exited the mountains at Seebe, we could barely see the road.<br />
It was like that for most of the trip to Calgary, and Alex was stuck driving. The rain was like driving under Takakkaw Falls, and the spray from the passing trucks didn&#8217;t make it any better. I&#8217;ve never seen Alex so tense &#8212; she couldn&#8217;t totally tell where the lines on the road were. Needless to say, she was relieved to see the rain let up when we passed Stoney Trail.<br />
Tomorrow is going to be ugly. I know it. I can feel it. I&#8217;m going to walk into the office, and everything will have gone to hell in a handbasket. I don&#8217;t need a crystal ball, this is the pattern that seems to have been set for me. This is why I don&#8217;t like going on vacations: the crap I see when I return pretty much wipes out all the good feelings I had about being on vacation.<br />
Oh well, that&#8217;s just part of life.<br />
The trip is over, but in a way it&#8217;s opening a new journey. What&#8217;s that, you ask? Well, it&#8217;s been seven days with Alex. Non-stop. Always together. Never apart. Not once did I feel like I had to get away from her for a while. Each and every moment was a pleasure, nay, a joy! This, I think, is one of the great tests. Spend a long time with someone, and you can still walk away happy, then you&#8217;ve found something good.<br />
If this isn&#8217;t a sign of true love, I don&#8217;t know what would be.<br />
[flickr]tag:threevalleygap+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:revelstoke+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:yoho+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">386</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Ruskin to Three Valley Gap</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2004 04:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kamloops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/07/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We awoke about an hour earlier than we have in mornings past, but for no real reason. We didn&#8217;t even hear the rooster! The porridge was followed, almost as soon as we could get ready, by a cat hunt. Allen has plans for his farm, which includes a new barn (of some kind). The problem, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Ruskin to Three Valley Gap"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We awoke about an hour earlier than we have in mornings past, but for no real reason. We didn&#8217;t even hear the rooster!<br />
The porridge was followed, almost as soon as we could get ready, by a cat hunt. Allen has plans for his farm, which includes a new barn (of some kind). The problem, of course, is that you can&#8217;t have a barn without having mice and rats &#8212; that&#8217;s just a side effect. They can be controlled, however, with cats.<br />
<span id="more-385"></span>Understand, Allen does not want cats for companionship. He doesn&#8217;t even want them in the house. Ever. He wants outdoor cats that will keep the rodents under control. They&#8217;ll have to contend with the wolves, coyotes, and bears &#8230; oh my.<br />
The trick will be creating a barn cat. A stray isn&#8217;t an automatic barn cat &#8212; it could just as easily be a wanderer and just leave the barn. To be honest, I have no idea how you&#8217;d do it. In my opinion, the only way to solve the problem is to create an &#8220;outdoor cat&#8221;, that roosts inside at night. That&#8217;s what both Sylvester (my first cat) and Spaz did. Both outdoor cats, but they knew where home was.<br />
The Maple Ridge SPCA had quite a few cats, most strays, almost all adults. Ideally, Allen would want to start with kittens, or at least non-adult cats, as they&#8217;d stand the best chance of getting familiar with the barn and consider it home. There were only two kittens there, so we headed out in search of more at a veterinary hospital at the opposite side of Maple Ridge.<br />
Striking out there, Allen headed off in search of something different &#8212; a haircut. Alex and I ended up on a quest of our own &#8212; the search for her grandfather&#8217;s grave. It had been 18 years and two days since he died, which was probably the last time Alex actually saw the grave. As you can expect, that meant it was exceedingly difficult to find. Despite a 40-minute search, the site remains unknown.<br />
We were back at the bagel shop again for lunch, where we met Allen with his fresh new &#8216;do. A bite to eat, and we were off back to the SPCA again (adoptions weren&#8217;t until noon, and the kittens seemed like a good idea). As we found out upon return, there were actually two sets of kittens. Two that were 12 weeks old, and two that were five months old. The interest was primarily in the older kittens (brothers named Tom and Jerry), since they were old enough to find for themselves, and young enough to not have any previous need to go anywhere.<br />
The kittens would not find a home today, however. Both sets required neutering first, and I think Allen was a little hesitant to move forward right away. This didn&#8217;t stop Alex from taking a moment to play with the two kittens, and an older cat named Hillary.<br />
(Alex would later tell me that Human Societies often give cats names to make them more appealing, even if they already have a name of some kind. So the names we saw were likely not their &#8220;real&#8221; names, if they had any to begin with.)<br />
As soon as we got back to the house, Alex and I packed our things up. The tent and fly had been moved to the front porch that morning to dry in the sun, the sleeping bags put through the washing machine and dryer. It was barely 30 minutes before we were all ready to go.<br />
We weren&#8217;t leaving the Lower Mainland just yet &#8212; we had one more stop to make: the family of Nicole&#8217;s adopted child. She had given birth three months ago, and given the baby up for adoption. Due to new adoption laws in British Columbia, you can now keep in contact with the adopting family, and even the child. Nicole actually has visitation rights.<br />
Why we were going was beyond me, and I didn&#8217;t want to question it. I think it was mostly to support Nicole. I have no connection to this child, emotionally or even through family. Even when Alex and I get married (no, we&#8217;re not engaged &#8212; calm down!), I still will have no connection. Alex&#8217;s connection is tenuous at best, as Nicole isn&#8217;t a blood relative. Then there is the question of how much contact there will be as the years go by &#8212; will the family, or Nicole, want to continue the visitations? It&#8217;s all very curious.<br />
We never met the father, but the mother (whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten) was extremely nice. They were certainly be outstanding parents for the young one, who will no doubt grow up in a loving, caring environment.<br />
Alex and I took our leave after a little while, deciding that we really didn&#8217;t need to be there. We had to be at Three Valley Gap before midnight, and had a long drive ahead of us. After a brief stop at the 7-11 on the Haney By-pass (for a Slurpee, of course), we headed to Hope.<br />
We stayed on Highway 7 for the trip out of the Lower Mainland, enjoying the quieter ride away from the Trans Canada. Passing through Hope, we switched to the Trans Canada (as it then turns north up the Fraser valley, with the bulk of northbound traffic going to the Coquihalla).<br />
The drive from Hope to Cache Creek is beautiful, but not fast. (The trip from Hope to Kamloops along the Trans Canada is over an hour longer than taking the Coquihalla.) The valley is narrow and deep, offering a wide variety of views as the road snakes its way along the canyon walls. Right along side the road are the two major railways: CN and CP, who use the Fraser canyon as their entry into the Lower Mainland.<br />
(CN and CP have an agreement that sends trains from both companies down one side, and up the other, effectively double-tracking the canyon. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd arrangement, considering how they compete with each other, but the predicent isn&#8217;t unheard of.)<br />
We stopped in and around Alexandra, which was once a station along CN&#8217;s line. Today, it is a name used only on a bridge, tunnel, and on a lodge that is now for sale. Alex wanted a photo with her name on it &#8230; literally.<br />
Kamloops appeared just before 19:00 (we&#8217;d left at 14:30). Instead of the other restaurants we&#8217;d eaten at over the last week, I wanted something a little nicer. So we stopped at Milestone&#8217;s. It was a chance to relax a bit before resuming our trip out to Three Valley Gap.<br />
Alex took over driving at this point, having to do the remainder in the dark. I felt bad about this &#8212; driving in the dark is difficult at the best of times. But we were driving through the mountains, which is not always fun. Fortunately (oddly enough), there were a lot of trucks on the same route, which makes driving a little easier.<br />
Unable to read any books, I read Alex my journals, which she cringed and corrected as I read. (Hopefully, all of the mistakes I made have been corrected.) Finishing that, we chatted for the remaining time.<br />
The lights of the Three Valley Gap Chateau blinked across the surface of Three Valley Lake. Suddenly, the anxious tension we were feeling (we really wanted to stop driving) melted away as we arrived at our destination for the day. We checked in, found the room, and took a necessary step towards restful bliss.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">385</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fort Langley</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fort-langley</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 04:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/06/bc-vacation-fort-langley/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[That stupid rooster woke us up again. We&#8217;ve taken to mocking it. If it crowed normally, we probably wouldn&#8217;t mind so much. I fell back asleep, though, and Alex went into the house. She came back to wake me up for breakfast. Fog was hugging the ground all down the river valley. (Not exactly unheard &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fort Langley"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That stupid rooster woke us up again. We&#8217;ve taken to mocking it. If it crowed normally, we probably wouldn&#8217;t mind so much. I fell back asleep, though, and Alex went into the house. She came back to wake me up for breakfast.<br />
Fog was hugging the ground all down the river valley. (Not exactly unheard of in the Lower Mainland.) Naturally, this set me off on a photography expedition. You have to move quickly with fog &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t last long once the sun starts coming up. I got some wonderful pictures, especially of a space amongst the trees near the tent.<br />
<span id="more-384"></span>Friends of Jean&#8217;s, visiting from Rocky Mountain House, arrived while I was traipsing around the yard. They were to be breakfast guests. Sadly, this would mean I couldn&#8217;t shower before eating. They had to meet me in all my &#8220;morning glory&#8221;. Thankfully, they seemed to not notice over the porridge, peaches, apricots, and toast.<br />
After breakfast (and a needed shower), Alex and I took Erika back to the ferry. But it was far from a direct trip. Although we crossed on the Albion Ferry again, we didn&#8217;t go straight through Fort Langley. Instead, we decided to hang around a while.<br />
Fort Langley holds an interesting place in British Columbia history. It was the first settlement in the Lower Mainland, and was the main outpost for the Hudson Bay Company. First founded in 1827, the original fort was abandoned due to small size and relocated upriver in 1838. A fire destroyed the fort, and it was rebuilt at the site of the current National Historic Park two years later. Twenty years later, for about one month, Fort Langley was the capital of the Crown Colony of British Columbia. (It was moved to Queensborough, now New Westminster, just after Christmas of 1858.)<br />
Although changed repeatedly over the last 150 years, Fort Langley tries to hold to a time long since past. This is evidenced by the well-maintained CN Fort Langley railway station (obviously no longer in use), the stores and shops down the main street (the IGA is almost unnoticable, until you see the sign), the Community Hall could be brand new &#8230; as of 1922. Not to mention the plethora of vintage cars that seem to frequent the area. (Along with, oddly enough, a near-endless string of dump trucks.)<br />
We zipped in and out of various stores (curious, antiques, hand crafts) until hunger got the better of us, and we stopped for lunch. Ham and cheese sandwich. (Thankfully, no diamonds.) With that, it was time to get Erika to Tsawwassen for her ferry to Sidney.<br />
After that, Alex and I were to go to Haney to go swimming. We were going to go to the water park near the ferry terminal, but at $20 each for a couple of hours, it seemed a bit pricey.<br />
We detoured through Delta, Surrey, and Langley in desperate search of a 7-11. (We did find a Canadian Tire, where we got rope for the hammock, and a set of knives for Allen and Jean as a &#8220;thanks for putting us up&#8221; gift.) You&#8217;d think that at least one of the main roads in those three cities would have a 7-11, right? Just one?<br />
Of course not &#8212; that would actually MAKE SENSE. What the heck is wrong with the world when you can&#8217;t find a 7-11?! Okay, yes, there were Macs stores, but we needed a 7-11 specifically, because we had a 7-11 Slurpee container that needed filling (and then emptying). I think we successfully killed over an hour searching for those illusive 7-11s. It was just wrong. The only ones we ever found were on the north shore of the Fraser River. It&#8217;s like the south shore is afraid of them, or something.<br />
The lineup at the Fort Langley ferry was long. But even with the length, it only took about three or four sailings before we got on. (About 40 minutes or so.) I was dying for something to drink. When we finally got across, we headed to Haney, and stopped at the 7-11/ESSO at the Haney By-pass. This solved two problems: Slurpee cravings, and a lack of fuel in the car. Our next stop was at the London Drugs, to drop off a roll of Alex&#8217;s film.<br />
This was where we were going to go swimming. As it was now so late in the date (the Slurpee search had killed a lot more time than we&#8217;d thought), swimming was dropped as an activity. (Turned out to be a good thing, since the Leisure Centre ended up being closed for annual maintenance.) Having to kill a little time before the pictures were ready, we looked at houses on the window of a local realtor. All I can say is, we won&#8217;t be moving to the Lower Mainland any time soon with those prices.<br />
Returning to the London Drugs, we first searched for a pair of sunglasses for Alex. She was having issues with the ones she had, and something new was in order. (When you&#8217;re missing an arm off the pair you have, a new pair is allowed.)<br />
The hammock was hung within 10 minutes of arriving back at the farm. It took a bit of effort, since the trees where we hung the hammock were rather smooth, having no small branches or knots to hold the rope high enough to use the hammock. Alex took to it almost immediately, while I went to help Allen with dinner.<br />
Roasted red peppers were my duty. Everything else was left over from the night before. This was when I finally met Nicole, Alex&#8217;s adopted sister. Nicole is one-quarter Cree. She had just returned from a summer in Toronto, working so she could go back to school this fall. We didn&#8217;t get a chance to talk much.<br />
Almost immediately after dinner, Alex, Nicole, and I headed over to Frank and Audrey&#8217;s house. Frank is Allen&#8217;s father&#8217;s brother, Audrey is his mother&#8217;s sister. Convenient family merger, ain&#8217;t it? Frank had just turned 90 &#8212; it was his birthday.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long, due to the late hour for them, and because Nicole was quite tired (her clock was two hours ahead of ours).<br />
[flickr]tag:fortlangley+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Trip to Tsawwassen</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-tsawwassen/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-tsawwassen</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-tsawwassen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2004 04:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/05/bc-vacation-tsawwassen/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a rooster not far from Allen&#8217;s farm. (Well, &#8220;farm&#8221; is using the term a bit loosely. It was a farm before he bought it, and it will be one again. But it&#8217;s going to take a bit of work.) This rooster isn&#8217;t particularly normal. We&#8217;ve been speculating why it doesn&#8217;t sound normal. Most roosters &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-tsawwassen/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Trip to Tsawwassen"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s a rooster not far from Allen&#8217;s farm. (Well, &#8220;farm&#8221; is using the term a bit loosely. It was a farm before he bought it, and it will be one again. But it&#8217;s going to take a bit of work.) This rooster isn&#8217;t particularly normal. We&#8217;ve been speculating why it doesn&#8217;t sound normal. Most roosters gain their sound by listening and mimicing the sound of other roosters. This rooster doesn&#8217;t seem to have rooster peers, so it lacks the stereotypical cockle-doodle-doo one would expect at 5:30 in the morning.<br />
This one sounds like a cross between a coyote and a freight locomotive horn.<br />
<span id="more-383"></span>Ruskin is in the as-of-yet undeveloped region to the east of Maple Ridge. Slowly, but surely, this area will likely be developed as the valley fills in. It will take time, but it will happen. (Joel lives about 40 streets west of here &#8212; not really that far &#8212; on a property that had previously been a farm.) So coyotes, wolves, and bears are normal. We haven&#8217;t seen any, but they&#8217;re known to frequent the area. As for the locomotives &#8212; Canadian Pacific&#8217;s main line is about 250 metres away. It would be louder, were there not a small rise in between the line and the house.<br />
Breakfast was in the house: porridge. I got turned onto this stuff hanging out with the Rocky Mountain Rail Society (Harry loves making the stuff, even if no-one else eats it). We had it with peaches, so it wasn&#8217;t too bland.<br />
After showering and dressing, we ran a few errands. On the list: chickens for dinner (I was to make beer can chicken for five), and to look at kittens (Allen seems to have agreed to acquire one, maybe two, to control the rat problem on the farm). We started off at Bruce&#8217;s Market, which had us coming up empty-handed &#8212; no whole, unfrozen chickens. We ended up at the Save On Foods in Haney. We also grabbed lunch at a bagel shop.<br />
We never made it to the Humane Society.<br />
Stopping only briefly at the house before leaving again, we headed out to Tsawwassen. Alex&#8217;s friend of 20 years, Erika, was coming over for a visit and we were going to pick her up. From Ruskin, there is no easy way to Tsawwassen. You either have to double-back about 20 kilometres to the Highway 11 bridge, go down Highway 7 about 20 kilometres to New Westminster, or use the Albion Ferry.<br />
The Albion Ferry is a free-of-charge service that takes cars between the north and south sides of the Fraser River, between Albion (just east of Haney) and Fort Langley (on the south shore). It&#8217;s heavily used, and you can incur long waits.<br />
And that&#8217;s the rub &#8212; either you risk the chance of having a long ferry wait, or you drive the distance to wherever it is you&#8217;re going. In our case, it was the ferry. Which was fine with me &#8212; I&#8217;d never taken it before.<br />
Driving quickly through Fort Langley (a beautiful little place), we headed south to the Langley By-Pass, and then onto Highway 10, which runs west across Surrey and Delta. This took us to Highway 99, which sped us across Delta to Highway 17, which takes us south and then west(ish) to the BC Ferries Tsawwassen Terminal.<br />
It had been a very long time since I had last been there (see [[Touring in and around Victoria]]), and it looked to have changed a bit. It&#8217;s hard to tell, though, since it has been so long since my last visit. We found Erika inside, though she hadn&#8217;t been expecting us &#8212; she had been expecting Allen, who was originally supposed to pick her up.<br />
We retraced our route back to Langley, looking constantly for a 7-11 (we were dying for a Slurpee). Failing at that, we settled for a Starbucks, attached to a Chapters on the Langley By-Pass. It was a long stop, as Alex and Erika felt the need to look at &#8220;sandwiches&#8221;.<br />
This is code for looking at diamond rings. Why? In a building separate from the Chapters is one that houses a Quizno&#8217;s Classic Subs &#8230; right next to a Spence Diamonds store. They declared they needed to look at sandwiches and headed for the Quizno&#8217;s, diving off to the Spence store at the last second.<br />
I eventually had to retrieve them so we could go pick up Alex&#8217;s grandmother.<br />
Instead of taking the ferry, we continued across the south side of the river until we were able to pass under the Trans-Canada Highway, and join up with Highway 11 to go across to the north side of the river. That&#8217;s Mission, and that&#8217;s where Alex&#8217;s grandmother, Christena, lives.<br />
She&#8217;s a wonderful woman. About 90 years old, Christena still has a high, young voice, and all the joy of life I hope to have when I&#8217;m that age. Make no doubt, she&#8217;s an old woman, and is missing some ability (she needs a hearing aid, and has a couple health problems). Aside from that, though, you wouldn&#8217;t know. And she&#8217;s still her her wittiness, which I can only pray to have developed by the time I&#8217;m that age!<br />
Arriving back at the house, Alex and Erika went for a walk around the yard while Christena took a bath. Allen and I set to the task of making dinner. I found that the barbeque chicken is best when using powered spices, rather than chopped up whole spices. (Out of necessity, discovery is sometimes made.) In fact, I would say that it was the best beer can chicken I&#8217;ve ever made.<br />
The vegetables were also made on the barbeque, using a grilling basket. This will forever change the way I make vegetables. I might never cook them in the kitchen ever again! A little spice (not much different than what went on the chicken), olive oil, and red wine vinegar, pop &#8217;em in the basket and dump &#8217;em in the barbeque, with an occassional stir. Mmm, mmm!<br />
After dinner, Alex, Erika, and I took Christena home. She lives in a seniors complex about 15 minutes from Allen&#8217;s farm (which Christena used to own until a couple of years ago, when she sold to Allen). It&#8217;s not unlike Nana&#8217;s place, with a separate apartment (Christena&#8217;s is larger than Nana&#8217;s), central dining and lounge area, various services, and so forth. Naturally, we got the tour.<br />
One thing Christena can no longer do is see small things, like fruit flies, which she had a minor infestation of due to all the fruit she has. While Alex and Christena played a game of cards, Erika and I went on a fly-killing expedition. It&#8217;s a lot harder than it sounds, as those little buggers are sometimes hard to swat. We at least cut the population down by 80%, and recommended that the fruit be moved into the fridge.<br />
For the first time since our vacation started, we could clearly see the stars at the place we were sleeping (we saw them in Cranbrook, but clouds concealed the celestial sky by the time we got back to Fairmont). It was cold due to the lack of cloud cover, but the tent was warm, and the sleeping bags comfortable.<br />
[flickr]tag:ruskin+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-tsawwassen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">383</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2004 04:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/04/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest star hire had backed out &#8212; an extremely disappointing turn of events. I wouldn&#8217;t talk to Cory about it until late in the afternoon.<br />
We were gone before 8:00. (We were to have left at 6:00, then 7:00, but last night&#8217;s arrival in Fairmont pushed us even later.) Allen was in Jean&#8217;s Honda Civic, Alex and I in Alex&#8217;s car. I drove while Alex read &#8220;Why I Hate Canadians&#8221;. Today&#8217;s lesson? Canada&#8217;s cast system, more formally known as how poorly we treat Indians. It&#8217;s a hard thing for a Canadian to admit that we don&#8217;t treat everyone fairly and equally. For a country known as being &#8220;nice&#8221;, we treat our aboriginal peoples very poorly. We&#8217;ve marginalized, forcibly contained, abducted and tried to convert them, even poisoned them with disease. And yet after 400 years, they&#8217;re still who they are.<br />
<span id="more-382"></span>A lot of people think Indians have it easy here in Canada &#8212; pay no taxes, live on welfare, do what they please when they want. Lest we forget that we made them wards of the state &#8212; they *have* to live this way, because there is no other way for them to live. We never gave them a chance.<br />
(Incidentally, this is a view I&#8217;ve long held, and the book has since backed up. Ferguson is definitely a socialist who supports equal rights, nationalism (he rather dislikes the ill-guided attempts of Quebec separatists), and believes the monarchy should take a hike.)<br />
When we arrived in Golden, right behind Allen&#8217;s car, we headed to the Humpty&#8217;s on the Trans-Canada Highway for breakfast. I&#8217;d never been to Humpty&#8217;s before, having always viewed it as a lower-end sort of place to obtain a meal. My opinion of that hasn&#8217;t changed (the state of the bacon alone held me to that perspective).<br />
The weather yo-yo&#8217;d constantly from the time we left Fairmont until we arrived in the Lower Mainland. It was cloudy, rainy, spittling, sunny, warm, foggy, and windy all at various times (and varying combinations) throughout the trip. Alex seemed to get the bulk of the bad weather from Golden to Revelstoke.<br />
I read &#8220;Mythic Journeys&#8221; aloud. I disagreed with some of the interpretation, and wasn&#8217;t too thrilled with the depth &#8212; quite often, there was more commentary than story. It doesn&#8217;t make for great reading.<br />
We stopped in Revelstoke for drinks and snacks, and once again changed drivers. We stopped barely five kilometres past Revelstoke to make reservations at the Three Valley Gap hotel, which is a bit of a landmark in the area, and one of Alex&#8217;s favourite locations to be. (It&#8217;s a long story, which I&#8217;m going to forego with repeating here.) We&#8217;ll be stopping there on our way back.<br />
Off to Kamloops we went. We would have driven straight through, had we not also come across Craigellachie (&#8220;cray-GAL-ah-kee&#8221;), which was where the last spike was driven on the Canadian Pacific Railway in 1886. There&#8217;s not much there other than a cairn, bearing stones from every province and territory, and a stone from Craigellachie, Scotland, where most of the original directors of the CPR hailed from.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long. Just enough for a couple of photos, and a chance to mock some idiotic 20-something tourists from Ontario. They were being typical of that age: stupid. Though I never remember being quite so dumb that I would have inspired someone else to think of me: &#8220;Look at me, I&#8217;m an idiot!&#8221;<br />
Pulling into Kamloops about an hour later, running almost on fumes, we headed for the ABC Country restaurant on the junction of the Trans-Canada and Highway 5A. When we went inside, I realized that it was the same restaurant where Greg and I had eaten breakfast four and a half years before, when he helped me move from Vancouver to Calgary (see [[Left Vancouver, Job, and Girlfriend for New Start in Calgary]]). This time, thankfully, I wasn&#8217;t doing anything even remotely traumatic.<br />
Alex took over for the last stint of driving to Ruskin (a hamlet next to Maple Ridge, BC), where her father lives. The trip was much shorter than I had expected &#8212; for some reason, I thought the distance from Kamloops to Hope was much longer than we experienced. Mind you, the distance from Hope to Highway 11 seemed almost as long. (It didn&#8217;t help that we got stuck in traffic.)<br />
Dairy Queen made a call to us as we pulled off the highway. We&#8217;d been dying for a Blizzard since half-way down the Coquihalla Highway, but had missed the turn-off in Hope. Fortunately, the one on Highway 11 would suffice &#8230; even if some of the patrons were a little strange.<br />
Continuing up Highway 11, across the Fraser River (and getting a dirty look from a police officer at a radar trap for going a little too quickly), we turned west on Highway 7. Another 15 minutes, and we arrived at the farm &#8212; Allen and Jean&#8217;s new home, built on the former location of Alex&#8217;s grandparent&#8217;s home.<br />
We got a tour almost as soon as we were in the house. It&#8217;s an impressive structure. It looks unassuming from the outside, but there is much hidden under the covers. First and foremost, it&#8217;s a green building. It&#8217;s made with the most energy-efficient materials available, has radiant heating in the floors, recycling wood for the flooring upstairs, low-wattage lights, and nice, large windows to allow sunlight to come in during the winter.<br />
But the best feature was found tucked away, behind the garage: geothermic heating. This is the créme de la créme of cool (or heat, depending on what season you&#8217;re in). Because the house is built on an acreage, there is sufficient space to build this. (I could probably do this in Calgary, but I shudder to think at what cost.) A space about 25 feet wide, 80 feet long, and about seven feet deep was dug out behind the house and filled with long spiral tubes, and partially filled with clay. The tubes are then filled with a vicous liquid which tranfers heat in and out of the house. The system also hooks into the hot water tank to cut down on the energy needed to keep the water hot.<br />
The end result? Theoretically, a lower energy bill. If Allen has his way, he&#8217;ll also build a windmill to generate some additional electricity, and maybe even cut his BC Hydro bill to zero.<br />
A dream worth shooting for, indeed.<br />
Alex and I ducked out for a quick tour of the yard. The acreage isn&#8217;t huge (about 6.2 acres), with the main property lot about 200 feet on both sides, and then extending about 30-50 feet into the woods and down to the creek. The landscaping potential of this place is amazing &#8212; I have great dreams of a staircase and deck space down at the creek level. Now I just need to convince Allen that it&#8217;s a good idea.<br />
I pitched the tent (Alex and I are sleeping outdoors) under four great cedar trees on the east side of the house. The ground underneath is spongy from decades of cedar leaves and soil growth. Tonight, we will sleep well.<br />
I certainly hope so, because although today&#8217;s trip was outstanding, it really wore me down.<br />
[flickr]tag:craigellachie+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">382</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
