<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>revelstoke &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/revelstoke/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 16:03:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Surprise birthday weekend in Revelstoke</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 16:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelstoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/07/17/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This weekend, it was my turn to be surprised. And surprises came in droves. Sunday was my 34th birthday. I find it a little hard to believe that I&#8217;m actually that old. I always figured when I was in my 30s, I&#8217;d be more &#8230; mature. And yet I find myself being more immature with &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise birthday weekend in Revelstoke"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend, it was my turn to be surprised. And surprises came in droves.<br />
Sunday was my 34th birthday. I find it a little hard to believe that I&#8217;m actually that old. I always figured when I was in my 30s, I&#8217;d be more &#8230; mature. And yet I find myself being more immature with each passing year. I guess I&#8217;m holding to my pattern &#8212; 18 years old, with a heap of experience. For now, I think that&#8217;s a good thing. Experience helps, and one can&#8217;t get too mature. You lose all the fun, after all!<br />
<span id="more-441"></span>I sprinted home from work. I can bike home now almost as fast as I used to drive. I can&#8217;t quite figure out how I&#8217;ve done that, but I can&#8217;t really complain, either. It&#8217;s a good thing. Except that damned 8th Street hill. It&#8217;s just evil. It&#8217;s not as bad as other hills in town I have to say, but it still sucks the life out of you.<br />
Following a shower, Alex packed me in her car, and off we went. Destination unknown. Quite literally. This weekend was my chance to be surprised. I don&#8217;t ask questions, though &#8212; I prefer to try and guess to myself. The process is usually pretty simple elimination. I can eliminate quite a large number of things without much effort. Alex, of course, knows this. So she makes sure to keep me guessing.<br />
Our first stop was Banff. Dinner. Nothing serious. Kind of an eat-and-run thing. The Wolf Street Grill completely ignored us, so we tried some Japanese place a couple of blocks away. (The sign out front, in Japanese, solicited a great deal of laughter from Japanese tourists. I&#8217;m now dying to know what it says.) We ate quickly before heading back to the car and our exit.<br />
Although we ended up making one side-trip into Abomindable Sports. Sandal-searching. And I found something &#8212; Tevas. My previous pair of leather sandals was Teva, and I rather like them. I wanted something that wasn&#8217;t leather, though, since I wanted to be able to use these in wet conditions (among other things). Tevas ain&#8217;t cheap, though. But they fit, and they don&#8217;t hurt. That&#8217;s a tough thing to overcome sometimes. Tevas it was&#8230;<br />
We continued past Lake Louise and the Icefields Parkway turnoff (much to my relief), then over the Big Hill into Field, BC. Passing Field, we headed into the valley towards Golden. I was trying to figure out where we were going, and constantly drawing a blank. There was a faint hope that it had something to do with 2816, since I knew she was in the neck of the woods during the weekend. But beyond that, I hadn&#8217;t a clue.<br />
It seems that finally someone had the sense to start work on the Trans Canada highway east of Golden. It&#8217;s been a mess there for decades, and is generally difficult to go through. The hills are steep, the road windy, and there are a number of 40 km/h corners. The new section that they&#8217;re building, so it looks, will create a massive fly-over to reduce the cornering and hopefully twin the lanes. It&#8217;ll be a few years until it&#8217;s open though &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of work to do.<br />
Being the master of deception that she&#8217;s becoming, Alex really threw me off with a visit to the 7-11 in Golden before going a mere two blocks to the Travelodge for our motel room for the night. I had no idea what was going on. Thoroughly stumped.<br />
The next morning we were back on the road, following a brief stop at the Humpty&#8217;s for breakfast, we continued west. Why we were going to Revelstoke, I had no idea. We stopped briefly at the railway museum (but didn&#8217;t go in &#8212; next time, I need to actually go in there). I had heard about a trip from Revelstoke to Golden with 2816, and thought that maybe that&#8217;s what we&#8217;d gone there. (Alex had mentioned that we needed to be &#8220;there&#8221; for 13:00.) We hopped back in the car, though, and continued south.<br />
Now I was stumped. I have no idea what&#8217;s south of Revelstoke. As it turned out, not much &#8212; we were on the wrong road. We ended up having to double-back to the Trans Canada and continue west. I was beside myself with confusion. Where the hell were we going?<br />
Three Valley Gap. That&#8217;s when the surprise revealed itself. As we took seats in the restaurant there, there were settings for four, not two. Someone was going to meet us &#8212; but who? I couldn&#8217;t think of anyone who lived in the area. And that&#8217;s when Allen and Jean appeared. The sneaky trio (apparently mostly Jean&#8217;s doing) had completely orchestrated the charade.<br />
The four of us had a lovely (long) lunch, followed by a transfer of inheritances that Allen and Jean had brought from Ruskin. We&#8217;ve now got some of Christena&#8217;s things that she&#8217;d left to Alex. Oddly enough, with no planning at all, they seem to fit with our house.<br />
Naps were next. Well, for three of the four of us. Not yet being tired, I went wandering with my camera. I was lucky enough to catch a west-bound coal train (the Canadian Pacific line runs right past the hotel), though I botched the timing and the train&#8217;s a bit blurry. Things to remember for the next time I try that. Fortunately, the other trains I shot don&#8217;t move.<br />
Three Valley Gap is the oddest place you&#8217;ll ever see. It&#8217;s very much a work in progress and comes complete with a variety of antiques, including five former passenger cars from the Canadian National and Canadian Pacific railroads (and technically VIA, but they&#8217;re ex-CN/CP). Included is the Eatonia, Sir William Eaton&#8217;s private railway car. Most are in poor condition, not being maintained at all and restoration seems not to be a consideration. They do make for interesting photography, though.<br />
I found the group in the main garden wandering about. We gathered, piled into Jean&#8217;s car, and drove out to Revelstoke for dinner. Our first stop sounded good on paper. But the rather angry dog and very unassuming appearance of the restaurant suggested we go elsewhere. This led us up a long windy road to the Glacier Lodge, about a stone&#8217;s throw from the Revelstoke Dam on the west side. A massive log hotel built in 1999, and apparently a great place for dinner.<br />
It was an outstanding dinner. Miso-marinated salmon encrusted with sesame and ginger. It was a powerful but tasty meal. Alex had a lamb shank done Moroccan-style, but became more intrigued with the joint she found in the meat than actually eating it. This tortured poor Boulder, one of the wilderness guide&#8217;s two dogs. He wasn&#8217;t allowed on the patio, but the proudly displayed bone was too much for him to handle. When the waitress scolded Boulder, I suggested that she scold my wife instead for being a tease.<br />
Night photography was marginally successful. The biggest success was capturing an east-bound sulphur train, the lights creating glowing lines across the frame and glinting across the water.<br />
I was woken with a &#8220;Happy Birthday&#8221;. The goal was to try and chase 2816 from Palliser to Calgary. Alex would be on her first train chase. But first, we had to have breakfast. We met up with Allen and Jean &#8230; and a few presents.<br />
Sometime in the next while, the group of us will go to Washington and ride the dinner train. That was my present from Allen and Jean. Very nice of them. Alex surprised me with a painting of the York Railway station, circa 1930s/1940s. The kicker is that I sort of knew that she&#8217;d bought <em>something</em> when we were there, but had been told I couldn&#8217;t look at it. Never even thought about it after we got back from England and had since forgotten about it. It was a very welcome surprise.<br />
The Empress had left Revelstoke heading east around 8:00. We passed her arriving at the MacDonald tunnel entrance heading into Roger&#8217;s Pass. In theory, we could have started the chase there. But I wanted to get to Palliser before her to set up, and I knew that the construction traffic would slow us down a bit.<br />
We stopped at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a light snack and teas. As expected, the construction did in fact slow us down. I kept a weather ear out for the train, trying to make sure it wouldn&#8217;t get past us. We arrived at Palliser and took up a position and waited. And waited. And waited.<br />
2816 was supposed to leave Golden at 13:00. At first, I believed that she was just behind schedule. Freight trains get priority in most cases, so it was concievable that a delay would put her off. But 90 minutes somehow didn&#8217;t seem right. Before long, I came to believe that, somehow, she&#8217;d gotten in front of us. Perhaps in Golden, when we were at the Tim&#8217;s. Heartbroken at having to give up on what should have been a great chase, we headed east without train pictures in hand.<br />
As it turned out, we were ahead of 2816. The delay was long, and had we stayed for another 10 minutes, we&#8217;d have gotten the picture. My friend Graham was there not long after we&#8217;d left. I missed a train. Me. The Trainstalker. I feel so ashamed. It put a bit of a downer on my birthday. It seems really trivial, I know, but I just hate missing trains! It was my own fault, though, a lack of patience and too much indecision did me in. Otherwise, it was a good 34th birthday.<br />
Another year older. Hopefully a bit wiser. And perhaps a lot richer. Last year, I wasn&#8217;t married. Next year &#8230; who knows?<br />
[flickr]tag:threevalleygap+birthday+2006@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">441</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Three Valley Gap to Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2004 04:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelstoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/08/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[No rooster, just the sounds of patrons leaving their rooms. I think I prefered the rooster. The Chateau&#8217;s name is a little misleading. One is brought to think of the Canadian Pacific (now Fairmont) hotels, with the old world grandeur and luxury. Make no mistake, folks, this ain&#8217;t the Banff Springs. It&#8217;s a 1950&#8217;s motor &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Three Valley Gap to Calgary"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No rooster, just the sounds of patrons leaving their rooms. I think I prefered the rooster.<br />
The Chateau&#8217;s name is a little misleading. One is brought to think of the Canadian Pacific (now Fairmont) hotels, with the old world grandeur and luxury. Make no mistake, folks, this ain&#8217;t the Banff Springs. It&#8217;s a 1950&#8217;s motor lodge with a fancy roof. But it&#8217;s comfortable, and the grounds a nicely kitchy. Besides, it&#8217;s a family business, and run very well.<br />
<span id="more-386"></span>Cleaned up, checked out, and darn hungry, we made a break for the restaurant adjacent to the hotel. It&#8217;s tacked onto a gift shop, in which we spent a bit of time after eating. Hitting the road, we actually double-backed on our route for a while. We weren&#8217;t going right home. We were going to the Enchanted Forest.<br />
Some of you have probably seen this before. A pair of green castle tower peaks at the west end of the parking lot, followed by a candy cane house, windmill, and castle walls. It seems kitchy and the sort of thing to avoid. Until today, that has always been my opinion of it. Alex had been here years before with her father. And she desperately wanted to go back. I figured that, if nothing else, it would be good for a laugh.<br />
The Enchanted Forest was built by Ernest and Doris Needham as a place for Doris to put her collection of hand-made cement fairy tale sculptures. Using only hand tools, Ernest and Doris created many of the paths in use today, and the candy cane house in which they lived. When the Trans Canada was pushed through in the late 50s, people began to stop and take a look. Finally, on 1 July 1960, the Enchanted Forest opened to the public despite a lack of a phone line (put through in 1980) and electricity (1981). By 1970, over one million visitors had walked the forest.<br />
The Needhams have long since left the Forest, but the dream continues with its current owners. They&#8217;ve expanded the forest, keeping to the Needham&#8217;s vision, and even added a nature trail free of fairy trappings.<br />
So what is the vision? Every fairy tale you remember (and a few you don&#8217;t). They&#8217;re all there. Even stories that aren&#8217;t fairy tales, but exercises of the imagination (Peter Pan, Winnie the Pooh, and Alice in Wonderland, to name a few). Yes, it&#8217;s meant more for kids, but even the young at heart can have a lot of fun.<br />
Especially when there&#8217;s hardly anyone else there. For the first hour or so, Alex and I were almost alone in the park.<br />
We walked through the castle (with its dungeon, including a motion-activated skeleton in the dark, which caught Alex off-guard), and then into the forest to look at all the exhibits. They&#8217;re spaced apart, enough that you feel like you&#8217;re moving from piece to piece. While the sculptures and &#8220;buildings&#8221; are artificial, everything else is real. The forest is virtually untouched, kept intact without plantings of any kind, and with as few trees removed as possible. Paths allow visitors to walk around without damaging any of the surrounding forest.<br />
Partway through, we found the nature trail, and decided to walk its length. We weren&#8217;t in a rush, and I had lost all sense of time (hence, felt no need to rush). By the time we&#8217;d returned back to the fairy world, a few other families had arrived with their children. One couple asked us if the trail would be suitable for their two small children. Alex and I suggested they skip the trail this time.<br />
Finishing the loop through the park (and gift shop) in about two hours, we hit the road (with me driving) for Revelstoke. Among other things, we needed gas, badly. We arrived at the Petro-Canada on fumes. It was when I was trying to pay for gas that I realized that my credit card was missing. First, panic set in as I worried about the card being misused. Then it hit me, slowly at first &#8212; the card was still at the Milestone&#8217;s in Kamloops.<br />
Doh!<br />
I would later call the Bank of Montreal and report the card lost. &#8216;Cuz I sure as hell ain&#8217;t going back to Kamloops for a lousy hunk o&#8217; plastic.<br />
I coaxed Alex to go into Revelstoke (I&#8217;d never been in the town before) to look at the Railway Musem there. They have a Mikado that I&#8217;d always wanted to see. Ernie spoke highly of it. However, with the loss of my credit card, I was suddenly not so much in a generous mood. Although the cost was minimal (only $6), I cheaped out and suggested we not go instead. I settled for a photo of a passing coal train.<br />
That was a bit of a mistake on my part. The direction of the light sent me to the opposite side of the tracks from Alex&#8217;s car to get the photo. And if you&#8217;ve seen a coal train on CP&#8217;s Shuswap Subdivision, you know how long they are &#8212; a mile, at least! And since it was leaving the Revelstoke yard, it wasn&#8217;t moving particularly quickly.<br />
One advantage of having to wait like that, you see a few things. No, I didn&#8217;t magically find my credit card. I found another 7-11! Once the train had moved on, we made another stop to refill our Slurpee addiction before continuing to Golden.<br />
Rogers Pass is an impressive place, although I had never really given it appropriate credit. Having seen the Rogers Pass Interpretive Centre on our way out (I hadn&#8217;t been driving at the time), I suggested we pull in for a gander. Luckily, our Parks Canada pass warranted us free entry.<br />
If you don&#8217;t learn something new every day, you aren&#8217;t trying hard enough. Today was definitely a learning day. When the Canadian Pacific had first come across Rogers Pass, it had to build an impressive set of bridges and snow sheds (31 of them in total) to keep the rail line clear of avalanches and the inevitably deep snow fall. In 1916, some of the difficulty crossing the mountain was solved by the construction of the Connaught Tunnel.<br />
Rogers Pass continued to be trouble, however, until 1980, when CP built the longest railway tunnel in Canada &#8212; the MacDonald Tunnel, over 25 kilometres under the mountain that gives the tunnel its name. The original rail line across the pass no longer exists, most of it having disappeared with the construction of the Trans Canada Highway. Only a few relics of show sheds and some of the old rail bed still exists. One day, I&#8217;m going to have go back and take a closer look.<br />
Smitty&#8217;s fed us lunch in Golden. It was obvious this particular restaurant had been there for a long time, not only from the décor and construction, but also due to the quality of food. They were obviously comfortable with feeding truckers. I&#8217;m comfortable in knowing that I&#8217;ll never be a trucker, if for no other reason than I&#8217;d have a tough time trying to eat at a lot of the places they seem to frequent.<br />
Alex took over driving for the remaining portion into Calgary, starting with a quick burst into Golden for, you guessed it, another Slurpee. (Hey, when you don&#8217;t get &#8217;em when you want &#8217;em, you build up a craving that takes a few days to kill off.)<br />
Field soon appeared in view, and the end of BC was coming up quickly. Before we tackled the Big Hill, Alex suggested a detour: Takakkaw Falls. I&#8217;d seen the sign for it a dozen times, but had never been there. So without further consideration, in we went.<br />
The road out to the falls is about 14 kilometres long. It winds all over the place (how they build those roads is beyond me), and includes the most insane switchback that I&#8217;ve ever seen. It&#8217;s so tight that signs suggest that RVs back up and down the middle portion because there is simply no way for them to actually turn around.<br />
The falls are a bit of a hike from the parking lot. We had to make a quick stop at the toilets before we went off, though. Due to the CUPE strike with Parks Canada, the toilets weren&#8217;t in the best state (Alex ended up having to use the men&#8217;s room).<br />
Takakkaw Falls are very high &#8212; about 254 metres tall. During the summer melt, it&#8217;s apparently a torrent that soaks anything around it. At this time of the year it&#8217;s a comparable trickle, though still quite exciting to see. I need to go back there late spring next year!<br />
Alex wanted to stay the night. We had the tent and sleeping bags, and certainly there would be available campsites. But I wanted to get home. The trip was great, but I wanted to bring it to a close. Besides, I wanted clean clothes, and didn&#8217;t feel like having to get up super-early to back up and get back to Calgary so I could go to work. I&#8217;m tired enough in the day as it is without having to do all that.<br />
Aside from a brief stop at the Spiral Tunnel lookout on the Big Hill, we didn&#8217;t stop again until we were back in Calgary. The trip back was without a doubt the worst part of the trip we&#8217;d had. Perhaps a little sympathetic with our mood about returning home, the skies had opened up and dumped a collossal storm upon the Alberta plains just east of the mountains. When we exited the mountains at Seebe, we could barely see the road.<br />
It was like that for most of the trip to Calgary, and Alex was stuck driving. The rain was like driving under Takakkaw Falls, and the spray from the passing trucks didn&#8217;t make it any better. I&#8217;ve never seen Alex so tense &#8212; she couldn&#8217;t totally tell where the lines on the road were. Needless to say, she was relieved to see the rain let up when we passed Stoney Trail.<br />
Tomorrow is going to be ugly. I know it. I can feel it. I&#8217;m going to walk into the office, and everything will have gone to hell in a handbasket. I don&#8217;t need a crystal ball, this is the pattern that seems to have been set for me. This is why I don&#8217;t like going on vacations: the crap I see when I return pretty much wipes out all the good feelings I had about being on vacation.<br />
Oh well, that&#8217;s just part of life.<br />
The trip is over, but in a way it&#8217;s opening a new journey. What&#8217;s that, you ask? Well, it&#8217;s been seven days with Alex. Non-stop. Always together. Never apart. Not once did I feel like I had to get away from her for a while. Each and every moment was a pleasure, nay, a joy! This, I think, is one of the great tests. Spend a long time with someone, and you can still walk away happy, then you&#8217;ve found something good.<br />
If this isn&#8217;t a sign of true love, I don&#8217;t know what would be.<br />
[flickr]tag:threevalleygap+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:revelstoke+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:yoho+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-three-valley-gap-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">386</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
