<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>movies &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/movies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Christmas Blitzkrieg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-blitzkrieg</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas Blitzkrieg"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of sleep than from trying to do too much.<br />
Heck, it even makes me feel a bit young! Ish. Sort of.<br />
Except for the prolonged yawning, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-3199"></span>Tuesday evening, I went on a mission to find &#8220;Santa&#8221; presents for Monkey and Choo Choo, for a party Evans Hunt was holding for all the company&#8217;s children. I failed miserably for them (Alex would later prove to be a much better Santa in this regard), though it wasn&#8217;t a total wash for Christmas as a whole.<br />
Wednesday night was wrapping, notably a batch of presents from my sister that came in sans trimmings and trappings. My folding skills got a dusting off.<br />
Thursday was the Evans Hunt End of the World / Last Pitch party, our annual fest with clients and spouses. I honestly feel like I leave these parties too early, and I miss out on the good stories. I got the backfill the following day, and was moderately relieved to have missed some of the trouble.<br />
Friday was something slightly different, but very exciting (for me). Along with Tamara, Adrian, and Barb, I went to go see <em>The Hobbit: An Expected Journey</em>. It had been 11 years (I&#8217;d thought it only 10 at the time, but I just double-checked) since Tamara, Adrian, myself, and a couple of others had sat and waited for hours in the hallways at the Famous Players Chinook theatre (now Scotiabank Cineplex) to wait for the opening night of <em>The Lord of the Rings: Fellowship of the Ring</em>. A lot has happened in those years since&#8230;<br />
Eleven years later, I still love movies like that: long, and epic.<br />
I passed out nearly as soon as I got home, mostly due to exhaustion. (I&#8217;d also been running around before getting to the theatre, trying to find a Car2Go that I could actually get into &#8212; their system has been having issues for a couple of weeks, now.)<br />
Saturday morning was a blur of surreptitious present wrapping for the afternoon&#8217;s Santa visit, helping/forcing the kids to clean up the basement, making breakfast, and something else that I now forget. Then it was a blur of lunch-making, dressing (notably the kids in their nice dresses), and then loading into the car for the trip down to Evans Hunt for the party.<br />
This was the first office party for kids that I&#8217;ve ever attended, at any company. For reasons I&#8217;m sure someone much smarter than me could explain, Evans Hunt employees have a statistically high number of kids under the age of 10, and I&#8217;m willing to bet at least half are two or younger. At any rate, the fact that all of these kids existed was what led to the scheduling of the party, which we parents were quite happy for.<br />
The sixth floor &#8212; the new part of the office &#8212; was chosen for the venue. The large boardroom was co-opted for gingerbread man decorating and crafts, the main space for what ended up being punch-clown tackling, with a large comfy chair set aside for the Big Man.<br />
The kids rapidly multiplied, until the point where I think there may have been almost more kids than adults &#8230; though there have been more adults acting like kids after a while.<br />
When Santa arrived (Santa was a friend of a friend who does this professionally), the kids went crazy &#8230; and Choo Choo almost never left his side, utterly desperate for, well, not so much a present as just talking to him. Quite the reverse of Monkey, who was terrified of Santa for the first three and a half years of life.<br />
Monkey, interestingly, was the first one called up. She happily hopped up on his lap, talked a bit, got her present, and got down (with a hurried &#8220;thank you&#8221;) before going off to find out what the present was. (For the record, &#8220;Santa&#8221; was brilliant at finding things the kids seem to love.)<br />
Poor Choo Choo then had to endure most of the other kids coming next, one after another. She sat, enthralled, desperately eager to get on his lap. I managed to drag her away after a little while to drink more of her juice, when suddenly Santa produced the present. Choo Choo was off my lap in the blink of an eye, and raced over to Santa as fast as she could. She happily jumped up, and promptly asked for a &#8220;plane&#8221;.<br />
I have no idea where this &#8220;plane&#8221; thing was coming from. It&#8217;s now what she wants for Christmas. She was moderately disappointed at the <em>Stella and Sam</em> book she got instead.<br />
Party over, we headed home so Alex and I could shower and change for the next event of the day, her office Christmas party. Grandma appeared shortly after 5:00, which was about the time I dropped dinner on the table for them, mostly so they could eat and not bother Alex and I long enough that we could get ready for going out.<br />
We were gone just before 6:00, stopped at the hospital for Alex to get the tickets, and at the Ceili&#8217;s at Southland before 6:20. We sat at a table with Sarah, one of Alex&#8217;s regular co-workers, and Casey, who was one of the co-workers until she left to work at the new South hospital. It was the best move, since it was a good chance for us to chat with people we already knew.<br />
We left by 9:00.<br />
But lest ye think we were done &#8230; think again. Our destination? Toys &#8216;R Us. And not one, but two of them &#8212; one less than five minutes from the restaurant, and the other way up in the north. We didn&#8217;t get home until nearly 11:45. I got to bed a half-hour later after taking Grandma home.<br />
Sunday. Today. Yet more stuff.<br />
Mostly me doing my Christmas shopping, notably picking up things for Alex, and picking up the Playmobile toys for the girls that Grandma and I had found on Friday.<br />
And then we went to Zoo Lights.<br />
We&#8217;ve done this many times before, but this year we opted to try something a little differently. We opted to try going by C-Train, now that the new West LRT is open, and happens to run from here out to the Zoo. It seemed like a good idea, and we were &#8212; at least initially &#8212; excited to try out the new route.<br />
For the record, the trip is a minimum of 35 minutes (45 if you happen to <em>just</em> miss the train, which we did on the outbound). And although it was only -3, it somehow felt quite a bit colder, which we all seemed to notice. Thankfully the kids were well-bundled, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad for them.<br />
We got home at 9:00, well after some people&#8217;s bedtimes.<br />
Like mine. Or at least, that&#8217;s what it feels like. &#8216;Cuz after all this, I feel really tired.<br />
Sleep. Need sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TV is dead. Long live the internet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TV is dead. Long live the internet!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial that changed the direction of the UHF antenna&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve lost you, haven&#8217;t I? I shudder to think how few of you have an <em>inkling</em> of what I&#8217;m talking about. Yeah, that&#8217;s how old I am. I remember when there were only a handful of channels, when almost all of the content was on ABC, NBC, CBS, CBC, CTV, Global, and a few independent stations (such as the awesome CityTV and the the extremely nacent Fox). I remember the introduction of cable. I remember having to wait for the summer reruns because I missed that crucial episode of <em>The A Team</em> that everyone was talking about in class the next morning. I remember when the season debuts were a big thing. I remember when missing a live televised event was significant, because it was gone forever.<br />
It seems somehow just as bizarre a concept as the Spanish Inquisition.<br />
<span id="more-3076"></span>Up until a few years ago, this model was still fairly static. Despite the massive influx of cable, the ridiculous proliferation of specialty channels (seriously, I cannot fathom how some of them make any money), Youtube, Torrents, and the like, the concept of &#8220;television&#8221; hadn&#8217;t really changed. You still relied on the networks. Waiting for the most recent <em>Survivor</em> was still a big thing. And people watched the evening news.<br />
In the last 24-30 months, however, I&#8217;ve seen a massive shift in service. The <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/research/2010/01/the-itunes-effect-and-the-futu.html">iTunes Effect</a> completely altered the way that we consume music (despite the music industry continually trying to roll the clock back as if nothing ever happened), and it&#8217;s echoed into the way we consume video. And I choose that word very carefully: <em>video.</em> Not &#8220;television&#8221;, not &#8220;movies&#8221;. The length of a given item, or its relevance to a related group of videos (say, a television series of yore, or a trilogy of films) is largely irrelevant. Thanks to devices such as DVRs, tablets, Boxees, Apple TVs, and so forth, we can consume video on our own terms, and not at those of the telecommunications companies to whom we enslaved ourselves for over five decades.<br />
A month and a half ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/upstairs-reno-the-fun-begins/">my family moved out of our home</a> so the kitchen renovation could begin in earnest. When we did that, we took our living room video display (I now loathe to call it a &#8220;TV set&#8221;) and the Apple TV so we could watch, well, <em>something</em>. For three weeks, all we had were whatever videos were on the Apple TV &#8212; we had no network connection to speak of, so no new videos during that time.<br />
When we got back into our home, the living room was far from any suitable state to be able to hook our video displays back up to the television display boxes. No TV. (In fact, hardly any video at all.) At the end of a month and a half, it&#8217;s hard for us to really &#8220;miss&#8221; television at all.<br />
We had Telus Optik. It was a decent service, and the only real complaint I had with it was that we had about 180 channels more than we watched. There were four on any form of rotation: Discovery (for my <em>MythBusters</em> fix), Treehouse (for the kids&#8217; shows), whatever channel showed <em>Greys Anatomy</em>, and one or two other channels were in the mix for a few things. But that was it. No kidding. No joke. We paid $80 to watch less than a half dozen things.<br />
Yesterday, I pulled the plug (not <em>completely</em>, mind you &#8212; I rather stupidly signed up for a three year contract, thinking this blog post was still quite a ways away; the account is in &#8220;suspension&#8221; for $5/month, though it counts towards the contract term), and we started onto a new path: internet-only content.<br />
We are far from the first to do this. I have several friends who cut their cable a while ago, and have sufficed quite well off of whatever they could glean from the internet. iTunes has been a major source of material, as has the ubiquitous YouTube. Many have turned to the less-legal Torrents to acquire television shows and movies, while others have looked to online services such as Netflix.<br />
My problem with the internet aspect until recently was twofold: fragmentation, and accessibility. There&#8217;s a lot of different venues in which to find the content one might want to watch &#8212; think of it as having two constantly criss-cross a typical urban mega-strip mall on an erratic shopping spree, rather than being able to go to a single store and finding all that you need. And then it&#8217;s an issue where you go to a given store expecting to find the very shirt your American friend told you about, but despite it being an American clothier, that specific shirt isn&#8217;t available in Canada. (Canada remains, frustratingly, a digital backwater when it comes to internet content.)<br />
So what&#8217;s changed? Aside from the realization that we just don&#8217;t watch regular television anymore, it was the introduction of a &#8220;content aggregator&#8221; (not sure what else to call it), some handy (but legally grey-area) tools, and the ability to be a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing. Allow me to introduce our new media setup&#8230;</p>
<h2>The Device</h2>
<p>Ultimately, you need a unit to actually serve content (the stuff &#8212; literally &#8212; doesn&#8217;t fly through the air, anymore). The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_TV#Apple_TV_First_Generation">Apple TV (version 1)</a> had been a decent first attempt, but it failed in a number of ways, not the least of which was a strong tie to iTunes and not a lot of expandability (even the <a href="http://firecore.com/atvflash">aTV Flash</a> hack offered little more). It meant that it was hard for us to use different media sources, or even watch DVDs through a single device.<br />
Enter the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_Mini">mid-2010 Apple Mac Mini, model A1347 (non-server)</a>. Slightly taller than the Apple TV, this is a complete computer, and can run any software we need. Furthermore, it has full support for 1080p video, complete audio support, and because it&#8217;s a full computer, it can be used by Monkey and Choo Choo as they grow up and need to use computers in their school (while Mommy and I get to help/watch). Even more key for this specific release of the Mac Mini, however, is that this is the last one that came with a SuperDrive built-in &#8212; the next release was without an optical drive, making it hard to watch those reams of physical media we&#8217;ve been accumulating.<br />
The Mac Mini is limited to 320 GB, which seems like a lot, but it&#8217;ll fill up quickly with the media we hope to deliver through it. So instead, I&#8217;m going to be attaching it to a terabyte drive (ideally a RAIDed one, with a secondary backup for real redundancy) that will store all the music, movies, photos, and various videos that our family will use. Our network is gigabit (thanks to Telus), so network speed shouldn&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<h2>The Software</h2>
<p>Operating system aside, the complete list is still pending, but I&#8217;m looking at:</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Duh. We have a significant amount of content in iTunes, and there is zero reason not to use iTunes to access it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plexapp.com/">Plex Server</a><br />
This is the aggregation tool. It offers a significant amount of functionality for linking disparate pieces of content (including iTunes) into a single interface, and offers a variety of &#8220;channels&#8221; for watching online content. Because it works full-screen, it&#8217;s a suitable replacement for the venerable Front Row. It also includes a player that can play software copies of DVDs&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://thelittleappfactory.com/ripit/">RipIt</a><br />
Boy, it didn&#8217;t take long to get back into that legal black hole, didn&#8217;t it? Yes, I am using a piece of software to extract the content from media I have purchased and am placing it in a non-public system for my own personal entertainment, digital lock provisions be damned. Big Media pushing bullshit like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">SOPA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_Canada">C-11</a> can <a href="http://www.freshnewsound.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/johnny_cash.jpg">suck my balls</a>. I don&#8217;t like physical media, it&#8217;s too prone to damage by jam-covered fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, we will install what&#8217;s needed, when it&#8217;s needed. Right now, I&#8217;m not sure what that is, but I&#8217;m sure we can adapt when the time comes.</p>
<h2>The Services</h2>
<p>The hardware and software alone will not solve our problems. It&#8217;s not really any different than buying a &#8220;regular&#8221; television set. The problem is that you still need to have content provided from <em>somewhere</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Again, duh. Our existing library is one thing, but iTunes still has an extensive (and lovely) collection of media from which to select. We&#8217;ve used iTunes for quite some time, and plan to keep using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://goo.gl/EY0O4">The Service I Can&#8217;t Really Talk About</a><br />
Okay, this is another one of those &#8220;grey area&#8221; items. Technically, Canadians can&#8217;t see American content (think Hulu, American versions of Netflix and iTunes, and Comedy Network) because some dumbass decided that we&#8217;re not allowed to see it. So our IP blocks are scanned and summarily blocked. This service makes you look like an American &#8212; a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing &#8212; and away you go. It&#8217;s not illegal, but I&#8217;m sure that some moron lawyer will cry foul (because he&#8217;s paid to do so) and it&#8217;ll get yanked. Hence, I refuse to name it. Like Plex, it also provides a number of channels, so we should be able to watch &#8230; well, pretty much anything we want, really.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.netflix.ca">Netflix</a> (the American verison!)<br />
My biggest gripe with Netflix is that the Canadian content is so wildly different than the American content &#8230; despite it running off the same system. So thanks to the aforementioned service, we get the added benefit of a larger library.</li>
</ul>
<div>Okay, what about live television? Say I want to watch the hockey game, or even the Olympics? Well, this is where the Mac Mini comes to the rescue again. Because it&#8217;s a full computer, it has a full browser (and various necessary plugins) so that we can visit a website and watch live feeds. Perfect? Probably not, but at least it&#8217;s better than channel surfing.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>The Result</h2>
<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know yet. From everything I&#8217;ve read and from everything everyone who&#8217;s already gone down this road has told me, this seems like a solid path. But I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that it won&#8217;t be a bed of roses (and, really, when you think about it, is a &#8220;bed of roses&#8221; all that appealing? Think of the thorns!) and this could fail. I doubt it will fail entirely, since we get content no matter what, it&#8217;s just the depth at which we get it.<br />
So what of actual &#8220;television&#8221;? We&#8217;re in the shift now, and already it&#8217;s showing. Advertisers are trying to find new ways to market to people who are willingly skipping commercials. Big Media is slow to adapt (surprise, surprise!), but is at least starting to recognise the revenue potential, so it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll fight against it. But the transition from network model (which provides funding and marketing for television shows) is at risk, given a more fragmented market.<br />
For us, this can only be a win-win. People want to make video, and we want to consume it. The question of <em>how</em> remains, and its only a matter of time before these bits of technology-in-infancy are replaced by more robust and &#8220;complete&#8221; systems that hide the mess of aggregation, bringing about a true &#8220;on demand&#8221; environment that has been promised for the better part of 20 years.<br />
As for our specific experience, we&#8217;ll keep you posted. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve got a Mac Mini to set up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why SOPA will (and must) fail</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-sopa-will-and-must-fail</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 04:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why SOPA will (and must) fail"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear reader, is something that you do need to be aware of, as it may very well affect this very website.<br />
The Stop Online Piracy Act is a bill before the Government of the United States of America that proposes &#8212; in a general sense &#8212; a series of rules and penalties in an effort to eradicate online piracy. At a high level, it certainly seems like a reasonable request. In fact, so reasonable that anyone not spending time reviewing the details of the bill might very well have missed some of the more draconian measures being implemented, allowing &#8212; in effect &#8212; individual companies to disable outright any website they believe to be infringing on copyright without right of trial, so long as said website has some dependency on US-based services (which a tremendous percentage of websites have).<br />
In effect, a US company can shut down your otherwise legal operation because they&#8217;ve told their government that you&#8217;re the bad guy.<br />
Sound unfair? It should. But this, dear reader, is also where things get more sinister.<br />
The authors of this bill are members of the American government, but that&#8217;s not who is really driving it. The backers? Big media. Notably, the same companies who have been engaging in a futile, misguided, and often grossly misdirecting effort to have laws enacted to protect their business models. <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/76259944/SOPA-Supporters">Companies represented by the RIAA and MPAA, and a host of old companies who don&#8217;t want to change.</a><br />
They&#8217;re flailing, and failing. They&#8217;re unable to grasp the concept of digital media. They&#8217;re used to their physical world &#8212; one book to one person, one CD in one CD player, one VHS tape showing on one tube-based television set. The new world allows a single copy to be copied, cut, remixed, and displayed on millions of devices simultaneously. The media companies chime: &#8220;Show me the money.&#8221;<br />
But instead of adapting, they cry foul. They cry piracy. They claim that they&#8217;re losing money hand-over-fist, and they will expire without the assistance of new laws. Yet, they&#8217;re not losing money. In fact, many of the music labels are making more than ever, largely in part to Apple, who strong-armed them into making music cheap, and &#8212; to absolutely no surprise to any armchair economist &#8212; removed the barrier to entry, and sold music in such quantities that the music industry was very likely saved from imminent death.<br />
Hence, SOPA. And while the White House chosen to not sign the bill, there is no reason to believe it won&#8217;t be back in some other odious form.<br />
Beyond the American government, I have reason to also fear this bill because of the efforts of my own government. The Canadian government has thrice shown to be spineless in its resistance to these same groups lobbying for ridiculous legislation in Canada that would put our own culture and identity as unwarranted in terms of content ownership. Our politicians, who had in decades previous been those who stand only for its own people, now show to be bowing to massive foreign conglomerates, leaving its own people to suffer as a result.<br />
SOPA, and bills like it must fail. Because they are flawed in their consideration of evolution, because they fail to take digital commerce into account, and because they will unnecessarily bind our children into false agreements and behaviours that will haunt them their entire lives.<br />
If you are an American, please write your congressperson. If you are Canadian, please write your MP. In either case, don&#8217;t let your government become party to Big Media&#8217;s insanity, don&#8217;t let our future be dictated by corporations. Learn more at <a href="http://americancensorship.org/">AmericanCensorship.org</a>.<br />
Content yearns to be free. Not free as in ownership, but free as in freedom, free as in life. Let content live.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2010-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Man, it feels like a year ago since I last wrote one of these &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;) 2010 was the year we made contact &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2010, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, it feels like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/">a year ago since I last wrote one of these</a> &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;)<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_(film)">2010 was the year we made contact</a> &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named Choo Choo. It was a year I changed my career outlook (yes, again), and found that I&#8217;m not (completely) useless. This was a year of family, for me, and that&#8217;s perhaps the most important aspect.<br />
But despite all that, I hesitate to call it &#8220;a year of change&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2829"></span>Got me as to why, though. Let&#8217;s be honest, there were a lot of changes, not the least of which are the ones noted above. But at no time did I feel like this is a sudden (and possibly unwanted) shift in my life. It actually feels like things are more settled this year, despite the apparent upheaval, than in previous years. Maybe one day I&#8217;ll make some sense of that little quandary.<br />
In the meantime, let&#8217;s review 2010:</p>
<ul>
<li>Began the year with tea at the Banff Springs, seeing my friend Sonny for the first time in about 15 years</li>
<li>Started working with some old friends at a new(er) company, Evans Hunt</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton for a &#8220;surprise&#8221; weekend (mostly for Monkey) and spent a great morning in the waterslides with her</li>
<li>Celebrated my Nana&#8217;s 97th birthday, which would also sadly be her last</li>
<li>Found out that I&#8217;m K+, my kids are K+, and my wife is anti-K</li>
<li>Spent many a sleepless night worrying about Choo Choo before she was born</li>
<li>Though originally disheartened, came to love and be thrilled by the 2010 Winter Olympics in Canada, and felt the massive pride for the successes of our athletes
<ul>
<li>Yes, I Twittered obsessively during the Men&#8217;s Hockey gold medal game</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bought our first flat-screen TV, to go along with our Apple TV</li>
<li>Welcomed my youngest, (code)named Choo Choo to our world</li>
<li>Watched Monkey&#8217;s first Easter egg hunt</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;ve got something called &#8220;narrow angles&#8221; in my eyes, and got laser surgery in both of them</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller, and visited the Royal Tyrell</li>
<li>Guided (albeit not as well as I could have) the technical launch of my first all-Drupal website: VisitCalgary.com</li>
<li>Experienced the abject terror of losing your child in a mall</li>
<li>Said &#8220;thank you&#8221; to my Nana &#8212; I never say &#8220;goodbye&#8221;</li>
<li>Went on my first train chase with Monkey</li>
<li>Went to dim sum a couple of times, but not nearly enough</li>
<li>Introduced Monkey to sushi &#8212; I think she likes it</li>
<li>Went to Heritage Park a couple of times, and even saw Thomas the Tank Engine (hey, I&#8217;m a parent <em>and</em> I like trains, it&#8217;s a win-win)</li>
<li>Went to the Zoo lots (it helps to have a pass)</li>
<li>Saw a few movies, but not enough for my liking (the favourite of the year was Toy Story 3, and no, not just because I&#8217;m a parent)</li>
<li>Went on the first Great Family Roadtrip:
<ul>
<li>Overnighted in Medicine Hat, AB; Whitewood, SK; Moosimin, SK; and Swift Current, SK</li>
<li>Went to Winnipeg</li>
<li>Went to some place east of Camper, out in the middle of nowhere, as part of Alex&#8217;s family reunion</li>
<li>Stopped off in Regina, Moose Jaw, and Portage La Prairie</li>
<li>Drove the whole way and back again, and the kids didn&#8217;t seem to mind at all</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got diagnosed with a hernia (yay, me)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 3rd birthday, her first in Canada (beyond the day she was born, that is)</li>
<li>Finally got right ticked off with Shaw&#8217;s horrid home internet service, and switched over to Telus &#8230; we&#8217;ll see how it all goes</li>
<li>Did some kitchen renovation:
<ul>
<li>Installed a new sink and tap</li>
<li>Tore out the Florida ceiling</li>
<li>Installed new lighting</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had new windows installed in the house</li>
<li>Returned to being a developer, rather than a pure manager (I&#8217;m still adjusting to this one)</li>
<li>Took Monkey out on her first real Hallowe&#8217;en</li>
<li>Grew a moustache for Movember (my first, and last time)</li>
<li>Went to the Currie Barracks location of the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market almost every weekend for a year, until the location finally (and sadly) closed in December</li>
<li>Went on our first family flight out to Abbotsford, to spend Christmas in BC</li>
<li>Visited with some old friends from Radical Entertainment</li>
<li>Went to downtown Vancouver for the first time in about five years, and remembered how much I love it there</li>
<li>Had my first green Christmas in many, many years</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains</li>
</ul>
<p>Whoof. That&#8217;s a lot for one year. Can&#8217;t wait to see what 2011 throws at me. Bring it, New Year &#8212; I&#8217;m ready for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four fun-filled days</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=four-fun-filled-days</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 03:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dim sum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Four fun-filled days"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and notably you, Monkey.<br />
The last four days have been a lot of fun. Maybe even too much fun. Both of us are pretty pooped. You went to bed and for the first time in a long while, there wasn&#8217;t hours of chatter from your room. I think you pretty much passed out. I won&#8217;t be too far behind you, I think, but I do wish to describe the fun that we&#8217;ve shared.<br />
&#8216;Cuz, frankly, I&#8217;m not sure how the heck I survived it all&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2688"></span>First off was Canada Day. This year, Mommy and I decided to try a visit at Heritage Park. If you got there early enough, you got a free pancake breakfast. It seemed like a fun thing to do. And it probably would have been more fun if it had been a few degrees warmer &#8212; it was rather chilly for the first day of July.<br />
Still, you had a lot of fun. Once we&#8217;d gobbled down the pancakes, we went and got ride tickets. You swung on a vintage ship-styled swing, rode the big steam train around the park, went on the paddlewheeler out in Glenmore Reservoir (although you barely stopped moving the entire time, necessitating me following you around the entire time), and went on the merry-go-round (you demanded to ride the white horse).<br />
You ate a pretzel, and drank some frozen lemonade with me. We saw the farm animals (you mooed at the cows, and nearly had your bright red Crocs eaten by a misguided horse). Then we went through Gasoline Alley. By this point, you were tired and got fairly cranky, so we all opted to go home.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762441701(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762451847(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762453683(square)[/flickr]<br />
Mommy wanted to go visit with Grandpa for a week, and had to take Choo Choo with her. (Choo Choo&#8217;s still nursing, so she goes wherever Mommy goes.) But &#8230; well, Monkey, all me to be rather honest for a moment &#8212; travelling with you lately requires a lot of high-test drugs to keep people calm. Either you or us, it doesn&#8217;t matter. But Mommy travelling with you and Choo Choo wasn&#8217;t even discussed as an option, and Mommy really wanted to go without all of us in tow. (You&#8217;ll understand this years from now, when you have a near-3 year old.)<br />
Of course, what all that means is, it was just you and me, kid. And we got off to it before Mommy and Choo Choo&#8217;s plane had taken off.<br />
Our first stop was the Galaxie Diner on 11th St., not far from Grandma&#8217;s house. There we enjoyed a filling breakfast, because we had a long day of chasing trains ahead of you. I hadn&#8217;t chased a train since before you were born, and I was itching to go out and take pictures. I figured you might like to see a big train in motion, and when my friend Graham told me CP 2816 was going out to Banff on 2 July, I couldn&#8217;t resist.<br />
After breakfast, we went home just long enough to get a few things together (like my camera), and then we went searching for our first place to wait. I originally thought of a place known as Keith, which is roughly where Stoney Trail crosses the Bow River. But as we came down Sarcee Trail towards the highway, I spied an even better location: where the train tracks cross 32nd Ave NW. It would give me an easy access for photography, a decent backdrop, and not far from the highway to get back out again.<br />
We ended up having to wait longer than I would have liked. One thing you&#8217;ll learn, kiddo, is that when you chase trains, you have to be patient and wait. A lot. Even though Graham was sending me text messages on the train&#8217;s status, it didn&#8217;t come quickly. We saw a freight train have to wait for CP 2816, too. But eventually, we got the note that she was heading west. Before long, we could hear its whistle echo through the valley. It came towards us, barrelling along as fast as it could, belching out black smoke.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762469809(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763109230(square)[/flickr]<br />
For a moment, I saw myself in you. When I was your age (maybe a little older), your granddad (my daddy) used to take my family (Nana, Auntie Cathy, and me) to the train tracks near our house, to watch another steam locomotive &#8212; CN 6060 &#8212; come racing by, huge clouds of black smoke filling up the sky. It used to scare the hell out of me. Of course, I look back at that now and I feel really glad that I did see that &#8212; it&#8217;s a fond memory. I hope maybe one day, it is for you, too.<br />
We hit the road and headed out to a place out towards the mountains called Ozada. You were asleep before we were outside city limits, and slept all the way there. Ozada is on the Stoney Indian reserve, and is one of Canadian Pacific&#8217;s old stations for servicing steam locomotives. (The concrete pylons for the coaling and water towers are still visible.) Today, it&#8217;s little more than a siding in the middle of nowhere, just off the highway. And we waited there because Graham had told me CP 2816 would be stopping there for servicing as well.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762477071(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762477937(square)[/flickr]<br />
We were not disappointed. We saw the train come in slowly, pass by, and stop in the siding. After it had passed, we drove to the other end of the siding, and watched it race westward. (The train was about two hours late, so they had a reason to move quickly.) We drove out to the highway, and saw the train&#8217;s smoke as we drove by it on the highway. We saw some other people we&#8217;d seen back in Calgary stop at the side of the highway to take more pictures.<br />
Finally, we stopped in Banff, and waited about halfway between the station and Bankhead. We had to wait a long, long time before we saw CP 2816&#8217;s lights. As CP 2816 was going on show at the station, the train stopped again not far from us for one last servicing before going in. This gave us a fantastic view, although the whistles did give you a bit of a scare &#8212; they were quite loud.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762480609(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763119200(square)[/flickr]<br />
After meeting up with Graham at the station (it seemed only fair to thank him in person for the information), we had lunch at Bruno&#8217;s, and then headed back to Calgary. You slept from Canmore all the way home.<br />
On Saturday, you and I went to the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market, mostly so you could go to the jumping castle &#8212; probably your most favourite thing in town (after me, of course). You ate your mixed berry crepe almost as fast as I could eat my ham and cheese crepe. I swear it&#8217;s the only thing you eat quickly &#8212; everything else requires a pry bar and a shovel&#8230;<br />
When I asked what you wanted to do next, you said: &#8220;I want [to see the] giraffes!&#8221; So off we went to the zoo. We went though the dinosaurs, then over to the giraffes, zipped by the gorillas, and spent a lot of time at the playground (you love the playground, there). Then it was into the Australian  pavilion  (I was devastated to find that the nocturnal animal area is permanently closed), through the monkey house, and then over to the elephants (where we had hot dogs), zipped over to the carousel (just opened), before going through the Canadian Wilds (where you were completely obsessed with the prairie dogs).<br />
[flickr]photo:4763125998(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762491661(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762511327(square)[/flickr]<br />
For dinner, I took you to a Japanese restaurant. I found that your chopstick skills had degraded quite a lot &#8212; we&#8217;ll have to work on that. But you ate half of the edamame, a couple of avocado rolls, and even a piece of hamachi sashimi (well, it was nigiri sushi, but it was just plain easier to give you just the fish). You wouldn&#8217;t touch the miso soup (I&#8217;ll work on that, too). For your first shot, I was very proud of you.<br />
The next morning, we walked over to the #2 bus stop. You were ecstatic about riding the bus. I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s from singing <em>The Wheels On The Bus</em> so much.   We went to the Silver Dragon restaurant, where we met up with my friend Tamara and her husband, Dan. There we ate dim sum (Mommy was rather annoyed that we went without her). It was so good. You ate buns, and pork dumplings, and quite a lot of deep fried squid. Yes, you ate squid. I kid you not. Mind you, as I&#8217;ve said to others, the squid tastes a lot like scrambled eggs. So I told you it was scrambled eggs. You couldn&#8217;t get enough.<br />
Following dim sum, you and I walked along the river over to Eau Claire Market (which really isn&#8217;t a market anymore &#8212; it&#8217;s mostly businesses and empty store space &#8212; nothing like it used to be), where you and I saw Toy Story 3. I cried a bit. You seemed to like it a lot, though. Especially anything with Woody.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762516489(square)[/flickr]<br />
In fact, you like Woody and Jesse (the Yodelling Cowgirl) so much, and because the Calgary Stampede is just around the corner, we walked over to Stephen Avenue afterwards to try and get you a cowgirl outfit. You&#8217;ve got the boots and jeans, but you need a hat and a shirt. Sadly, we were less than successful &#8212; no-one seemed to have a cowgirl shirt in your size.<br />
On the way home, much to our luck, we ran into Grandma on the bus (she was coming to our house, anyway &#8212; we just had really good timing). You had some fun with Grandma while I went off to get something for us to eat for dinner.<br />
In fact, I&#8217;m so tired from all of this excitement that it&#8217;s taken me a while to write all of this. But I hope you had fun, Monkey. I know I did.<br />
And now, I need to go to bed. &#8216;Cuz I&#8217;m really, really, <em>really</em> tired.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flash: I&#039;m not dead yet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/flash-im-not-dead-yet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=flash-im-not-dead-yet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/flash-im-not-dead-yet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 05:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rich media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m getting a little tired of this topic. I was tired of it about a day after Steve Jobs first showed the iPad to the world, and the infamous blue LEGO appeared where a Flash plug-in should have been. It wasn&#8217;t really so much a shock to the world &#8212; Apple had been denying Flash &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/flash-im-not-dead-yet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Flash: I&#039;m not dead yet!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I&#8217;m getting a little tired of this topic.</strong> I was tired of it about a day after Steve Jobs first showed the iPad to the world, and the <a href="http://www.thebluelego.com/">infamous blue LEGO</a> appeared where a Flash plug-in should have been. It wasn&#8217;t really so much a shock to the world &#8212; Apple had been denying Flash applications on their iPod/iPhone platform all along. But this seemed to start off a little maelstrom the likes of which I haven&#8217;t read <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endianness">since people argued over on which end to start eating a hard-boiled egg</a>.<br />
The events of the last few weeks have been extremely tiresome to say the least. Far too many people and groups have been  prognosticating  the future of personal computing, and <strong>there&#8217;s been far too little in doses of reality</strong>. The future is coming, but it&#8217;s not coming nearly as quickly as everyone thinks it is, and rushing to meet the future will likely only harm the present. A little rational thought would be appreciated.<br />
Okay, let&#8217;s address the elephant in the room, first. <a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2010/04/why-steve-jobs-hates-flash.html"><strong>Steve Jobs hates Flash.</strong></a> There, I&#8217;ve said it. Now let&#8217;s move on.<br />
<span id="more-2644"></span>I&#8217;m not here to argue about openness or stability, or any of the <a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/">claims</a>/<a href="http://jessewarden.com/2010/04/steve-jobs-on-flash-correcting-the-lies.html">counter-claims</a> made by anyone. There&#8217;s no point, since a large part of it is highly subjective. <strong>Apple will do whatever Apple wants to do</strong>, regardless of any other company&#8217;s desires, intentions, or abilities. And while Apple might be on the right path to the next major shift in personal computing, we&#8217;re still quite some time from critical mass.<br />
Right now, in the industry, <strong>we have a need for rich, engaging experiences</strong>. These experiences are the things that help capture attention and keep people using a website or service long enough for that website or service to deliver its message and achieve its function. It could be easily argued that a much simpler user interface can do the same thing, but I can also easily argue that <strong>there is a wide gulf between utility and ubiquity</strong>: I love the simpleness that comes with pure utility, but the ubiquity of &#8220;fun&#8221; is what wins the day.<br />
As a result of Apple, a lot of people are starting to tout the death of Adobe (formerly Macromedia) Flash. It&#8217;s doomed because Apple said so, or at least that&#8217;s the narrowly simple version of the story. A longer version introduces the <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/html5/">up-and-coming HTML5 standards</a>, which start to <strong>blur the lines between what Flash does now and what could be done without Flash</strong>. That&#8217;s what a lot of the major players (<a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/195362/google_official_reaffirms_html5_readiness.html">Google</a> and Apple being the two most obvious) are moving towards, and there&#8217;s no reason why their direction shouldn&#8217;t be taken as the final chapter on Flash, right?<br />
Right?<br />
To the best of my knowledge and five minutes on Google,  <strong>there has never been a technology that has up-and-vanished overnight</strong> (even figuratively-speaking) merely because one company said so. While I have a significant amount of respect for Apple and their attention to detail, and I nearly worship at the Altar of Google, I&#8217;d be quite the fool to be agreeing to abandon Flash.<br />
Yes, you heard me. <strong>Dropping Flash is a foolish idea. </strong><br />
I know, I know. Don&#8217;t I hate Flash? Aren&#8217;t I the one who railed against it for years and years and years. In a word: no. <strong>I&#8217;m technology agnostic.</strong> I&#8217;ve been agnostic for a almost a decade. I learned a long time ago that ignoring a solution merely because you don&#8217;t like it immediately cuts you out of possible success, and <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2006/08/my-expectations-of-a-technology-team/">you end up reinventing wheels</a>. I don&#8217;t hate Flash &#8212; I hate inappropriate use of a technology.<br />
Flash, as a platform for providing a rich media solution, has a place in our industry. For today, tomorrow, and the foreseeable short-term future (I&#8217;m saying at least two years, personally), <strong>any company pulling support for Flash is being extremely short-sighted</strong>. It&#8217;s like ditching your extremely reliable car at the side of the road to climb into an open chassis that has no doors, no roof, the colours and interior are still being decided, the engine periodically doesn&#8217;t work properly, and you&#8217;d better hope the dang thing has brakes.<br />
Yes, <strong>you can do a lot without Flash right now</strong>. A number of websites (the <a href="http://www.nissanusa.com/leaf-electric-car">site for new Nissan Leaf</a>, the <a href="http://apirocks.com/html5/html5.html#slide1">HTML5 presentation</a>, <a href="http://ajaxian.com/archives/blowing-up-html5-video">HTML5 video</a>, <a href="http://acko.net/blog/javascript-audio-synthesis-with-html-5">HTML5 audio funkiness</a>) have proven that you can use these new standards quite effectively, and move away from Flash. And to that end, I say &#8220;congratulations, I hope you do well&#8221;. You&#8217;re going to need a lot of help, and pray that you can get away with it.<br />
Why? Well, guess what folks, the <strong>HTML5 &#8220;standard&#8221; isn&#8217;t complete</strong> &#8212; It&#8217;s still a working draft. CSS3? Not finished, and not properly/fully supported by any browser. Video? Well, as much as Apple has tried to say that H.264 is the de facto standard, it&#8217;s patented, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/H.264/MPEG-4_AVC#Patent_licensing">license fees will kick in at the end of 2015</a>. Google&#8217;s bought On2, with the widely-held <a href="http://arstechnica.com/open-source/news/2010/04/google-planning-to-open-the-vp8-video-codec.ars">hope that they&#8217;ll release the VP8 codec openly</a>. <a href="http://www.h-online.com/open/news/item/Mozilla-defends-Firefox-s-HTML5-support-for-only-Ogg-Theora-video-912003.html">Firefox is only supporting Ogg Theora.</a> And lest we forget the Browser That Just Won&#8217;t Die: <strong>Internet Explorer 6 will make your life a living hell</strong>.<br />
<strong>Anyone remember the standards fights from the late 1990s?</strong> Does any of this look at all familiar?<br />
Okay, so let&#8217;s assume that you can develop to some standards. How many authoring tools are you going to need? How many libraries? There&#8217;s <strong>no one consistent authoring tool</strong>, and your developers are going to need some seriously good (and seriously expensive) skills to make it all blend together smoothly.<br />
Now let&#8217;s add in the <strong>added complication of rights management</strong>. Try find that little detail in the HTML5 specs. Go on, take a look, I&#8217;ll wait. Didn&#8217;t see anything? That&#8217;s because it&#8217;s not there. Big Media (read: Dinosaur Media) needs this in their vain attempt to keep their archaic business models creaking forward. <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5461711/giz-explains-why-html5-isnt-going-to-save-the-internet">They need DRM.</a> They need  encryption. They need the stuff built into Flash to keep their delivery systems operating. If for that reason alone, Flash has a long life ahead of it.<br />
I&#8217;m not dancing around here with rose-coloured glasses. <strong>Flash is dying, of that I have no doubts.</strong> As a plug-in solution, its days are numbered. More than likely, it&#8217;ll morph into a development system not unlike Microsoft Studio, where it will be a rich media solution system. What it generates as a final product will depend on the need, supporting different outputs is definitely a possibility.<br />
<strong>But for now, I&#8217;m sticking with Flash.</strong> It&#8217;s helpful, it&#8217;s handy, and it works.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/flash-im-not-dead-yet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2644</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copyrights are the new Colonialism</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Copyrights are the new Colonialism"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The late 16th Century was the dawn of the British Empire. England had triumphed on the seas, and had set its eyes on colonising the New World (before its enemies did). Patents were issued, companies were founded, and flotillas of ships dispatched to every corner &#8212; known and unknown &#8212; of the planet in the name of Queen/King and country. Colonies were born out of determination, slavery, and blood extracted from those too weak to defend themselves from British will.<br />
In time, a phrase was born: The sun never sets on the British Empire. Great Britain&#8217;s influence extended far beyond its native shores, its power unquestionable. A few thrived under the colonial system, but the majority &#8212; the people living under colonial rule &#8212; were marginalised as being little more than the ignorant masses; significant numbers suffered horribly.<br />
It&#8217;s really no wonder that the Empire collapsed under its own weight.<br />
<span id="more-2512"></span>Flash forward now to our present, a world where corporations, not governments, run the world. Oh, sure, we see the laws passed by governments in the interests of its people, but it&#8217;s not the governments creating them. It&#8217;s lobbyists, working on behalf of the corporations. It&#8217;s the corporations funding political careers through donations (legal or otherwise). It&#8217;s the corporations funding large-scale advertising campaigns placing candidates more friendly to their needs into office.<br />
It is these corporations directing the current colonialism: copyrights. Think of these not as the legalese that they are &#8212; instead, think of them as land claims, which were a significant part of the British Empire. A land claim meant you had title to earn money from people who worked your land, and the power to treat them however (un)fairly you wished. If anyone tried to take your land, you were obliged to defend it with as deadly force as you could muster.<br />
Copyrights have been with us &#8212; and have been a controversial topic &#8212; ever since Thag copied Zog&#8217;s cave painting, and Zog hit Thag over the head with a rock. Interestingly, that form of retribution hasn&#8217;t changed much in the roughly 45,000 years since. It&#8217;s been a battle for recognition of ownership, of artistry, and for &#8220;what&#8217;s right&#8221;.<br />
One of the biggest problems is that copyright enforcement hasn&#8217;t been particularly consistent over the years, either. Zog was lucky enough to avoid a complex judicial system. Until the early 1990s, we had to rely mostly on physical presence (namely, you had to buy an actual piece of art). Software copyrights existed, but were poorly enforced, even within large law-abiding corporations. The advance of technology broke the physical barrier, gave people the ability to access materials on their behalf &#8230; and shortly afterwards, gave corporations the ability to know who was breaking their rules.<br />
We saw the first signs of the new colonialism at the turn of the 21st century, when one of the corporations &#8212; the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recording_Industry_Association_of_America">Recording Industry Association of America</a> (RIAA) &#8212; launched what would be come the first of many public and painful lawsuits. Metallica brought the battle into the public eye when they effectively offended the then-denizens of the internet, decrying the &#8220;fair use&#8221; belief held by many (the legality of said perspective notwithstanding). It was the first shot fired in the new independence, the first time that people showed to the world that they wanted things on their terms, not someone else&#8217;s.<br />
The weapon wielded by groups like the RIAA and the MPAA (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion_Picture_Association_of_America">Motion Picture Assocation of America</a>) was not a battle axe or a howitzer, but the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Millennium_Copyright_Act">Digital Millennium Copyright Act</a> &#8212; the DCMA. This law, enacted in the United States of America, implemented two of the treaties agreed upon by WIPO (World Intellectual Property Organization) in 1996. This is how we came to know DRM (Digital Rights Management). They used it <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2003/11/movie-ticket-prices-and-acts-of-piracy/">to guilt us to not copy</a>, and then <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=riaa+lawsuits">slaughter us when we did</a>. The corporations had found legitimacy for their battle through governments.<br />
In theory, this should have worked entirely to the corporation&#8217;s wishes. Within their own borders, the laws were clear, and things went (mostly) according to plan. But they weren&#8217;t so effective in the international reality. Not all countries recognised, or even seemed to care, about other country&#8217;s laws &#8212; and certainly not about the ones that enforced copyrights. Governments were engaged again to help enforce the corporations&#8217; will.<br />
When you have to go up to the biggest kid in the schoolyard and ask for your toy back, all you can do is whine. I imagine &#8220;aw, come on!&#8221; was heard a lot when the United States asked China not to copy software, movies, or CDs. But China opted to give only a token of acceptance &#8212; sort of like giving back only one of the wheels from the Tonka truck. China can do that, because it owns a huge portion of the United States debt, and provides the United States with cheap imports.<br />
Where were the WIPO and the World Trade Organization (WTO) in all of this? Someone&#8217;s got to run world court, right?<br />
But the rules started changing. In the last two years, Canada had to improve its own copyright legislation, also based on DCMA, and driven by the industry &#8212; the corporations &#8212; and not by the people whom the government should represent. The sledgehammer just fell on <a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/4697/125/">Costa Rica: fix your copyrights, or the United States will stop importing sugar</a> (note that coffee and bananas were excluded from the ban).  Lo siento, Costa Rica, but CAFTA/TLC won&#8217;t help you here &#8212; remember, the United States wrote the core of it to benefit themselves.<br />
Costa Rica and Canada are not alone. Dozens of countries are now working on ACTA &#8212; the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2010/01/actas-shameful-secret.ars">Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement &#8212; a virtually secret pact</a> designed to do only one thing: enforce a DCMA-like mandate worldwide. Governments don&#8217;t want to talk about it. The corporations? They&#8217;re smiling like buddhist cows.<br />
Colonialism was best defined when the powerful centre took after its weaker neighbours and opponents. You either fought them, or you joined them.  The colonists in all of this are us, the people. We&#8217;re the ones being handed the royal decrees without benefit of democracy, the ones getting taxation without representation. We&#8217;ll be the ones held in stockades, heads put on pikes, and held up as terrorists to the state (covering for the corporation).<br />
Now lest anyone thing I&#8217;m against copyrights, I&#8217;m not. I respect the creativity needed to make something new, and the need for that artist is duly compensated for their efforts. But I&#8217;m against the inappropriate use of copyrights (and patents, for that matter). When copyrights are flaunted by corporations and not by the artist, it becomes a debate of what&#8217;s more important &#8212; stockholder dividends, or protecting the artist&#8217;s needs?<br />
&#8216;Cuz from what I&#8217;m seeing, another war for independence is coming. But this one will cross nearly every border, involve almost everyone, and probably install a new form of class structure in the process. Suddenly, that remote cabin in the mountains looks a lot more appealing&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/copyrights-are-the-new-colonialism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2512</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WALL-E: What is Disney-Pixar not telling us?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 15:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had an epiphany this morning as I waited for my carpool. I don&#8217;t know why it came to me, it just did. I can&#8217;t even remember how I got onto the thought. But as I stood there, I had the clear vision: There are no old people on the Axiom. I&#8217;ve seen WALL-E now &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "WALL-E: What is Disney-Pixar not telling us?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had an epiphany this morning as I waited for my carpool. I don&#8217;t know why it came to me, it just did. I can&#8217;t even remember how I got onto the thought. But as I stood there, I had the clear vision:<br />
There are no old people on the <em>Axiom</em>.<br />
<span id="more-1933"></span>I&#8217;ve seen <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0910970/">WALL-E</a></em> now about 30 times. That&#8217;s a bit of a guess, mind you. I&#8217;ve seen it not just because it&#8217;s an awesome movie, but because it&#8217;s Monkey&#8217;s favourite thing after the Backyardigans. (She&#8217;ll either ask for &#8220;Ya-yas&#8221; or &#8220;Wally&#8221;, and rarely anything else.) I have no problem when she wants to watch it, so the two of us will sit and watch.<br />
When you watch something enough, you begin to notice little things that had previously escaped notice. And in this case, it came after my mind apparently was chewing away subconsciously. Although Buy &#8216;N Large advertised the Axiom with an eldery woman on a hover chair, 700 years later the <em>Axiom</em> seems devoid of anyone past their 30s. No grey hairs. No wrinkles.<br />
Okay, yes, I&#8217;ll grant you that in their &#8220;big baby&#8221; states, humans might keep their youth longer, but human biology wouldn&#8217;t likely weed out the aging process.<br />
My take?<br />
It&#8217;s a <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074812/">Logan&#8217;s Run</a></em>-meets-<em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070723/">Soylent Green</a></em> thing. When someone turns 30, their hover chair dumps them into into a processor to end up as the next day&#8217;s special.  Seriously! Did you see any greenhouses? Why is all the food ingested through a straw?<br />
Maybe Pixar should make a really cool darker prequel, where the previous captain discovers the truth, and races through the ship on his hover chair, yelling:</p>
<blockquote><p>Stop eating! Your Sexcentennial Cupcake-In-A-Cup is made of people! <em>IT&#8217;S MADE OF PEOPLE!</em></p></blockquote>
<p>They could even use Charleton Heston&#8217;s voice.<br />
C&#8217;mon, it&#8217;d be great.<br />
Come to think of it&#8230; Did anyone see any children or teenagers, either? Hmm&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I think of the new Star Trek movie</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 15:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night, I saw J.J. Abrams&#8217; re-envisioning of Star Trek. It didn&#8217;t suck. But I&#8217;m not about to stand up and laud the praise that so many others had. I&#8217;m not convinced it deserves it (or the #71 ranking in the IMDB&#8217;s Top 250), but it&#8217;s a vast improvement over some of the shlock that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "What I think of the new Star Trek movie"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I saw <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0796366/">J.J. Abrams&#8217; re-envisioning of Star Trek</a>. It didn&#8217;t suck. But I&#8217;m not about to stand up and laud the praise that so many others had. I&#8217;m not convinced it deserves it (or the #71 ranking in the <a href="http://www.imdb.com/chart/top?tt0796366">IMDB&#8217;s Top 250</a>), but it&#8217;s a vast improvement over some of the shlock that Star Trek movies have been of late.  <br />
I went in, admittedly, with higher than normal expectations (press is hard to ignore entirely, and even <a href="http://wilwheaton.typepad.com/wwdnbackup/2009/05/geek-in-review-star-trek-has-been-reborn-and-it-is-spectacular.html">Wil Wheaton claimed it was awesome</a>). So there is a certain amount of disappointment. But now that I&#8217;ve had time to ruminate on the film, the plot, the acting, etc., I&#8217;d like to think I&#8217;ve got a decent view.  <br />
And for those of you who haven&#8217;t seen the movie: Beware! <strong>Thar be spoilers ahead!</strong><br />
<span id="more-1363"></span>Okay, first off, let&#8217;s cover all the stuff that J.J. Abrams + Co. did (very) well:  </p>
<ul>
<li>Casting was spot-on. Excellent choices, there were the right people doing the right roles. Pine was an excellent young, rebellious, and a sooner-than-TOS captain (read: more brash, more in-your-face). Quinto might as well be Nimoy&#8217;s actual son for his ability to look like a young Spock.</li>
<li>Acting was well-suited. A few people have called out Urban&#8217;s portrayal of Bones McCoy as being a bit &#8220;odd&#8221;, but the more I think about it, the more I actually like his mildly pissed-off, slightly backwater personality. I&#8217;m curious to see how he and Spock pit themselves together in successive movies (yes, I&#8217;m assuming sequels).</li>
<li>Special effects done exceptionally well. Gone are the days of models (which I lament), but the CG executed in the movie is very good, almost seamless in some places. The collapsing Vulcan was oustanding.</li>
<li>Many excellent references to previous movies and series episodes, for those of you paying attention.  </li>
<li>Sulu still fences, but he has a switch-blade katana, and saves Kirk&#8217;s life.  </li>
<li>Star Trek finally adopts the &#8220;used universe&#8221; for its sets. Using a brewery for the inside of a massive ship was a brilliant stroke of genius, as it made the ship look more &#8220;real&#8221;. (Although because I knew it was a brewery, I couldn&#8217;t quite get into the fact that it was supposed to be a starship.)</li>
<li>The introduction of the alternate reality.  </li>
</ul>
<p>I want to focus on that last point for a moment. This bugged me at first, but then I not only saw the wisdom in this decision, but also came to praise the breaking from pattern that came with it. In the movie (<strong>SPOILER ALERT</strong>), an event 129 years in the future creates a black hole through which Nero (the bad guy) and the Original Spock (Nimoy) get sucked back in time. This creates an alternate reality (which is actually acknowledged by the characters in the movie) where things do not follow the previous Star Trek canon.  <br />
Namely, the planet Vulcan and most of the Vulcan civilisation is destroyed.  <br />
In pretty much every previous incarnation of Star Trek, some event occurs in the course of the given episode/movie that allows the regular timeline to be returned to normal. But Abrams and crew deliberately avoided hitting the &#8220;Reset Button&#8221; (<a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Voyager">Star Trek: Voyager</a>, I&#8217;m looking at you!). Result? Uhuru and Spock are love interests, Vulcan is still destroyed, Kirk is a captain much earlier than in the regular timeline, and the technology is more advanced that it would be normally (though this pattern was started with <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek:_Enterprise">Star Trek: Enterprise</a>).  <br />
What does this mean? It means Abrams (and future Star Trek movie makers) are not tied to the previous canon, and are free to create some of their own. We&#8217;ll likely see certain characters return, albeit slightly different, and some characters may never enter the new world (it&#8217;s possible we&#8217;ll never meet <a href="http://khaaaaaaan.ytmnd.com/">KHAAAAAAAAAAAAAAN</a>!).<br />
The other thing it means is it (mostly) shortcuts all the nitpickers. Trekkies and Trekkers alike are nitpickers. They love tearing apart episodes and movies for continuity errors, plot issues, scientific problems, acting (especially important given the brand new cast), and gaffes. Because of the alternate reality, they can&#8217;t start claiming that something isn&#8217;t canon, or that a character wouldn&#8217;t do X, or that the planet Vulcan was never destroyed.  <br />
I say &#8220;mostly&#8221;. Because there are some problems with the movie, too, that transcend the alternate reality. Remember, I&#8217;m a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/?s=reformed+trekkie">reformed Trekkie</a>, which also makes me a nitpicker.  </p>
<ul>
<li>Supernovae destroy solar systems, not whole galaxies. That&#8217;s a pretty damned big plot hole to have, as it negates the events that lead up to the alternate reality being created in the first place.  </li>
<li>Last I checked, anything &#8212; even a speck of dust &#8212; that enters a planetary atmosphere will start to heat up from friction (hence shooting stars). Yet Kirk, Sulu, and the ill-fated-red-shirt Olsen all &#8220;space dive&#8221; without ill effect.  </li>
<li>Kirk is promoted to captain (from an officer cadet with no serving experience) after receiving a commendation for his actions in the movie. Spock, a &#8220;distinguished graduate&#8221; already holding the rank of Commander, who literally puts his life on the line (was mere heatbeats from colliding the small ship he was piloting into Nero&#8217;s ship to stop an attack), is apparently overlooked entirely and made subservient to someone who&#8217;s barely graduated the academy. I&#8217;m all for the Kirk/Spock relationship thing, but I&#8217;m having some trouble with this one.</li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s a new world for Star Trek, and Abrams&#8217; approach to setting up that new world was done (mostly) wisely. For an odd-numbered Star Trek movie, it&#8217;s also pretty good (the only other exception being <a href="http://memory-alpha.org/en/wiki/Star_Trek_III:_The_Search_for_Spock">Star Trek III: The Search For Spock</a>, which I like mostly due to Christopher Lloyd&#8217;s Kruge). But it definitely doesn&#8217;t top the charts for me. I think it sets a good precedent, though, and I am eager to see what they can come up with next.<br />
May the new Trek live long and prosper!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/05/what-i-think-of-the-new-star-trek-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A few of my favourite movies</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/03/a-few-of-my-favourite-movies/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-few-of-my-favourite-movies</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/03/a-few-of-my-favourite-movies/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 05:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve had a lot of people ask me over the years what movies I have in my Top 10 (or Top 5 or Top 3) list. There&#8217;s a lot of good movies out there, and a number of them definitely get listed among my favourites.   But make no mistake, I have no actual Top &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/03/a-few-of-my-favourite-movies/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A few of my favourite movies"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had a lot of people ask me over the years what movies I have in my Top 10 (or Top 5 or Top 3) list. There&#8217;s a lot of good movies out there, and a number of them definitely get listed among my favourites.  <br />
But make no mistake, I have no actual Top Whatever list. I rarely ever rank movies because that suggests that I place one movie over another. Which I don&#8217;t and can&#8217;t. There are some movies I watch because I&#8217;m simply in the mood to watch them. Others remain special for me, even if I haven&#8217;t watched them in a long time.  <br />
The key thing of every movie in this list: I&#8217;ll watch it if I see it on TV, and if someone hands me the DVD, I&#8217;ll be happy to sit down to watch without a second thought.  <br />
And now, in no particular order&#8230;</p>
<h3><span id="more-1260"></span><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0095016/">Die Hard</a></h3>
<p>(This appears first because I&#8217;m watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099423/"><em>Die Hard 2</em></a> at the moment.) Not only was Die Hard the prototype for the &#8220;ordinary guy caught in extraordinary circumstances&#8221;, it made <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000246/">Bruce Willis</a> a movie star. The second movie, though not as good as the first movie, still holds its own as an action movie. The third &#8212; <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112864/"><em>Die Hard With A Vengeance</em></a> &#8212; could very easily hold a position in this list on its own. I&#8217;m not totally thrilled with <em>Live Free or Die Hard</em>. It&#8217;s a good movie, but I don&#8217;t think it quite holds up to the first three.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099810/">The Hunt for Red October</a></h3>
<p>I still remember the first time I saw this movie in the theatres. Not only does it have excellent pacing, good special effects, solid dialog, but it has the best hair <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000125/">Sean Connery</a> has in his post-Bond work. The last 30 minutes of the movie are so well-executed that I totally forgot the popcorn I had been eating during the movie. If I had an actual Top 3 list, this would likely be in it.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120616/">The Mummy</a></h3>
<p>A lot of people look at The Mummy as a big ball o&#8217; fluff: no substance, nothing special. But this movie &#8212; and its first sequel, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0209163/"><em>The Mummy Returns</em></a><em> </em>(the second sequel, <em>Tomb of the Dragon Emperor</em>, was an utter waste) &#8212; are pure fun. These are the kind of movies that <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000409/">Brendan Fraser</a> does well &#8212; they suit his style of bravado and self-mockery. (That, and the first two feature <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001838/">Rachel Weisz</a>.) These are not movies that invoke thought &#8212; they allow you to sink into campy fun, not unlike the Indiana Jones movies. Speaking of which&#8230;</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/find?s=all&amp;q=indiana+jones">Indiana Jones</a></h3>
<p>I grew up to these movies, and it was a very happy day when I realised that, yes, classic movies were being made in my lifetime. The first three movies are cinema gold for me, supplying that sense of adventure that only comes from serial-inpired plots, characters, and dialog. (I have yet to see <em>Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</em>, however.)  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/find?s=all&amp;q=star+wars">Star Wars</a> (Eps 4-6)</h3>
<p>Here we enter the dilemma. I need not reason why <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076759/">Episodes 4 (<em>A New Hope</em>)</a> and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080684/">5 (<em>The Empire Strikes Back</em>)</a> are on this list. If you&#8217;re not sure why, go watch the damn movies. I include <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0086190/">Episode 6 (<em>The Return of the Jedi</em>)</a> because it does a nice job wrapping up the original trilogy, even if the Ewoks are a little irritating. However, I do not include the three prequels because, as a collected group, they are far inferior to the original trilogy. Technically, I could include <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0121766/">Episode 3   (<em>Revenge of the Sith</em>)</a> as it is a good movie, but then I have to acknowledge the bantha poodoo that are Episodes 1 and 2.  <br />
The big dilemma? What will I show my children &#8212; the entire saga, or start with just <em>A New Hope</em>? (This is a question friends of mine and I have debated for a while.) My answer: just the original trilogy. I&#8217;ll certainly allow my kids to watch the first three, but with the caveat that it&#8217;ll possibly ruin the original trilogy.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084726/">Star Trek II</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092007/">IV</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102975/">VI</a>, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117731/">First Contact</a></h3>
<p>You&#8217;ll note that I&#8217;m leaving out several of the Star Trek movies. I leave them out because they&#8217;re inferior. Grossly so, in some cases (*cough* Star Trek V *cough*). For me, these are the classics, and Star Trek II stands above them all as one of the finest pieces of science-fiction filmmaking. It is, quite simply put, nearly perfect as a movie.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120737/">The Lord of the Rings</a></h3>
<p>In principle, this is a trilogy. In reality, it&#8217;s a 12 hour epic that&#8217;s been conveniently cut into three pieces to allow easier viewing. If you view it only on the herculean effort it took to make the movie, the leap of faith it took from the production companies to willing make it into three movies (instead of one). While I will watch any of the three (even out of sequence) willingly, I really do need the time &#8212; the shortest of the three is 3 hours and 28 minutes.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0258463/">The Bourne Identity</a></h3>
<p>I&#8217;m a sucker for spy movies. Always loved them, and I&#8217;m not really sure why. Either way, the premise has always fascinated me. While Bourne himself isn&#8217;t a spy per se (he&#8217;s an assassin), it&#8217;s still along the same lines. The action is solid, and it has some of the best vehicular action scenes in recent movies.   No, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000354/">Matt Damon</a>  is not the best actor, and his performance can be criticised as being a little two-dimensional. But I also think that&#8217;s what makes the character work a bit more &#8212; Jason Bourne doesn&#8217;t have a lot of substance, since he doesn&#8217;t even exist.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/find?s=all&amp;q=james+bond">James Bond</a></h3>
<p>Like I said, I&#8217;m a sucker for spy movies. And I&#8217;d be remiss to mention the James Bond series. And yes, I still think <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000125/">Sean Connery</a> makes the best Bond. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0058150/"><em>Goldfinger</em></a><em> </em>rides very high on the list as my favourite. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001096/">Timothy Dalton</a>, sadly, rides lowest on my list for best Bond. And while I think <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0185819/">Daniel Craig</a> has far exceeded all expectations of being an adequate James Bond, the latest Bond movie &#8212; <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1139644/"><em>Quantum of Solace</em></a><em> </em>&#8212; isn&#8217;t really a James Bond movie. It&#8217;s a (damn good) spy action flick with some Bond elements.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0317705/">The Incredibles</a></h3>
<p>Possibly <a href="http://www.imdb.com/company/co0017902/">Pixar</a>&#8216;s best movie, even considering <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0910970/"><em>Wall-E</em></a>. Excellent story, great voice action, amazing soundtrack, and they were willing to put the time in to tell the story as it needed to be told, and not cut it short. That said, I put pretty much any Pixar movie in with <em>The Incredibles</em>, and am willing to watch pretty much any of them without so much as a second thought.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090728/">Big Trouble in Little China</a></h3>
<p>This is one of those classic cult movies from my teenage years. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000621/">Kurt Russell</a> in one of his best roles, playing a totally campy, over-the-top egotistical, bombastic buffoon who yet somehow still turns out to be a hero. It&#8217;s all in the reflexes.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106308/">Army of Darkness</a></h3>
<p>When my friend Chris took me to see Army of Darkness when we lived in Ottawa, I&#8217;d never heard of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0132257/">Bruce Campbell</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000600/">Sam Raimi</a>, or <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0083907/"><em>The Evil Dead</em></a>. We saw the movie three times that week, and by the end were quoting lines along with over half the audience. We&#8217;d quote lines for another 3 months afterwards. And still do.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120591/">Armageddon</a></h3>
<p>A lot of people give me grief for this one. It&#8217;s too American flag-waving, it&#8217;s too silly, too unrealistic, too bla bla bla. I&#8217;ll tell you what this movie is: pure fun. It&#8217;s 2 hours of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000881/">Michael Bay</a> at his best when it comes to glorious camera angles, cinematography (the sequences towards the end of the movie are stunning), and the characterisations are nearly perfect. Incidentally, most Michael Bay movies fall into this category, including <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112442/"><em>Bad Boys</em> I</a> and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0172156/"><em>II</em></a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117500/"><em>The Rock</em></a>, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0418279/"><em>Transformers</em></a>. But not <em>Pearl Harbor</em>. Sorry, Mikey, but I can&#8217;t hack that one.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057115/">The Great Escape</a></h3>
<p>One of the <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000537/">Steve McQueen</a> classics. A fictional version of a true story, it&#8217;s a beautifully-told story, combined with comedy, drama, and a bit of action. Even though McQueen went diva during production (where do you think the motorcycle sequences came from?), the end result is still and endlessly-watchable film. In a similar vein is <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050212/"><em>Bridge On The River Kwai</em></a>, though that one I don&#8217;t watch as much, mostly because I think of the lack of comedic sequences.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120611/">Blade</a></h3>
<p>First off, I love vampire movies. I have for years. I can watch all manners of vampire movies without much pause. <em>Blade </em>in particular is a wonderful movie because of the Blade character, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000648/">Wesley Snipes</a>&#8216; portrayal. I don&#8217;t dig the sequels as much, though I&#8217;ll watch <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0187738/"><em>Blade II</em></a><em> </em>fairly readily. I won&#8217;t touch <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0359013/"><em>Blade: Trinity</em></a><em> </em>&#8212; there&#8217;s a number of plot points that bug the crap out of me, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005351/">Ryan Reynolds</a>&#8216; character is just plain annoying.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0320691/">Underworld</a></h3>
<p>See above note about vampires. (The same applies to werewolves, for the record.) Add to that <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000295/">Kate Beckinsale</a> in skin-tight leather and laytex. Um. Yeah. That makes up for stinkload of acting issues (someone tell me how <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005454/">Scott Speedman</a> keeps getting major roles?) and plot issues. Same applies for <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0401855/"><em>Underworld Evolution</em></a>. (I haven&#8217;t seen <em>Rise of the Lycans </em>yet, however.)</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0137523/">Fight Club</a></h3>
<p>The first rule of <em>Fight Club </em>is &#8230; tell everyone to watch the movie. I&#8217;ve said this many times, but <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000093/">Brad Pitt</a> needs to do roles where he has a slight out-of-balance character, otherwise he&#8217;s just window dressing and really dull to watch. This is a movie where he excels, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001570/">Edward Norton</a> really balances out the roles. That, and when I first saw this movie, I really identified with Edward Norton&#8217;s character.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112384/">Apollo 13</a></h3>
<p>I was fascinated with space every since I was a kid, so I knew the story of Apollo 13 before the movie was made. But there&#8217;s the documentary version of the story, and then there&#8217;s Hollywood&#8217;s version. And frankly, accuracy notwithstanding, I much prefer this telling. It&#8217;s not a significant difference &#8212; it&#8217;s the little things that make it truly sing.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0211915/">Amélie (Le Fabuleux destin d&#8217;Amélie Poulain)</a></h3>
<p>If I had a Top 3 list of movies, this would be in it. And not just because <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0851582/">Audrey Tatou</a> creates perhaps the single cutest character in the history of filmmaking. It&#8217;s because of the story it tells &#8212; the need to help people find balance, the need for one to find the perfect love, and the playfulness one can find in life. The only thing I wish this movie had is complete English subtitles on the DVD release &#8212; they&#8217;re crap, and my French is still too weak to handle the movie without them.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120917/">Emperor&#8217;s New Groove</a></h3>
<p>I didn&#8217;t see this in the theatres, but bought the special edition DVD on a whim. I watched it that afternoon with Chris, Calvin, Doug, Adrian, and a couple of other friends, and we all nearly pissed ourselves laughing. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0457755/">Eartha Kitt</a> creates &#8212; without any doubt or question &#8212; the best Disney villian. She was a perfect voice actor, and her loss is a dreadful shame on the industry for not using her more.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/find?s=all&amp;q=wallace+and+gromit">Wallace and Gromit</a></h3>
<p>This (currently) comprises four films: the three shorts (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0104361/"><em>A Grand Day Out</em></a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108598/"><em>The Wrong Trousers</em></a>, and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112691/"><em>A Close Shave</em></a>) and the full-length feature film (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0312004/"><em>The Curse of the Were-Rabbit</em></a>). I was introduced to Wallace and Gromit by my friends Brenda and Marek when I was working in Toronto back in the mid-late 1990s, and have loved them ever since.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0401792/">Sin City</a></h3>
<p>Aside from the fact that I love <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001675/">Robert Rodriguez</a>&#8216;s films to begin with, this is one of those opus works that will be hard for Robert to outdo. (Though I eagerly await the chance that he might.) It&#8217;s a tough movie to have filmed, and the resulting work is outstanding. It&#8217;s exceedingly violent, so it&#8217;s a movie I need to watch on my own, or at least with someone who also loves the movie.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133093/">The Matrix</a></h3>
<p>The original Matrix movie was a ground-breaker. I still remember walking into the theatre with my coworkers from Radical Entertainment, thinking I wasn&#8217;t going to like it. It was a Keanu movie, after all, and I didn&#8217;t have a heap of faith given that the trailers didn&#8217;t really say much. My eyebrows raised when Trinity did that first bullet-time leap at the beginning, and I was sold when Neo wakes up in the power tower. After that, I was all over it. And while I do <em>accept </em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/"><em>Matrix Reloaded</em></a><em> </em>and <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0242653/"><em>Matrix Revolutions</em></a><em> </em>as sequels, there were a number of issues I saw that prevented them from ever equalling the original.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080339/">Airplane!</a></h3>
<p>I am serious. And don&#8217;t call me &#8220;Shirley&#8221;. It&#8217;s a real classic. I could watch this movie repeated for a week and still laugh at it. It gets better with age.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0083658/">Blade Runner</a></h3>
<p>I&#8217;m still not sure which version I like more. Although the Director&#8217;s Cut is extremely good, there is something about the voiceovers I&#8217;ve always liked.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/">Batman Begins</a> / <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/">The Dark Knight</a></h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t separate these movies for two simple reasons: First, they both did extremely good jobs at making Batman &#8220;real&#8221;, and <em>The Dark Knight </em>made The Joker into a villian worth of an Oscar performance. Second, because there&#8217;s enough intelligence that it&#8217;s not just fluff. One day, I&#8217;ll convince Alex to watch them. I hope&#8230;</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0325980/">Pirates of the Caribbean</a></h3>
<p>Two words: Jack Sparrow. I could give a crap about Will Turner, myself. (I could almost not care about Elizabeth Swann, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that it&#8217;s <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0461136/">Kiera Knightley</a>.) Performances in this movie redefined the pirate genre for me. I remember the first time I saw the movie, when my friend Adrian and I weren&#8217;t entirely certain if it would be any good, but didn&#8217;t care. Afterwards, we couldn&#8217;t stop talking like pirates, much to our friends&#8217; annoyance.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0245429/">Spirited Away</a></h3>
<p>Before I get too much into this movie, I pretty much include anything made by <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0594503/">Hayao Miyazaki</a>. The man is a genius when it comes to story-telling, and his artwork is utterly fantastic. This, in my opinion, is his best work. Story-telling aside, I think it really brings out some of the great parts of Japanese mysticism, the needs of children to know when to grow up, and even a nice little view on the evils of greed.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0151804/">Office Space</a></h3>
<p>Anyone who&#8217;s ever worked in an office laughs at this movie. It&#8217;s hard not to. It&#8217;s brilliantly-written and performed. About the only wrong thing with it is Jennifer Aniston &#8212; I&#8217;m not entirely sure why she&#8217;s in the movie. It could be any other actress and it would be just as good.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0122690/">Ronin</a></h3>
<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001239/">John Frankenheimer</a> left us the best cinematic car chases ever filmed. Yes, even better <em>than </em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0062765/"><em>Bullitt</em></a>. It&#8217;s a complex story, and the MacGuffin actually gets distracting. Some people don&#8217;t like it on the first watch. But watch it two or three times, and you&#8217;ll see what an excellent piece of work it really is.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0240772/">Ocean&#8217;s Eleven</a></h3>
<p>Not the Sinatra version &#8212; I mean the 2001 &#8220;remake&#8221; with <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000123/">George Clooney</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000093/">Brad Pitt</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000332/">Don Cheadle</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000354/">Matt Damon</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005348/">Carl Reiner</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001285/">Elliott Gould</a>, etc. Aside from the fact that it&#8217;s a heist movie (and I love heist movies), it is the definition of &#8220;cool&#8221; in filmmaking. I don&#8217;t mean &#8220;cool&#8221; as in &#8220;boy, isn&#8217;t that cool&#8221;, but in being suave, collected, having an amazing attitude and behaviour. If I had a Top 3, this would likely be in it.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071853/">Monty Python and the Holy Grail</a></h3>
<p>I went to the <a href="http://www.uwaterloo.ca/">University of Waterloo</a>. If there were an official movie for the school, this would be it. When I was there, it was shown regularly in the Campus Centre, and pretty much every residence on any given weekend. It was an unwritten requirements to be able to quote most of the major scenes, especially if you were in the Mathematics faculty.  </p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0434409/">V for Vendetta</a></h3>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Moore">Alan Moore</a> might be a whiny little twit about this movie (if you&#8217;re going to whine about how people interpret your work, don&#8217;t sell the right in the first place), but I felt this was beautifully executed. I think when I die, I want my corpse detonated to the <em>1812 Overture</em>. And I&#8217;m amazed at <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000204/">Natalie Portman</a>&#8216;s English accent.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111161/">The Shawshank Redemption</a></h3>
<p>This is a bit of a weird one for me. Not in that it&#8217;s not an outstanding movie (it&#8217;s been at the top of the IMDB lists for years), but in that it&#8217;s a movie I own, but I&#8217;ve not gotten around to watching on DVD. Yet I&#8217;ve watched the movie about two dozen times on TV. There are few perfect movies out there, this would be one of them.</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0162661/">Sleepy Hollow</a></h3>
<p>I&#8217;ll watch nearly any <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000318/">Tim Burton</a> movie without a second thought, but this one in particular stands out for it&#8217;s characterisations (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000136/">Johnny Depp</a> is a brilliant actor, no two ways about it) and it&#8217;s sheer creepiness (the adaptation of the story is very intelligent). And it&#8217;s got <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000207/">Christina Ricci</a>. I mean, c&#8217;mon&#8230;</p>
<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0208092/">Snatch</a></h3>
<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0208092/">Guy Ritchie</a> makes a good movie, especially a good heist movie. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005458/">Jason Statham</a> might be no Shakespearean thespian, but he delivers probably the best performance (so far) of his career. That, and it&#8217;s one of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000093/">Brad Pitt</a>&#8216;s weirdest roles (which thusly makes it one of his best, as well). There&#8217;s not a single &#8220;good&#8221; character in the entire movie, which is why it&#8217;s just plain dirty fun.  </p>
<h3>Hey, what about&#8230;?</h3>
<p>Yes, there&#8217;s a whack of other movies that could easily be in this list. There&#8217;s even a few I cut out (<em>The Fifth Element</em>, <em>The Muppet Movie</em>, <em>The Princess Bride</em>, to name but a few) that nearly made the grade, but were dropped for one reason:  <br />
When I made this list, and flipped through my pile of DVDs, I zipped past them without a thought. That for me suggests that they&#8217;re as watchable as the others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/03/a-few-of-my-favourite-movies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1260</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
