<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>friends &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/friends/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:58:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Catching up with a few Radical friends</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/catching-up-with-a-few-radical-friends/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=catching-up-with-a-few-radical-friends</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/catching-up-with-a-few-radical-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radical Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not long after our trip out to the Lower Mainland entered the books, I hit up some old friends of mine through Twitter, to see if they&#8217;d be interested in a get-together. I hadn&#8217;t actually seen some of them in over a decade (even Joel I hadn&#8217;t seen in at least three years), and it &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/catching-up-with-a-few-radical-friends/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Catching up with a few Radical friends"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not long after our trip out to the Lower Mainland entered the books, I hit up some old friends of mine through Twitter, to see if they&#8217;d be interested in a get-together. I hadn&#8217;t actually seen some of them in over a decade (even Joel I hadn&#8217;t seen in at least three years), and it just seemed a perfect thing to do.<br />
Twitter has become a perfect way of bringing people together. Just as last year, when I <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/">met up with my old friend Sonny</a>, I&#8217;m finding Twitter to be an intensively useful tool to meet up with friends long-unseen. In this case, it became a catalyst, and we dragged in a non-Twitterer while we were at it.<br />
And it was a good evening, however short.<br />
<span id="more-2816"></span>I&#8217;m on vacation, but the others aren&#8217;t &#8212; they have to work. So the plan was to meet at <a href="http://www.thewhiprestaurant.com/">The Whip</a> on E 6th (just off of Main St.) for 18:30. That gave Alex and I time to do a little visit of our own, out to Granville Island. Leaving Monkey with the grandparents (Choo Choo had to come with us), we trucked our way from Ruskin down to False Creek.<br />
We stopped along the way at the Toys &#8216;R Us in Coquitlam to find a Jessie the Yodeling Cowgirl doll for Monkey, as this was what Santa was supposed to bring. Jessie, it seems, is a lesser object of desire when it comes to co-marketing, and we hadn&#8217;t capitalised on our sole opportunity. The Toys &#8216;R Us store was devoid of anything Jessie-related, meaning one little girl would be wondering why Santa was such a yutz. Alex and I started formulating backup plans.<br />
The remainder of the trip was met mostly by construction, which seems to permeate the Vancouver area. Given the Olympics were only earlier this year, I&#8217;m rather surprised to see so much. One would think the public coffers were rather dry by now. But the improvements are plainly needed.<br />
The aforementioned Olympic improvements also threw me for a loop. My old memory of driving around the east end of False Creek were thrown off by the road realignments for the Olympic Village. It took a couple of detours before we finally found the entrance to Granville Island.<br />
Our first stop (after parking) was to the Kids Market, one of the buildings that is packed to the brim with perfect toys (and by perfect, I mean ones that don&#8217;t need batteries, and aren&#8217;t all made in China) &#8230; but no Jessie doll. Still, we spent nearly an hour just looking around, wishing that Monkey had come with us after all.<br />
Then we wandered around the various streets, looking into shop windows, my mind racing back to the days when I plodded the same streets as a resident of Vancouver, and not a visitor. Reaching the west end of the island, I found myself looking out onto False Creek, across to the towering glass walls of the West End condos, and the lighted arches of Burrard Bridge. The smell of the sea almost seemed to dance over my soft palate.<br />
[flickr]photo:5285102766[/flickr] [flickr]photo:5285102346[/flickr]<br />
We went inside the Granville Island Market. If you&#8217;ve ever had a smell trigger a powerful memory, you know how disorienting it can be. I almost tripped. Immediately, I remembered why &#8212; as much as I loved the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market &#8212; I always felt it was lacking. The Granville Island Market is the prototype, I think, and sets the benchmark. I loved it then, and I&#8217;m pretty sure I still do, even though it&#8217;s gone a little more yuppie in the last decade.<br />
Running low on free time, we headed back to the car and found our way out to The Whip, a neat little restaurant just off of Main St. There we waited for my friends to arrive. Katrina was the first, and even in the dimmed light, she looked almost exactly the same as she had the last time I&#8217;d seen her, when I&#8217;d made a short visit to Vancouver in December of 2000.<br />
Katrina is, with little question, one of the smartest people I know, without all that annoying &#8220;know it all&#8221; baggage that often accompanies such intelligence. She&#8217;s instantly personable, and is one of the people I missed most when I left Vancouver. She sat nearest to me at <a href="http://www.radical.ca/">Radical Entertainment</a>&#8216;s old offices in Yaletown, and was a mean Worms player. That, and I&#8217;m intensely jealous that she&#8217;s worked at Pixar.<br />
Lee was next. Lee picked The Whip for us, and I wasn&#8217;t the only one to think that The Whip was very &#8220;Lee&#8221;. Lee had been the QA lead at Radical, as well as our softball team&#8217;s coach. One of my earliest memories of her was actually a bio that had been made for a magazine (I think) that included a fact that read:</p>
<blockquote><p>Number of piercings: 25<br />
Number of piercings above the neck: 16</p></blockquote>
<p>(Numbers are totally approximate to my memory, which is often famously bad with numbers &#8230; but we&#8217;ll leave it at &#8220;a lot&#8221; of piercings.)<br />
Lee&#8217;s piercings (visible, anyway) have taken a serious nosedive over the years, and I was rather stunned at the lack. And she explained the origin of her Twitter handle, <a href="http://twitter.com/squirrelbaffle">squirrelbaffle</a>. It does, believe it or not, actually have to do with squirrels. (Incidentally, I recommend following Lee, if only because her tweets are often hilarious.)<br />
Neall rolled in shortly afterwards. Neall is exactly one day older than me, which is a point I&#8217;ve tried to use every year (though I can&#8217;t claim to be wholly consistent on it). Neall sat in the same room as I did, against the window, and regularly scared the bejezus outta me. Not in that he was frightening, but in his demonstration of skill. That, and his tendencies to overhaul his cars to the point of near self-destruction (the cars, not himself) on epic proportions.<br />
Katrina, Neall, and I worked in a group called Pure3D, which created and maintained the 3D rendering engine used in Radical&#8217;s games. It was a complex and powerful library that allowed the game teams to focus on the important parts of the game &#8212; namely the gameplay and how it looked &#8212; and ignore the tedious stuff that made the game actually work.<br />
I wasn&#8217;t involved with the coding. I wasn&#8217;t then, now, or ever will be good enough to code like them. Whenever other developers, especially in my current industry, tell me that they&#8217;re good programmers (or know good programmers), I usually scoff and tell them about the Pure3D. I tell them how they&#8217;d code inline assembler into C functions from memory. Or how they&#8217;d spin out conversion tools that made use of 3D matrices without cracking a single textbook. There was a guy (Mark) who had a masters in puzzles, and took perverse pleasure in leaving mind-bending puzzles on our desks from time to time. They are, still to this day, the smartest group of people I&#8217;ve ever had the extreme good fortune to work with. (Me? I wrote software manuals.)<br />
Joel was the last to arrive. I still owe Joel a debt of gratitude for helping me move out of Vancouver all those years ago (that was a very different time for me). He now runs another gaming company with some other ex-Radicalites, but back in our Radical days he worked on a special project, building a plugin for Maya that allowed artists to use h-splines to create models.<a href="http://www.cs.ubc.ca/nest/imager/contributions/forsey/dragon/hbsplines.html"> Never heard of an h-spline?</a> Yeah, neither had I. Frankly, I&#8217;m kind of surprised they haven&#8217;t taken off. My favourite memory of Joel was walking into the Rodin team&#8217;s room (&#8220;Rodin&#8221; was the name of the plugin) and finding Joel and teammate Jean-Luc taste-testing a line of thoroughly evil-looking hot sauces, using words such as &#8220;smoky&#8221; and &#8220;peppery&#8221;, rather than gasping for air and clutching at his throat as it burned apart from the inside.<br />
Stories. We had lots of them. Although some of us had kept in loose touch (Lee and Neall more than most), we all had our individual histories to cross over &#8212; what had we done, where had we gone, what was &#8220;new&#8221; (and notably, what was recent), and of course talk about the old days at Radical. Radical&#8217;s no longer the company I left, of course. Years of change will always do that. It&#8217;s inevitable. When I was there, Radical was privately-owned. Today, it&#8217;s a subsidiary of Activision Blizzard, and &#8212; so it seems &#8212; a shadow of its former self. Most of the originals are gone, with only a handful remaining that I still know.<br />
I could have stayed at that table and chatted all night, if they&#8217;d have let me. But it was Choo Choo who called an end for me, declaring that she&#8217;d had enough, dear Daddy, and please take me home. It was hard to leave, hard to say goodbye again. But it felt good &#8212; very, very good &#8212; to see them again, even if just for a short while. To remember, to laugh, and to share.<br />
[flickr]photo:5282239778[/flickr]<br />
It&#8217;s nearly an hour to drive from downtown Vancouver to Ruskin. Our trip was over three hours, but not for any reason other than Santa-driven necessity. The Toys &#8216;R Us on Broadway offered nothing new. Oddly enough, the Superstore at Metrotown in Burnaby ended up our saviour, even if it isn&#8217;t exactly the doll we&#8217;d hoped to get. We wanted something simple and cloth. We got plastic and electronic. At this point, any doll would suffice, so long as it was Jessie.<br />
Then, putting my poor map memory to work, I got us lost in Surrey, rather than finding the right route back to Highway 7. It was Alex that steered us right again, and put the GPS to work to get us back out to Highway 1, and then onto the new Golden Ears toll bridge. (There&#8217;s nothing as fun as listening to a GPS go berserk trying to recalculate a path when you&#8217;re on a road that it doesn&#8217;t know about, perched overtop a wide river.)<br />
Tomorrow, we&#8217;re going to the North Pole&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/catching-up-with-a-few-radical-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2816</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RIP: Sean Lineham</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=rip-sean-lineham</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 02:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rolex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I arrived back in Costa Rica with my family in tow. Little did I know that my &#8220;other&#8221; family &#8212; my friends and colleagues back in Calgary, were facing quite the tragedy. I found out no sooner than I turned on my computer to send a quick note to my partners here in Costa &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "RIP: Sean Lineham"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I arrived back in Costa Rica with my family in tow. Little did I know that my &#8220;other&#8221; family &#8212; my friends and colleagues back in Calgary, were facing quite the tragedy. I found out no sooner than I turned on my computer to send a quick note to my partners here in Costa Rica (remember, I have no phone with which to call them), and I got an IM request from Dave. All he said was: &#8220;Call me. Urgent.&#8221;<br />
It would appear that my friend, colleague, and fellow watch geek (though I could never ascribe to the level he attained) Sean Lineham passed away last night.<br />
<span id="more-1023"></span>Needless to say, I was shocked. It&#8217;s never easy to hear that a friend has died. It&#8217;s even harder when there seemed to be no warning. No chance to say anything, no opportunity to change the outcome.<br />
I can&#8217;t imagine how hard it must be for my old team back up in Calgary. Sean was a core part of the Rolex team, and was the heart of knowing all there was to know about watches. And since his switch to I&amp;P, he was the guy we bugged to figure out our next directions with technology. His enthusiasm and joy about the things we did were tangible at every moment. It is a terribly sad loss to lose that kind of energy.<br />
Farewell, Sean. May you find peace, and with luck our paths may cross again in this strange little universe.<br />
Here&#8217;s to you Sean!<br />
[flickr]photo:2299900469(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/rip-sean-lineham/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Was Benno</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/i-was-benno/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-was-benno</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/i-was-benno/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 04:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/31/i-was-benno/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, I had a truly moving experience. I watched a movie. Not just any movie, but an experimental film created by a friend. A movie with a message (unlike much of the shlock that comes out of Hollywood). The message is universal, and I think everyone who watched the movie could see it. It was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/i-was-benno/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I Was Benno"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I had a truly moving experience. I watched a movie. Not just any movie, but an experimental film created by a friend. A movie with a message (unlike much of the shlock that comes out of Hollywood). The message is universal, and I think everyone who watched the movie could see it.<br />
It was particularly important because the movie was about my friend. A journey beyond his regular life, to find if there was more to himself than what he had here in Calgary.<br />
<span id="more-854"></span>I&#8217;ve known Masanori Benno almost since the day I started at Critical Mass some seven and a half years ago. Benno, as most people call him, was the creative lead on my first project. He&#8217;s one of the most senior people at Critical Mass, having tenure of over a decade. And those long years take their toll.<br />
The movie, titled <em>I Was Benno</em>, opens with Benno tell you about himself, his job, his home, the people he knows, the city he lives in. How all of these things, and the things he&#8217;s done, define himself. As he put it, his glass is full of experiences. He quotes a Japanese proverb:</p>
<blockquote><p>A frog in a well cannot comprehend the ocean.</p></blockquote>
<p>Benno saw much, but could not comprehend the ocean. So he did something that only a brave few would consider: empty his glass of experience, and thrust himself into the unknown. On the other side of the world, in a place he didn&#8217;t know, a language he couldn&#8217;t speak. And refill his glass with new and different experiences.<br />
The movie switched to a busy street in Karachi, Pakistan. Benno, wearing traditional garb, selling newspapers out of hand to passing motorists. Surreal, almost a version of the squeegee kids we&#8217;re more familiar with here in North America. The character of Benno in the movie says nothing the entire time. He moves through the actions. He smiles. He strides in a nervous confidence as he goes about earning enough money so that he can eat.  The narrator Benno tells us what&#8217;s going on in the character&#8217;s head.<br />
This is a Benno we barely recognise. The narrator confirms this.<br />
Benno is now driving a motorised rickshaw. He doesn&#8217;t know the city at all. He takes directions in the form of pointing from passengers. He is but a passenger himself, as he translates the pointing into direction for the rickshaw. He doesn&#8217;t understand the language, but he is able to communicate.<br />
In Lahore, he becomes a tea maker. He works hard to understand the mixture, to delivery tea quickly to the patrons. One person actually speaks Japanese and tries to engage Benno in conversation, but he is too busy with the others, and cannot spare the time. At the end, the owner of the shop makes tea for Benno. It is the best he&#8217;s ever tasted.<br />
In Islamabad, he sells vegetables in the marketplace. He cannot understand what is being said to him, but he understands the needs.<br />
Finally, we find Benno on the shores of the Indian Ocean, carrying a bundle of balloons. The sun is setting after another day being a stranger in a strange land. The Benno we see is not the Benno I know. He has changed. He is wiser. He has grown.<br />
He was Benno. Perhaps now, I will have to call him Masanori. Or perhaps even Benno-san.<br />
I have a great deal of respect for Benno. I travelled around the world, but I did not engage in the activities that would fill my glass with experience. I did not engage. I did not involve. I observed. I have always observed. Passive, even removed. To dive into a culture, an uncomfortable place, to learn more about oneself is to live without the fear of failure. It&#8217;s to know that survival is always possible. It&#8217;s strength and power.<br />
I would not say that my glass is in anyway empty, however. While I might not approach experiences in the same way as Benno, I still feel that I&#8217;ve had opportunity to define my experiences through opportunity. Yet, I do envy Benno to an extent. Because he&#8217;s been somewhere I haven&#8217;t been:<br />
Back at the beginning, to see a clearer future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/i-was-benno/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">854</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Return of 36 Chambers of Shaolin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/05/36-chambers-shaolin-return/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=36-chambers-shaolin-return</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/05/36-chambers-shaolin-return/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2001 18:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[know-it-all]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2001/05/22/36-chambers-shaolin-return/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little over two months ago, Dave &#8220;36&#8221; Chambers left Calgary for Toronto, where we were opening another office. On Friday, he came back to visit, and it was up to us to remind him why it was (or wasn&#8217;t) a bad idea to leave. This was a weekend for travelling &#8212; many CMassers were &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/05/36-chambers-shaolin-return/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Return of 36 Chambers of Shaolin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A little over two months ago, Dave &#8220;36&#8221; Chambers left Calgary for Toronto, where we were opening another office. On Friday, he came back to visit, and it was up to us to remind him why it was (or wasn&#8217;t) a bad idea to leave.<br />
This was a weekend for travelling &#8212; many CMassers were moving about the country. Some were coming to Calgary, some were going to Toronto, but most (of the travellers) were going to Vancouver for a wedding. Shawn was Toronto-bound, conveniently about 45 minutes after Dave&#8217;s plane was to land. Making my trip completely useful, I took Shawn to the airport, he tagged off with Dave, and I took Dave back to our place.<br />
For a game night of near-epic proportions.<br />
<span id="more-152"></span>Actually, it ended up being more of a &#8220;Welcome Back&#8221; party than a game night. Although a large number of people showed up, only about half active engaged in video games for the entire night. The other half engaged in pockets of conversation. But don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8212; we all eventually got back to the Dreamcast and Virtua Tennis. Yes, tennis. Not much more than a very flashy version of Pong. But amazingly fun and VERY addictive.<br />
The only thing missing was Mike, who was still in Toronto.<br />
Dave was hung over the next morning. That wasn&#8217;t entirely surprising considering what he drank the night before. (Cory and Colin had brought a small stash of imported European beers, one of which was technically a barley wine. At 10% alcohol by volume, it&#8217;s a bit stronger than most North American beers.) However, I should point out that had Dave not told me he was hung over, I never would have known.<br />
Chris had to disappear into the office. Not entirely sure what Dave wanted to do, I suggested we go down to Chinook Centre, wander around a bit, and maybe see a movie. Luckily (in a way) for us, this was the day of wacky weather &#8212; massive wind, snow, rain, hail, small children &#8212; basically anything you could imagine came whipping through the city. Dave and I didn&#8217;t notice, though &#8212; we were safely inside.<br />
Along with half of Calgary. (Chinook gets pretty busy on weekends.)<br />
The first order of business was food. I was a little hungry, but Dave was starving. We hit the food court and got our lunch sorted out. In the process of elimination, I make the fatal error of not having Japanese, as I had planned. Instead, I got a burrito from Taco Time. Shortly thereafter, I remembered why I don&#8217;t eat fast food Mexican anymore.<br />
After a quick stop into Sport Chek (more on this in a paragraph or two), we headed down to the south end of the mall, where Famous Players has their Paramount theatre. It&#8217;s a MASSIVE complex with 16 screens (all of which will probably be playing Pearl Harbor this Friday night), mocked up in an Egyptian motif. Basically, it looks like the theatre was stolen from Vegas. And at $9.50 for a matinee, it ain&#8217;t cheap either.<br />
The movie of the day was &#8220;Shrek&#8221;. This is a computer-animated fairy tale from DreamWorks. It stars the voices of Mike Myers (Austin Powers), Eddie Murphy (Trading Places), John Lithgow (3rd Rock From The Sun), and Cameron Diaz (Charlie&#8217;s Angels). It&#8217;s funny. I didn&#8217;t find it as funny (initially) as some of the sillier parts of Disney and Pixar movies, but the humour is a little more enduring, I think.<br />
We returned to Sport Chek afterwards, so I could spend a small heap of someone else&#8217;s money. For some reason, I&#8217;ve been listed as the person who referred Chris. So when Chris crossed his six-month mark here, I received a wad of gift certificates for referring Chris. Needless to say, I was a little surprised &#8230; but I got enough to buy some new shoes. Unfortunately, they weren&#8217;t the gym shoes I wanted (they were out of my size), but I finally got some casual walking shoes.<br />
Picking up Chris from the office, we stopped briefly at home before heading up to the northwest, where we were going to see &#8220;A Knight&#8217;s Tale&#8221; with Stuart and Therese. Dave, Chris, and I ate dinner first at Montana&#8217;s, partly because we hadn&#8217;t eaten yet, and partly because it was where Chris could get his Jack Daniel&#8217;s Maple Glazed Salmon. Or at least, we thought he could. He was denied by about a week &#8212; it (presumably) had been off the menu for the winter, and wasn&#8217;t due back for another 7-10 days.<br />
The next morning was dim sum, our weekly ritual, and something Dave had been looking forward to since he left Calgary. Following our Chinese repast, we headed over to Dragon City Mall so Dave could get some Pocky (a chocolate-covered cookie stick treat), and then off to A&amp;B Sound, and finally home again. We didn&#8217;t amount to much on Sunday, preferring to watch movies and TV. It was relaxing to say the least.<br />
On Monday, Dave had to go into the office to meet with Cory, our department head, to try and establish some stronger lines of communication between Calgary and Toronto. This left Chris and I to our own devices &#8230; such as the 10-hour &#8220;Best of Deep Space Nine&#8221; marathon on the Space channel.<br />
I love cable TV.<br />
Originally, Chris and I were to go to Banff with Stuart and Therese. However, I had forgotten at the time that Dave was coming out to visit. That negated my ability to go to Banff, and Chris opted to stick around at visit with Dave, too. Hopefully we&#8217;ll be able to back out to Banff before too long.<br />
Dave didn&#8217;t return until almost 3pm, after having lunch with friends. We sat around and talked, complaining a little bit about our jobs &#8212; specifically about some of our Project Managers, most notably one I&#8217;m having trouble with. I was in the middle of a rant when Chris said: &#8220;You know, there are probably people with not-so-great things to say about you.&#8221;<br />
Although the comment didn&#8217;t slow me down at the time, it did give me something to think about. There were two cases: 1) Chris was being observant, or 2) Chris had heard something. In either case, the simple fact was that it made me look at my attitude, and how I&#8217;ve been acting. It didn&#8217;t take long for me to realize that since mid-January or so, my attitude has degraded quite a lot. I&#8217;ve become a cocky know-it-all (for all you jokers saying &#8220;hey, that&#8217;s no different!&#8221;, put a sock in it, okay?) with a dour outlook on the projects I work on. I&#8217;ve been bossing people around, overstepping my bounds, and making a lot of assumptions. Basically, I&#8217;ve been a Grade A Jerk.<br />
Luckily for me, I have a friend like Chris, who isn&#8217;t afraid about telling me when I&#8217;m being a jerk. Becoming too complacent has become a detriment to me, and I&#8217;ve got to rectify the problem before I dig a hole I can&#8217;t get out of. This was something I was afraid might happen. I became a senior, put in a place of responsibility, and let it get to my head. Bad Geoff, bad! The strange part is, this is the first time this has happened &#8212; even though I&#8217;ve had this level of responsibility before.<br />
Just goes to show you that no matter how old you get, or how much work experience you have, there is always something you can still learn about yourself.<br />
We continued to watch the marathon until just before 5pm, at which time I took Dave up to the airport. It wasn&#8217;t so hard seeing him off this time, probably because I knew that this had been a short visit anyway. We&#8217;ll see him again (and hopefully other friends of ours who went to Toronto) this summer at the Getaway.<br />
Dave again played tag on his way out. As we rounded the corner to the gate, we ran into Angie, one of our co-workers, waiting for Rich (another co-worker who had been in Vancouver for the wedding). Dave and Rich greeted each other, Rich went to get his bags, and Dave went through security to his flight.<br />
Oh, you&#8217;re probably wondering about the &#8220;36&#8221; thing, eh? Well, although I can&#8217;t remember who exactly bestowed this nickname, it was one of the Designers. For some reason, it stuck.<br />
Now if he could just learn a little kung fu&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/05/36-chambers-shaolin-return/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">152</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
