<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>internet &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/internet/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 04:57:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Things I learned by leaving social media</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 04:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On 8 November 2016, Americans elected their new president, whom I hope to never have to publicly acknowledge. That night, I came to a rather painful conclusion: I needed to abandon social media for a while. In this particular election, the media had (unwittingly, foolishly, stupidly, or all of the above) enabled a level of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Things I learned by leaving social media"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On 8 November 2016, Americans elected their new president, whom I hope to never have to publicly acknowledge. That night, I came to a rather painful conclusion: I needed to abandon social media for a while.<br />
In this particular election, the media had (unwittingly, foolishly, stupidly, or all of the above) enabled a level of insipid, unchecked banter that intelligence and logic were utterly cast aside in favour of whomever had the best catchphrase. Basically, a Hollywood political satire come to life. Very real, very <em>painful</em> life.<br />
It hurt so bad that I had to turn it off.<br />
<span id="more-3553"></span><br />
So I left Twitter and Facebook behind. (I already mostly ignore LinkedIn, except for reference checks when hiring people. I don&#8217;t use any other tool for sheer sanity.) I even stopped listening to CBC Radio, for the same reasons. I just needed to ignore The Stupid for a while and worry about myself, and my family.<br />
I returned on 1 January. I&#8217;d just had <a href="http://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/16/disney-world-2016-the-kids-find-out/">a wonderful vacation</a>, I&#8217;d been away from the nonsense long enough, and to be honest &#8230; I was missing my friends. It seemed like a good time to go back online. (Whether that&#8217;s still the case remains to be seen&#8230;)<br />
It&#8217;s at this point that we need to acknowledge some lessons learned. And no, this isn&#8217;t one of those articles that suggests <em>everyone </em>should abandon social media. For some, it makes total sense. For me, however, it&#8217;s just not an option.</p>
<h2>More pressure, than less pressure</h2>
<p>The biggest problem is expectation. It doesn&#8217;t matter that you leave a great big sign that says &#8220;Gone Fishin'&#8221;, people expect you to be there. And yes, I do mean people, as in actual humans.<br />
Whether anyone readily acknowledges it or not, when you engage with someone on social media, it&#8217;s not just text &#8212; there&#8217;s a real human behind that text: a family member, a friend, or a colleague. Someone with real emotions who might start to wonder what&#8217;s up. And your &#8220;out of office&#8221; notice doesn&#8217;t say anything useful.<br />
That started to weigh on me pretty hard. I am proud to say that I have a lot of friends. And in my daily life, I get to see about ten of them &#8230; because they work next to me. The other thousand or so? Some I get to see once in a while, after some careful planning, for a few short hours. Others live out of the city, and as much as technology enables real-time video conversations, the reality is that I see them almost never. One of my favourite recent pictures is when I saw a whole bunch of them all at once last summer.<br />
Email? Honestly, how many people write personal emails these days? We cram so many things into our daily lives that we don&#8217;t have the time to write. Believe me, I know &#8212; I&#8217;ve used that excuse for close to four years as a reason for not blogging. Personal emails? &#8220;Close to never&#8221; is the best definition for me.<br />
I use social media. Whether it&#8217;s a chance to vent for a moment, or get input, or share something I find really interesting, all of it matters. And <em>not</em> being able to do that really started to wear on me.</p>
<h2>Wait, you did what?!</h2>
<p>The other major problem with getting off social media is completely losing track of your friends. I thought I was doing myself a service. Since then, I&#8217;ve learned of deaths in families, a good friend is undergoing cancer treatment (again!), and another one is nearly in the midst of a career crisis.<br />
My friends need friends, too, and I&#8217;d abandoned them in the process of trying to save myself. There&#8217;s a certain amount of &#8220;me&#8221; that I need to deal with, yes, but there&#8217;s no nobility in turning one&#8217;s back &#8212; unintentionally or not &#8212; against your friends.<br />
My friends are important to me. Because I&#8217;ve learned what it&#8217;s like to not have them, and I can&#8217;t afford to lose the ones I have.</p>
<h2>Oh that&#8217;d make a great tweet!</h2>
<p>Two times a day, <em>minimum</em>, I thought of great tweets. (Well, &#8220;great&#8221; to me, anyway.) Several times I caught myself reaching for my phone, ready to blurt it out to the world.<br />
I&#8217;m vocal. (Yeah, I know: <em>duh</em>.) Even if nearly no-one is listening, that&#8217;s okay. I still need to talk. And if I&#8217;m just talking to myself &#8230; well, I&#8217;ve been to those doctors. I&#8217;d rather just talk to my friends.</p>
<h2>Filter or die</h2>
<p>Here&#8217;s my lesson to you, dear reader. Out of all of this, the greatest lesson I&#8217;ve learned is the need to filter: follow only those you need to follow, ditch the ones who don&#8217;t help.<br />
Yes, you can easily argue that you should engage people on social media, especially those who need a different point of view. I&#8217;ve tried. I&#8217;ve seen others try. The sad truth is, you can&#8217;t.<br />
Social media doesn&#8217;t change minds, it just helps people find like minds to reinforce their beliefs.<br />
I used to have a policy of following people even if I disagreed with them, because there was a learning opportunity. But all I learned was that people are easily angered, often seen as ignorant (regardless of factual basis), and arguments can go on for days without any resolution.<br />
I&#8217;ve dropped those people. I&#8217;ve shrunk my circle to the ones who matter, the ones who can truly influence me, the ones who have thoughts that I feel matter. Those who want to promote different agendas aren&#8217;t of interest to me, nor do I have the patience to sit through rhetoric I don&#8217;t agree with.<br />
I know many people who aren&#8217;t me, and are quite happy to do what I can&#8217;t. (I know a few who likely crack a bottle of wine, sit down at their keyboards, and see how many people they can rile in an evening.) Me? I want to know how you&#8217;re doing, what new things are going on, hopefully help out in some way. And I hope that maybe you&#8217;d return the favour down the road to me.</p>
<h2>Staying &#8230; for now</h2>
<p>I&#8217;m back to my old ways, and hopefully even the oldest one, blogging. Whether I stay here remains to be seen. The year(s) to come will be hard. The right wing of the world is flapping hard, stirring up fear and hatred in an effort to seize control. There may yet come a point when I delete my accounts. (And possibly move to a remote island&#8230;)<br />
For now, I&#8217;m happy to engage. Just so long as everyone else is happy, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/01/things-i-learned-by-leaving-social-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3553</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>20 Years a Web Developer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=20-years-a-web-developer</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 22:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twenty years ago this month &#8212; and very possibly this week, though I&#8217;m not 100% certain of that &#8212; I entered into the very nascent industry of digital marketing. At the time, the project had been little more than a simple idea, something to possibly prove my own abilities, a problem that sort of needed &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "20 Years a Web Developer"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twenty years ago this month &#8212; and very possibly this week, though I&#8217;m not 100% certain of that &#8212; I entered into the very nascent industry of digital marketing. At the time, the project had been little more than a simple idea, something to possibly prove my own abilities, a problem that sort of needed solving. And yet, little did I know at the time, it would send me down a long and sometimes disturbingly windy path.<br />
It&#8217;s also a milestone where one does need to consider &#8230; well, everything. Honestly, a bit of reflection and introspection is needed from time to time, but the decade markers seem to have a certain extra amount of importance. Though to be honest, that&#8217;s just a perceived thing; there&#8217;s no legal or social reason that I&#8217;m aware of. It&#8217;s more about having a well-defined chunk of time to really take that step back and say:<br />
&#8220;Ye gods I&#8217;m getting old&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-3426"></span><br />
Twenty years seems like such a long time. Indeed, it&#8217;s just less than half of my life at this point. A lot has happened in those twenty years, not just in my own personal life (which is considerable), but also in my industry, which as I noted earlier, barely existed when I started.<br />
I learned HTML in my ENGL 209 course at the University of Waterloo, taught by <a href="https://uwaterloo.ca/english/people-profiles/neil-randall" target="_blank">Professor Neil Randall</a>. Why an English professor was teaching markup was a bit baffling at the time. I learned later that he wrote frequently for <em>PC Magazine</em>, and was a hardened geek. (He still is.) When he gave us the option of filing &#8220;webpages&#8221; instead of papers, I leapt at the change. (Yes, <em>change</em>, not <em>chance</em>.)<br />
Not long afterwards, I took at a job at a company near Don Mills and the 401 in Toronto, writing manuals for a financial software company. Nearby was a small store called &#8220;Movie Poster Warehouse&#8221;. One day, at lunch, I strolled over to peer in and see what it was all about.<br />
Shelley, the owner, told me a bit of their history, most of which went clear through my head at the time: I was absolutely enthralled with the (literal) <em>warehouse</em> of movie posters. Not the junky Imaginus stuff that does the campus circuit. I mean <em>real</em> movie posters. Some of them decades old, and many in pristine original condition. As a rather hard-core movie addict (at the time, anyway), I couldn&#8217;t resist buying one before my lunchtime ran out.<br />
But as I left, I asked if they had a website. &#8220;What&#8217;s a website?&#8221; she asked. And so it began&#8230;<br />
Their <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19961222132316/http://www.movieposter.com/" target="_blank">first website went up in March 1995</a>. My friend Scott did the design, I did the build. I look back on it and cringe a bit, but it was my first professional foray, and my first real beginning to understand how marketing and commerce would work online. (They&#8217;re still online, <a href="https://ca.movieposter.com/" target="_blank">though under a different domain</a>.)<br />
Since then, I&#8217;ve done websites for so many companies that I&#8217;m not even sure I can remember them all. I&#8217;ve done nearly every kind of website at some point, for companies and organizations of nearly every size, in a dozen different languages, in at least a dozen different countries. I&#8217;ve lived the Agency Life<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, and lived to tell about it. Well, tell about some of it. I can&#8217;t tell you all of it, either due to having forgotten, or &#8230; well, some things do need to remain a secret.<br />
So, twenty years down the road, I&#8217;m still at it. I&#8217;m still a developer at heart, looking at the technology and technical needs of a solution. Not necessarily &#8220;site&#8221;, I should add &#8212; not all problems lead to a website, and the internet is so much more than HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. You need to know a lot more to make a solution work: you need to know what works, how it works, and when best to use it. And all of that has changed from those first few HTML tags I learned so many years ago.<br />
I look back and I can say there&#8217;s been really only one constant in all of this: change. I know that&#8217;s something you&#8217;ll hear a lot in nearly every industry, but the truth is that digital marketing changes constantly. Daily, even. There hasn&#8217;t been a single week in those twenty years when I&#8217;ve not had to look into something different or new. Because that&#8217;s the nature of the internet, which is the real basis for digital marketing: it allows that kind of change.<br />
And if you don&#8217;t keep up with that change? You die. Or worse, you become irrelevant. Not changing, not keeping up with change, is a death sentence. Others will eclipse you in short order, and no matter how loud your thunder may have been, someone else&#8217;s lightning will be crisper, brighter, and faster.<br />
In a way, web developers become slaves to change: we&#8217;re always on the watch for new things, new ideas. We&#8217;re simultaneously excited by them, and terribly burdened by them. The vast majority of us are self-taught, having learned by trial and error, and often trial by fire. We&#8217;ve all been burned, overloaded, unappreciated, misunderstood, belittled, and regularly forgotten.<br />
It&#8217;s an ugly reality, but it&#8217;s a painful truth of where web developer lie in the digital marketing world: we&#8217;re the nameless few. We don&#8217;t win awards for amazing code; we get praised for being on budget (which is difficult), and chastised when things don&#8217;t work perfectly (it&#8217;s exceptionally difficult &#8212; and expensive &#8212; to be perfect).<br />
&#8220;Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic,&#8221; wrote Arthur C. Clarke. I offer a corollary: &#8220;Any sufficiently skilled developer can make the impossible seem magical.&#8221; When we do our jobs well, no-one notices. How&#8217;s that for irony?<br />
Actually, that&#8217;s not entirely true. When you do your job better than someone else, then you&#8217;re noticed &#8230; and not in a good way. Hence, the first rule of the internet: There will always be someone better than you. That means you need to be ready to adapt at a moment&#8217;s notice. And the day I can no longer adapt is the day I forever leave this industry, because I won&#8217;t be able to keep up.<br />
Today is not that day. Tired, I may be. Exhausted even. That&#8217;s a result of age (I&#8217;m no spring chicken, anymore), home life (my kids are awesome, but they have boundless energy), and evolution (the act of changing is draining). But I&#8217;m not done.<br />
I won&#8217;t be done until I say I&#8217;m done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to be a Technical Writer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-be-a-technical-writer</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s surprising how often I&#8217;ve been asked this question over the last few months. Once upon a time &#8212; some dozen years ago &#8212; I was a technical writer. I wrote manuals, technical documentation, and various forms of other literature for a living. And, to be quite honest, I hated it. Well, hate is a strong &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to be a Technical Writer"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s surprising how often I&#8217;ve been asked this question over the last few months. Once upon a time &#8212; some dozen years ago &#8212; I was a technical writer. I wrote manuals, technical documentation, and various forms of other literature for a living. And, to be quite honest, I hated it.<br />
Well, <em>hate</em> is a strong word. I got bored of doing it. (Long story, suffice to say, I ended up making websites for a living.) But certainly the skill has never left me (I still write documentation to this day as part of my job), and I do know a few things about writing clearly and effectively.<br />
Sadly, it&#8217;s not something that is done particularly well&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3135"></span>If you&#8217;re reading this, you&#8217;re (obviously) on the internet. And you&#8217;ve seen how badly the internet has been written. Spelling mistakes aside (even today&#8217;s modern spell checkers miss grammar and some syntax resulting from correctly-spelled, but incorrectly-used words), many people have trouble forming a cohesive idea, and an even harder time expressing it. As much as some scholars have said that the internet has (overall) improved the habit of written communication, I personally find the quality a bit lacking at times.<br />
These days, you can easily find some fantastic how-to books on how to write documentation. This is not a new field, by any means &#8212; humanity&#8217;s been writing stuff like this for a couple hundred years, really. But over the years, I&#8217;ve found that most of the details can be boiled down to a few key points that you always keep in mind, and then you need to practice them over and over and over and over and over and over.<br />
Oh, and you need to have a vicious editor. (Ideally, another writer with more experience.) Someone who can <em>objectively</em> tear apart your work, show you what&#8217;s good, what&#8217;s not so good, and help you improve your work. I learned more about the art of technical writing from two editors than I did from any book or professor, and I&#8217;m thankful for those people&#8217;s efforts (regardless of any heated arguments at the time). Writing is a two-person job: the author and the editor, and I&#8217;ll debate anyone who says otherwise&#8230;<br />
There&#8217;s six fundamental parts to any good documentation (technical, or otherwise):</p>
<ol>
<li>Organisation of concepts</li>
<li>Understanding your audience</li>
<li>Clarity</li>
<li>Brevity</li>
<li>Visual reinforcement</li>
<li>Consistency</li>
</ol>
<h2> Organisation</h2>
<p>This is Number 1 on the list for a reason. Even if you bugger everything else up in your documentation, you <em>need</em> to get this right. How you divide your document really speaks to how you introduce the concepts, explain them, and allow people to dig into things at a pace that&#8217;s comfortable for them.<br />
As a general rule, you always start at a very high level &#8212; you <em>introduce</em> the very thing you&#8217;re about to explain. For example, imagine you&#8217;re writing a document on a plane. Your document may eventually detail the specific bolt that&#8217;s used to attach the engine, but you <em>first</em> have to start by telling the reader what a plane is, what it does, and (in some cases) even a wee bit of history. (Incidentally, a lot of Wikipedia articles are organised like this, and many are good examples of documentation.)<br />
You then break your document into sections (or chapters, whatever you want to call them), which are the major topics of discussion. In the case of a plane (for example), you might want to have sections for the fuselage (the basic chassis of a plane), the powerplant (what makes a plane move), the wings (what makes a plane actually fly), the avionics (what helps the pilots steer the plane), the landing gear (because everything that goes up eventually has to come down), and the empennage (basically, the rear control mechanisms at the tail that allow steering).<br />
Then, within each of those sections, you can more succinctly break down the topic more independently, allowing each section to have isolation from the other sections. Though not <em>total</em> isolation &#8212; any good documentation should refer to other parts of itself, or other documents, that provide additional detail.<br />
It&#8217;s a simple mantra: start big, go small.<br />
Thus we get to headings! All documentation has headings &#8212; it&#8217;s what breaks it up into parts that are digestible. All documentation has a heading hierarchy, too: always going from the first heading (often called Heading 1) to the second, to the third, and so on. You <strong><em>never, never, ever</em></strong> skip a heading. If you feel the urge to skip a heading, you have a flaw in your organisation.<br />
The depth of heading hierarchies (how many heading levels you need) depends on the document. Some documents can get away with two; some (and I&#8217;ve written ones like this) need six or more. Don&#8217;t creating heading levels you don&#8217;t need &#8212; always keep a document as shallow as you can &#8212; but don&#8217;t be afraid to use them when you&#8217;re discussing a complex thing that needs a lot of breakdown.<br />
It should be noted, especially with software documentation, that a heading hierarchy isn&#8217;t always a heading (such as &#8220;Organisation&#8221;, above). Sometimes it&#8217;s a function or a method that you need to document. For people reading API (application programming interface) specifications, the name of the function is in many cases far more valuable than heading you could create.</p>
<h2>Understanding your Audience</h2>
<p>It might sound trite, but you&#8217;re not writing a document for yourself. You&#8217;re writing it for someone else. You should always keep this in mind, as it will help focus the language you use, and the detail you need to provide.<br />
Again, consider the plane documentation. There&#8217;s several different audiences who may need such a document: the people building the plane (they&#8217;ll need detailed specifications, including assembly instructions), the mechanics who&#8217;ll fix the plane later (similar to the build specifications, but they&#8217;ll also need information on best practices for repairs), pilots (who need to know how to fly the plane), and even passengers (they want to know more about the plane, and especially safety procedures). All of these audiences need special attention, and (frequently) very different information.<br />
You would (almost) never write a general document that would address all people. It&#8217;s not to say that it can&#8217;t be done &#8212; it&#8217;s done every day, and done badly &#8212; but such a document becomes very hard to read, and even harder to understand. Writing different documents often helps make sure you&#8217;ve got the right subject and language for the right people.</p>
<h2>Clarity</h2>
<p>This is a tough one, and it relates to the previous two items. The more complex your topic, the more clarity you may need to provide. By &#8220;clarity&#8221;, I mean the ability to explain an inherently complex thing in (reasonably) simple terms.<br />
I&#8217;ve written loads of technical documentation regarding software development and server architecture, often for project managers and clients who do not possess my level of understanding. (This is usually because I have to get budgets approved, and simply saying &#8220;we need to rewrite some code&#8221; isn&#8217;t good enough.) I&#8217;ve had to explain a problem in detail, propose the solution, and draw potential conclusions from the actions. All of it in such a way that someone who doesn&#8217;t need (or want) to understand the details.<br />
I won&#8217;t lie: this is <em>hard</em>.<br />
So how do you do it? <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metaphor" target="_blank">Metaphor</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simile" target="_blank">simile</a>. (I provided links, in case you can&#8217;t remember what those terms are. And yes, you could use <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allegory" target="_blank">allegory</a> as well, but it takes a lot more effort, and we&#8217;re trying to keep things simple.) You need to convert the concept into something more familiar to the audience at hand.<br />
For example, in software, we often talk about using a &#8220;framework&#8221; when building complex things. A framework is like being given a lumbermill to carve up an entire tree, rather than having to use a handsaw to do it all by yourself.<br />
See what I did there? You&#8217;ve probably never sawed an entire tree by yourself &#8212; but you can imagine how much work it is. You don&#8217;t have to know what a &#8220;framework&#8221; really does, but you suddenly have an idea of what it can do for programmers. Hence, the importance of explaining things a different (but still valid!) way.<br />
It&#8217;s important that you&#8217;ve explained a concept sufficiently. You have to carry an explanation all the way to the end, so that someone has a complete thought. Imagine if I&#8217;d stopped halfway through my framework definition, and left it at &#8220;lumbermill&#8221;. You&#8217;d probably be wondering where I was going with the idea, and likely no better off than when I&#8217;d started.<br />
You also need to be specific. Avoid using vague words when you can use the actual term instead. This is particularly important as your detail increases. At a high level, you can talk about the bolts that go into assembling a plane; when you get to the exact bolt needed to attach a winglet to the wingtip, you&#8217;d better have the part number to go along with it.</p>
<h2>Brevity</h2>
<p>Those of you who know me will be snickering at me for this one. Yes, you need to try write the shortest documentation you can, all the while building on the items I&#8217;ve already mentioned. I say this because, generally, I still struggle with it.<br />
It is very difficult to not want to explain everything in huge amounts of detail. I&#8217;ll tell you this (because I&#8217;m always telling it to myself): give people just <em>enough</em> information, not <em>all</em> the information &#8212; let someone learn enough to know what they need to get going, and they&#8217;ll (usually) figure out the rest for themselves.<br />
Also, you keep it short because people just don&#8217;t want to read lots of words. They want the information, and move on. We&#8217;re a society of soundbites, not one of novels. That also means writing short sentences and short paragraphs &#8212; long ones are fine for telling stories, but they suck at instruction.</p>
<h2>Visual Reinforcement</h2>
<p>When you&#8217;re writing some documentation, you&#8217;ll come across the need to explain something that is inherently so complex that it&#8217;s difficult to write in words.<br />
So don&#8217;t.<br />
The saying &#8220;a picture&#8217;s worth a thousand words&#8221; is <em>very</em> true, and a single picture can eliminate the need to write lengthy explanations. In some cases, a diagram is the <em>only</em> way to properly provide information (such as technical specifications for the previously-mentioned airplane mechanics).<br />
Do you have to make these diagrams yourself? Not always, but often a simple drawing tool will save you hours of hunting through the internet for an appropriate picture, or waiting for someone else to make it for you. Visio and Omnigraffle are life-savers when it comes to building quick and easy diagrams, especially where complex ideas like process flows need to be explained.</p>
<h2>Consistency</h2>
<p>I have this as a &#8220;last&#8221; important point, but it&#8217;s no less important than the previous two (<strong>Brevity</strong> and <strong>Visual Reinforcement</strong>). It&#8217;s important not because it helps convey information any more easily &#8212; it&#8217;s because it won&#8217;t annoy your reader.<br />
Consistency, in this case, is about your writing style. You need to make sure you&#8217;re always approaching your writing in the same manner, in the same style, in the same voice, throughout an entire document. (This is where an editor really comes in to save a day, incidentally.)<br />
Changing styles, or how you write, does not change the information you&#8217;re providing. But it does cause the reader to unconsciously start to hate you, because it&#8217;s difficult for a human to read different styles or word usage from page to page (or section to section).<br />
Stick with your choice of spelling. You&#8217;ve probably noticed that I use &#8220;organisation&#8221;, not &#8220;organization&#8221;. I use a version of Canadian spelling. (This is in itself a bit debatable, as some Canadian spelling is British, and some is more American.) But once you start using it, keep using it. (Incidentally, I don&#8217;t normally use &#8220;organisation&#8221; &#8212; I&#8217;m using here to illustrate the point.)<br />
You should also stick with your choice of terms. Once you start using a term, you need to keep using it, and use it in the correct context. As mentioned with the bolts earlier, if you ever mention a &#8220;19 mm close tolerance bolt&#8221;, you need to keep using that term, lest someone get confused with a different kind of bolt.<br />
Similarly, once you start using a particular meme for your metaphors, you need to stick with them. If you start using planes as your metaphor, <em>keep talking about planes</em> &#8212; don&#8217;t switch to using trees and lumbermills. (See what I did there?)<br />
Yes, this is a bit of psychology. But you want someone to read your document, and hopefully recommend it to someone else.</p>
<h2>Some Final Notes</h2>
<p>It ain&#8217;t easy summarising an entire career into a single blog post. Heck, it&#8217;s fool-hardy, really. But still, there&#8217;s a few other things that you might want to consider looking into.<br />
First of all, read some examples. You don&#8217;t need to <em>learn</em> the material, but look at them for what they are. I&#8217;ve already mentioned Wikipedia, which is maintained by an army of editors, for whom I have the deepest respect. Also consider reading some books &#8212; things like the <a href="http://www.dummies.com/" target="_blank"><em>For Dummies</em></a> series and pretty much anything out of <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/" target="_blank">O&#8217;Reilly</a> are great examples of complex ideas broken down into digestible terms.<br />
Your style is important, but not critical. Still, there are a few things you should keep an eye on:</p>
<ul>
<li>There is no &#8220;I&#8221; in technical writing, so don&#8217;t use it (the author might have a fancy picture on the cover, but inside the book they shouldn&#8217;t make themselves known)</li>
<li>There is a &#8220;you&#8221; &#8212; always speak to your reader, it helps them attach themselves more to the topic</li>
<li>Companies (et al) are referred to in the third person; avoid &#8220;we&#8221; if you can</li>
<li>Avoid colloquialisms, vulgarity, stereotypes, catchphrases, and so on &#8212; those are for literature, not documentation</li>
</ul>
<p>Learn some of the typographical aspects of writing. For example, the difference between a dash, an &#8220;en dash&#8221; and an &#8220;em dash&#8221;. You&#8217;d be surprised how often a simple change like that can affect the readability of a document. Similarly, spacing between headings and paragraphs, how to create legible lists, and simple formatting go a long way to making a document &#8220;friendly&#8221;.<br />
Practice. You won&#8217;t get it right the first time. Or the second. Or the tenth. But you will get better, if you keep at it, and have a (trusted) person review your work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/how-to-be-a-technical-writer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3135</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TV is dead. Long live the internet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TV is dead. Long live the internet!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial that changed the direction of the UHF antenna&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve lost you, haven&#8217;t I? I shudder to think how few of you have an <em>inkling</em> of what I&#8217;m talking about. Yeah, that&#8217;s how old I am. I remember when there were only a handful of channels, when almost all of the content was on ABC, NBC, CBS, CBC, CTV, Global, and a few independent stations (such as the awesome CityTV and the the extremely nacent Fox). I remember the introduction of cable. I remember having to wait for the summer reruns because I missed that crucial episode of <em>The A Team</em> that everyone was talking about in class the next morning. I remember when the season debuts were a big thing. I remember when missing a live televised event was significant, because it was gone forever.<br />
It seems somehow just as bizarre a concept as the Spanish Inquisition.<br />
<span id="more-3076"></span>Up until a few years ago, this model was still fairly static. Despite the massive influx of cable, the ridiculous proliferation of specialty channels (seriously, I cannot fathom how some of them make any money), Youtube, Torrents, and the like, the concept of &#8220;television&#8221; hadn&#8217;t really changed. You still relied on the networks. Waiting for the most recent <em>Survivor</em> was still a big thing. And people watched the evening news.<br />
In the last 24-30 months, however, I&#8217;ve seen a massive shift in service. The <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/research/2010/01/the-itunes-effect-and-the-futu.html">iTunes Effect</a> completely altered the way that we consume music (despite the music industry continually trying to roll the clock back as if nothing ever happened), and it&#8217;s echoed into the way we consume video. And I choose that word very carefully: <em>video.</em> Not &#8220;television&#8221;, not &#8220;movies&#8221;. The length of a given item, or its relevance to a related group of videos (say, a television series of yore, or a trilogy of films) is largely irrelevant. Thanks to devices such as DVRs, tablets, Boxees, Apple TVs, and so forth, we can consume video on our own terms, and not at those of the telecommunications companies to whom we enslaved ourselves for over five decades.<br />
A month and a half ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/upstairs-reno-the-fun-begins/">my family moved out of our home</a> so the kitchen renovation could begin in earnest. When we did that, we took our living room video display (I now loathe to call it a &#8220;TV set&#8221;) and the Apple TV so we could watch, well, <em>something</em>. For three weeks, all we had were whatever videos were on the Apple TV &#8212; we had no network connection to speak of, so no new videos during that time.<br />
When we got back into our home, the living room was far from any suitable state to be able to hook our video displays back up to the television display boxes. No TV. (In fact, hardly any video at all.) At the end of a month and a half, it&#8217;s hard for us to really &#8220;miss&#8221; television at all.<br />
We had Telus Optik. It was a decent service, and the only real complaint I had with it was that we had about 180 channels more than we watched. There were four on any form of rotation: Discovery (for my <em>MythBusters</em> fix), Treehouse (for the kids&#8217; shows), whatever channel showed <em>Greys Anatomy</em>, and one or two other channels were in the mix for a few things. But that was it. No kidding. No joke. We paid $80 to watch less than a half dozen things.<br />
Yesterday, I pulled the plug (not <em>completely</em>, mind you &#8212; I rather stupidly signed up for a three year contract, thinking this blog post was still quite a ways away; the account is in &#8220;suspension&#8221; for $5/month, though it counts towards the contract term), and we started onto a new path: internet-only content.<br />
We are far from the first to do this. I have several friends who cut their cable a while ago, and have sufficed quite well off of whatever they could glean from the internet. iTunes has been a major source of material, as has the ubiquitous YouTube. Many have turned to the less-legal Torrents to acquire television shows and movies, while others have looked to online services such as Netflix.<br />
My problem with the internet aspect until recently was twofold: fragmentation, and accessibility. There&#8217;s a lot of different venues in which to find the content one might want to watch &#8212; think of it as having two constantly criss-cross a typical urban mega-strip mall on an erratic shopping spree, rather than being able to go to a single store and finding all that you need. And then it&#8217;s an issue where you go to a given store expecting to find the very shirt your American friend told you about, but despite it being an American clothier, that specific shirt isn&#8217;t available in Canada. (Canada remains, frustratingly, a digital backwater when it comes to internet content.)<br />
So what&#8217;s changed? Aside from the realization that we just don&#8217;t watch regular television anymore, it was the introduction of a &#8220;content aggregator&#8221; (not sure what else to call it), some handy (but legally grey-area) tools, and the ability to be a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing. Allow me to introduce our new media setup&#8230;</p>
<h2>The Device</h2>
<p>Ultimately, you need a unit to actually serve content (the stuff &#8212; literally &#8212; doesn&#8217;t fly through the air, anymore). The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_TV#Apple_TV_First_Generation">Apple TV (version 1)</a> had been a decent first attempt, but it failed in a number of ways, not the least of which was a strong tie to iTunes and not a lot of expandability (even the <a href="http://firecore.com/atvflash">aTV Flash</a> hack offered little more). It meant that it was hard for us to use different media sources, or even watch DVDs through a single device.<br />
Enter the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_Mini">mid-2010 Apple Mac Mini, model A1347 (non-server)</a>. Slightly taller than the Apple TV, this is a complete computer, and can run any software we need. Furthermore, it has full support for 1080p video, complete audio support, and because it&#8217;s a full computer, it can be used by Monkey and Choo Choo as they grow up and need to use computers in their school (while Mommy and I get to help/watch). Even more key for this specific release of the Mac Mini, however, is that this is the last one that came with a SuperDrive built-in &#8212; the next release was without an optical drive, making it hard to watch those reams of physical media we&#8217;ve been accumulating.<br />
The Mac Mini is limited to 320 GB, which seems like a lot, but it&#8217;ll fill up quickly with the media we hope to deliver through it. So instead, I&#8217;m going to be attaching it to a terabyte drive (ideally a RAIDed one, with a secondary backup for real redundancy) that will store all the music, movies, photos, and various videos that our family will use. Our network is gigabit (thanks to Telus), so network speed shouldn&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<h2>The Software</h2>
<p>Operating system aside, the complete list is still pending, but I&#8217;m looking at:</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Duh. We have a significant amount of content in iTunes, and there is zero reason not to use iTunes to access it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plexapp.com/">Plex Server</a><br />
This is the aggregation tool. It offers a significant amount of functionality for linking disparate pieces of content (including iTunes) into a single interface, and offers a variety of &#8220;channels&#8221; for watching online content. Because it works full-screen, it&#8217;s a suitable replacement for the venerable Front Row. It also includes a player that can play software copies of DVDs&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://thelittleappfactory.com/ripit/">RipIt</a><br />
Boy, it didn&#8217;t take long to get back into that legal black hole, didn&#8217;t it? Yes, I am using a piece of software to extract the content from media I have purchased and am placing it in a non-public system for my own personal entertainment, digital lock provisions be damned. Big Media pushing bullshit like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">SOPA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_Canada">C-11</a> can <a href="http://www.freshnewsound.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/johnny_cash.jpg">suck my balls</a>. I don&#8217;t like physical media, it&#8217;s too prone to damage by jam-covered fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, we will install what&#8217;s needed, when it&#8217;s needed. Right now, I&#8217;m not sure what that is, but I&#8217;m sure we can adapt when the time comes.</p>
<h2>The Services</h2>
<p>The hardware and software alone will not solve our problems. It&#8217;s not really any different than buying a &#8220;regular&#8221; television set. The problem is that you still need to have content provided from <em>somewhere</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Again, duh. Our existing library is one thing, but iTunes still has an extensive (and lovely) collection of media from which to select. We&#8217;ve used iTunes for quite some time, and plan to keep using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://goo.gl/EY0O4">The Service I Can&#8217;t Really Talk About</a><br />
Okay, this is another one of those &#8220;grey area&#8221; items. Technically, Canadians can&#8217;t see American content (think Hulu, American versions of Netflix and iTunes, and Comedy Network) because some dumbass decided that we&#8217;re not allowed to see it. So our IP blocks are scanned and summarily blocked. This service makes you look like an American &#8212; a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing &#8212; and away you go. It&#8217;s not illegal, but I&#8217;m sure that some moron lawyer will cry foul (because he&#8217;s paid to do so) and it&#8217;ll get yanked. Hence, I refuse to name it. Like Plex, it also provides a number of channels, so we should be able to watch &#8230; well, pretty much anything we want, really.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.netflix.ca">Netflix</a> (the American verison!)<br />
My biggest gripe with Netflix is that the Canadian content is so wildly different than the American content &#8230; despite it running off the same system. So thanks to the aforementioned service, we get the added benefit of a larger library.</li>
</ul>
<div>Okay, what about live television? Say I want to watch the hockey game, or even the Olympics? Well, this is where the Mac Mini comes to the rescue again. Because it&#8217;s a full computer, it has a full browser (and various necessary plugins) so that we can visit a website and watch live feeds. Perfect? Probably not, but at least it&#8217;s better than channel surfing.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>The Result</h2>
<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know yet. From everything I&#8217;ve read and from everything everyone who&#8217;s already gone down this road has told me, this seems like a solid path. But I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that it won&#8217;t be a bed of roses (and, really, when you think about it, is a &#8220;bed of roses&#8221; all that appealing? Think of the thorns!) and this could fail. I doubt it will fail entirely, since we get content no matter what, it&#8217;s just the depth at which we get it.<br />
So what of actual &#8220;television&#8221;? We&#8217;re in the shift now, and already it&#8217;s showing. Advertisers are trying to find new ways to market to people who are willingly skipping commercials. Big Media is slow to adapt (surprise, surprise!), but is at least starting to recognise the revenue potential, so it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll fight against it. But the transition from network model (which provides funding and marketing for television shows) is at risk, given a more fragmented market.<br />
For us, this can only be a win-win. People want to make video, and we want to consume it. The question of <em>how</em> remains, and its only a matter of time before these bits of technology-in-infancy are replaced by more robust and &#8220;complete&#8221; systems that hide the mess of aggregation, bringing about a true &#8220;on demand&#8221; environment that has been promised for the better part of 20 years.<br />
As for our specific experience, we&#8217;ll keep you posted. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve got a Mac Mini to set up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada: You&#039;re about to lose your freedom</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 17:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ll keep this one short folks, I promise. Do you use the internet (even watching videos on YouTube and Facebook counts)? Do you use an iPod/iPhone/iWhatever? Do you watch downloaded movies? Are you a student (or thinking of going back to school)? Then you&#8217;d better pay very close attention, because your beloved Federal Government under &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada: You&#039;re about to lose your freedom"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ll keep this one short folks, I promise.<br />
Do you use the internet (even watching videos on YouTube and Facebook counts)? Do you use an iPod/iPhone/iWhatever? Do you watch downloaded movies? Are you a student (or thinking of going back to school)? Then you&#8217;d better pay very close attention, because your beloved Federal Government under Stephen Harper is about to <strong>pull the rug out from under you</strong>.<br />
If you somehow missed the bruhaha over the United States&#8217; failed SOPA bill, you cannot afford to miss Canada&#8217;s attempt at the same thing. We&#8217;re very close to passing bill C-11, a bill sponsored by big media (notably movie studios, the music industry, and publishing giants) who want to <strong>control the way you access your music, TV, and books</strong>. They want this control because they are unable to cope with the digital economy, and want the Government to create laws that heavily restrict your actions, and impose ridiculous punishment.<br />
Now I am no expert on these things, but I read someone who is: <a href="http://www.commonlaw.uottawa.ca/en/michael-geist.html" target="_blank">Professor Michael Geist of the University of Ottawa, the Canada Research Chair of Internet and E-Commerce Law</a>. (I mean, really, could you possibly get anyone better?) He has written some excellent articles on just how <em>bad</em> C-11 is &#8212; and has been very clear on how it could be improved so it&#8217;s not so terrible. (The Government, to no surprise, is not listening.)<br />
I offer you the following from Geist&#8217;s blog. The intros here are my paraphrased summaries of the articles.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6307/125/" target="_blank">Mr. Geist&#8217;s response to the CRIA (Canadian Recording Industry Association)&#8217;s op-ed saying that C-11 isn&#8217;t that bad (as you can guess, it<em> really is</em> that bad)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6033/125/" target="_blank">The politics behind why Canada is keeping digital lock rules that will greatly hamper fair use of video, music, and books. That means: no more funny YouTube videos, and good luck at quoting books or articles for your research papers.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6287/125/" target="_blank">The Canadian music industry threatens critics of C-11, effectively branding them as criminals. It&#8217;s the moronic &#8220;you&#8217;re either with or, or against us&#8221; stance.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6275/125/" target="_blank">Mr. Geist asks ten key questions of the various copyright agreements. The answers aren&#8217;t pretty.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6257/125/" target="_blank">What&#8217;s going on behind closed doors, and how these bills are ending up in our Legislature.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6264/125/" target="_blank">Could YouTube become illegal in Canada?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.michaelgeist.ca/content/view/6243/125/" target="_blank">How US lobbyists are pressuring the US Government to exclude Canada from international agreements because we haven&#8217;t bowed to their demands. Worse still, they refuse to allow for any cultural considerations (remember, we are a multicultural nation!)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And he also visited with <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/strombo/technology-1/soapbox-michael-geist-on-bill-c-11.html" target="_blank">Strombo on the CBC to talk about C-11</a>. It&#8217;s less than two minutes, and it explains just about everything. Even if you don&#8217;t read the above articles, <strong>you really should watch this video</strong>.<br />
In short, our beloved Government is refusing to adopt the perspective that they <strong>represent the Canadian people</strong>. They are preferring to listen to corporations and corporate associations, and worse still &#8212; <em>foreign</em> corporations who have <em>no business</em> dictating our laws.<br />
Okay, so what do you do?<br />
First, <a href="http://openmedia.ca/lockdown" target="_blank">sign up with OpenMedia&#8217;s petition</a>. It only takes a moment, and every single little bit helps. (SOPA died in the United States because the vocal backlash was loud enough.)<br />
Then, can I suggest sending the following text to the Rt. Hon. Stephen Harper (<a href="mailto:stephen.harper@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">stephen.harper@parl.gc.ca</a>), the  Minister of Industry and Minister of State (Agriculture) Hon. Christian Paradis (<a href="mailto:christian.paradis@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">christian.paradis@parl.gc.ca</a>) (he&#8217;s the Minister putting C-11 forth, and hence is responsible for our impending nightmare), Nycole Turmel (<a href="mailto:nycole.turmel@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">nycole.turmel@parl.gc.ca</a>) (she&#8217;s our official, albeit interim, Leader of the Opposition), Hon. Bob Rae (<a href="mailto:bob.rae@parl.gc.ca" target="_blank">bob.rae@parl.gc.ca</a>) (our most experienced elder statesman in Parliament), and <a href="http://www.parl.gc.ca/Parlinfo/Compilations/HouseOfCommons/MemberByPostalCode.aspx?Menu=HOC" target="_blank">your Canadian Member of Parliament</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p>Dear Gentlemen and Madams,<br />
I am writing to express my deep concern regarding Bill C-11, now put forth in our Parliament.<br />
While I am very much aware of the need to address copyright laws within Canada to ensure that they meet international agreements, the terms and conditions being put forth in C-11 appear to be overlooking the needs of the Canadian people, both in the present and in the future. These terms go far past those required by international agreement, and introduce unnecessary restriction and overly  punitive  damages.<br />
The proposed conditions are being driven primarily by corporations, and are also heavily influenced by foreign governments and foreign corporations who have no right to comment on Canada&#8217;s laws. The Canadian Federal Government is supposed to stand for its people, yet we are being considered last in this process.<br />
Please stop the blind approval of this damaging legislation and reopen it to Canadian legal experts who have offered wise and just opinion on how C-11 could still address the needs of Canadian law while not imposing unnecessary (and unfair) restrictions on law-abiding Canadians.<br />
Most sincerely,<br />
[Your name here. Please use a real one.]</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/02/canada-youre-about-to-lose-your-freedom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why SOPA will (and must) fail</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-sopa-will-and-must-fail</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 04:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why SOPA will (and must) fail"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Across the internet, the letters S-O-P-A have inspired a particular level of hatred and vitriol. Beyond the internet, the Stop Online Piracy Act has barely registered any significant presence within mainstream media. The reasons for this are &#8230; well, circumspect, especially given the damage that SOPA would bring to the internet. And this, my dear reader, is something that you do need to be aware of, as it may very well affect this very website.<br />
The Stop Online Piracy Act is a bill before the Government of the United States of America that proposes &#8212; in a general sense &#8212; a series of rules and penalties in an effort to eradicate online piracy. At a high level, it certainly seems like a reasonable request. In fact, so reasonable that anyone not spending time reviewing the details of the bill might very well have missed some of the more draconian measures being implemented, allowing &#8212; in effect &#8212; individual companies to disable outright any website they believe to be infringing on copyright without right of trial, so long as said website has some dependency on US-based services (which a tremendous percentage of websites have).<br />
In effect, a US company can shut down your otherwise legal operation because they&#8217;ve told their government that you&#8217;re the bad guy.<br />
Sound unfair? It should. But this, dear reader, is also where things get more sinister.<br />
The authors of this bill are members of the American government, but that&#8217;s not who is really driving it. The backers? Big media. Notably, the same companies who have been engaging in a futile, misguided, and often grossly misdirecting effort to have laws enacted to protect their business models. <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/76259944/SOPA-Supporters">Companies represented by the RIAA and MPAA, and a host of old companies who don&#8217;t want to change.</a><br />
They&#8217;re flailing, and failing. They&#8217;re unable to grasp the concept of digital media. They&#8217;re used to their physical world &#8212; one book to one person, one CD in one CD player, one VHS tape showing on one tube-based television set. The new world allows a single copy to be copied, cut, remixed, and displayed on millions of devices simultaneously. The media companies chime: &#8220;Show me the money.&#8221;<br />
But instead of adapting, they cry foul. They cry piracy. They claim that they&#8217;re losing money hand-over-fist, and they will expire without the assistance of new laws. Yet, they&#8217;re not losing money. In fact, many of the music labels are making more than ever, largely in part to Apple, who strong-armed them into making music cheap, and &#8212; to absolutely no surprise to any armchair economist &#8212; removed the barrier to entry, and sold music in such quantities that the music industry was very likely saved from imminent death.<br />
Hence, SOPA. And while the White House chosen to not sign the bill, there is no reason to believe it won&#8217;t be back in some other odious form.<br />
Beyond the American government, I have reason to also fear this bill because of the efforts of my own government. The Canadian government has thrice shown to be spineless in its resistance to these same groups lobbying for ridiculous legislation in Canada that would put our own culture and identity as unwarranted in terms of content ownership. Our politicians, who had in decades previous been those who stand only for its own people, now show to be bowing to massive foreign conglomerates, leaving its own people to suffer as a result.<br />
SOPA, and bills like it must fail. Because they are flawed in their consideration of evolution, because they fail to take digital commerce into account, and because they will unnecessarily bind our children into false agreements and behaviours that will haunt them their entire lives.<br />
If you are an American, please write your congressperson. If you are Canadian, please write your MP. In either case, don&#8217;t let your government become party to Big Media&#8217;s insanity, don&#8217;t let our future be dictated by corporations. Learn more at <a href="http://americancensorship.org/">AmericanCensorship.org</a>.<br />
Content yearns to be free. Not free as in ownership, but free as in freedom, free as in life. Let content live.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/why-sopa-will-and-must-fail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Switching from Shaw to Telus</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=switching-from-shaw-to-telus</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For those of you not already following the story, I&#8217;ve sworn off Shaw. As much as I am tied &#8212; nay, symbiotically attached &#8212; to the internet, I would have been quite willing to end the service at home with the continued lack of service I was receiving from Shaw. It was past &#8220;infuriating&#8221;, past &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Switching from Shaw to Telus"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those of you not already following the story, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/">I&#8217;ve sworn off Shaw</a>. As much as I am tied &#8212; nay, symbiotically attached &#8212; to the internet, I would have been quite willing to end the service at home with the continued lack of service I was receiving from Shaw. It was past &#8220;infuriating&#8221;, past &#8220;mind-bendingly torturous&#8221;, and I was way passed &#8220;pissed off&#8221;. We had to move, or I could have possibly killed someone. Consider that move a public service, folks.<br />
We moved to Telus. Not solely because they&#8217;re really the only other option in town, but partly because the new Optik service had proved highly appealing (nicer interface, and free PVR with long-term contract), and a very lucrative introductory offer combined with Shaw&#8217;s epic failure really cinched the deal.<br />
Not that it&#8217;s gone completely flawlessly&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2773"></span>If you followed the link above, you&#8217;ve already read that the install didn&#8217;t go according to plan. In fact, thanks to Telus&#8217; internal systems, it didn&#8217;t go at all. Telus was almost painfully apologetic about the incident, and has made strides to make up for the oversight. Nearly a month after calling, they did finally arrive, on the 29th, to set us up with brand-new service.<br />
The installer, Glenn, arrived just after 9:00 and proceeded to make sure he knew where everything was, notably the TVs, and the Telus phone panel. The TVs, easy to find. The panel? Not so much. Over the course of renovating the basement and a year and a half abroad, our phone panel had gone <em>missing</em>. And, equally inexplicable, the Telus line outside the house was completely cut. (We had a second cable, yes, but apparently both were Shaw &#8212; Shaw told us one was Telus.)<br />
Glenn had to run all-new wiring, which I viewed as a good thing. Sadly, for simplicity&#8217;s sake, it also meant running along the wall outside, since there was no easy way for it to enter the house where the Shaw line went in. It&#8217;ll be something we can live with for the time being, and when we do proper renovations upstairs, we&#8217;ll move it.<br />
Once inside, Glenn set to work removing the Shaw hardware (which is headed back to Shaw tomorrow &#8212; I wanted to wait a bit, and you&#8217;ll see why in a moment), and hooked up the DSL router (quite literally, a black box) and the Telus wireless router (a special one that allows TV signals to be routed as well). He then set up the PVR in the living room, and the set-top box in the bedroom. The two are networked via the cable and the wireless router (though I can&#8217;t see them on the network &#8212; the HDPA part of the network is invisible, sadly).<br />
Telus quoted four hours. Glenn was done in under three. Barely before he was out the door, I&#8217;d already set up the PVR to start recording every episode of <em>MythBusters</em> and <em>Dirty Jobs</em>. I also lobbed in a setting to start recording some of Monkey&#8217;s favourites, the ones Alex and I use when we need 30 minutes of peace.<br />
In theory, this should have been the ultimate end of Shaw. But knowing my luck, I opted to hang onto the Shaw stuff, just in case something else went wrong.<br />
Which it did.<br />
Two days after install. Suddenly, the TV and internet signals were gone. (The phone, now a hard-wired landline, continued unabated.) Alex called Telus, and after a short wait, was told to reboot both the DSL box and the wireless router. Boom, TV and internet were back.<br />
Problem solved, right?<br />
Sunday evening, same thing. Rebooted both DSL and router again, without calling Telus, and all was well. One time, I could understand. Two was beginning to look like a pattern. I swore that if it happened once more, I was calling Telus. Which I did, on Monday evening.<br />
I was talking to a human within five minutes. The problem was already flagged in their system as &#8220;reoccurring&#8221;, which apparently immediately afforded me a lot of attention. The first tech (yes, <em>first</em>) and I went over the scenario, and reset the system before he transferred me (and did the introductions) to the next guy, who worked with the hardware group. We proceeded to check the router settings and make sure that it wasn&#8217;t the problem.<br />
Which, he felt, it might be. Here&#8217;s where the Telus setup has a flaw: unlike Shaw, where you provide your own internal router, Telus has to provide one in order to deliver the TV service. The router, made by D-Link, has custom firmware to allow all the fancy stuff (namely the TV signals embedded in the DSL channels, and the PVR network). Part of that requires a bridging of wireless and wired networks. In theory, this is transparent to the user, and you&#8217;d never know. <em>In theory.</em> In reality, there&#8217;s a weird behaviour where wireless devices (notably Apple devices) are unable to see wired devices. Sort of like, say, an Apple TV trying to wirelessly sync with a wired computer.<br />
I discovered this through the wonders of the internet a few nights earlier, after I became unable to sync the Apple TV. This drove me to re-enable my Linksys router to serve the Apple TV, and routed the desktop computer appropriately. Boom, problem solved. But the second tech thought this could actually be a problem, where the two wireless routers were now fighting, and the Telus router might hiccup and hang. Odd, yes, but D-Link stuff (at least in my experience) has always been a bit &#8220;odd&#8221;, so I wasn&#8217;t surprised.<br />
Telus wireless disabled, and we moved on in life. Which meant tech #3, who worked in the networking group. He wanted to send out a tech to verify that the lines were okay. He felt it might be an issue. Seemed perfectly fine to me, so we set up an appointment. Total call time? Nearly 90 minutes. Very little of it on hold. I&#8217;ve been on short calls that had me really, really angry. After 90 minutes, you&#8217;d think someone had just given me a million dollars, I was so happy.<br />
Now I should point out that Glenn actually left us his card, with instructions to call if there were issues. In my (crappy) defence, I saw that only as a nice token, and that real work wouldn&#8217;t get done unless I called Telus. This was, after all, how Shaw has treated me for the last nine months &#8212; why should Telus be any different, right?<br />
J.P., the next service tech, came out and looked the place over. He did a couple of trivial things, checked the lines (and spent an hour doing so), and all seemed to be well. Emphasis on &#8220;seemed&#8221;. Sure enough, boom, the TV and internet dropped again. We tried calling J.P., but for some reason, we could never connect. Fortunately, Telus was very nice to set up a call for Saturday. Lo and behold, Glenn came to the door.<br />
Glenn was fairly well-briefed with the situation, and having already been to the house, was familiar with the setup. His thought? The card at the other end &#8212; the part that our line eventually plugs into to access the Telus network. He swapped it, and that was pretty much it. In my view, this makes sense &#8212; it was the DSL modem locking up, and if it was losing sync with the network because the card was faulty, it would explain why we were having trouble.  That was almost five days ago, and we haven&#8217;t had a single issue since.<br />
And because so many people have asked, here&#8217;s how I net out Telus&#8217;s offering thus far:<br />
<strong>TV</strong>: Mildly irritated that I have to get the next package up to get my <em>MythBusters</em>, but the extra channels are kinda nice. The ability to search for a TV show is the killer app, here, and the only real improvement would be to allow recording for a given show across any channel, not just one.<br />
<strong>Internet</strong>: Po-tay-toe, pah-tah-toe &#8212; roughly the same as Shaw, and I&#8217;m in no screaming need for insanely fast internet. I just don&#8217;t (ab)use it enough at home to need it. 15 down, 1 up is plenty for my needs.<br />
<strong>Phone</strong>: Landline. Enough said.<br />
<strong>Service</strong>: Here&#8217;s the real deal-breaker, kids. So far, Telus is <em>lightyears</em> beyond what Shaw had offered me. They&#8217;ve actually reestablished my faith in the telecommunications industry, and make me feel like they&#8217;re listening to my concerns and have a <em>genuine</em> interest in repairing my problems. The issues cropped up two days after install, and were resolved just over a week later (I hope). Telus&#8217;s staff have treated me with dignity, kindness, and respect (even talking techie with me once they realise that I do know what I&#8217;m talking about), and have been very good with promptness and callbacks. And the two-hour window (opposed to Shaw&#8217;s five-hour window) makes planning life a lot easier.<br />
So far, I&#8217;m glad we switched. I hope it stays that way&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2773</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the frying pan&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=from-the-frying-pan</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 04:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Before we returned to Calgary last December, we did a fair amount of investigation into what services we would get at home. In particular consideration were television, internet, and phone service. (In my ideal world, it would have also included cellphones, but no-one does the full bundle in Calgary &#8230; yet.) After an extensive amount &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "From the frying pan&#8230;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before we returned to Calgary last December, we did a fair amount of investigation into what services we would get at home. In particular consideration were television, internet, and phone service. (In my ideal world, it would have also included cellphones, but no-one does the full bundle in Calgary &#8230; yet.) After an extensive amount of investigation, cost comparison, and service review, the only real option (at the time) was <a href="http://www.shaw.ca">Shaw Communications</a>.<br />
Some nine months later, I&#8217;m ready to heave Shaw out the door like a long-overstayed houseguest, and welcome in a new tenant: <a href="http://www.telus.com/">Telus</a>. Since our last major investigation, <a href="http://telus.com/content/tv/iptv/">Telus has rolled out a new television service</a> (which, at least from reports, is quite good) and is taking on Shaw toe-to-toe to steal and cajole whatever marketshare they can. In theory, it&#8217;s a buyer&#8217;s market.<br />
There&#8217;s only one problem: both of them have serious service issues.<br />
<span id="more-2763"></span>For those of you following <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey">me on Twitter</a>, you know <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/23173872117">I made this decision to change</a> back at the beginning of the month. This was a result of the last service fiasco with Shaw, after our internet and phone (Shaw implements a VoIP system that goes over the same cable as the TV and internet) up and died without warning at the end of August. We went on vacation, unable to call Shaw (we were literally leaving the next day, and no-one would have been here to resolve the questions), with a faint hope it might be resolved while we were gone. Hey, it <em>could</em> have been a line issue.<br />
Yeah, and my grandmother was a Chinese fighter pilot&#8230;<br />
Not unexpectedly, the phone was still out when we got back. This precipitated some of the most infuriating conversations I&#8217;d yet had with Shaw. Okay, in their defence, I was calling during a long weekend. That&#8217;s fair, and I&#8217;ll grant them the lower staff/higher call volume than usual. But Shaw has no message telling you how long you&#8217;re going to wait, and their &#8220;scheduled callback&#8221; service was never presented as an option.<br />
First call, I waited about 30 minutes to talk to someone. The tech calls this a &#8220;recurrent issue&#8221;, and says we get to jump the queue a bit. I think: <em>Fantastic! We&#8217;ll get this resolved quickly!</em> Only problem: They have to check for when someone can come, but will call me back.<br />
There&#8217;s no call the remainder of the day, or the following morning. At 11:20, I call Shaw again to find out when/if we&#8217;re going to see someone. The tech says that &#8220;a message was left&#8221;, and that we&#8217;d see someone between 8 and 12. That morning. Oh, did I mention that we were not at home at the time? The tech says that they guy hadn&#8217;t come yet, and would be arriving closer to noon. We flew home, only to find the lovely green ticket that says: &#8220;Sorry we missed you.&#8221;<br />
It should have said: &#8220;Sorry, we&#8217;re idiots&#8221;.  I called Shaw again, just short of spitting fire. Wait time? Nearly <em>45 minutes</em>.<br />
Shaw Tech: We left you a message!<br />
Me: How?<em> We have no phone!</em><br />
Shaw Tech: (Silence, while checking) Confirmed, sir, we left   you message at 403-XXX-XXXX.<br />
Me: (Stunned silence. The phone number they gave me was my old cell number, <strong>disconnected in 2008</strong>, before moving to Costa Rica. This is a new Shaw account. I have no idea how the hell they got that old number.) That number hasn&#8217;t existed in over two years.<br />
Shaw Tech: (Silence) I&#8217;ll put in an urgent request. Someone will call you with a time.<br />
Me: At what number?<br />
Shaw Tech: 403-YYY-YYYY. Oh, that&#8217;s your home number. It doesn&#8217;t work, right?<br />
Me: (Gumbling.) Correct.<br />
Shaw Tech: Do you have another number we can call you at?<br />
At this point, I&#8217;m continually reminding myself that I once had this guy&#8217;s job years ago, when I did computer tech support, and had to deal with people as irate as I was acting. But, still, there&#8217;s a certain amount of logic that&#8217;s just not being followed. Of course I have another number &#8212; <em>how the hell do you think I&#8217;m calling you?!</em><br />
The next day, still without any update on time, we&#8217;re in Garrison Woods running errands. I&#8217;ve taken the Monkey and Choo Choo down to the playground, a good 10-minute walk from the car and Alex. Which, of course, is exactly when Shaw calls me to tell me that the technician will arrive at our house sometime between 12 and 5 &#8230; which is in just over <strong>15 minutes</strong>.<br />
A 15 minute warning. Thanks, Shaw, for recognising that people never leave their houses, and are always available for when you decide to get around to showing up.<br />
I abort all activities, resulting in the Monkey crying all the way back to the car, embarrass the hell out of Alex (who&#8217;d arranged and pre-paid for Monkey&#8217;s haircut, and now had to get a refund), and break a few laws trying to get back home before the Shaw technician arrived. (Which, incidentally, wasn&#8217;t for a couple of hours.) Thanks for that, Shaw. I love torturing my family to support your  asinine  business practices.<br />
The technician gets to work, and after a while pronounces things fixed. The first thing he says: &#8220;The last technician didn&#8217;t know what he was doing.&#8221; Funny statement, that &#8212; it was the <em>same thing</em> the previous three technicians told me, almost word-for-word. Which says to me to believe that a) Shaw hires people who don&#8217;t know what they&#8217;re doing, and b) are missing massive opportunities to win confidence with their customer base.<br />
Example: (Shaw, you paying attention?) Every time I called Shaw to ask what was wrong with my internet, they&#8217;d tell me how they could see that the modem had been &#8220;flapping&#8221;. Well, here&#8217;s a thought, Shaw &#8212; if you have the ability to see the flapping, maybe you should write a few programs to check for flapping modems and preemptively schedule service calls so people think you&#8217;re paying attention, preventative, and not constantly trying to clean up after yourselves.<br />
Oh, and I really hate the underlying message of all that, too: &#8220;It&#8217;s not my fault. Don&#8217;t blame me.&#8221;<br />
After that, I was done. Past done. The very next thing I did was call Telus. (It also helped that we had a card from Telus with a really-hard-to-argue introductory offer, which would save us a lot of money over the first year.)<br />
And this, folks, is where I thought things would get better. I really should learn <strong>not</strong> to be an optimist &#8212; it just sets you up for disappointment.<br />
Today, we were to have a new Telus installation. But by noon, there had been no installer, and Telus had promised a window between 8 and 10. I called Telus, and was left with a poor woman who bore the brunt of my rapidly-rising frustration.<br />
Telus: There was a problem with the order, sir.<br />
Me: A &#8220;problem&#8221;? What does that mean?<br />
Telus: We couldn&#8217;t put the order through. We have to cancel it.<br />
Me: Cancel? What? Why didn&#8217;t someone call me?<br />
Telus: I don&#8217;t know, sir. We have to cancel it.<br />
Me: (Feeling very forlorn, and thinking I&#8217;ll have to stay with Shaw.) So I don&#8217;t get the pricing deal?<br />
Telus: You still can have the pricing, sir. We just have to re-enter the order.<br />
Me: (Forlorn gone. Frustrated again. I go on a rant about my little experience.)<br />
Telus: I&#8217;ll escalate this to a manager, sir. They&#8217;ll be able to help you much more easily. You can expect a call in about four hours.<br />
So I wait. Four hours. I&#8217;ve already waited nearly two weeks, because Shaw requires seven business days to release the phone number (we&#8217;re porting it over). Four more hours, and a bit of hope that before this weekend is out, I&#8217;ll have a hard-line I can trust again. <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/24781148324">I tweeted my experience</a>, since I know a few people have been following this little escapade. I get a response from <a href="http://twitter.com/TELUSsupport">@TelusSupport</a>. I like these guys &#8212; they helped me with my cellphone problem a couple of months ago. End result: have to wait for the manager to call.<br />
When the manager calls, I receive an apology for the trouble that actually sounds sincere. She explains what happened &#8212; a breakdown in their internal systems that caused part of the order to fail, but didn&#8217;t raise any alarm &#8212; and immediately offers to correct the situation, along with sizeable credit on the account. There&#8217;s two more calls, the net result of which has a new install date, on 29 September.<br />
Why the wait? Well, there&#8217;s still that 7 day wait period with Shaw, and because of the internal kafuffle, the entire order has to be restarted. It&#8217;s going to be nearly a month from start to finish. &#8220;Frustrated&#8221; doesn&#8217;t begin to describe how I feel. I made sure the manager also knew that using the word &#8220;cancel&#8221; with a customer was a poor choice of word, regardless of Telus&#8217;s internal terminology, and even offered a replacement.<br />
And then I went on a rant with the poor woman.<br />
Okay, so here&#8217;s the deal, Telus: you&#8217;re on a short leash. You&#8217;ve screwed up pretty badly, and are catching the brunt of my troubles with Shaw, to boot. Don&#8217;t make me angry. You won&#8217;t like me when I&#8217;m angry. (And yes, there are places to go beyond you.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2763</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The end of the individual experience</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/the-end-of-the-individual-experience/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-end-of-the-individual-experience</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/the-end-of-the-individual-experience/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 22:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few years from now, my kids will be old enough to ask me questions that will require a lot of explanation. Like, for example, what the internet was like when I was their age, how I survived without a mobile data device, did I watch TV in black and white (interestingly enough, I did, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/the-end-of-the-individual-experience/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The end of the individual experience"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few years from now, my kids will be old enough to ask me questions that will require a lot of explanation. Like, for example, what the internet was like when I was their age, how I survived without a mobile data device, did I watch TV in black and white (interestingly enough, I did, but only because the TV was black and white), and what did I name my pet dinosaur (&#8216;cuz, you know, every kid makes that joke of their parents).<br />
One question I also expect them to ask is how I watched TV without having my computer in front of me, firing off notes through Twitter, Facebook, or whatever social media network will be in vogue in 5-8 years from now. I&#8217;ll look at their cute, adorable little faces, and tell them as seriously as I can: There was a time when we watched TV on our own. We went to sporting events in small groups, we went shopping without telling everyone what we were doing, and we could vanish for hours on end without anyone knowing where we were.<br />
The idea that we exist solely as individuals is rapidly becoming extinct.<br />
<span id="more-2633"></span>I&#8217;ll freely admit that I&#8217;m on the leading (okay, okay, <em>obsessive</em>) edge when it comes to Twittering et al. I&#8217;ve been broadcasting status updates (in one form or another) for a couple of years, in frequencies varying from every few days to every few seconds &#8212; those of you following me during the 2010 Olympic Men&#8217;s Ice Hockey gold medal game or during last night&#8217;s Oscars know what I mean. That means I&#8217;m not only keenly aware of the potential these services offer, but also the potential impact.<br />
Let me rewind a couple of weeks to the start of the Olympics on 12 February. While most of you watching the opening ceremonies might have had a word or two between you, there were a few of us (I&#8217;ll estimate at least a few thousand) who were offering up our views as the show proceeded. In real-time. Publicly. You could track the entire thing under <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_(metadata)#Hash_tags">hashtags</a>, or even by following a few people.<br />
As the Olympics proceeded, the effect only continued to grow. For me, it was a way of communicating &#8212; and to some degree, even participating &#8212; with the games through friends who were actually there. (Of particular note is Canada&#8217;s unofficial Lucky Charm, my friend Katrina, who was present for no less than two gold medal wins.) It was a real-time feedback, and a way for me to feel that I wasn&#8217;t just trapped here in Calgary, unable to witness it for myself.<br />
And lest we forget the Olympic Men&#8217;s Ice Hockey gold medal game between the USA and Canada. All epic-ness of the game aside (I stand by my statement that the game is the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Summit_Series">Summit Series</a> of my generation), the game probably produced the largest amount of Twitter and Facebook traffic from Canada this year (and that includes all events yet-to-come). You almost didn&#8217;t have to watch the game on TV (although, really, it was one of the best-ever hockey games) &#8212; follow a few people, and you almost got the play-by-play, along with healthy doses of (<a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/9795031562">periodically profane</a>) comments about plays, shots on goal, and so forth. The only thing that would have made it better is if <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_Cherry_(ice_hockey)">Don Cherry</a> were tweeting it.<br />
Which, interestingly enough, was what happened last night on the Oscars. Except it wasn&#8217;t Don Cherry, it was <a href="http://twitter.com/ebertchicago">Roger Ebert</a>. Though not nearly as copious with comments as I had expected (he was live-blogging as well, which I didn&#8217;t have access to), events were still punctuated with exceptionally-timely thoughts, all backed-up with his decades of experience in the industry.<br />
Okay, so what does this all mean?<br />
I didn&#8217;t watch alone. I might have been alone in the room, in front of my TV, but my network of friends and contacts kept me company. For years, people had talked about interactive TV as being a major shift in the industry, but to virtually no fruition. The act of side-conversation might not be the interactive we all had in mind, but imagine the joy of side-discussions (and even trash-talking) with people who have the same interest, without the ugliness of having to pack everyone into a small room at once.<br />
I don&#8217;t see this ending soon, either. While I don&#8217;t watch a lot of TV (I generally avoid everything except <em>MythBusters</em> and <em>Dirty Jobs</em>), this sort of thing would definitely play out for regular sporting events (hockey, football, basketball, and even &#8212; dare I say it? &#8212; golf), reality shows like <em>Survivor</em> and <em>Big Brother</em>, soap operas, and similar genres that tend to collect an obsessive and conversational bunch (imagine if <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em> or the rebooted <em>Battlestar Galactica</em> came out now).<br />
And, of course, this goes beyond televised events. People in the stands of the game, people following poker tournaments, people watching parades, let alone <a href="http://network.nationalpost.com/np/blogs/posted/archive/2009/12/17/u-s-geological-survey-uses-twitter-to-track-earthquakes.aspx">people broadcasting the latest disaster</a> (follow the <a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23temblor">#temblor</a> hashtag sometime &#8212; <a href="http://twitter.com/USGSted">the USGS does</a>).<br />
This is the promise of social media, folks. We always thought it was just about bringing people together. In reality, it&#8217;s about keeping us from feeling alone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/the-end-of-the-individual-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2633</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Make April 1 &#034;IE6 Dies&#034; Day</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=make-april-1-ie6-dies-day</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 18:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the moment, IE6 still holds about 20% of the market (according to today&#8217;s metrics from NetMarketShare). That&#8217;s far too large a share for a 8.5 year old browser, especially one that has been  superseded  by successive releases of its own code by two versions. It&#8217;s far too much for a browser that costs too &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Make April 1 &#34;IE6 Dies&#34; Day"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the moment, <strong>IE6 still holds about 20% of the market</strong> (<a href="http://www.netmarketshare.com/browser-market-share.aspx?qprid=2">according to today&#8217;s metrics from NetMarketShare</a>). That&#8217;s far too large a share for a 8.5 year old browser, especially one that has been  superseded  by successive releases of its own code by two versions. It&#8217;s far too much for a browser that costs too much to support, and despite several service packs still bears significant security issues. It continues to haunt the internet, acting like a lazy bouncer allowing the seediest of activities to go on unchecked.<br />
I propose <strong>April 1st be &#8220;IE6 Dies&#8221; Day</strong>.  It&#8217;s time that IE6 be shown the door. But we&#8217;ll need help.<br />
<span id="more-2574"></span>This isn&#8217;t the first time people have called for IE6 to go away. But previously, these were developer-led challenges, all of which met the same problem: <strong>we&#8217;re not the ones who get to make that decision</strong>. All a client needs to do is pull out a report from their stats engine to prove why they need it. (Or simply open their company-issued laptop to show the IT-mandated browser.) Going against this kind of weight, we&#8217;re lost.<br />
<strong>We need to go the other way.</strong> Not to the browser makers (they&#8217;re on our side), but to the people offering services that people want to see. Want to punish a child? Take away its access to its toys.<br />
We need to call out to the Big 3 search engines. <strong>Google, Bing, and Yahoo: Block access to IE6.</strong> And I don&#8217;t mean provide a subtle hint page, I mean block it entirely. With a big, bold page that says:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;font-size: 1.5em">We&#8217;re sorry, but your browser is no longer supported. Please upgrade to one of the following [insert browser list here]. If necessary, please contact your IT department.</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s already on this path. Microsoft has encouraged upgrades to IE8. Yahoo hasn&#8217;t really said anything yet, but I imagine they&#8217;ve thought something similar. Take these three pages away, and you <strong>cut off a primary tool</strong> that millions of IE6 users go to daily. With these unavailable for no reason other than a browser update, it should help drive that final spike into the heart.<br />
So why April 1? Well, there&#8217;s the obvious reason: IE6 has been &#8220;fooling&#8221; us for far too long, and it&#8217;s time that we prove that we&#8217;re not fooled any longer. But a bigger reason is time: Namely, <strong>give companies some warning</strong>. The upgrade cost can be  significant, and companies need time to get things in place. Frankly, they&#8217;ve had enough, but a sudden stop without warning can cause some pretty major headaches. (I may be a jerk, but I&#8217;m not without sympathy for IT teams, having some good friends who do IT, and having enough IT to respect the problems they solve.)<br />
I can&#8217;t do this alone. For this to work, <strong>we need as many people as possible</strong> to spread the message. Tweet/retweet this message as much as you can (please use the hashtag #ie6diesday, if possible). Send them this message:</p>
<blockquote><p>Dear Search Provider,<br />
Due to the on-going security and support problems with Internet Explorer 6, I would like to suggest that you consider April 1 &#8220;IE6 Dies Day&#8221;, and block IE6 from accessing your search engine. There are many other options and alternatives. http://bit.ly/bZTUej<br />
Sincerely,<br />
[Your name here]</p></blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s some quick links to get you started!</p>
<ul>
<li>Yahoo: <a href="http://help.yahoo.com/l/us/yahoo/search/indexing/webmaster-01.html">http://help.yahoo.com/l/us/yahoo/search/indexing/webmaster-01.html</a> and <a href="http://www.ysearchblog.com/">http://www.ysearchblog.com/</a></li>
<li>Google: <a href="http://www.google.com/support/contact/bin/request.py?bdpg=1&amp;hl=en">http://www.google.com/support/contact/bin/request.py?bdpg=1&amp;hl=en</a> and <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/">http://googleblog.blogspot.com/</a></li>
<li>Bing: <a href="https://feedback.discoverbing.com/default.aspx?productkey=bing">https://feedback.discoverbing.com/default.aspx?productkey=bing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Spread the news. Let&#8217;s convince the search engines that <strong>it&#8217;s time for IE6 to die</strong>, once and for all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2574</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
