<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cars &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/cars/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 06:31:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A new year, a new car</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/01/a-new-year-a-new-car/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-new-year-a-new-car</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/01/a-new-year-a-new-car/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 06:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Alex and I picked up our new car. And it&#8217;s new, not a previously-enjoyed vehicle. It&#8217;s a 2016 Honda CR-V. Yes, it&#8217;s an SUV, the very thing I often rail against. It&#8217;s not even our first. (More on both of those in a bit.) It was not a decision taken lightly, I assure you. It&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/01/a-new-year-a-new-car/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A new year, a new car"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, Alex and I picked up our new car. And it&#8217;s <em>new</em>, not a previously-enjoyed vehicle. It&#8217;s a 2016 Honda CR-V. Yes, it&#8217;s an SUV, the very thing I often rail against. It&#8217;s not even our first. (More on both of those in a bit.) It was not a decision taken lightly, I assure you.<br />
It&#8217;s a bit of a weird feeling having such an expensive new toy, even though it is still (kind of) the Christmas season. It&#8217;s also weird trying to talk myself <em>out</em> of going for drives, as all I really want to do is get in the car and drive around. Given that I spend most of my travel time in busses and trains, feeling the urge to drive is definitely a change for me.<br />
It&#8217;s a good change. And a bit overdue.<br />
<span id="more-3521"></span><br />
Since the end of 2009, when we returned to Canada from Costa Rica, we&#8217;ve been driving a 2006 VW Jetta TDI as our primary family vehicle. It was a purchase we started before we&#8217;d even stepped foot back home, knowing that we <em>needed</em> a car to exist within Calgary. (Yes, it&#8217;s possible to do everything by transit, I can&#8217;t deny that. But ask anyone who&#8217;s tried that with young children, and they&#8217;ll give you a look that is generally only seen in George Romero films.)<br />
Even discounting the emissions issues with VW diesels that erupted in 2015 (and our car technically wasn&#8217;t on the list, though I suspect after all this, we have the same engine as the newer models), we had issues with the Jetta. The single biggest issue was its size: it&#8217;s small. Or to be more specific, too small.<br />
Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I don&#8217;t like big cars. I never have. And in this city, we have a plethora of oversized vehicles driven by people with undersized brains. So my personal dislike of large cars is compounded by the perception that &#8220;if you drive an SUV, you&#8217;re a moron&#8221;. Needless to say, I resisted the push for an SUV for many, many years.<br />
Which is hypocritical of me. We have owned an SUV before. When we lived in Costa Rica, we needed a car. (Calgary is difficult without a car; Costa Rica was borderline impossible without a vehicle.) And due to the road conditions (which are pretty iffy when you get out of the city), we opted for a 4&#215;4 (all of us who went down initially did the same): a small, red Suzuki Vitara. And though I hate to admit it, that was a great little car. In many ways, I really wish we could have brought that one home with us (the costs associated with that were so prohibitive to erase all thought).<br />
I went &#8220;green&#8221; when I came back, and I wanted something that would sip fuel. (Yes, I do realise in hindsight that I buggered the math with emissions.) Hence, the diesel vehicle. Which at the beginning, made sense. But as the years wore on, and the kids got bigger, things didn&#8217;t seem quite so clear.<br />
Then, on 30 October 2013, things changed.<br />
We&#8217;d gone for dinner at our favourite Vietnamese Restaurant, Pho Huong Viet, and were returning home. I was driving. There was one car in front of us, waiting to turn onto 17th Ave SW. I was scanning east and west, to see how long it might take for us to get onto the road, which at that hour was still quite busy.<br />
Out of the corner of my left eye, I caught a flash. Turning, I found it wasn&#8217;t an emergency vehicle, it was a car moving far too quickly for the road (a posted limit of 50 km/h). The car&#8217;s lights suddenly appeared in the far lanes, swerving around a pair of cars, the lights owner naturally following. The car fishtailed around the cars, sliding back into the eastbound lanes, barrelling towards us at a speed I could only believe to be around 100 km/h. The car fishtailed again, likely an overcorrection, and it started to head back into the westbound lanes. In the span of only 4-5 seconds, the car had appeared in my field of vision, slid through it, and <a href="http://www.660news.com/2014/02/23/charges-laid-in-october-fatal-crash/">drove nearly head-on into a late model Jeep Grand Cherokee</a>.<br />
The car, an older Dodge Neon, spun wildly, bounding up on the north shoulder of the road. The Grand Cherokee, spun about 270 degrees, and roughly faced us. I was the only one in the car who witnessed the accident. Alex and the kids only saw the aftermath. Alex called 911 immediately. The police and fire department &#8212; both barely a few hundred metres down the road &#8212; were on the scene in moments.<br />
The Neon was barely recognizable, having its front end mangled. The shock had managed to ripple through the car, distorting the rear end. Four people had been in the car; three of them died on the scene. The fourth, the driver, survived. So far as I know, he&#8217;s rotting in jail for a very, very long time. (I nearly testified at the trial, before the defence realised that a trial was stupid, and went with the guilty plea.) There is still a cross and flowers tied to the fence next to the point where the Neon came to rest.<br />
The Grand Cherokee nearly looked like it could drive away. The front end still looked like a Cherokee, though a bit banged up. The airbags had all gone off, and I imagine the engine was likely dead. But we could see the car&#8217;s occupants &#8212; mostly older women &#8212; and they all looked alert and uninjured.<br />
Based on that event, very nearly bought an SUV the following weekend. The only thing that stopped us was our financial analyst at the bank, who told us (wisely!) that it was an &#8220;emotional purchase&#8221;. She strongly urged us to reconsider, until our Jetta became a burden.<br />
That happened the first time we went camping with the girls. The car was so full, they had things shoved under their feet. We&#8217;d officially maxed out the Jetta&#8217;s capacity. We had to buy a roof rack and a roof bag to carry the extra things. The extra volume on the roof sucked away every advantage of a diesel engine.<br />
We revisited the decision to buy a larger car. Which meant pulling out the spreadsheet I&#8217;d originally made back in 2013 to determine which car made sense. I&#8217;m a numbers guy. I like numbers because they can be added and subtracted and compared, unlike an emotional attachment, which can be a real twerp to deal with. And when you add in numbers from the IIHS, JD Power, Consumer Reports, Transport Canada, and so forth, you can end up with a pretty powerful matrix of options. And, most importantly, undercut the ridiculous marketing that goes into selling cars.<br />
Have I mentioned that I spend several years working on the digital marketing for Mercedes-Benz USA?<br />
That&#8217;s how we came to look at the Honda CR-V. And while we did look at the pre-loved ones, in the end I wanted a warranty, and none of the questions of what the previous owner had done to it. (Our Jetta&#8217;s clutch plate exploded six months after we bought it. Nothing like a $2,000 repair to really make you hate used cars.)  It wasn&#8217;t the best warranty in the biz &#8212; and yes, that was also a factor in the calculations &#8212; but it was certainly good enough for our needs.<br />
But even before we stepped into one, Alex found the one she wanted, on the dealer&#8217;s website. She wanted it because it was brown. (I deal with numbers, Alex deals with aesthetics. I argue that they&#8217;re equally important.)<br />
So on 28 December, we went over to the local Honda dealer to have a look-see at an actual CR-V. The one in the showroom didn&#8217;t put us off one bit, and if anything, answered a lot of the nagging questions about options, size, and in-person appearance. We were soon met by the salesman, who immediately twigged my &#8220;newbie&#8221; alarm. After a couple of decades of working with high-pressure sales people (on both sides of the fence), this poor guy stood out as a junior member of the sales team. That said, he had a decent personality, and didn&#8217;t piss me off. So went for a drive.<br />
The second biggest issue I have with the Jetta is that it&#8217;s not really designed for life in Canada. I&#8217;m always turning off the traction control, because I see it as a liability when you&#8217;re in snow. (It&#8217;s a manual. Why on Earth someone set up a manual car to have such a poor traction control baffles me.) When we took the CR-V onto the road, it had been snowing for twelve hours. There was 4-6 inches of fresh snow, the roads were white and slippery. I <em>gunned</em> it rounding onto Sarcee Trail, just to see what the car could do. I could about hear it laughing at the mostly-frozen slush as it tore onto the covered road. Alex took over after I pulled off, and took it onto some slippery, nasty surfaces.<br />
The car sold itself. Between the features (our requirements: heated front seats, and all-wheel drive, though the car came with much, much more) and the performance, there was little else that we needed to know.<br />
Then the sales guy made the classic &#8220;the sale is done&#8221; move, and tried to get us to start signing papers. It bothered me because we hadn&#8217;t actually said &#8220;yes&#8221; to anything. We&#8217;d asked about trade-in value on the Jetta (I knew it was going to suck; we were offered a mere $1,500), and somehow that had translated into a sales process. That wasn&#8217;t to say that we weren&#8217;t interested, but the shifting of gears (yes, pun intended) didn&#8217;t sit with me.<br />
As it happened, we had an appointment to meet, and couldn&#8217;t handle paperwork at the time, anyway. We would return later that afternoon, at which point, we went into more detail. And then pulled the proverbial trigger. And braced for the inevitable increase of several thousand dollars on an already-expensive vehicle.<br />
That&#8217;s not to suggest we have buyer&#8217;s remorse. We don&#8217;t.<br />
I research things when I look to spend more than $100 on something. Unless there&#8217;s a clear reason to go with one option, I like to know what the pros and cons are. So we walked into this one well-informed. We&#8217;re also two-income family, so it&#8217;s not a financial burden (our other cars are both paid off, and we don&#8217;t carry credit balances), so those numbers spoke just as loudly as the ones that said the car was safe.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Today, Alex and I walked over to the dealership, the plate from our Jetta in-hand, to pick up the CR-V. It&#8217;s &#8220;Kona Coffee&#8221;-coloured (aka &#8220;brown&#8221;), with chrome bits in various places. So when one of the kids (I can&#8217;t remember which) suggested that we call the new car &#8220;Chewbacca&#8221;, it seemed very appropriate. They hadn&#8217;t seen the car until we picked them up in this afternoon, and have been pretty excited about it ever since. Which is good, because Monkey didn&#8217;t do well with the news that we were going to sell Jedi (yes, that&#8217;s the name for the Jetta) &#8212; it&#8217;s the car our kids know best.<br />
The real question now is: where do we go next with it? I&#8217;m itching for a road trip&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/01/a-new-year-a-new-car/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3521</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A funny thing happened on my way home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 17:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Ed. Note: I&#8217;ve stripped out a bit of unnecessary bit at the beginning, and it was suggested that I sanitize it for sensitive eyes&#8230;] So last week, I was huddled with my mom back in Oakville, Ontario. No, I didn&#8217;t publicize this because &#8212; and utterly no offense meant to anyone &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A funny thing happened on my way home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[Ed. Note: I&#8217;ve stripped out a bit of unnecessary bit at the beginning, and it was suggested that I sanitize it for sensitive eyes&#8230;]</em><br />
So last week, I was huddled with my mom back in Oakville, Ontario. No, I didn&#8217;t publicize this because &#8212; and utterly <em>no</em> offense meant to anyone &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to see anyone but my Mom (and by extension, my sister and her family).<br />
The story here isn&#8217;t the journey to Oakville, or even the events in Oakville. This is about my trip home to Calgary.<br />
<span id="more-3182"></span>To maximize all the time I could get with Mom, I booked an early morning departure from Calgary, and the last possible flight home. The last possible flight departed from Toronto (as normally scheduled) at 21:45, via WestJet (I don&#8217;t fly Air Craptastic anymore, unless I have <em>literally</em> no other option). This meant I could do visiting, and have a (mostly) relaxing flight back.<br />
Murphy, it seems, stowed away in my luggage.<br />
First off, there was a heavy snowfall warning in Calgary yesterday. This normally leads to massive delays (and cancellations) at the airport &#8212; hell, even <a href="http://www.calgarysun.com/2012/06/14/storms-stall-flights-at-calgary-airport">a good thunderstorm can screw things up for hours</a>. So I started watching the (online) arrivals board constantly, looking for problems.<br />
(Side note, airports <em>and</em> airlines: Honestly, get your mobile support for your websites figured out. I want to <strong>RELOAD</strong> a page frequently, not resubmit a <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> form. Also: checking a flight status should always be prominent on your mobile home page. ALWAYS. And yes, <a href="http://calgaryairport.com">calgaryairport.com</a>, you need a mobile version. Badly.)<br />
The day, however, seemed to go well in that respect, and the worst that happened was a posted 30 minute delay on my flight, because the equipment in use was inbound from Cancun (and presumably incurred a delay there). Half an hour is annoying, not brutal.<br />
Cathy was very kind to drop me off at the airport (in lieu of a taxi); I had her drop me off early so I could get some more work done while waiting for the plane (I also knew she wanted to get home and relax herself, and the earlier she was home, the better). I had hoped to hang out in a bar, notably the Mill St. Brewery, which has a brewpub at Toronto Pearson.<br />
Problem: Mill St.&#8217;s pub is in Terminal 1. WestJet flies from Terminal 3. I wasn&#8217;t keen on hopping terminals, just in case the flight got bumped to a different plane, and the times changed. That left Fionn McCool&#8217;s, an &#8220;Irish&#8221; pub just beyond security. I use the term &#8220;Irish&#8221; only in the sense that the term is what&#8217;s used to set expectations &#8230; every single one of which McCool&#8217;s missed. As I commented last night, <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271422493133262848">the place was grossly lacking in authenticity</a>.<br />
The beer seemed half-strength in every possible meaning, and they somehow produced <a href="https://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271427759346180096">sweet potato fries without any discernible flavour</a> whatsoever. Now, given, I was officially sick (exactly where I&#8217;d obtained said illness is a matter for pointless debate), so yes, I could chalk that up to dulled sense, I suppose. But I can&#8217;t, because I knew damn well I could taste the &#8220;spicy mayo&#8221;, which was &#8230; well, I dunno what was in it, and I&#8217;m not sure I want to. Saving grace, at least <a href="https://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271428334095826944">the staff there was so unorganized</a> that I didn&#8217;t have to pay for the fries.<br />
The plane for our flight didn&#8217;t arrive until nearly 20 minutes after time we were supposed to <em>depart</em>. It was another 40-45 minutes (honestly, I stopped keeping track) until we boarded (I half-expected WestJet to just cancel the flight and reschedule for the morning).<br />
My highlight of the night? WestJet&#8217;s satellite TV. Discovery Channel. Three hours of <em>MythBusters</em>. I&#8217;m somewhat ashamed to say I passed out for about 30 minutes of one episode. (I&#8217;d been up since 6am; I was exhausted.)<br />
We landed in Calgary just after 01:00 MT, taxied to the terminal, and headed down to get our bags. The moment I hit the baggage claim &#8212; the carousel hadn&#8217;t even started yet &#8212; I was on the phone with the Alberta Motor Association (our provincial branch of the CAA), to arrange for someone to come and unlock the car so I could go home.<br />
Oh, right, I didn&#8217;t get to this part yet. Lemme rewind a couple days.<br />
On Monday, it was realized that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Allen and Jean (who&#8217;d come out to help Alex with the kids while I was gone) needed a way to get to the airport.</li>
<li>The process in which I&#8217;d driven to the airport, and deposited the keys with left luggage so Allen could pick up the car when he arrived in Calgary, had worked splendidly.</li>
<li>It would cost about $120 for two taxi rides (Allen and Jean to the airport; myself home).</li>
<li>Wouldn&#8217;t it make sense to do another car exchange? (Even with a $10/day parking fee.)</li>
</ol>
<p>Well, there were some logistical issues. Notably: left luggage closes at 23:00, and I wasn&#8217;t (originally) due until midnight, thus making key exchange difficult to the point of impossible. (Well, without running fear of theft, anyway.)<br />
The major problem was how to get into the car. I needed a key. After some back-and-forth, it was decided to mail the key to me in Oakville. Well, not so much &#8220;mail&#8221; as &#8220;least expensive couriered option possible&#8221;, since an overnight package for a mere <em>car key</em> would have been &#8212; <em>wait for it</em> &#8212; nearly $80. Which is a bit much. End result: two-day package with Canada Post, which &#8212; in theory &#8212; had enough time to arrive.<br />
Now, I have to say &#8220;in theory&#8221; because that requires Canada Post to actually <em>deliver</em> the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> thing. Which, <em>three days</em> later, they still haven&#8217;t. The tracking information says it&#8217;s only been accepted in Calgary. So far as we know, it <em>still hasn&#8217;t left the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> city of origin.</em><br />
EPIC. FAIL.<br />
Realizing this at 13:00 MT on Wednesday, we started Plan B. Which, oddly enough, was not to just take a taxi (which was my original preference, as I figured I&#8217;d be dog tired by the time I got in, and struggling with a car wasn&#8217;t on my list of things I wanted to do). Instead, I figured this was an excellent time to do something I&#8217;d been seriously considering for a while (but hadn&#8217;t done), and sign up for AMA again. We&#8217;d let our old membership expire when we moved to Costa Rica, and driving around with two kids was starting to worry me about having a car problem. (I&#8217;d had one before &#8212; thankfully solo &#8212; which was my first regret for not having the membership.)<br />
$90 later, I had a membership number, and a backup in case the key didn&#8217;t show. Which, as of 19:00 ET last night, it still hadn&#8217;t. (As of 09:30 MT today, <em>it still hasn&#8217;t</em>.)<br />
I called AMA as soon as I could because I figured it&#8217;d be a long wait, especially with all the snow. The agent confirmed that: roughly an hour and a half, but they&#8217;d seen calls answered in as little as 55 minutes. Either way, I had a while to wait.<br />
I got my bag, found a bench, and tried to occupy myself doing things that didn&#8217;t involve using my iPhone, because I needed the battery to hold its charge long enough to get the call and meet with the AMA truck.<br />
(Side note #2: My iPhone&#8217;s battery went <em>way</em> longer in Oakville than it does in Calgary. What the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> is up with that, Rogers??)<br />
The call came 26 minutes later. I was actually shocked. It was an automated call saying the truck would arrive in 10 minutes. So I grabbed the bags, bundled up for the -14 degree weather, and went to go find the car. Which, as my father-in-law had stated, was pretty much where I&#8217;d left it a week earlier. (How&#8217;s that for good parking karma?)<br />
The truck arrived about 10 minutes later, as promised. The first words out of the driver (whose name, regrettably, I don&#8217;t think I ever got) was: &#8220;Is that a 2003?&#8221;<br />
We have a 2006 Jetta TDI. It&#8217;s a decent car. (Read: Not a &#8220;great&#8221; car. It works. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d recommend it as a purchase. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d buy another one.) But apparently, Jettas are some of the hardest cars to get into, notably because of the security systems and the electronic locks, and 2003&#8217;s are particularly dicey. The driver, conferring with his AMA experts (who seem to know damn near everything), determined that the 2006 shouldn&#8217;t be too bad, and we should be able to open it. So, yay, we&#8217;re off to the races.<br />
Or so we thought&#8230;<br />
Getting the jimmy in the door wasn&#8217;t too hard. After that &#8230; well, the driver was stumped as to why the locks weren&#8217;t disengaging. If you&#8217;ve never seen a door jimmy, these are pretty interesting things. It&#8217;s basically a sturdy steel wire shaped with a big U, with a bent end and a metal tab that looks not unlike a guitar pick. The U part lets the tab duck under the window (which is assumedly raised, &#8216;cuz why else would you need someone to open the damn door), and then with some deft twisting, you press the tab into the door lock button, and presto! the door opens.<br />
Except that it didn&#8217;t.<br />
And wouldn&#8217;t.<br />
No matter what the guy did, the door just sat there, laughing at him. And worse, he <em>had</em> to get the door open, because he needed his tool back, and you <em>can&#8217;t remove the tool if you can&#8217;t open the door</em>.<br />
Did I mention that it was well after 02:00, -14 with a northerly wind, with lots of blowing snow? And this guy had frostbitten hands? (And my gloves were not meant for that cold.)<br />
We huddled back in the truck, letting the blasting heat warm us up a bit. The guy hopped on the radio to discuss other options.</p>
<ol>
<li>Break the window. Thanks, but no thanks. I did not want to pay untold (large) sums of money for a new window. I&#8217;d rather wait for the key to be returned, and pay the extra days to get it out of the lot.</li>
<li>Get a locksmith to break in. See above, but even moreso on the &#8220;no&#8221; side, merely for expense alone.</li>
<li>Tow the car to a dealership and let them get into the car. Still involves a lock, see above notes for cost.</li>
<li>Try the longer tool again?</li>
</ol>
<p>In addition to the jimmy was a long (also very sturdy) metal rod that could be squeaked through the door (with an inflatable &#8220;jack&#8221; to move the door over a little), in hopes it could do a better job. The first one (he had two) hadn&#8217;t really done that great of a job, and had little effect. But after a pep talk, and a bit of hunting to find the &#8220;bigger&#8221; rod, we decided for one last shot before calling it a night. Early morning. Way too tired to really know which is better&#8230;<br />
Anyway&#8230;<br />
Bigger rod inserted (no euphemisms, please), and more fishing, pressing, hoping, and attempting to shine the light in the right place.<br />
POP!<br />
Two grown men, shouting like high school football players. That&#8217;s what you would have seen at 02:50 in the Economy Lot of the Calgary Airport Authority, just next to the #8 pole. Holy <em>crap</em>, were we ecstatic!<br />
Swearing profusely, I managed to dig the key out of the trunk (I had to pull down one of the seats; the narrowest one, of course) and use the flashlight app on my phone (so glad I have one, and why isn&#8217;t this a built-in feature?) to retrieve the key that was, of course, as far away as it could possibly be from me. The car, realizing that the game was finally up and there was no more point in resisting, started without complaint.<br />
The tool was removed, hands shook, bags loaded, car scraped (mostly) clean of the snow and ice, and home headed towards.<br />
Hmm.<br />
I titled this &#8220;A funny thing&#8230;&#8221;, didn&#8217;t I?<br />
Oh well&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
