<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pets &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/pets/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 17:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>How to bring a pet into Costa Rica: Simplified</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, so a while back I was having kittens (pun intended) about bringing Asia into Costa Rica. Mostly because I simply could not seem to get a straight answer from anyone about the proper process. It was driving me batty. So, to anyone bringing in their (small) dog or cat (this might also work for &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to bring a pet into Costa Rica: Simplified"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so a while back I was having kittens (pun intended) about bringing Asia into Costa Rica. Mostly because I simply could not seem to get a straight answer from anyone about the proper process. <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/">It was driving me batty.</a><br />
So, to anyone bringing in their (small) dog or cat (this might also work for rabbits, but don&#8217;t expect success with gerbils or hamsters or any form of rodent; and it&#8217;s a one-way trip for all birds, you can&#8217;t take them out again) into Costa Rica, allow me to present the (current) process. It&#8217;s really easy.<br />
<span id="more-1005"></span></p>
<ol>
<li>Check with your government&#8217;s agricultural agency (the Ministry of Agriculture in Canada, for example) and find the International Health Certificate. (There is an American equivalent from the Department of Agriculture, but I&#8217;m not sure what it&#8217;s called.) Print it out.</li>
<li>Go to your vet, and ensure that your cat/dog has all their most recent vaccinations. Get documentation about all of it. It&#8217;s important, you&#8217;ll need it when you arrive. You&#8217;ll also need the vet to fill out the specifics of the aforementioned International Health Certificate, which they also need to sign.</li>
<li>In Canada (I can&#8217;t say for certain with the United States), you&#8217;ll need to schedule an appointment with the Ministry of Agriculture to have them sign the document as well, and stamp it to make it official. This is necessary &#8212; without this form, your pet will not be joining you.</li>
<li>Bring the pet with you on the plane in a carrier that fits under the seat. Not all airlines will do this anymore &#8212; Continental Airlines still does. Air Canada does not. This way, you can be assured that the pet is with you when you arrive, and does not go automatically into quarantine.</li>
<li>When you arrive in customs, you need to go to the Agricultura desk (it&#8217;s easy to see) and have them look over the papers. Provided you are not bringing the animal in for resale (e.g. it&#8217;s not merchandise), it&#8217;s a quick stamp, a scribble in the register, and you&#8217;re free to go &#8212; no duty required.</li>
</ol>
<p>Notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>If your pet does not fit under the seat and/or must travel cargo (with you on the same flight), the process might be the same, provided you can collect your pet with your luggage. I&#8217;m not sure, as I didn&#8217;t see any other pets there.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re bringing in animals for resale, expect to pay a duty.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1005</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enroute with the cat</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=enroute-with-the-cat</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 20:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, we&#8217;re on our way. I was up until almost midnight last night packing. Was originally thinking three bags, but went down to two. Which is good, because apparently I&#8217;d have been denied the third bag. As it stands, the backpack was overweight by three lousy pounds, so I got stuck with an extra bag &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Enroute with the cat"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we&#8217;re on our way. I was up until almost midnight last night packing. Was originally thinking three bags, but went down to two. Which is good, because apparently I&#8217;d have been denied the third bag. As it stands, the backpack was overweight by three lousy pounds, so I got stuck with an extra bag fee and an overweight fee.<br />
Where the heck did all these fees come from? It even costs me $100 to get the cat on the plane. Three and a half hours later, I&#8217;m in Houston, with a cat in a bag. Tried letting her out at the &#8220;Pet Relief Area&#8221; over in Terminal B, but all she wanted to do was hide in the tropical plants. I&#8217;m not even sure if she relieved herself at all.<br />
Lunch was at Ruby&#8217;s, while Asia watched people go by. She&#8217;s been exceedingly good, and hasn&#8217;t had one freak-out as a result of all this. Whether or not she&#8217;s still in one piece when we get to our hotel in Costa Rica is another question.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1003</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bringing my cat into Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re bringing Asia with us. Not the continent; she&#8217;s our cat. We don&#8217;t want to part with her. She&#8217;s a wonderful pet and truly part of the family. She was our first baby before Mi Ni単a Peque単a came along. Giving her up is just not an option. Getting her through the border is the trouble. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Bringing my cat into Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re bringing Asia with us. Not the continent; <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2142575972/in/set-72157603438169851/">she&#8217;s our cat</a>. We don&#8217;t want to part with her. She&#8217;s a wonderful pet and truly part of the family. She was our first baby before Mi Ni単a Peque単a came along. Giving her up is just not an option.<br />
Getting her through the border is the trouble. Mostly because there is no de facto source of information on how this is done properly. What I have found is confusing and very contradictory. For someone who is going to be spending 12 hours with an annoyed kitteh (LOLCat spelling) &#8212; she might be stuck in that cage the entire time &#8212; I need to know that getting into the country isn&#8217;t going to kill her.<br />
Or me.<br />
<span id="more-982"></span>On <a href="http://www.sailcharbonneau.com/Sailing%20With%20Pets/QuarantineImport.htm">three</a> <a href="http://www.costarica.com/Trip-Planning/Travelers-Info/Pets%10Animals/">separate</a> <a href="http://www.costarica.com/Blog/2006_09_01_archive.html">pages</a>, I found that it really boils down to needing the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>A pet health certificate (that includes the original rabies vaccination document) provided by my vet, and signed by (in Canada, anyway) the Ministry of Agriculture.</li>
<li>A personal letter stating the value of my cat. (Highly debatable, since Asia was a stray, and her &#8220;value&#8221; was the adoption fee.) I think this is mostly if you went out of country to buy a pet, then came back in.</li>
<li>Proof of payment of the Pet Customs Duty. This is related to the previous item (I think), and is not always applicable.</li>
<li>A Pet Quarantine Permit issued by the Ministerio de Agricultura y Ganaderia (Ministry of Agriculture and Animal Control).</li>
</ul>
<p>The last one is the catch. Apparently, you can&#8217;t get that unless you&#8217;re in Costa Rica. But you need the papers from your vet to get the permit. And you can&#8217;t get the pet through the border without the permit. Seems very chicken-and-egg in nature (segue: &#8220;chicken and egg&#8221; is a bad metaphor; the egg came first, long before the chicken evolved).<br />
Colour me worried.<br />
So I did more digging, including calling Javier in Costa Rica to ask him. I figured he&#8217;d gone through this with the three gorgeous dogs that he has. Turns out, I was right, but he did it differently, where he shipped the dog in. And the above applies. He had a friend, however, who flew back with a puppy.<br />
Turns out that if you fly with your pet, all you should really need is the documentation from your vet, and signed by the appropriate animal control authority (the Ministry of Agriculture, in my case). Within 10 days of travelling, of course.<br />
All I have to do now is figure out if I can actually get down there with Asia on-board. I suppose in the worst-case scenario, she ends up in a quarantine for a little while. I would really hope to avoid that, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">982</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
