<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>butterflies &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/butterflies/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 03:53:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A trip to La Paz</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/a-trip-to-la-paz/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-trip-to-la-paz</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/a-trip-to-la-paz/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 03:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkeys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2212</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Our time is dwindling in Costa Rica, Monkey. Our little experiment draws to a close in just over a month. That&#8217;s five weekends (not counting the one we just had &#8212; that would have made it six). Our Costa Rica &#8220;bucket list&#8221; is a little longer than we&#8217;d like, and there are just things we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/a-trip-to-la-paz/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A trip to La Paz"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our time is dwindling in Costa Rica, Monkey. Our little experiment draws to a close in just over a month. That&#8217;s five weekends (not counting the one we just had &#8212; that would have made it six). Our Costa Rica &#8220;bucket list&#8221; is a little longer than we&#8217;d like, and there are just things we are not going to get to see. It&#8217;s a little tragic, considering how long we&#8217;ve been here, but I guess this is what happens when the joys of life sometimes hold on a little harder than with others.<br />
Being in good shape (namely, none of us was sick), we decided to take a little journey north to <a href="http://www.waterfallgardens.com/">La Paz Waterfall Gardens</a>. It&#8217;s listed in all the tour books as one of the places &#8220;you must visit&#8221;, and we&#8217;d waited more than long enough to go.<br />
We kinda had to wait, though. It took them a while to rebuild&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2212"></span>You probably don&#8217;t remember <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/">the earthquake from back in January</a>. Grandma had left for Calgary just that morning, when suddenly the ground shook. I was at work, and was fairly freaked out &#8212; mostly to make sure you and Mommy were okay.<br />
But what we felt was nothing compared to what La Paz had experienced. Being barely a kilometre from the earthquake&#8217;s epicentre, <a href="http://www.waterfallgardens.com/quake/index.html">the earthquake had done a considerable amount of damage</a>. So much so that the park only reopened back in July, and almost half of the trails still remain closed. We couldn&#8217;t even see two of the <a href="http://www.waterfallgardens.com/lapaz-waterfalls.html">four waterfalls</a> there &#8212; one of which is the the most famous there, and the park&#8217;s namesake: La Paz.<br />
Mind you, we didn&#8217;t know that until we got there. And as the saying goes, getting there is half the fun. We drove up through Cuidad de Alajuela, winding towards the Poas Volcano. Having remembered this from back in January, I sort of knew where to turn to find La Paz. The trip itself was beautiful wound through the farmlands on the slopes of Poas, as well as on the north side of the Central Valley mountains.<br />
At one point, we got stopped as a small herd of cows were being driven down the road. As we could do was stop and let them pass by, mooing softly.<br />
The closer we got to La Paz, the more the terrain became affected by the earthquake. Even though it&#8217;s been over 10 months since the quake hit, repairs are still on-going &#8212; and likely will be for years to come. The hills are being sculpted carefully, presumably to prevent the massive slides that killed all those people, and destroyed countless kilometres of roadways. The massive red-brown terraces made it feel like we were driving through an open-pit mine. Many of the roads were reduced to dirt and gravel, with pockets of torn asphalt.<br />
We arrived at La Paz about 90 minutes after we&#8217;d left Santa Ana. It was, and remains for now, the end of the road. The road from there through towards Arenal is apparently impassible, and is blocked by large boulders. La Paz seems to be at or near the edge of the cloud forest, as we saw the familiar white wispy tufts wafting in from the valley beyond.<br />
The cost to enter La Paz is steep. It&#8217;s US$35 per adult. We knew it was expensive before we went there, but we knew it was some place we wanted to go. I didn&#8217;t tell Mommy the full price until we were inside, and after I&#8217;d managed to use the bathroom. The bathroom was pretty neat &#8212; it had a waterfall instead of a tap. I really should have taken a picture of it.<br />
We walked down the stairs, watching as workers continued the reconstruction of the buildings above us. We walked over to the Aviary, which was our first exhibit. The aviary was full of birds that we&#8217;d never seen &#8212; or not seen easily. Some were very small, barely larger than some of the sparrows back home. As we went further in, we saw four ducks that seem to fly around inside, perched right next to a hawk and what looked like some kind of eagle.<br />
Soon, we found the toucans, which were in a larger building along with parrots and what Mommy and I are calling &#8220;love birds&#8221;. The toucans are in a very large cage, which have a pair of doors so you can go inside with them. This was something neither Mommy or I had expected.<br />
The first time Mommy and I saw a toucan was before we were married. We&#8217;d come to Costa Rica for her birthday in 2005 (it was that trip that led to us moving here in 2008). We&#8217;d gone on a hike through the forest on the south side of the Arenal Volcano. Our guide, Oscar, claimed to have seen a toucan well over a kilometre away, and had shown us through a telescope. I never thought I might get to see a toucan any closer.<br />
You might not remember this, Monkey &#8212; we have video to prove it to you, though &#8212; one of La Paz&#8217;s staff sat a toucan right on my arm. They are absolutely beautiful birds and despite their massive beaks, these were very tame. You didn&#8217;t want a bird on your arm. I can&#8217;t say I blame you.<br />
There were some bright red macaws outside the hut, as we headed towards the butterfly conservatory. You&#8217;ve seen butterflies before, Monkey, and in far greater quantities than at La Paz. (I would probably put La Paz at #4 &#8212; maybe #3 &#8212; on the best butterfly places we&#8217;ve seen in Costa Rica. It&#8217;s not bad, but it wasn&#8217;t really great.) In fact, I think you were a little bored having to see butterflies <em>AGAIN</em>. You were far more interested in the sloths, and in what I think was a small anteater.<br />
We would have left fairly soon after arriving had it not been for the sudden downpour outside. And with our umbrellas in the car (short-sighted decision making on your parents&#8217; behalf), going outside was not a wise idea. Thankfully, the rain was short-lived (only about 10 minutes).<br />
Next up? Your favourite: The monkeys. You love monkeys, Monkey. You saw the white-face capuchins almost as soon as we left the butterfly conservatory. You called them &#8220;baby monkeys&#8221;, which I can only assume is because of your baby/mommy stuffed monkey. Some of them seemed to rush over to the edge of the cage, as if to say &#8220;hi!&#8221;. Mommy found one that seemed to almost dance when it saw you.<br />
Next to the capuchins was a cage with spider monkeys. One of them, you called &#8220;momma monkey&#8221;, which Mommy and I couldn&#8217;t really understand. We laughed nonetheless. I thought it looked more like Chewbacca than anything else (wait a couple of years, and this will make more sense &#8212; I promise!).<br />
Then down the stairs to the hummingbirds. La Paz has a series of feeders, and the entire area buzzed with small and large(r) birds all whizzing around. It was definitely something else to see as all these birds vied for time at the feeders.<br />
Further down the hill, we came to the &#8220;ranarium&#8221;, which is where we found the second of your two most favourite animals: frogs. La Paz does a rather neat trick with their frog display &#8212; they let the frogs move about in a room filled with large-leaved plants, and then affix little signs with clips to tell you where the frogs are, and what species. None of them really moved while we were there, unfortunately, so we could only get the picture of them all curled up.<br />
After a short walk, we came to a small wooden building, in front of which were a pair of bulls pulling an old-fashioned colourful coffee cart. Mommy and I put you in the cart, and then you and Mommy went for a short ride around the circular garden that was there. Mommy felt like she was going to fall out, but you seemed to love it.<br />
Then came time to see the waterfalls. After all, why go to La Paz and not?<br />
This was when it became really apparent that we couldn&#8217;t see everything. Only Temple and Magia Blanca&#8217;s trails are open &#8212; the others are still undergoing safety repairs. Still, it was a lot of steps down just to see Temple. (<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/">But it was infinitely easier than when we went to La Fortuna!</a>) The earthquake damage was still clearly visible there, too &#8212; the greenery of other pictures I&#8217;ve seen was largely reduced to rock and soil. It might be decades before it looks as good as it once did.<br />
We decided not to see anything else and walked all the way back up. The man at the top of the stairs &#8212; who I think was actually La Paz&#8217;s owner &#8212; said you were a brave girl for climbing all those stairs!<br />
We continued up the path to the Jungle Cats exhibit. Sadly, not much to see as the cats were &#8230; well, doing what cats do best: sleep. That is, except for one cat. Either a mountain lion or a cougar. Admittedly, I&#8217;m not sure which it is. This cat had been curled up in a log, sleeping soundly, until you came by. You were probably calling out &#8220;kitty, kitty&#8221;, when it opened its eyes and looked at you. Wherever you loved, it kept looking at you. Sizing you up. Deciding if you would be a good meal, or just a snack, I can only presume. Mommy told the kitty to &#8220;forget it&#8221;.<br />
Lunch was next. From there to the restaurant for a fairly pricey meal (7-8,000 colones for each of Mommy and I). The food was good, though, and you did eat a lot. You also made some friends. As we decided what to eat, a man younger than me walked over and asked to take your picture.<br />
This is not the first time we&#8217;ve seen this, and Mommy and I are getting used to the fact that you attract a lot of attention. Let&#8217;s be honest, Monkey &#8212; you&#8217;re insanely cute and blond. It attracts a lot of people. You liked the first man, though &#8212; you weren&#8217;t much impressed by the others. Something I found a little amusing.<br />
We stopped by the monkeys again after lunch, and one of them came right over to see you. If it hadn&#8217;t been for the double caging, the two of you might have been able to touch each other quite easily. The monkey seemed to like you &#8212; though hopefully not the same way the cougar did. It seemed cold and unhappy, which is not unsurprising. Although the cage is very large, and offers lots of room, it&#8217;s not the same as being in a jungle.<br />
We went back through the butterfly conservatory to the aviary, as Mommy wanted more pictures of the toucans. (I wish I&#8217;d done the same, having seen my pictures now, and they&#8217;re just not as good as I&#8217;d hoped for. Such is life.) We headed back up to the main building, where Mommy got you a bracelet. You won&#8217;t be able to wear it for a couple of years, but maybe it&#8217;ll help you remember your life in Costa Rica.<br />
The trip back was foggy and wet &#8212; it rained most of the time. You don&#8217;t remember &#8212; you slept almost all the way back into Alajuela. We saw where construction is still ongoing, as they try to fix all the roads. Some areas probably still look no different then when the earthquake hit. It&#8217;s a scary sight.<br />
Next weekend should be different again! When Grandpa and Granny get here, we&#8217;re going back up to Villa Blanca again. You&#8217;ll see more hummingbirds, and you&#8217;ll get to spend lots of time with Grandpa, too! And with any luck, Mommy and I will get to relax a little.<br />
[flickr]set:72157622589446293[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/a-trip-to-la-paz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2212</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A (wet) birthday vacation</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-wet-birthday-vacation</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 04:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1464</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, I just turned 37 &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit. It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A (wet) birthday vacation"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/07/im-not-old/">I just turned 37</a> &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit.<br />
It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I doubt you&#8217;ll ever see that much rain ever again.<br />
<span id="more-1464"></span>The planning for this little sojourn was long, convoluted, and more than a little painful. Especially given all that I was looking for was a few days away from Santa Ana, to see something new in Costa Rica, and to spend time with my family &#8212; something I don&#8217;t get to do nearly enough of, which is something I deeply regret with each passing day.<br />
Ultimately, it was decided that we&#8217;d go to Arenal. This would be your second time to the area, and Mommy and my third trip. (It will likely be our last for a very long time. I&#8217;m now officially quite tired of Arenal.) I had told Nana that she&#8217;d get to see a volcano (and hopefully see it erupt at night), that we&#8217;d stay at a really nice place, and that the Arenal area was fantastic.<br />
Given <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/">our previous trip to Arenal</a> (and the one before that), it seemed a fairly decent and honest thing to say. It would appear, however, that Uncle Murphy had also come along for the ride. You remember Uncle Murphy &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/04/dear-murphy-fuck-off-and-die/">he&#8217;s the one who takes our plans and ruins them every time</a>.<br />
The trip up was reasonably nice. You fell asleep along the way, despite playing with Mommy quite a lot, somewhere around the Los Angeles cloud forest. Nana was watching all the hills and valleys, lush with rainfall, while I watched for all the lunatic drivers. I&#8217;m not used to driving such distances during the week &#8212; I&#8217;m usually at work worrying about network traffic, not oncoming cars.  You woke up only after a short pee break somewhere north of La Tigra.<br />
We arrived in La Fortuna somewhere around 14:00, and I rather foolishly thought it would be a good idea to check in to our hotel first, rather than do the smart thing, which was eat. You will learn, Monkey, that your father is often none-too-bright and does some really stupid things. (Mommy will remind you of this quite often, I&#8217;m sure.) We finally got to the restaurant somewhere near 14:30, and didn&#8217;t eat until nearly 15:00.<br />
Given that your father (that would be me) had hoped for a really nice dinner that evening, it wasn&#8217;t exactly the wisest thing. I made it even less wise when we went in search of the ice cream shop Mommy and I had found when we&#8217;d first gone to Arenal in 2005 for Mommy&#8217;s birthday. It wasn&#8217;t where we thought it would be (it had moved), but it was nice. We put you in a little kid&#8217;s ride that looked like a double-decker bus. You didn&#8217;t like it one bit.<br />
Returning to our hotel &#8212; the <a href="http://arenalparaiso.com/">Arenal Paraiso</a> (where we had a nice little two-suite cabin, ironically number #404) &#8212; both you and I went down for a short nap. You were a little overdue, and I was plain wiped. (The last many weeks of work have sapped much of my energy, prompting the time off, and the drive had taken a big punch out of me, too.) Mommy woke us up at 17:00.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737015049[/flickr]<br />
I had decided that we would eat at The Springs, a new hotel that had opened in the Arenal area only eight months earlier. My friends (and co-workers) Mark and Denise had stayed there a month or so ago, and swore the quality couldn&#8217;t be beat. They neglected to also tell us the state of the road, which was something near &#8220;unpassable&#8221;. (It&#8217;s a wonder they could build the place with roads that bad.) The three kilometre(-ish) trip took nearly 20 minutes, and was very bumpy.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737020375[/flickr]<br />
The hotel is right out of Disney World in terms of engineering, marvel, appearance, and professionalism. (Hopefully by the time you actually read this, Monkey, you&#8217;ll have been to Disney World and have some idea what the heck I&#8217;m talking about.) Due to my previous mistake, I didn&#8217;t get the dinner I wanted. Instead, we had the buffet (this was mostly to benefit your current eating habits, I should point out). It was very good, and the service was beyond outstanding.<br />
(A note to anyone thinking of going to the Arenal area: If you can afford it, <a href="http://www.thespringscostarica.com/">I highly recommend The Springs Resort and Spa</a>, it is truly amazing.)<br />
That night, as we all laid in bed, Uncle Murphy arrived to join us. Along with near-three solid days of torrential rain. It was also the first of three very sleepless nights for me.<br />
The next morning, we drove down to the restaurant for dinner. We drove because the rain would have soaked us to the bone, and because Nana would have had trouble walking that far on a rain-slicked road. The buffet was typical Costa Rican, with gallo pinto, fruit (papaya, pineapple, and watermelon), scrambled eggs, and various breads. Mommy, Nana, and I each had two cups of coffee.<br />
The problem was what to do with our day. It was, after all, raining quite a lot. So we decided the only thing to try was do some shopping. We headed into La Fortuna, hitting a woodwork studio, children&#8217;s clothing store, two or three souvenir shops, and you and Mommy ran up and down a ramp three times. The rain becoming quite the hindrance, we returned to the car to seek more adventure.<br />
Again with the brilliant planning, I thought we&#8217;d search out a German bakery that I&#8217;d read about in the Tico Times a few months ago. All I knew was that it was west of Fortuna along the shores of Lake Arenal. Which, in theory, is enough. And based on what I saw on maps, looked to be pretty straight-forward.<br />
Right?<br />
Well, one thing Costa Rica maps are notorious for is the lack of detail &#8212; notably when the map indicates a straight (or relatively straight) line, but the actual road is weavy and windy, and what should take no more than 30 minutes ends up being an hour-long trip. So about 20 minutes into the trip, we turned around and headed back. (Mommy had a massage appointment at 13:00, and we didn&#8217;t want her to miss it.)<br />
Instead, I (again, using my ever-so-powerful intellect) decided that we&#8217;d do lunch at the Arenal Lodge, which was just before the road over the dam. The rain kept pouring, and we were traveling up a steep, wet, mossy, and windy road barely three kilometres long that took us about 10 minutes to travel. Thankfully, we have four-wheel drive on our little Suzuki.<br />
Lunch was rather disappointing. The Lodge might be a neat place (it&#8217;s VERY out of the way), but the food is something less-than-desirable in my book. (My caesar salad was watery and lacking in flavour, and my ceviche tasted too much like fish and not enough like ceviche.) And it rained. A lot. To the point where when it was time to leave, I went to get the car rather than subject the three of you to walking through it.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737820576[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737825284[/flickr]<br />
While Mommy went to her massage, you and I went to splash around in the pool. It would be the only time you and I would go swimming over the last five days, sadly. I had hoped for much, much more than that. When Mommy returned, we all headed back up to the cabin so you could have a nap.<br />
Mommy got a recommendation for a restaurant downtown in La Fortuna called <a href="http://www.donrufino.com/">Don Rufino</a>. From the outside, it&#8217;s not the fanciest-looking place &#8212; in fact, it looks like every other bar in La Fortuna. But the food &#8230; the food! I was beside myself. I ordered a tuna dish that came with jumbo shrimp. Even though there were no vegetables, I was in heaven. (I&#8217;d been wanting a tuna for a very long time.) I think the only one who wasn&#8217;t over the moon with their dinner was you, Monkey.<br />
It rained all through dinner, all that night, and right into the next morning.<br />
We had thought that it might be fun to take Nana out to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>. Which was a risky venture, given the rain, but there&#8217;s very little to do in Arenal that doesn&#8217;t involve going outside. The drive involves a 8-9 kilometre-long, very rutted, very pot-holed, very bumpy road. Nana wasn&#8217;t particularly thrilled with it. (You almost fell asleep twice.) But once again, Mommy and my &#8220;Rain Luck&#8221; kicked in, and for the time we were at the Conservatory, it didn&#8217;t rain. We even learned a few more things thanks to a couple of volunteers from Seattle who could give us a bit more information we didn&#8217;t have last time.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737830482[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737834892[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737047843[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737055589[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737855464[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737087559[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3740775171[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3741617198[/flickr]<br />
It was raining by the time we got back to the main road. Mommy and I had booked a zip-line for that afternoon, but somewhere 12:45 became 13:15 (or vice versa) and we ended up missing our trip. It rained all that afternoon. In fact, while you were napping, the rain came down so hard that the gutters overflowed and we literally had waterfalls come off the roof. I became horribly depressed about the weather, missing the zip-line, not being able to do anything else, not being able to sleep, and so forth.<br />
[flickr]photo:3741594030[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was at Don Rufino again, not having any other better idea (and I&#8217;d ruled out eating at the hotel). It was the bright spot of my day. You didn&#8217;t eat at all.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737094433[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737893582[/flickr]<br />
Rain. All night.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737902800[/flickr]<br />
The next morning Mommy and I were supposed to go on our re-booked zip-line. But the non-stop rain was putting that to an end, once and for all. Despite being here a year, I have yet to actually zip-line through the canopy. At the rate I&#8217;m going, I might never get a chance.<br />
I was so put off by the weekend that I basically forced us to breakfast, so we could check out and leave. I had no desire to spend another minute in the rain. The only stop we made heading out of town was so Nana could get a couple of gifts for those back home.<br />
Had the rain not actually stopped as we&#8217;d headed south, I might not have had my coup de grace in bad ideas and passed right by the Fortuna Waterfall. However, with the break, I thought there might be a salvageable moment in the weekend.<br />
Sorry Monkey, your father will never learn.<br />
After you travel up the half-paved, half-bumpy road to the waterfall park&#8217;s parking lot, you pay US$10 each, and then walk along &#8220;600 metres of well-maintained path&#8221; to the observation point. What they do not tell you, in any way, is that the path includes a 100+ metre drop into the canyon, down one of the toughest staircases I&#8217;ve ever climbed. Nana (rather wisely) gave up only 1/5 of the way down. Mommy decided that she couldn&#8217;t go any futher than about 40 metres down before she stopped &#8212; she and you never got to the bottom to see the waterfall up-close. I was there for a mere five minutes before going back up to rejoin you.<br />
[flickr]photo:3744396992[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743603157[/flickr]<br />
For the record, you didn&#8217;t climb the stairs. We carried you. Why the heck we thought it was a good idea to bring you when Nana was at the top is beyond me. Instead, we lugged 20 kilos of wringling dead-weight up and down wet stairs.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737910724[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3737124555[/flickr]<br />
Worst. Idea. Ever.<br />
By the time I got the top again, my heart pounded so hard I could hear it, my chest was heaving, and my knees were so weak I was terrified that they&#8217;d give out and I&#8217;d drop you. About the only thing I had going for me was my pig-headedness to not giving up. I could barely walk. (Today, my legs are so sore I can barely climb stairs at all.)<br />
The rain started up again as we hit the road south to San RamÃ³n. You fell asleep not long after.<br />
At this point, Mommy took over decision-making, and wisely took us to a place neither you or Nana had been to before &#8212; Villa Blanca. Mommy and I had gone there for Mommy&#8217;s birthday in January, and she had gone again with her friend Erin back in May. Although it meant an extra 20 minute drive along another windy (but not nearly as bumpy) road, we arrived at a cloud-filled and peaceful place.<br />
For the first time in days, I actually felt good. It was quiet and calm. All I wanted to do was sit on a bench and let the clouds drift over me, taking away all the crappy feelings that had been building up for weeks.<br />
Lunch was, as expected, fantastic. You even ate most of your lunch, and even a little bit of Mommy&#8217;s.<br />
The drive home was marked only by the usual retinue of morons on the Pan American who don&#8217;t understand the concept of lanes or allowing others to pass freely when you&#8217;re driving too slowly. (Mommy was not pleased at my driving, and rightly so.) We got home in one piece.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737937674[/flickr]<br />
I tried to make dinner that night &#8212; pupusas. They were pretty lousy, unfortunately. There&#8217;s gotta be a different technique that I need to learn. You didn&#8217;t eat anything, again. I was the only one who actually seemed to eat dinner &#8212; either everyone else wasn&#8217;t hungry, or my dinner was horrible.<br />
For my last day off before going back to work, we&#8217;d decided to try going into San José. But at breakfast, you would barely eat anything you normally like &#8212; even toast &#8212; and you made it sound like you were having tummy problems. You and Mommy returned home, while Nana and I went into the city.<br />
I took Nana to the Central Market, where I&#8217;d last been about a year ago. I wound her through the narrow aisles, through little stalls selling just about everything imaginable (and a few unimaginable), before stopping at the Central Market Café. This is where Jason, Mark, and I had stopped for coffee (I had hot chocolate, not yet having started to drink coffee) while on our tour. Nana and I both bought coffee. I would later buy the torilla press we&#8217;d been looking for.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743790614[/flickr]<br />
Leaving the market, we went down Avenida Central towards the Plaza de Cultura, where we went to the Gran Hotel for lunch. My poor ceviche at the Arenal Lodge was redeemed by possibly the best ceviche I&#8217;ve yet had, while Nana had a fried Cambenbert and strawberry sauce tapas. Spying the dark clouds that suggested rain, we headed into the Museo de Oro for an hour or so.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743022225[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743826248[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743033867[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743848398[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743053189[/flickr]<br />
The rain, for once, didn&#8217;t come. When we came back out, it was only to walk back to the car and drive back home again.<br />
Mommy and I made pizza for dinner, which was very good. You barely ate your corn on the cob or the pizza (both were favourites), which still worries us greatly.<br />
So ends my birthday vacation. I wish I could say I had a better time, Monkey, but I&#8217;ll be honest &#8212; spending time with you, Mommy, and Nana were my shining points. Otherwise, it was a pretty lousy time. Had I known the weather would be that bad, I&#8217;d have suggested we just stay here at home.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743072335[/flickr]<br />
It&#8217;s time for me to go to bed (you&#8217;ve been asleep for about 2.75 hours already). Hopefully tonight I&#8217;ll catch up on some of the sleep I&#8217;ve been missing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend at Tabacon</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-at-tabacon</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1096</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend at Tabacon"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active Arenal volcano, and dinner and a splash at the <a href="http://www.tabacon.com/">Tabacon Hot Springs</a>.<br />
At the time we&#8217;d been there, it was highly magical. We&#8217;d seen lava (in the form of red-hot tumbling rocks) rolling down the side of the mountain, the clouds of steam rolling through the trees illuminated by the carefully-placed lights. It was something to behold.<br />
Ever since then, Alex had wanted to go back. Rack up Surprise Weekend in Costa Rica #3.<br />
<span id="more-1096"></span>We left Saturday just after lunch, taking a route up through Naranjo, Cuidad de Quesada (also known as San Carlos), and then angling west through La Fortuna. This was not exactly an ideal route, since it&#8217;s a national highway &#8212; despite the insane amount of curves present in the road &#8212; which means a lot more (slow) truck traffic.<br />
We arrived around 16:30 (it&#8217;s about a 3-3.5 hour drive, albeit a very nice drive) and checked in right away. A nice room (with air conditioning), two on-site <a href="http://www.cafebritt.com/">Cafe Britt</a> stores (one in the hotel, the other in the hot springs facility), and a couple of very nice restaurants.<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+hotel+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was when we found out how expensive Tabacon can be. Although the room rate for the weekend wasn&#8217;t too bad (technically less than the one at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/">Ylang Ylang</a>), it does not include any meals (whereas Ylang Ylang covered breakfast and dinner). A $75 buffet bill said that we were in for a pricey weekend.<br />
That&#8217;s the first myth of Tabacon &#8212; very nice hotel, but far too-expensive food for the quality that you get. The second myth is that the hot springs open at 8:00 in the morning. Which is true &#8212; they do, but you&#8217;ll find the water levels in the river are practically non-existent, as the water is diverted to fill the swimming pools, which starts around 9:00. So you can&#8217;t really use the hot springs until at least 10:00.<br />
On Sunday, we went out for an excursion to find a butterfly farm (Alex had promised Mi Pequeña Niña that we&#8217;d go see butterflies). We had to drive to the south side of Lake Arenal to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>, which took us on a very picturesque journey around the volcano. Which &#8212; apparently a sign of good luck &#8212; was mostly free of clouds for once. Many photos were taken.<br />
[flickr]tag:arenal+volcano+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The Butterfly Conservatory is near the end of a very rough road, off of a bumpy and rocky gravel road, off of another dirt road. (Driving back onto pavement after all that was a joy.) It sits atop a hill that provides &#8212; without question &#8212; one of the finest views of the Arenal volcano. This would be an exceptional place to take pictures at night during an eruption, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that driving there in the dark is a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢.<br />
The tents that contain the butterflies are down in a valley (a former cattle ranch turned into a reforestation project, after it was realised that putting cattle on volcanic soil is also a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢), which pretty much eliminated all breeze, and turned it into a bit of a boiler. Everyone was sweating profusely. But the butterflies were in significantly larger numbers than at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/">Spirogyra</a> &#8212; and some species that we hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+butterflies+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Luckily, we&#8217;d gained a tour guide part-way through the second (of four) butterfly tent, who not only showed us the butterflies and their names (given her limited English and our even more-limited Spanish), but also played with Mi Pequeña Niña while Alex and I snapped pictures). Sadly, I never did get her name, so all I can say is &#8220;Thanks, whomever you are!&#8221;<br />
Butterfly Conservatory also has a little frog habitat with some of the native Costa Rican frogs. Our guide was kind enough to bring the non-poisonous ones to the front of their enclosures so we could see them more closely. Otherwise, it would have been a bit hard to see them at all.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+frogs+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Naturally, Alex and I visited the hot springs whenever we could &#8212; what else would be the point of staying at Tabacon if we didn&#8217;t? Alex also took advantage of the five-star spa there, and hasn&#8217;t stopped talking about it yet. (I have to admit, it does sound wonderful.)<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+waterfall+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Even MPN got a chance to try the hot waters, while Alex was at her massage. Yes, I took my daughter into 39 degree Celsius water. And she loved it. I tried her in the cooler pools first, just to make sure, but when I slowly put her into the hot pool, it must&#8217;ve felt like heaven for her &#8212; she splashed around like a seal. The bridge overlooking the pool was soon filled with spectators. We might as well have been the featured attraction at Sea World.<br />
This is normal, by the way &#8212; it&#8217;s rather absurd the amount of attention MPN attracts down here.<br />
Monday being a holiday in Costa Rica (Independence Day), we took a leisurely return Monday afternoon, going through San Francisco and San RamÃ³n instead of San Carlos and Naranjo. This is the route that we had travelled (in the other direction) 3.5 years ago with Interbus on our way to Arenal. But Alex and I didn&#8217;t remember a thing, something we feel pretty guilty about. Alex claims that it was culture shock at the time. I think I can live with that.<br />
We stopped only twice &#8212; once to feed MPN (and have a Coke), and another at a gift shop we&#8217;d stopped at with Interbus 3.5 years ago. The only other place in the area that we knew of. It was weird because we didn&#8217;t really recognise it, but we did remember it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2862455883(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Sadly, this weekend cost a lot more than I&#8217;d budgeted for, so we&#8217;re not likely to do anymore long-distance trips for a while. (Besides which, we&#8217;re out of long weekends until Christmas). Of course, there&#8217;s still stuff around us for day trips, so stay tuned for more adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Butterflies and getting lost</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=butterflies-and-getting-lost</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 04:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traffic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1084</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[You can only stay around Santa Ana for so long before you start to feel a little caged in. And given that Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña are here all day, every day, there was a distinct need to explore a bit beyond our bounds. So Saturday morning (yes, I know this is a little &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Butterflies and getting lost"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can only stay around Santa Ana for so long before you start to feel a little caged in. And given that Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña are here all day, every day, there was a distinct need to explore a bit beyond our bounds. So Saturday morning (yes, I know this is a little late, I&#8217;ve intentionally been keeping away from my computer this weekend) we went off in search of adventure.  <br />
And butterflies.  <br />
<span id="more-1084"></span>This was Alex&#8217;s decision. I&#8217;ve suggested a lot, but Alex (presumably on a recommendation from her friend Rebecca, who lived in Costa Rica for a collective couple of years) suggested Saturday&#8217;s excursion. I hope to hear more desires of places to go (beyond &#8220;Arenal&#8221;, which I&#8217;ve heard a few times since we arrived in late July), as that&#8217;ll give us a good chance to see more of the country.  <br />
Anyhoo, Alex chose a placed called Spirogyra Butterfly Garden (the name is pronounced &#8220;spee-roh-HEE-ra&#8221; en Español), and we headed off around 10:00, effectively skipping MPN&#8217;s morning nap. (Though she did sleep a bit in the car on the way there.)  <br />
According to Google, Spirogrya is just north of La Sabana park, which didn&#8217;t take us long to get to. Well, the park didn&#8217;t take us long to get to. I neglected to realise that one cannot actually turn to the left to run down Avenida 4 from Calle 41 (for those of you in San Jose, that&#8217;s trying to turn onto the road at the north side of La Sabana from the road at the end side of La Sabana). If you go north of Avenida 4, you end up on Highway 1.  <br />
Not what I&#8217;d planned for.<br />
So after a 20-minute detour/return trip, we finally got back to Avenida 4, and turned down the road where<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=spirogyra+butterfly+garden&amp;sll=9.938417,-84.0903&amp;sspn=0.052163,0.058193&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.942982,-84.085064&amp;spn=0.052162,0.058193&amp;t=h&amp;z=14&amp;iwloc=B"> Google had put Spirogyra on the map</a>. I was a little suspicious about a butterfly farm being there, but since it&#8217;s possible to have a factory right next to a neighbourhood (zoning doesn&#8217;t really seem to exist here), I wasn&#8217;t about to be one to challenge the wisdom of Google.  <br />
That said, Google was wrong.<br />
Leaving the neighbourhood, we ended up having to go around La Sabana to get ourselves back to Paseo Colon, cutting through the San Jose to get to Calle Central, which would take us north of the downtown, across the river, where we could scoot over towards El Pedro (an apparently defunct mall). But not far from turning onto Avenida Central (not the one right downtown, I should add &#8212; San Jose can be very confusing), we saw the sign for <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;hl=en&amp;msa=0&amp;ll=9.940007,-84.072747&amp;spn=0.00326,0.003637&amp;t=h&amp;z=18&amp;msid=106619148814639590944.0004565abbf7a50d3a3c6">Spirogyra Mariposa JardÃƒ ­n</a>.  <br />
We were the only ones there. No-one else came during our 45-minute romp through a black netting-covered garden that was &#8230; well, not &#8220;filled&#8221; with butterflies, but there were certainly a number of them. A few even landed me on me, mistaking me apparently for a rotting log.  <br />
[Insert joke about lack of sexual prowess here.]<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña didn&#8217;t seem too particularly thrilled with the butterflies, at least not as much as I thought she&#8217;d be. Pretty much any animal, and she goes ga-ga until the animal is out of sight. Insects? Not so much.  Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it&#8217;s a nice place. Next time I go back, it&#8217;ll be with my SLR (at least once it&#8217;s working properly) to get all these wonderful things on film.  <br />
[flickr]photo:2838949976(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838957648(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838962534(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838134253(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838975040(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838149761(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838157243(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838164869(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838178969(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838183957(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838189155(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The cafe there was closed, so we decided to make a break for San Pedro Mall, on the east side of San Jose. In theory, not a long drive from Spirogyra.  <br />
In theory.  <br />
Also, in theory, the roads here are marked well enough that you can easily find your way without getting horribly lost. Which is precisely what happened to us. Well, not so much &#8220;horribly&#8221;, but definitely &#8220;lost&#8221;. My fault, I will state for the record, as I had incorrectly made a few assumptions about direction and distance, and believed that we would cross a highway that runs along the east side. Turns out we passed over said highway and ended up someplace completely different.  <br />
Like, I can&#8217;t even <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=Santa+Ana,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+Costa+Rica&amp;daddr=Point+of+Lost+Return+%409.944382144667635,-84.01358842849731&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=%3BFT69lwAd7A3--g&amp;mra=ls&amp;sll=9.944815,-84.013792&amp;sspn=0.00326,0.003637&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.944863,-84.013095&amp;spn=0.01304,0.014548&amp;t=h&amp;z=16">find the name of the area that we ended up in</a> kind of different. Oops.  <br />
Ironically, I had made not one, but two collosally bad turns. The first was not realising when I&#8217;d arrived at the #2 highway, which would have taken us to San Pedro. The second was turning left, not right, and driving AWAY from the San Pedro on a road that would have taken us TO San Pedro.  <br />
Methinks my internal compass is screwed up. Normally, I&#8217;m not this bad.  <br />
Finally arriving at San Pedro Mall, we went in search of lunch. The usual fast-food adorned the food court, including the ubiquitous Kentucky Fried Chicken, or KFC as it&#8217;s known here. KFC is a really weird phenomenon in Costa Rica. Apparently, so the story goes, it used to be really bad. Then some American guy came down, bought the chain, and overhauled the marketing. (If you ever think marketing isn&#8217;t useful, you clearly have never paid attention to its affects.) Now it&#8217;s the most successful one. Mark, Jason, and I have commented several times on quitting our jobs and opening a few KFCs &#8212; there&#8217;s always lineups at these things!<br />
Not wanting to eat any North American fast-food (I&#8217;m in a different country, darn it, I want something local), we went to Pollos Campaneros. Fried chicken. Tasted like KFC. Go figure.  <br />
Actually, the taste took me back to my last year of high school. In the summer, my friends and I (Stuart, Therese, Chris, James, Linda, Ali, Kathryn, Hil, Eva, and J) would go to <a href="http://www.canadaswonderland.com/">Canada&#8217;s Wonderland</a> for the day. The entire day. We&#8217;d be there when the park opened at 10:00, and leave when the park closed at 22:00. For lunch, we&#8217;d take buckets of cold KFC, which for some reason we were all completely fascinated with.  <br />
Good days, those.  <br />
The San Pedro Mall is kind of odd. It has some higher-end stores, but one end of the mall looks like a run-down outlet-type configuration. There&#8217;s even a place on the lowest level that sells (reasonably accurate) Rolex, Breitling, Hublot, and Omega knock-offs. The sweep isn&#8217;t quite right, but whatever. For $150, what do you expect?<br />
The route home I need to perfect a little better (there are faster routes through downtown), but it&#8217;s at least familiar. One of these days, though, I need to check out the fort in San Jose. It looks pretty neat, albeit totally devoid of tourists every time we&#8217;ve seen it.  <br />
This weekend coming up is another adventure. Where will this one take us? You&#8217;ll just have to wait and see&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1084</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
