<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>waterloo &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/waterloo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 05:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Memories of Grandma</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/memories-of-grandma/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=memories-of-grandma</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/memories-of-grandma/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 05:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ginger ale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waterloo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I still remember the day. December 6, 1995. I had been working at my part-time job at a computer store just off-campus, suffering through a wicked head cold. I&#8217;d begged my manager to let me leave early, but he&#8217;d needed me to stay. (I remember feeling not only put out, but tortured &#8212; I hadn&#8217;t &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/memories-of-grandma/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Memories of Grandma"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I still remember the day. December 6, 1995. I had been working at my part-time job at a computer store just off-campus, suffering through a wicked head cold. I&#8217;d begged my manager to let me leave early, but he&#8217;d needed me to stay. (I remember feeling not only put out, but tortured &#8212; I hadn&#8217;t done much all day.) I had trudged the two-odd kilometres back home just itching to crawl into bed and not emerge for a day or so. But when I placed my foot on the driveway of the house I was living in, I had a feeling that something wasn&#8217;t right.<br />
I rushed inside, quickly descending to the room in the basement I&#8217;d rented (I was one of seven students in the house; four up, three down), and immediately went over to my phone, not removing my jacket. There was the familiar pulsing tone that said I had voicemail. It was my father. Dad never called me.   Mom would always call, then hand over to Dad. He was quiet, saying only to call home when I got in. The news was short.<br />
Grandma had died.<br />
<span id="more-2570"></span>My grandmother &#8212; my Dad&#8217;s mom &#8212; had not been well. She was in her late 80s (I think she was 87 at the time of her death), and like many people her age, some of the senses had waned over the years. Her vision had been a problem for a few years previous, such that she no longer drove and required a large magnifying glass to read. Unknownst to us, until my Aunt Ruth happened to find out by accident, Grandma&#8217;s sense of smell had also gone. Sour milk and a too-far-gone chicken breast were the last straw, and with much cajoling, Grandma finally had to give up her home of 60 years. It was hard on everyone.<br />
Grandma moved into a retirement  condominium in Oakville, about a 10 minute drive from our home. It was a nice place, and we tried to visit as often as we could. It was there I saw my Grandma on a warm September day, on my way up to Waterloo for my fall semester. It was my second semester in a row, having decided to do a full year at school to make up time for my discipline change, and subsequent delay in graduation.<br />
I stayed about long enough to have a quick lunch with her, chat a bit, before I had to hit the road. I can&#8217;t remember what haste I was in to get back to Waterloo, and I&#8217;m sure now that I wasn&#8217;t as important as it was to have stayed longer. In hindsight, as is often the case with things or people that go away or are lost, you wish you&#8217;d spent more time.  As I left, she handed me a can of pop, for the road, so I wouldn&#8217;t get thirsty. Little did I know that when I left, it would be the last time I would ever see her.<br />
[flickr]photo:4314664943(small)[/flickr]<br />
For some reason, I never got around to drinking the pop, a can of Our Compliments ginger ale. In fact, it inexplicably ended up sitting in my room, unopened, for months. Then word came that Grandma had an accident. She&#8217;d fallen, and broken her hip. She was moved to the hospital in Oakville, where she would remain under watch for weeks. Her condition never really improved, and she slowly slipped away. Among the regrets of my life is not having gone to see her. I&#8217;m sure I had excellent excuses, all of which now amount to nothing.<br />
I don&#8217;t remember if I cried. If I did, there&#8217;s no way to know if it was at all influenced by my own illness. (I don&#8217;t even remember the continuation of the illness after my phone call with Dad.) But I was saddened by her passing. She had been a part of my life for as long as I could remember. She had baked amazing Christmas cookies. We&#8217;d always gone to Grandma&#8217;s house for New Year&#8217;s dinner. She drank sherry, and ate those sugary fruit gels from Laura Secord. We&#8217;d play with my Dad&#8217;s old Dinky cars on her ornate rug, looking at a painting of two sailing ships over her fireplace.  The painting, incidentally, now resides in my basement.<br />
I didn&#8217;t go to my Grandma&#8217;s funeral. It was a hard decision for me to make. I had a project due the day after the funeral, and two classmates, Kim and Amber-Lynn, depending on me to help deliver it. I wore a black band on my arm (made of two black socks I tied together &#8212; it was all I had) all day.<br />
But I didn&#8217;t open the can.<br />
The can stayed unopened for over 14 years. It moved from Waterloo, to Oakville, to Vancouver, to Calgary. I displayed it prominently on shelves in my apartments. People would look at it, and wonder why it was on a shelf. But no-one ever tried to open it. Very few people even asked. (I suspect most of them thought I was just a slob.) But it was there, my memory in clear view. It stayed in storage for the year and a half we were in Costa Rica, and probably even longer prior to us moving (I&#8217;m not exactly sure when it went into storage, to be honest).<br />
While unpacking our stuff over the last month and a half, I pulled it out and dusted it off. It felt only about half-full. But there were no holes, no leaks that I could see. So far as I could tell, the liquid inside had evaporated out. (I presume that&#8217;s possible?) Beside the can were piles of things to be donated, recycled, or outright thrown away. Things that had long pre-dated the can, and things that had carried a lot of sentimentality. I thought about the can&#8217;s prominence, what the can meant, and even the potential dangers it now presented to my family. I came to one conclusion:<br />
It was time for the can to go.<br />
One last picture. A pause, then I cracked it open (no fizz left), and emptied the contents. (Sorry, Grandma, but after over 14 years, I&#8217;m sure the contents would border on being unsafe for human consumption.) Then I took a last look, and recycled the can.<br />
In the end, it&#8217;s not the can that mattered. It was who it represented. The physical manifestation of a memory doesn&#8217;t make the memory any stronger, or any more pertinent in my life. If nothing else, this entry helps me appreciate what she did for me, for my family. Her values, her sense of adventure, her stubbornness have all played significantly in my foundation, either directly from her or handed down through the family line.<br />
So if you&#8217;re reading, Grandma, thank you. Thank you for the things you&#8217;ve done, and the things you&#8217;re yet to do. You&#8217;ve got some great-grandchildren who&#8217;ve yet to hear your tales, and will smile widely at the stories I have to tell.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/memories-of-grandma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2570</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friends from university</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=friends-from-university</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 22:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waterloo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/26/friends-from-university/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pretty much keep with the trend, I woke late again. When I walked out of the bedroom, though, I found the door to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s bedroom open. Given the time of the morning, I assumed Craig would be asleep. I peered in to see if perhaps he had simply not closed the door. &#8220;Good &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Friends from university"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pretty much keep with the trend, I woke late again. When I walked out of the bedroom, though, I found the door to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s bedroom open. Given the time of the morning, I assumed Craig would be asleep. I peered in to see if perhaps he had simply not closed the door.<br />
&#8220;Good morning, Geoff&#8230;&#8221; a voice from behind said. I damn near had a heart attack.<br />
<span id="more-329"></span>Craig was still awake, playing solitaire on the computer in the third bedroom. He looked like hell, like he hadn&#8217;t slept in days. To some degree, it wasn&#8217;t far from reality &#8212; while Craig had been catching sleep, the schedule of his workload was certainly taking its toll. Craig was staying awake a while longer to try and reset his sleeping schedule. I remembered my days of looking like him, when I worked hours far beyond reason.<br />
Those are days I do not miss.<br />
I showered, shaved, dressed, and hopped in Craig&#8217;s car. I was off to Waterloo to visit more friends, and take a little trip down memory lane. That journey started before I even left Oakville town limits. I was amazed at the amount of construction that seemed to stretch endlessly. I hadn&#8217;t driven north on Trafalgar Road for quite some time, and my memory of farmland was replaced with subdivisions.<br />
I drove quickly, soon arriving at the 401, where I started my trip west. The first thing I noticed was the dramatic increase in truck traffic that now seemed to plague the highway. Back in the days I used to drive it to Waterloo, trucks averaged maybe 1/3 of the vehicles on the road. Now they numbered well over half &#8212; maybe as many as 2/3 in some places. The second thing I noticed, which I&#8217;ve noticed before, is that everyone in this province has slowed down far too much. No-one exceeds the speed limit anymore.<br />
The trip to Waterloo was quite uneventful. There were a few new things along the way, but mostly the scenery was as I remembered it. The only major difference was more construction where the #85 joins with King St. This was a hated junction for me, because the on-ramp and off-ramp were too close together, and probably caused too many accidents, hence the new overpass they were building.<br />
University Avenue wasn&#8217;t too different. There were a few things that had changed, mostly stores, but nothing really stood out any differently than it had from my university days. I pulled into the University of Waterloo campus, and went in search of a parking spot. My meagre memory told me there would potentially be spots in the parking lot wedged between the Davis Centre, Biology 2, and Engineering 3.<br />
Imagine my surprise to find a new building there.<br />
It was the first of several new things to find on campus. This was the long-awaited Environmental Engineering building, planned from when I was an undergrad. I would later find the new Co-operative Education building, a new student residence, and some changes to old buildings (such as the upgraded Engineering Lecture Hall). It wasn&#8217;t the same campus I had known, but it wasn&#8217;t far off.<br />
I met up with Kim outside the Davis Centre library. We headed off to the Campus Centre strip mall, adjacent to the Engineering buildings. We went to a new Persian restaurant that offered some rather interesting cuisine. Despite being fast food, I had a wonderful dish made of chicken in a pomegranate and walnut sauce.<br />
Kim asked for a ride to Conestoga Mall. She had a gift card to spend at the HBC stores, and Zellers was the nearest store she could get to. Without a car, she had no easy way to get up there (a bus takes forever), and me with a car, it all seemed like a good plan. Besides, I had nothing else better in mind to do.<br />
After sucking up all but the remaining $0.40 of her gift card, we headed back in the direction of the university. We got sidetracked by Chapters. Kim needed a guide book for Dublin, Ireland. She&#8217;s going there for a conference, proof that Kim not only knows what she&#8217;s doing in her line of study, but also that she knows how to save enough money to do it on her own.<br />
We headed back to the university, guidebook in hand, and did a little driving tour around the campus, so I could see what had changed. We even went over to the Columbia Lake Townhouses to view the expansion. And it&#8217;s quite an expansion &#8212; an entire new set of buildings, which are quite a bit more impressive than the ones I had lived in many years ago. I mentally wished that the new units are built better than the ones I lived in.<br />
We ended up parking in the south lot of the university, so Kim could show me her office and the pictures of her last trip to Ireland. Before long, though, I had run out of time and had to head back to Oakville. As far as I knew, I had to be back by 16:00 so Craig could go to work. It was already well past 15:00.<br />
I&#8217;d never driven so fast down a highway before &#8230; well, in Ontario, at least. The trip back was a little frustrating, mostly due to people cruising in the driving lanes. But I made excellent time, getting back to Trafalgar Rd. in a length of time that was exceedingly short. The plethora of trucks, however, caused me to miss my exit. As it turned out, it was a fortunate happenstance, since I got to take the much quicker 407 instead. Calling Craig to let him know I was running a little late, I found out he didn&#8217;t need the car until 17:30, which gave me ample time to not only vacuum out the car, but wash it, too.<br />
Not long after getting back to Cathy and Craig&#8217;s, my phone rang. It was Duncan, an old friend and roommate from university. We had made loose plans to meet up, and had more or less solidified them over the course of the day. We would join forces at the Jack Astor&#8217;s at Square One, at 19:30.<br />
The last time I&#8217;d seen Duncan was sometime in 1997, though I honestly can&#8217;t remember when. He was a roommate in my last year of university, the two of us having met a couple of years earlier in my first rhetoric class. We&#8217;d hit it off and have been friends ever since. Just before we&#8217;d moved in with each other (and another friend of mine, Mike), Duncan had met Marla, who was working on her Psychology Masters at the time. They were married last year.<br />
I arrived at the restaurant mere seconds after they did. Despite it having been almost eight years since I&#8217;d last seen Duncan, and even longer since the last time I&#8217;d seen Marla, I recognized them immediately. Duncan didn&#8217;t really look any different. Marla, however, had gained a little weight &#8230; about nine month&#8217;s weight, if you know what I mean.<br />
I know far too many pregnant people.<br />
None of us had eaten, so took a table, ordered some food, and began a 2+ hour conversation trying to catch up on most of a decade. It really brought to life the need to see old friends a little more frequently than I do. It made me wish that I&#8217;d seen my old roommate Scott when I&#8217;d been in Waterloo earlier in the day (but hadn&#8217;t thought about it until that point).<br />
Things I need to change. Too many people, and never enough time.<br />
We talked until Marla looked really tired. Considering that she was only two weeks from giving birth, I could hardly blame her. We parted ways, all of us wishing that we could have spent more time, and Marla wishing she could have had a beer.<br />
I returned home, the clock ticking louder than ever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">329</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
