<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>drumheller &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/drumheller/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 05:50:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A Dinosaur Day in Drumheller</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/a-dinosaur-day-in-drumheller/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-dinosaur-day-in-drumheller</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/a-dinosaur-day-in-drumheller/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 05:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drumheller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kids, I know it&#8217;s been far too long since my last letter. Sadly, it&#8217;s that worst excuse of poor excuses: I&#8217;ve been working a lot. Back in January, I started with a new company, the Evans Hunt Group. The project has been a tough one (I&#8217;ll tell you all about it when it&#8217;s ready &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/a-dinosaur-day-in-drumheller/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Dinosaur Day in Drumheller"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kids, I know it&#8217;s been far too long since my last letter. Sadly, it&#8217;s that worst excuse of poor excuses: I&#8217;ve been working a lot. Back in January, I started with a new company, the <a href="http://www.evanshunt.com/">Evans Hunt Group</a>. The project has been a tough one (I&#8217;ll tell you all about it when it&#8217;s ready for public consumption), but it&#8217;ll be rewarding for a number of reasons (not the least of which is how much more I know about things in Calgary that you&#8217;ll both like).<br />
I&#8217;m working with friends, people I&#8217;ve known for years &#8212; they&#8217;re people I also trust implicitly, so I have no reservations about working long hours. The downside, of course, is that I&#8217;ve seen less of you two. That&#8217;s probably what&#8217;s been hardest on me. Especially since Monkey probably feels a little neglected with all the time Mommy needs to spend with Choo Choo. It&#8217;s also why, despite the workload, I simply had to take some time to be with you and Mommy, and do something fun.<br />
So went to see dinosaurs in Drumheller.<br />
<span id="more-2673"></span>Okay, Choo Choo, you didn&#8217;t really &#8220;see&#8221; them. You&#8217;re only nine weeks old right now, so your observational capacity is limited to something like a metre in front of you. Not to mention that about the only things you do currently are eat, sleep, pee, and poo. (There&#8217;s a few moments of alert time thrown in there, too, usually followed by some pretty loud crying when you realise that you&#8217;re hungry again.) One day, you&#8217;ll find them more interesting, but for now &#8230; well, it is what it is.<br />
As for you, Monkey, you were pretty excited about seeing dinosaurs. You were excited about it for days, after the first suggestion. So Sunday morning, we packed up into our loaner Impala (the Jetta&#8217;s in the shop, following a nasty transmission failure last Tuesday evening), and headed out for adventure.<br />
Our first stop was breakfast: Cora&#8217;s at Northland Mall. We got there around 9:30, by which time the lineup was well out the door, and almost out the mall&#8217;s doors. I think I nearly broke Mommy&#8217;s heart when I suggested we find somewhere else. I was starving, and I figured we&#8217;d be well over an hour before eating, let alone heading towards Drumheller. We settled for what I consider to be pretty darn good breakfast sandwiches at the Second Cup.<br />
Soon, we were out of the city, and heading into the prairie countryside. I always feel reinvigorated when I go into the prairies &#8212; there&#8217;s something about the endless horizon and the huge blue sky that makes me feel more alive. I don&#8217;t know if you two feel this way (you were asleep, Choo Choo, so I suspect you didn&#8217;t even notice), but maybe one day you&#8217;ll be able to tell me.<br />
We arrived in Drumheller just after noon, and we went right to the <a href="http://www.tyrrellmuseum.com/">Royal Tyrrell Museum of Palaeontology</a> (or as most people I know call it, &#8220;The Tyrrell&#8221;), which is one of the best museums I know of for dinosaurs. (Truth be told, though, it&#8217;s not just dinosaurs. Although dinosaur fossils are plentiful in parts of Alberta, the museum prefers to cover the entire timeline from the dawn of life all the way up to modern man &#8212; there just happens to be a big portion that&#8217;s dinosaurs.) We&#8217;d all snacked in the car, so we pretty much skipped lunch.<br />
Thankfully, you both are free right now, and will remain so until you&#8217;re 7 years old. Mommy had to take Choo Choo off for a feeding (Choo Choo is usually very hungry when she wakes up), but Monkey and I dove right into the museum.<br />
Although you&#8217;ve played with dinosaur toys and watch <a href="http://pbskids.org/dinosaurtrain/"><em>Dinosaur Train</em></a>, Monkey, you&#8217;d never seen anything remotely &#8220;life size&#8221; before. When you first entered the museum, you were met with a small pack of raptors, and a pair of massive theropods (Albertosauruses, I think). Oh, and a herd of humans. I&#8217;m not sure which you were more hesitant of &#8212; the replica dinosaurs, or the throngs of people. Either way, you needed a little leading.<br />
You wanted to see the &#8220;bones&#8221;. (I&#8217;m not sure where you picked up the need to see bones; Mommy swears it wasn&#8217;t her.) We had to round corner, but soon you were looking at arms, and skulls, and legs, and even a half-uncovered skeleton. I&#8217;m not sure what you thought of it, and I think you were a little overwhelmed at first. I got a picture of you next to a sauropod leg (you&#8217;re under a metre in height right now, and barely were above the leg&#8217;s ankle bones).<br />
[flickr]photo:4644120102(small)[/flickr]<br />
Walking past the lab where the technicians dig out the bones from the rocks, we found ourselves face-to-face with your first Tyrannosaurus Rex. At first, you gasped, exclaiming &#8220;dinosaur!&#8221;, and we walked towards it. Then you stopped,  shivered a bit, and mumbled &#8220;don&#8217;t like dinosaurs&#8221; and tried to go back the way we came. I managed to calm your fears, and we looked at the skeletons, and even got a picture of you in front of the T. Rex.<br />
From there, we followed the path through the museum: up the ramp through the special exhibits to the &#8220;time tunnel&#8221;, which leads up to the start of the regular exhibits. You love ramps, and were quite happy to sprint up and down the ramp several times (me having to keep up with you, I might add), pausing at the top to look at the massive wall of purple-lit bubbles. The time spent here wasn&#8217;t wasted, having to wait for Mommy and Choo Choo to catch up to us.<br />
[flickr]photo:4644123990(small)[/flickr]<br />
Finally managing to move past the ramp and the bubbles, you looked down into the Dinosaur Hall (exclaiming, again, &#8220;dinosaur!&#8221;, followed with a &#8220;rawr!&#8221;) and looked directly at the head of a T. Rex. You didn&#8217;t seem at all fazed. You raced through the Burgess Shale (I had difficulty catching up), and paused only long enough at the Devonian Reef to declare: &#8220;fishies!&#8221;, before racing down the stairs into the Terrestrial Palaeozoic exhibit. You spent only long enough here to look almost at Dimetrodon before Mommy and Choo Choo caught up to us.<br />
[flickr]photo:4644125240(small)[/flickr]<br />
Already, you were showing signs of being too tired. You didn&#8217;t blink at a 21-metre  Ichthyosaur, tried to run into the Allosaurus exhibit (thankfully, we caught you before that), and generally wanted only to play with blocks and be carried by Mommy (I was carrying Choo Choo in the Bjorn). We sped along through the rest of the museum and into the gift shop (because, don&#8217;t all museums end in gift shops?). There, you decided on a small &#8220;baby&#8221; T. Rex doll &#8212; though you could have easily gone with something much larger. I was impressed.<br />
We headed back into downtown Drumheller, finally stopping at Gus&#8217; Corner Cafe for lunch. It wasn&#8217;t much, but it was something. By the time we got to our hotel, it was nearly 16:00, and you were just plain baked. Down you went, like a log, for a short nap. Mommy, Choo Choo, and I went down to the lobby to let you rest.<br />
A little over an hour later, I woke you up so we could go for a swim. It had been <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/">a long time since I&#8217;d taken you to a pool</a>, and I didn&#8217;t want to miss out on an opportunity. There were a lot of people there, so we couldn&#8217;t do very much. We spent the time practising how to swim: kicking and pulling. You&#8217;re getting a lot better Monkey, and with more practise, you might even be ready to swim on your own (with water wings, mind you) by your birthday!<br />
We went to O&#8217;Sheas, an &#8220;Irish restaurant&#8221; near our Super 8 hotel for dinner. It was &#8230; well, it was &#8220;okay&#8221; at best. Mommy and I have had the luxury of eating in actual Irish restaurants, and &#8230; well, let&#8217;s say they take a few creative liberties about their food. It wasn&#8217;t that it was bad or anything, just that it wasn&#8217;t as Irish as I expected. Oh, and you ate spaghetti.<br />
After dinner, you and I went back to the museum on our own. There was barely anyone else there. You wanted to run around on your own, which you pretty much did. In fact, we went through the museum twice, because you just had to see the bubbles again. Afterwards, we stopped at the <a href="http://www.traveldrumheller.com/worlds-largest-dinosaur.html">World&#8217;s Largest Dinosaur</a> &#8212; I just had to get a picture of you with it in the background. No matter how hard I tried, though, I just couldn&#8217;t get you to go &#8220;rawr!&#8221; again.<br />
[flickr]photo:4644130550(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4644132900(square)[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:4644134134(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4643522249(square)[/flickr]<br />
Maybe it was all the excitement of the day, maybe it was the short nap, maybe it was that we stayed up too late, or maybe it was that you and I shared a bed &#8212; but no matter what the reason, you didn&#8217;t sleep well. You woke up a few times, screaming. Deciding that it was probably because you kept kicking me as you rolled around, I moved to the couch. Not that it helped much&#8230;<br />
We headed home on Monday, unable to stay any longer. It was a fun trip, Monkey, and I hope we get to do it again before too long. As for you, Choo Choo, I can&#8217;t wait until you&#8217;re able to express interest in things like this. I&#8217;ll make going to museums a lot more fun than they are now.<br />
[flickr]photo:4644139626(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/05/a-dinosaur-day-in-drumheller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2673</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise Visit to Drumheller</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-drumheller</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2004 03:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drumheller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/06/28/surprise-weekend-drumheller/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come. The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise Visit to Drumheller"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come.<br />
The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is a &#8220;Jerks BBQ&#8221;, you might ask? The group of people that I work with most around the office are The Jerks. Effectively, we&#8217;re mostly web developers. Why &#8220;Jerks&#8221;? Well, we have a rather odd term of endearment around here: &#8220;JERK!&#8221;. Hence, we&#8217;re Jerks.<br />
<span id="more-363"></span>This was only the second barbecue I&#8217;ve had since I bought the house (see [[My Housewarming Party]]), and was a far cry from the housewarming audience. Suddenly, I remember why I only have these barbecues once in a while &#8212; they&#8217;re a lot of work.<br />
For example, I was up late putting together the fixin&#8217;s for the barbecue, specifically hamburgers and potato salad. I didn&#8217;t want to buy pre-made burgers (they taste like crap, and you really don&#8217;t know what goes into those things). I decided to make everything. Wanna know what went into them? I can&#8217;t give you quantities (I made it up as I went), but it went like this:<br />
Hamburgers<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
&#8211; medium ground beef (you need the fat for flavour)<br />
&#8211; beer (specifically Big Rock Traditional)<br />
&#8211; caramelized onions<br />
&#8211; garlic (lots of it)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; cumin<br />
&#8211; rosemary<br />
&#8211; thyme<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; seasoning salt<br />
&#8211; oregano<br />
&#8211; chipotle powder (adds a great kick)<br />
Potato Salad<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
&#8211; roasted potatoes (with coarse salt, olive oil, and rosemary)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; olive oil<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; balsamic vinegar<br />
&#8211; scallions<br />
&#8211; red, orange, and yellow peppers<br />
Everything was ready for when my guests arrived Friday after work &#8230; about 20 minutes before it began to rain. At first, it only rained a little. Soon, it was raining a lot. Apparently someone had decided to ignore my purchase order for a nice, sunny evening. We ended up cramming into the kitchen and living room. Still, a good time seemed to be had by all, which is all I really wanted.<br />
Pat and Scott were the last two to roll out the door, shortly before 22:30. That gave me time to go over to Alex&#8217;s. Which was important for activities the next day&#8230;<br />
&#8230;starting with the Inglewood Festival, and the pancake breakfast. We were originally going to walk from Alex&#8217;s, but when she found out that her sister had a layover in Calgary on her way back to Vancouver, the plan changed to driving. Though we walked from the south side of the Zoo to Inglewood.<br />
The breakfast was put on as part of the festival, but I think also for the footrace runners so they could eat after their event. The food was quite good (there&#8217;s nothing like greasy spoon flapjacks and Spolumbo&#8217;s sausage), and we were serenaded by local group, The Wake Ups.<br />
We did a quick circuit of the various stalls (many still setting up) before running back for the car, and heading up to the airport. Sadly, we would not see Nicky that day, as she had only 40 minutes between flights, and I gather the staff felt she wouldn&#8217;t have enough time to see anyone. We headed back down to downtown.<br />
Originally, the intent had been to go back to Inglewood. To go easy on parking, we stopped at the Calgary Zoo, planning to walk from there. But we soon found ourselves at the entrance to the Zoo. We had the option of going around, or going in. Suddenly, the Zoo seemed so much more appealing.<br />
It was a perfect day to see the Zoo. I&#8217;d only been there two times before, and both times were cold and nasty, and not all the animals were really active. This time, we were tripping over them &#8212; especially the flock of peacocks that seemed to be running around the grounds (including peahens with their peachicks). And then there were all the kids. Hundreds of &#8217;em. They were almost as interesting as watching the monkeys.<br />
We started off in the dinosaur section. This is little more than a static display and a garden, with some dinosaur sculptures thrown in for accent. They&#8217;re not the best models, perhaps, but for a portion of the zoo, it&#8217;s not too bad. Then we were off in search of elephants, bears, monkeys, horses, and tigers before we had to stop for lunch. After eating a fresh Spolumbo&#8217;s sandwich (albeit a little pricey), we were off to Africa (to see hippos, giraffes, zebras, ostriches, lions, gorillas, more moneys, bongos, several species of birds), the botanical garden to see various plants and the butterflies (which even after three times, have been very light in numbers), then over to Australia.<br />
The Australian section (which until this weekend I didn&#8217;t even know existed) included kangaroos (which didn&#8217;t move much), one of the roaming peacocks, and a building full of oddities from Down Under. Part of the building is dedicated to &#8220;Creatures of the Night&#8221;, a rebranding for the nocturnal section.<br />
Inside there, it&#8217;s dark. Really dark. You almost feel like squinting, it&#8217;s so dark. In there, you find things like a little fox with REALLY big ears, wallabies, and of course, bats. Lots of bats. But my favourite thing was a little mouse-sized creature, the name of which I currently forget. This little marsupial zipped along at high speed, and could crawl up the surface of a vertical pane of glass. (Apparently, sweat glands in its feet create suction.) It was quite an experience.<br />
Then it was off through the Canadian Wilds. Nothing particular here, just the usual cougars, lynxes, moose, ducks (but they&#8217;re everywhere, so you can&#8217;t avoid them), bison, wolves, caribou, owls, hawks, porcupines, deer, elk, and goats. Y&#8217;know &#8212; the same stuff you see every day on your way to work. (Sorry, that&#8217;s a bit of an in-joke for us Canucks.) That concluded our Zoo visit, and it was time to get on with the day.<br />
A quick stop at London Drugs retrieved photos that Alex has been taking for the last couple of months. One of them was of her bedroom wall, which she painted milk chocolate brown. Prior to painting it over completely, she&#8217;d drawn a large heart, inside of which she wrote: &#8220;AA + GS&#8221;. Although I&#8217;d known that she drew something on that way, she wouldn&#8217;t tell me what was there until I saw the photograph.<br />
Have I mentioned that I love this woman?<br />
Collecting our things, it was time for the surprise (it might take a while, but you knew I was going to get to it eventually). First off was dinner. For that, we tried to find Mother&#8217;s Pizza in Beddington Town Centre. However, it appears that the store front is currently hidden under the mask of renovation. I only hope it makes a return. We ended up at the Boston Pizza, instead.<br />
From there, we headed out towards Deerfoot Trail, and then north. You need to understand that, at this point, I had no idea where we were going. In &#8220;return&#8221; for the surprise I pulled on Alex in Banff (see [[Jazz Up Your Weekend at the Banff Centre]]), Alex wanted to take me somewhere mysterious. Her &#8220;clue&#8221; had been misinformation, to throw me off the scent. I had guessed Kananaskis. As we drove north on Deerfoot, I assumed that she was taking a very circuitous route.<br />
When we turned east onto one of the many regional highways at the north end of Airdrie, I put Kananaskis off to the side. I soon thought it might be Irricana, though I couldn&#8217;t imagine why. When we passed it on Highway 9, I tried to think of something else. When we passed Beiseiker, there weren&#8217;t many options left. Alex was trying to convince me it was Saskatoon. While this was the same route I&#8217;d take when we&#8217;d moved Nana to Calgary (see [[Moving Nana from Prince Albert to Calgary]]), the drive out is a little long. I felt it safe to assume she was trying to distract me from our destination: Drumheller.<br />
Though when we first pulled into the downtown core, I had second thoughts. Alex passed by most of the hotels, and started taking South Dinosaur Trail away from downtown! (It&#8217;s all industrial park out there.) It wasn&#8217;t until she crossed over the railway tracks and pulled into the Newcastle Inn that the surprise was fully exposed.<br />
The Inn is a small place, with about 12 rooms. It looks sort of like your grandmother&#8217;s place, but with an extra fridge in the kitchen, and a bathroom for each bedroom. Family photos adorn the walls. The Inn was mostly empty when we were there, save for the owner, and two other couples (who seemed to be in the basement). It was certainly comfortable enough for us for the night.<br />
We checked in just before 22:00, dumped our bags, and headed out for a short walk. Which ended up being a long walk (about 30 blocks) to the 7-11 and back. The night was cool, but not uncomfortable. Many small homes, and a few with firepits (we smelled a little like smoke by the time we got back). The unmistakeable scent of prairie-bound small town was just the sort of thing I needed to clear the head.<br />
The next morning, woken up by the other guests who had decided to eat their breakfast on the patio outside our window &#8212; the first ones to do so since the Inn opened &#8212; we ate our breakfast on the patio next to the kitchen. Cereal, toast, and a little fruit salad. We showered, dressed, packed up, and headed out for the adventure of the day.<br />
Our first stop was at the Tourist Information Centre. Why? Originally, to find the local TD Canada Trust, of which there is none in Drumheller. Every other bank is there, just not the TD. While we were there, we felt it necessary to do the tacky tourist thing, and climbed the World&#8217;s Largest Dinosaur.<br />
The 26.2 metre (85 ft.) tall structure is a massive version of a tyrannosaurus rex (or something similarly nasty), about 4.5 times the life-sized versions found in a museum not too far away. It&#8217;s not nearly as life-like, but that&#8217;s part of the charm. The internal structure is steel, though aside from the stairs it&#8217;s hard to tell &#8212; the inside is a plastic &#8220;tunnel&#8221; lined with fossil reproductions.<br />
The tunnel ends at the dinosaur&#8217;s jaws, where you peer westward over the town of Drumheller. It&#8217;s a pretty neat view, especially with the teeth in the way. Alex and I got a great view of the city, and the children playing in the water park just beneath the dinosaur.<br />
Then it was off to the real thing &#8212; the Royal Tyrell Museum. It&#8217;s been a while since the last times that I&#8217;ve been there (see [[Kathryn comes for a visit]], [[Touring Alberta, Calgary Stampede, Columbia Icefields, Lake Louise, Banff (Bamf!), Drumheller]], and [[A Boys Night out in Calgary, Drumheller, Banff (Bamf!), and Star Wars]]), and it was good to be back and see it again. Especially with someone who really wanted to see it because of personal interest.<br />
If you might remember, Alex is an x-ray technician, which means she spends a lot of time with bones. That, and her degree in science, leads to a lot of questions. For example, there&#8217;s a skeleton of a lambeosaurus (duck-billed), that showed a lot of spines from the tail bones. This puzzled Alex, as did the series of long bony-looking lines running the length of the spine between the shoulders and the hips. Before, I&#8217;d not have thought twice about this. Alex, however, is very good with anatomy, and knew this wasn&#8217;t right. A passing staff member told us the long bony structures were fossilized tendons (who knew?) and the tail spines were to create the thickness of the tail.<br />
We tried to take our time, but we ended up only taking a couple of hours. One thing about visiting museums off and on &#8212; you see different things upon subsequent returns. That&#8217;s what made it so interesting. I suspect the air conditioning also hasted our movement, since even for me, it was a little chilly.<br />
We ran out to the hoodoos east of downtown for a quick photo stop. Since I was there last, the Royal Tyrell has taken over management of the area, and created paths for people to walk on, trying to keep people from prematurely destroying the hoodoos. A bold and very noble initiative, since you don&#8217;t have to pay for the privilege of seeing them. So kudos to the Tyrell!<br />
With that, we headed back towards Calgary. We stopped at Horseshoe Canyon for a look-see. This meant a lot of climbing. Once we hit the valley floor, Alex was off like a shot, feeling a need to run up and down the slopes. For a while, I thought I was the dog that no-one wants, and was trying to ditch me out in the middle of nowhere. Fortunately, I managed to not fall too far behind.<br />
The trip back was into the setting sun. The excitement of the two days hit me, and for a short period of time, I slept. Soon, we were back in Calgary. We finished our weekend with a simple Greek meal at Santorini. Along the way to the restaurant, we were confronted by a friendly cat who stirred a few old memories in Alex, of a cat she&#8217;d had as a little girl. I had to take a picture for her.<br />
Now it&#8217;s my turn for planning the next surprise. I&#8217;m not sure what to do just yet, but I&#8217;ve got &#8220;It&#8217;s a Small, Small World&#8221; playing in my head&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:drumheller+june+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">363</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
