<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>shopping &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/shopping/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Christmas Blitzkrieg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-blitzkrieg</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas Blitzkrieg"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of sleep than from trying to do too much.<br />
Heck, it even makes me feel a bit young! Ish. Sort of.<br />
Except for the prolonged yawning, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-3199"></span>Tuesday evening, I went on a mission to find &#8220;Santa&#8221; presents for Monkey and Choo Choo, for a party Evans Hunt was holding for all the company&#8217;s children. I failed miserably for them (Alex would later prove to be a much better Santa in this regard), though it wasn&#8217;t a total wash for Christmas as a whole.<br />
Wednesday night was wrapping, notably a batch of presents from my sister that came in sans trimmings and trappings. My folding skills got a dusting off.<br />
Thursday was the Evans Hunt End of the World / Last Pitch party, our annual fest with clients and spouses. I honestly feel like I leave these parties too early, and I miss out on the good stories. I got the backfill the following day, and was moderately relieved to have missed some of the trouble.<br />
Friday was something slightly different, but very exciting (for me). Along with Tamara, Adrian, and Barb, I went to go see <em>The Hobbit: An Expected Journey</em>. It had been 11 years (I&#8217;d thought it only 10 at the time, but I just double-checked) since Tamara, Adrian, myself, and a couple of others had sat and waited for hours in the hallways at the Famous Players Chinook theatre (now Scotiabank Cineplex) to wait for the opening night of <em>The Lord of the Rings: Fellowship of the Ring</em>. A lot has happened in those years since&#8230;<br />
Eleven years later, I still love movies like that: long, and epic.<br />
I passed out nearly as soon as I got home, mostly due to exhaustion. (I&#8217;d also been running around before getting to the theatre, trying to find a Car2Go that I could actually get into &#8212; their system has been having issues for a couple of weeks, now.)<br />
Saturday morning was a blur of surreptitious present wrapping for the afternoon&#8217;s Santa visit, helping/forcing the kids to clean up the basement, making breakfast, and something else that I now forget. Then it was a blur of lunch-making, dressing (notably the kids in their nice dresses), and then loading into the car for the trip down to Evans Hunt for the party.<br />
This was the first office party for kids that I&#8217;ve ever attended, at any company. For reasons I&#8217;m sure someone much smarter than me could explain, Evans Hunt employees have a statistically high number of kids under the age of 10, and I&#8217;m willing to bet at least half are two or younger. At any rate, the fact that all of these kids existed was what led to the scheduling of the party, which we parents were quite happy for.<br />
The sixth floor &#8212; the new part of the office &#8212; was chosen for the venue. The large boardroom was co-opted for gingerbread man decorating and crafts, the main space for what ended up being punch-clown tackling, with a large comfy chair set aside for the Big Man.<br />
The kids rapidly multiplied, until the point where I think there may have been almost more kids than adults &#8230; though there have been more adults acting like kids after a while.<br />
When Santa arrived (Santa was a friend of a friend who does this professionally), the kids went crazy &#8230; and Choo Choo almost never left his side, utterly desperate for, well, not so much a present as just talking to him. Quite the reverse of Monkey, who was terrified of Santa for the first three and a half years of life.<br />
Monkey, interestingly, was the first one called up. She happily hopped up on his lap, talked a bit, got her present, and got down (with a hurried &#8220;thank you&#8221;) before going off to find out what the present was. (For the record, &#8220;Santa&#8221; was brilliant at finding things the kids seem to love.)<br />
Poor Choo Choo then had to endure most of the other kids coming next, one after another. She sat, enthralled, desperately eager to get on his lap. I managed to drag her away after a little while to drink more of her juice, when suddenly Santa produced the present. Choo Choo was off my lap in the blink of an eye, and raced over to Santa as fast as she could. She happily jumped up, and promptly asked for a &#8220;plane&#8221;.<br />
I have no idea where this &#8220;plane&#8221; thing was coming from. It&#8217;s now what she wants for Christmas. She was moderately disappointed at the <em>Stella and Sam</em> book she got instead.<br />
Party over, we headed home so Alex and I could shower and change for the next event of the day, her office Christmas party. Grandma appeared shortly after 5:00, which was about the time I dropped dinner on the table for them, mostly so they could eat and not bother Alex and I long enough that we could get ready for going out.<br />
We were gone just before 6:00, stopped at the hospital for Alex to get the tickets, and at the Ceili&#8217;s at Southland before 6:20. We sat at a table with Sarah, one of Alex&#8217;s regular co-workers, and Casey, who was one of the co-workers until she left to work at the new South hospital. It was the best move, since it was a good chance for us to chat with people we already knew.<br />
We left by 9:00.<br />
But lest ye think we were done &#8230; think again. Our destination? Toys &#8216;R Us. And not one, but two of them &#8212; one less than five minutes from the restaurant, and the other way up in the north. We didn&#8217;t get home until nearly 11:45. I got to bed a half-hour later after taking Grandma home.<br />
Sunday. Today. Yet more stuff.<br />
Mostly me doing my Christmas shopping, notably picking up things for Alex, and picking up the Playmobile toys for the girls that Grandma and I had found on Friday.<br />
And then we went to Zoo Lights.<br />
We&#8217;ve done this many times before, but this year we opted to try something a little differently. We opted to try going by C-Train, now that the new West LRT is open, and happens to run from here out to the Zoo. It seemed like a good idea, and we were &#8212; at least initially &#8212; excited to try out the new route.<br />
For the record, the trip is a minimum of 35 minutes (45 if you happen to <em>just</em> miss the train, which we did on the outbound). And although it was only -3, it somehow felt quite a bit colder, which we all seemed to notice. Thankfully the kids were well-bundled, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad for them.<br />
We got home at 9:00, well after some people&#8217;s bedtimes.<br />
Like mine. Or at least, that&#8217;s what it feels like. &#8216;Cuz after all this, I feel really tired.<br />
Sleep. Need sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hangin&#039; out in Panama</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/hangin-out-in-panama/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hangin-out-in-panama</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/hangin-out-in-panama/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 02:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[panama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m sitting near the edge of the illuminated blue-green pool, laptop burning a hole through my lap (as usual, the laptop is too wam to actually keep on a lap), spending some time outside while Mi Pequeña Niña is sleeping.   Yes, we leave her in a hotel room to sleep alone. It&#8217;s either that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/hangin-out-in-panama/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Hangin&#039; out in Panama"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m sitting near the edge of the illuminated blue-green pool, laptop burning a hole through my lap (as usual, the laptop is too wam to actually keep on a lap), spending some time outside while Mi Pequeña Niña is sleeping.  <br />
Yes, we leave her in a hotel room to sleep alone. It&#8217;s either that or we go to bed way too early, or we keep her up. Not much wiggle room, there.  <br />
Anyhoo, we&#8217;re sitting down by the pool to relax a bit before going to bed.  <br />
<span id="more-1123"></span>Our first day in Panama was much quieter than I&#8217;d expected. After breakfast, we wanted around the hotel a little bit before we all ended up in bed (MPN long before Alex and I). Arriving at the hotel at nearly 01:00 this morning and getting up at 8:00 after very little sleep (and a very long week) really takes its toll on you.  <br />
After that, it was off to Multiplaza Pacifica for a little shopping (we only ended up buying a book and a pair of water wings for MPN) and lunch. I had hoped we might be able to do Casco Viejo today, but time didn&#8217;t allow.<br />
Dinner was pretty much a let-down as well, as we couldn&#8217;t stay far due to the wee one&#8217;s need to eat. Combine that limitation with a loud, annoying live band, it made for a limiting day. Admittedly, not renting a car added to that, so we can&#8217;t really complain too much. In retrospect, we probably should have rented a car due to the lack of seatbelts in cars here &#8212; national law seems to only mandate them for the front seat. And without a car seat for El Bebe, we need to have them for us to hang onto her.  <br />
Not sure what we&#8217;re going to get up to tomorrow. Alex has hinted she&#8217;d like to see the Canal, but she also wants a pedicure. So we&#8217;ll see what happens.  <br />
Admittedly, I find this an interesting test for the work we&#8217;re doing with Panama Tourism, as this is exactly the situation we want to appeal to &#8212; people here on weekends. Now the question is: how to make it accessible?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/hangin-out-in-panama/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>San JosÃ© Airport is no fun after 20:00</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/san-jose-airport-is-no-fun-after-2000/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=san-jose-airport-is-no-fun-after-2000</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/san-jose-airport-is-no-fun-after-2000/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 03:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, we&#8217;re here waiting at the airport for our flight to Panama. A flight that I&#8217;m not really looking forward to, only because I&#8217;d rather not to go Panama this weekend (would rather do this intentionally than being forced into it).   I will say this: Normally this isn&#8217;t such a bad airport given the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/san-jose-airport-is-no-fun-after-2000/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "San JosÃ© Airport is no fun after 20:00"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we&#8217;re here waiting at the airport for our flight to Panama. A flight that I&#8217;m not really looking forward to, only because I&#8217;d rather not to go Panama this weekend (would rather do this intentionally than being forced into it).  <br />
I will say this: Normally this isn&#8217;t such a bad airport given the stores that you can spend a couple of hours searching through. But everything closes here at 20:00, leaving us not much to do. And considering that the lines are non-existent at the check-in counter in the evening, we&#8217;ve got a lot of time to kill.  <br />
Sigh.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/san-jose-airport-is-no-fun-after-2000/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Butterflies and getting lost</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=butterflies-and-getting-lost</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 04:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traffic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You can only stay around Santa Ana for so long before you start to feel a little caged in. And given that Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña are here all day, every day, there was a distinct need to explore a bit beyond our bounds. So Saturday morning (yes, I know this is a little &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Butterflies and getting lost"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can only stay around Santa Ana for so long before you start to feel a little caged in. And given that Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña are here all day, every day, there was a distinct need to explore a bit beyond our bounds. So Saturday morning (yes, I know this is a little late, I&#8217;ve intentionally been keeping away from my computer this weekend) we went off in search of adventure.  <br />
And butterflies.  <br />
<span id="more-1084"></span>This was Alex&#8217;s decision. I&#8217;ve suggested a lot, but Alex (presumably on a recommendation from her friend Rebecca, who lived in Costa Rica for a collective couple of years) suggested Saturday&#8217;s excursion. I hope to hear more desires of places to go (beyond &#8220;Arenal&#8221;, which I&#8217;ve heard a few times since we arrived in late July), as that&#8217;ll give us a good chance to see more of the country.  <br />
Anyhoo, Alex chose a placed called Spirogyra Butterfly Garden (the name is pronounced &#8220;spee-roh-HEE-ra&#8221; en Español), and we headed off around 10:00, effectively skipping MPN&#8217;s morning nap. (Though she did sleep a bit in the car on the way there.)  <br />
According to Google, Spirogrya is just north of La Sabana park, which didn&#8217;t take us long to get to. Well, the park didn&#8217;t take us long to get to. I neglected to realise that one cannot actually turn to the left to run down Avenida 4 from Calle 41 (for those of you in San Jose, that&#8217;s trying to turn onto the road at the north side of La Sabana from the road at the end side of La Sabana). If you go north of Avenida 4, you end up on Highway 1.  <br />
Not what I&#8217;d planned for.<br />
So after a 20-minute detour/return trip, we finally got back to Avenida 4, and turned down the road where<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=spirogyra+butterfly+garden&amp;sll=9.938417,-84.0903&amp;sspn=0.052163,0.058193&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.942982,-84.085064&amp;spn=0.052162,0.058193&amp;t=h&amp;z=14&amp;iwloc=B"> Google had put Spirogyra on the map</a>. I was a little suspicious about a butterfly farm being there, but since it&#8217;s possible to have a factory right next to a neighbourhood (zoning doesn&#8217;t really seem to exist here), I wasn&#8217;t about to be one to challenge the wisdom of Google.  <br />
That said, Google was wrong.<br />
Leaving the neighbourhood, we ended up having to go around La Sabana to get ourselves back to Paseo Colon, cutting through the San Jose to get to Calle Central, which would take us north of the downtown, across the river, where we could scoot over towards El Pedro (an apparently defunct mall). But not far from turning onto Avenida Central (not the one right downtown, I should add &#8212; San Jose can be very confusing), we saw the sign for <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;hl=en&amp;msa=0&amp;ll=9.940007,-84.072747&amp;spn=0.00326,0.003637&amp;t=h&amp;z=18&amp;msid=106619148814639590944.0004565abbf7a50d3a3c6">Spirogyra Mariposa JardÃƒ ­n</a>.  <br />
We were the only ones there. No-one else came during our 45-minute romp through a black netting-covered garden that was &#8230; well, not &#8220;filled&#8221; with butterflies, but there were certainly a number of them. A few even landed me on me, mistaking me apparently for a rotting log.  <br />
[Insert joke about lack of sexual prowess here.]<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña didn&#8217;t seem too particularly thrilled with the butterflies, at least not as much as I thought she&#8217;d be. Pretty much any animal, and she goes ga-ga until the animal is out of sight. Insects? Not so much.  Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it&#8217;s a nice place. Next time I go back, it&#8217;ll be with my SLR (at least once it&#8217;s working properly) to get all these wonderful things on film.  <br />
[flickr]photo:2838949976(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838957648(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838962534(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838134253(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838975040(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838149761(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838157243(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838164869(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838178969(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838183957(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2838189155(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The cafe there was closed, so we decided to make a break for San Pedro Mall, on the east side of San Jose. In theory, not a long drive from Spirogyra.  <br />
In theory.  <br />
Also, in theory, the roads here are marked well enough that you can easily find your way without getting horribly lost. Which is precisely what happened to us. Well, not so much &#8220;horribly&#8221;, but definitely &#8220;lost&#8221;. My fault, I will state for the record, as I had incorrectly made a few assumptions about direction and distance, and believed that we would cross a highway that runs along the east side. Turns out we passed over said highway and ended up someplace completely different.  <br />
Like, I can&#8217;t even <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;saddr=Santa+Ana,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+Costa+Rica&amp;daddr=Point+of+Lost+Return+%409.944382144667635,-84.01358842849731&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=%3BFT69lwAd7A3--g&amp;mra=ls&amp;sll=9.944815,-84.013792&amp;sspn=0.00326,0.003637&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.944863,-84.013095&amp;spn=0.01304,0.014548&amp;t=h&amp;z=16">find the name of the area that we ended up in</a> kind of different. Oops.  <br />
Ironically, I had made not one, but two collosally bad turns. The first was not realising when I&#8217;d arrived at the #2 highway, which would have taken us to San Pedro. The second was turning left, not right, and driving AWAY from the San Pedro on a road that would have taken us TO San Pedro.  <br />
Methinks my internal compass is screwed up. Normally, I&#8217;m not this bad.  <br />
Finally arriving at San Pedro Mall, we went in search of lunch. The usual fast-food adorned the food court, including the ubiquitous Kentucky Fried Chicken, or KFC as it&#8217;s known here. KFC is a really weird phenomenon in Costa Rica. Apparently, so the story goes, it used to be really bad. Then some American guy came down, bought the chain, and overhauled the marketing. (If you ever think marketing isn&#8217;t useful, you clearly have never paid attention to its affects.) Now it&#8217;s the most successful one. Mark, Jason, and I have commented several times on quitting our jobs and opening a few KFCs &#8212; there&#8217;s always lineups at these things!<br />
Not wanting to eat any North American fast-food (I&#8217;m in a different country, darn it, I want something local), we went to Pollos Campaneros. Fried chicken. Tasted like KFC. Go figure.  <br />
Actually, the taste took me back to my last year of high school. In the summer, my friends and I (Stuart, Therese, Chris, James, Linda, Ali, Kathryn, Hil, Eva, and J) would go to <a href="http://www.canadaswonderland.com/">Canada&#8217;s Wonderland</a> for the day. The entire day. We&#8217;d be there when the park opened at 10:00, and leave when the park closed at 22:00. For lunch, we&#8217;d take buckets of cold KFC, which for some reason we were all completely fascinated with.  <br />
Good days, those.  <br />
The San Pedro Mall is kind of odd. It has some higher-end stores, but one end of the mall looks like a run-down outlet-type configuration. There&#8217;s even a place on the lowest level that sells (reasonably accurate) Rolex, Breitling, Hublot, and Omega knock-offs. The sweep isn&#8217;t quite right, but whatever. For $150, what do you expect?<br />
The route home I need to perfect a little better (there are faster routes through downtown), but it&#8217;s at least familiar. One of these days, though, I need to check out the fort in San Jose. It looks pretty neat, albeit totally devoid of tourists every time we&#8217;ve seen it.  <br />
This weekend coming up is another adventure. Where will this one take us? You&#8217;ll just have to wait and see&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1084</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Vegas</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-in-vegas</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 21:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/08/back-in-vegas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back in Vegas"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for the good, I should say.<br />
If you&#8217;ve watched CSI, you&#8217;ve seen a stylised version of Las Vegas. And it ain&#8217;t the one that&#8217;s here. This is half gambling, half drunken idiots, half shopping, half selling sex, with some shows tossed in for fun.<br />
Yes, I know that adds up to well more than 100%. But this is a city of excesses.<br />
<span id="more-909"></span>Why am I here? My friend Tamara is getting married. It&#8217;s hard having been Tamara&#8217;s friend for the last year. Technically, I&#8217;m her boss. So I have to keep a &#8220;respectful distance&#8221;. Which sucks, since I&#8217;ve known her nearly eight years &#8212; nearly three of which we were housemates. We know each other pretty well. But I can&#8217;t act around her the way I would normally at work, since it might cast a light of favouritism.<br />
But when she asked me to come to her wedding, there was no question. None. Well, except whether or not Alex and the Wee One would come. As it is, they didn&#8217;t, and I&#8217;m running solo. Yeah, I know what you&#8217;re thinking: woo hoo, a weekend in Sin City for Geoff!<br />
I have a 7-month old and a wife, both of whom I love more than life itself. Do you really think I&#8217;m going to do something stupid?<br />
Besides, I&#8217;m too old to drink to the point of being sick (which I saw more than once yesterday), I never gamble with my money &#8212; only my life, and frankly I really don&#8217;t want to find out what weird diseases the hookers in this city pass around.<br />
That was a part of this city I&#8217;d forgotten about. It&#8217;s not just the newspaper box-like containers that distribute catalogues for hookers (no, I&#8217;m not kidding), it&#8217;s all the people who stand along the sidewalks, picking off all the guys (solo or in groups) to hand them cards. They flick them in their fingers like a nervous poker player. But instead of a royal flush, it&#8217;s a royal &#8230; well, y&#8217;know. It&#8217;s pathetic to see, and I actually feel sorry for these people.<br />
The Vegas of old where everything is cheap is long gone, too. Everything here is insanely expensive. It was $15 just to travel the 1.5 kms from the airport to my hotel. And that was moving pretty darn zippily, I might add. Meals are insanely expensive, too. Although I managed to find the Tea House in the Imperial Palace. A roast beef meal with all-you-can-drink lemonade for $20 with tip. At the newer hotels, that&#8217;s just your drink.<br />
I&#8217;m staying at the Tropicana, in a hotel room that hasn&#8217;t seen a renovation in about three decades. The maintenance hatch to the bathroom plumbing is rusting at the edges, the silicone seals have dried and peeled away, and the sink doesn&#8217;t drain worth a damn. The bed must be wrapped in plastic from what I could feel.<br />
Tamara and Dan, by comparison, are in the 18th floor of the Mandalay Bay. Their place is bigger and nicer than most of the apartments I&#8217;ve stayed in. It&#8217;s almost criminal. But they&#8217;ve never been here before, so they&#8217;re allowed the experience. Besides, it&#8217;s their wedding, right?<br />
I spent today shopping. Clothes for the Wee One, a trinket or two for Alex. I tried to find a cheap camera flash for me, but be darned if there isn&#8217;t a single freakin&#8217; camera store closer than a $20 cab ride. I&#8217;ve done enough cab rides for now. I&#8217;ll stick to the monorail.<br />
Tonight is the &#8220;night before&#8221;. Tamara and her crew are going to the Stratosphere to have fun. Dan&#8217;s at a show until 22:00 or so, so I&#8217;ll run around and get some night pictures (would you expect any less of me?)<br />
Well, only 1 minute left on this internet cafe computer, so I&#8217;ll wrap up this entry. Tomorrow&#8217;s the wedding, so with luck I&#8217;ll hammer something more out. And yes, pictures will come once I can get them all uploaded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">909</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buying a suit</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/buying-a-suit/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=buying-a-suit</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/buying-a-suit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2005 12:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/11/buying-a-suit/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So one of my missions here in Hong Kong (self-imposed, I should add) is to find a suit. Not just any suit, but the one for my wedding. So needless to say, there&#8217;s a certain amount of care needed in ensuring that what I get is what I need. I mean, I&#8217;m getting married in &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/buying-a-suit/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Buying a suit"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So one of my missions here in Hong Kong (self-imposed, I should add) is to find a suit. Not just any suit, but the one for my wedding. So needless to say, there&#8217;s a certain amount of care needed in ensuring that what I get is what I need. I mean, I&#8217;m getting <em>married</em> in this. Yet, I don&#8217;t want to break the bank.<br />
For some reason, dress-makers are on Hong Kong Island, but the tailors are in Kowloon. An interesting divide, but it meant that I couldn&#8217;t do anything until yesterday.<br />
<span id="more-573"></span>After we&#8217;d checked in to our new hotel here in Tsim Sha Tsui (and cooled down enough that my shirt wasn&#8217;t entirely filled with sweat), I wandered down to the bell hop/concierge (I swear every hotel in Hong Kong has full concierge service) and asked for who the hotel recommends for a tailor. I expected right away that whoever they did recommend would cost an arm and a leg.<br />
Baron Kay&#8217;s. Nice place. Good staff. But wrong colours (and we looked through at least 20 or so books of fabrics) and over $700 for just the jacket and suit. Definitely a different clientele than people like yours truly. So off I go (back into heat that I can only describe as the kind used to cook bamboo baskets of dim sum delectables) in search of a new place. I decided to give the Lonely Planet&#8217;s suggestion a whirl&#8230;<br />
Stitch-Up Tailors is in the Star House, on the south side of the building. The main sales guy, whose name I still haven&#8217;t gotten (he was on top of me even before I was in eyesight of him, he&#8217;s that aggressive), sized me up, quoted me, and then we engaged in the mandatory price bartering. Not being a sales person myself, I didn&#8217;t manage to push him down as far as I wanted, but I still got a better price than what I could get in Calgary, and with the colour I wanted. That, two shirts, and a tie. I certainly can&#8217;t complain too much.<br />
So while we&#8217;re trying to pin down the time for me to do a first fitting (some FOUR HOURS later!), he&#8217;s trying to sell me another suit. More shirts. Pants. Anything. It&#8217;s almost like he&#8217;s unable to breath without selling someone an article of clothing. &#8220;Hugo Boss&#8221; is a period of a sentence for him. It&#8217;s sheer overload. After I&#8217;d put down a deposit, I finally manage to ask him a question: How does he deal with this heat? It&#8217;s kill me, and he doesn&#8217;t seem phased. He&#8217;s lived here 35 years and must have a secret of some kind (given, he&#8217;s from India). He looked at me, smiled, and said:<br />
&#8220;Beer&#8221;.<br />
Then he offered me one. Be darned if he wasn&#8217;t right!<br />
I finally manage to break away, and find my way (sweating buckets &#8212; here, you can&#8217;t fry an egg on the street; it would hard boil in the egg before you could crack it) to the hotel and make plans with Amy, who was going off for her dress fitting (as you&#8217;ve already read).<br />
Spin ahead to 18:30, and I&#8217;m back at Stitch-Up. The suit comes in. About 50% completed. The jacket is missing a sleeve, but it looks like a suit. And it fit pretty well, given that there were no zippers or buttons. The tailor, who spoke not a single word of English, tugged and pulled and scrawled a few numbers, then darted off again with the unfinished garment. And then while I attempted to get the finished fitting arranged, the sales guy bombarded me with an unending sequence of &#8220;what colour of pants would you like?&#8221;, &#8220;how many shirts in this blue?&#8221; (holding out a fabric that, while nice, I wouldn&#8217;t wear), &#8220;you need to wear suits &#8212; how many do you need, two, three&#8221;?<br />
When I finally managed to convince him that I don&#8217;t wear suits enough to warrant one, he tried to get me to pay for Scotch Guarding and permanent pressing, things I really don&#8217;t need. Especially at the price he was trying to get me to pay. It took a lot of effort for me to finally get out of that store.<br />
And lest you think that he&#8217;s just out to scam people, <strong>all</strong> the tailors here are like that. Most of them are even worse. Amy and I dodged no less than a dozen of them in the span of 100 metres before hitting the cafe tonight!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/buying-a-suit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">573</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend in Edmonton</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-edmonton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2004 04:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/08/22/surprise-weekend-edmonton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend in Edmonton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away.<br />
It was a bit of a special one, but for no other reason than we&#8217;d barely seen each other in almost three weeks. I was away in San Jose for a conference (see [[Search Engine Strategies Conference 2004 San Jose, Calgary to San Jose]]), followed immediately by the Calgary Dragon Boat Festival (see [[2004 Calgary Dragon Boat Festival]]), and then Alex was off in Ontario for a week and a half. So I had to plan this weekend&#8217;s getaway so we&#8217;d have some time to ourselves.<br />
<span id="more-378"></span>That&#8217;s the tricky part, actually. I had a devil of a time finding something quasi-romantic, yet equitable, and that wouldn&#8217;t put a major dent in my wallet. Easier said than done when you consider that it&#8217;s high season out here for tourism. So I decided to go some place somewhere unconventional for tourism. The sort of place that doesn&#8217;t immediately come to your mind as a destination. (It is, at least at this end of Alberta, even considered a punishment by some.)<br />
Edmonton.<br />
It&#8217;s a large city, with interesting things, comfortable hotels, and a wee bit of shopping. (Yes, that&#8217;s a joke.) I&#8217;d only ever been there three times before (once on my Trans-Canada tour in 1997, again with the Rocky Mountain Rail Society in October 2001, and then with the CBC almost a year later). In those three times, I&#8217;d barely seen anything of Edmonton, so this was a chance to see &#8230; well, more than I had. Now all I had to do was keep Alex in the dark as to where she was going.<br />
That&#8217;s a lot harder than it sounds. Alex wanted to know &#8212; who doesn&#8217;t want to know what a surprise is? Be damned if she didn&#8217;t really dig for it, too. In fact, Thursday night, she kept at me for nearly two straight hours of questioning. She was persistent, and sometimes really sneaky when composing her questions. I was quite proud of myself for not supplying the answer, while not lying about the destination.<br />
But everyone has their Achilles heel. Mine is Miao-Yin.<br />
Alex took a turn of what was supposed to be silly questioning, where she asked if the cat would like where we were going. Would the cat enjoy the view? Would she like to drive? What about if she wanted to stop and get out for a while? Hey, maybe she could take us out for dinner one night! It was supposed to be in fun, but I got stuck on the more serious side: namely, the cat wouldn&#8217;t survive the trip down the block without me going insane from her yowling, let alone the three hour drive to Edmonton&#8230;<br />
Insert a long string of emphatic expletives here. Because that&#8217;s what spewed out of my mouth immediately after &#8212; letting the cat out of the bag &#8212; I said where we were going.<br />
So that piece of the surprise was divulged the night before. Doh. But Alex didn&#8217;t know where we were staying, or why she had to bring a nice outfit. And those I kept quite tightly under wraps.<br />
Despite leaving Calgary a little later than I&#8217;d planned Friday evening, we arrived in Red Deer before 19:30. Hunting for a restaurant downtown (and turning up empty), we ended up at the White Spot. (Not my first choice of places for dinner, but it holds a particular place in Alex&#8217;s heart from when she was younger.) It took everything I had not to mock our waiter, obviously a student from Red Deer College, either trying to be an actor or a radio personality, and failing miserably. His schmaltzy shtick dripped of goofiness, despite an obvious desire to be taken seriously. I know more than a few people who would have talked back to him in the same manner.<br />
I&#8217;d never arrived in Edmonton from the south before. Fortunately, signs weren&#8217;t too hard to follow to downtown, and the road was actually familiar from the time the CBC crew had taken a shuttle bus to the train station &#8212; surprisingly, I still remembered it. The hard part was then finding the hotel. Despite having the address, the grid system actually confused me rather than helped. Alex was rhyming off building names or companies, starting at the names of hotels before slipping into ones like banks, insurance companies, restaurants, and the YMCA. Finally, I found the Westin, and we pulled in.<br />
Why the Westin? One reason: The Heavenly Bed. I spent a weekend in one during a prison term in Cincinnati (see [[Live from Cincinnati, Surviving Memorial Day]]) and haven&#8217;t forgotten it. Given how much Alex and I hadn&#8217;t seen each other, and Alex&#8217;s less-than-stellar trip to Ontario, I felt that perhaps a really comfortable stay would help. It certainly couldn&#8217;t hurt&#8230;<br />
We checked in on a very auspicious weekend. In addition to the Fringe Festival (an annual event in Edmonton), there was also the Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival (Topmade sent the Dragoneers, and Sang and Colette were also paddling for Crew Yahoo of the Calgary Dragon Boat Club), the Jazz Festival (I think), the 100th Anniversary of Edmonton, and the coup de grace, being held at the Westin, the National Bodybuilding Championship.<br />
Be still my beating heart.<br />
After waking up quite late the following morning (we were both quite content to stay in the Heavenly Bed), we went in search of breakfast. A flip through the phonebook was a bit frustrating due to the lack of options. Eventually, we decided on the Denny&#8217;s, about 12 blocks from the Westin. It would have been a nice walk, had it not been cold, windy, with a spattering of rain mixed in for flavour. We cut through the mall downtown to save ourselves from the chill.<br />
The Denny&#8217;s was packed. But it was also one of the only eateries that we could find in the area that serves breakfast, at least from judging by the line-up inside. It took nearly a half hour to get a seat for two. It would take about the same amount of time to actually get our breakfast once ordered.<br />
While we waited, we babbled nearly incoherently about whatever kept coming to mind. (Hey, we had almost three weeks of events and trivial crap to catch up on.) While we chatted, a semi-familiar silhouette passed through my peripheral vision, heading into the washroom.<br />
Me: &#8220;I think that&#8217;s Mo!&#8221;<br />
Alex: &#8220;Mo? Topmade Mo?&#8221;<br />
Me: &#8220;Yeah&#8230; it *is* Mo! And there&#8217;s Byron, and Arnold!&#8221;<br />
The Topmade Dragoneers were in town (the aforementioned Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival), and some of the team had apparently decided to grab a meal at Denny&#8217;s in between the races. (The Edmonton Festival, unlike it&#8217;s Cowtown counterpart, is planned very well. It also had the sense to judge teams by the times they logged racing, not by some idiotic point system &#8212; Calgary Festival organizers, take note!)<br />
Arnold was surprised by our appearance:<br />
&#8220;You&#8217;re the last two I expected to see here!&#8221;<br />
Yeah, I know, what the heck does that mean? I was wondering that, slightly miffed. It wasn&#8217;t like we didn&#8217;t enjoy ourselves paddling. I&#8217;m rather looking forward to it next year. Actually, if anything, I&#8217;m miffed that I&#8217;m not getting the club updates (they were looking for volunteers this weekend; not that I&#8217;d have been able to go even if I had got the notice). We promised to drop by later on.<br />
We trudged out into the rain following our meal, and decided to take a shortcut through Grant McEwan Community College, just across the street. (Partly because it&#8217;s an interesting-looking building, but also because it was warm and dry.) The college campus is situated on the old Canadian National rail yard that used to run through downtown Edmonton (well, what is now downtown Edmonton &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t downtown when the yard was built). With the yard relocated to the north end of the city, the lands were freed up for other uses. The $16 million parcel of land was donated to the College, which then built its main campus.<br />
The College&#8217;s namesake, Grant McEwan, is a man of considerable distinction. Alex and I didn&#8217;t really know who the man was. Thanks to an exhibit in the main lobby, we found out that the Honourable Mr. McEwan was a Professor and the Director of the School of Agriculture at the University of Saskatchewan, a magazine editor (and prolific author), a Calgary alderman and a three-year Mayor of our fair city, became an MLA for Calgary and was elected the Liberal Party leader, became the Lieutenant Governor of Alberta for eight and a half years before going into semi-retirement. He never slowed down, however, and continued humanitarian work until his death in 2000 (at the age of almost 98).<br />
There are times when you simply can&#8217;t avoid feeling humbled.<br />
We ended up having to dive back into the rain, thoroughly unable to avoid it. We trudged through the Farmer&#8217;s Market before finally finding our way back to the mall we&#8217;d cut through earlier in the morning. We did some window shopping (I ended buying a new fleece jacket, mostly because I hadn&#8217;t come properly prepared for the weather) before returning to the hotel. We napped. It was great.<br />
Dinner was a surprise I managed to keep on tap, though Alex guessed the destination by some of the clues I had let out (but by then, I didn&#8217;t mind) &#8212; Fairmont&#8217;s Hotel MacDonald, about a block from the Westin. Specifically, the Harvest Room. I was told this was one of the best restaurants in town, and I wanted to take Alex there. I even wore a suit and tie for the affair.<br />
Oh, one thing I need to point out. While we were preparing for dinner (mainly me ironing my clothes), we listened to the radio. Much to our surprise (and near shock), we came across 92.5, known as Joe FM. Now this might sound a little weird &#8212; why would I identify a radio station, you might ask? It&#8217;s a sister station of 96.9 Jack FM. Same commercials, same commercial voice dude, but it just didn&#8217;t sound right. Even the slogan was different: Playing &#8230; Anything! (In Calgary, it&#8217;s &#8220;Playing &#8230; what we want!&#8221;) Yet another reason why Edmonton and Calgary don&#8217;t get along.<br />
I have to say that I was mildly disappointed with the experience. The hotel itself is nice, but the Harvest Room lacked the old-world quality you often find in the older Fairmont hotels (most notably the Banff Springs). The food was well done, but I felt I&#8217;d had better meals here in Calgary, and much &#8220;lower-end&#8221; restaurants. I also felt the service wasn&#8217;t quite to the level I&#8217;d expect for Fairmont. (Or more importantly, a Canadian Pacific Hotel.) Such as it is, the meal was wonderful, as was the company. Next time, though, I think we&#8217;ll go somewhere else.<br />
By the time the meal was done, it was nearly 20:00, so we opted for a dip in our hotel&#8217;s hot tub (it was a little chilly outside). After a cold beverage in the bar, we headed for bed. Despite really doing nothing, we were both quite tired.<br />
Awaking late again the next morning, we rose, showered and packed, while watching the Olympics. I haven&#8217;t watched much of it this year (partly due to the time change), but what little I have seen kind of annoys me. And it&#8217;s not he performances, it&#8217;s all the media.<br />
C&#8217;mon folks, it ain&#8217;t about the medals. So what if Canada isn&#8217;t getting that many this year? Big deal! Our athletes are out there, competing, and doing a pretty good job, all things considered. Are they gonna bring home the bacon? Maybe, but will the world end if they don&#8217;t? Probably not. Just let them compete without all the additional pressure &#8212; they went there to represent Canada, not be bad-mouthed by us.<br />
Checking out, we drove (as it was raining even harder Sunday morning) for Denny&#8217;s. No-one from Topmade was there that time, so we ate in relative anonymity. We headed back to our hotel&#8217;s parking lot, though, to go down to the festival area to see our friends and team-mates.<br />
We arrived just in time for the Sistership tribute. This is something they do almost every festival (they didn&#8217;t do it in Calgary, for some reason). It&#8217;s in tribute to those lost to breast cancer. Sistership is a club whose members are all cancer patients, past and present.<br />
Passing by the boards, we found the scores of the previous day. Topmade Dragoneers had done quite well, and were ranked up with EDBC and Jetstart (from Toronto). One of the others under the tent commented that the first race was going to be a good one. Alex and I would not wait to see it, as we were cold and wet, and really not wanting to stick around in the weather.<br />
Finding Topmade&#8217;s tent, we found Sang and Collette inside. We chatted for a while before following them down as they went to get something to eat. We left them at the food vendors and returned to the car. We were off&#8230;<br />
&#8230;to West Edmonton Mall. The largest mall in the world. The megalopolis of merchandising.<br />
It&#8217;s a weird place, if you&#8217;ve never been. Parts of it make sense. But then you run into Galaxyland (formerly known as Fantasyland), which is the midway there. Rides that you would normally see at the Calgary Stampede, PNE, or CNE are permanent showcases there. Even the infamous rollercoaster on which people died a number of years ago. It&#8217;s loud. It&#8217;s hard to believe you&#8217;re in a shopping mall.<br />
And then there&#8217;s the ice rink, the water park, the indoor golf course, the submarines, and the model of the Santa Maria.<br />
Oh, and lest we forget the over two decade-old design? That place is in *serious* need of a facelift. (It also didn&#8217;t help that the glass roof leaks, probably due to that nasty hailstorm and flooding of a couple months ago.)<br />
Considering its size, the mall wasn&#8217;t that bad for crowds &#8212; we had little or no trouble getting around. Well, except for size &#8212; the mall is huge, after all. I was disappointed to see that Sega Playdium had closed down. Considering the other attractions in the mall, however, I could understand.<br />
After about four hours, we&#8217;d had enough, and it was time to head home. Alex tried to cross-stitch as we headed out of town, but eventually switched over to reading for a while (reading to *me*, I might add) to take a break.<br />
We stopped again in Red Deer for dinner, this time going to Boston Pizza for, well, pizza. Nothing outlandish, we split a small (10&#8243;) between us, which was just perfect. Then it was back on the highway in the rain, drizzle, and fog, before arriving back at Alex&#8217;s shortly after 21:00.<br />
The weekend was good, despite the weather. Edmonton isn&#8217;t exactly the vacation destination I had thought it might be, but then we didn&#8217;t see much of it either. Next time, we&#8217;ll have to go somewhere else, though. Someplace less urban.<br />
And if you&#8217;re looking for hints here, Alex, you&#8217;ll have to try harder than that!<br />
[flickr]tag:edmonton+august+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2004 23:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[osaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/02/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;. The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;.<br />
The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from our hotel to the Osaka Aquarium, our first destination of the day.<br />
<span id="more-340"></span>The problem was that Jen&#8217;s stomach was beginning to rebel. It doesn&#8217;t appreciate the Japanese diet the same way mine does. Mind you, mine&#8217;s been tempered with age, and isn&#8217;t wholly dependant on low-fat, unsweetened milk (which Jen&#8217;s seems to be). So the lack of milk and high fish content (which Jen&#8217;s not a particular fan of) really didn&#8217;t create an ideal situation.<br />
So we were a little later leaving than I had planned.<br />
We arrived at the aquarium about five minutes ahead of my prediction (noon), despite all the trains and transfers we&#8217;d had to take. Overall, not such a bad thing. Why were we going to an aquarium on the opposite side of the planet? Simply put: because Osaka Aquarium is one of the largest in the world, and features a whale shark, which I&#8217;ve never seen.<br />
Jen got screwed on the entrance fee. According to their fee schedule, she is still a child, which meant a mere 900 yen fee (rather than the 2000 yen adult fee). However, even armed with her passport (as proof of age), the clerks simply didn&#8217;t believe that she was 15. If only we had those guys from the izakaya (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]]) for assistance.<br />
We headed into the aquarium, going up a long escalator into the main building&#8217;s 7th floor, where we were introduced to the Japan Forest, at the heart of the building. This started us on a slow spiral all the way down to the 4th floor, taking us through the Aleutian Islands, Monterey Bay, Gulf of Panama, Ecuadorian Rain Forest, Antarctica, Tasman Sea, Great Barrier Reef, Pacific Ocean, Seto Inland Sea, Kelp Forest, Coast of Chile, Cook Strait, and the Japan Deeps.<br />
Each portion of the trip represented one part of the Ring of Fire, of which Japan is part. (The Ring of Fire is a geological name for the ring around the Pacific Ocean, characterized by tectonic and volcanic activity.) It also is arranged in a way that is supposed to representative of the Gaia theory, which states the world is in fact a living organism from which the life we see sprouts, and returns to upon death.<br />
At the top, the aquarium is interesting, but not particularly thrilling. Monterey Bay was a bit of a laugh, having been to Monterey myself (see 18 July 1998) and having seen the Monterey Bay Aquarium (which I would quite willingly put on the same scale as the Osaka Aquarium for size and quality). As you spiral down, you&#8217;re given a deeper look into some parts, and completely exposed to others for the first time.<br />
At the core of the aquarium is the Pacific Ocean exhibit. This massive tank, sealed in by 30cm-thick acrylic walls, contains 5,400 tons of water and a huge number of aquatic species, including tuna, sun fish, manta rays, oscars, a couple kinds of sharks, especially the whale shark (a species that grows to 12m in length; this one was only about 6m).<br />
We were treated to many different views from several different levels of all the environments, before finally reaching the Japan Deeps, a small, dark tank with the largest, most creepy-looking crabs you&#8217;ve ever seen. It was like something out of &#8220;Alien&#8221;. Down an escalator, and we were at the jellyfish. We heard a lot of &#8220;kawaii&#8221; (Japanese for &#8220;how cute!&#8221;).<br />
Leaving the aquarium, we headed over to the Tempozan Marketplace for food and shopping. The latter was scarce, but the former wasn&#8217;t hard to find in good quantity. Jen inhaled not only her lunch, but half of mine (I wasn&#8217;t keen on eating all the rice) and was still hungry. Apparently, the sauce is the key.<br />
After calling a draw on a seriously insane air hockey game, featuring two paddles per player and three pucks at any given time, we decided to give the Tempozan Giant Ferris Wheel a whirl. This is apparently the world&#8217;s largest giant ferris where (as opposed to the world&#8217;s largest miniature ferris wheel, I can only suppose), and runs to a height of about 100m. The view from up there is quite something.<br />
We headed back to the JR Loop line (via subway) and hopped over to the other side of the city to check out Osaka Castle. This structure dates back to the 16th century, when it was built by Toyotomi Hideyoshi (a warlord who unified Japan) as his stronghold showpiece. After he died, his forces lost to the Tokugawa Shogunate, and it became a Shogun&#8217;s residence until the capital was moved to Edo (now Tokyo). The main building was destroyed by fire in the 17th century and left abandoned until the 20th century, when Osaka chose to rebuild the tower and reopen the castle for all to see. The existing structure is now concrete (hence not original), but the appearance is believed to be correct.<br />
The JR Loop line stops right at the castle grounds. However, it is not a short walk. It&#8217;s well over a kilometre to reach the tower itself. But it&#8217;s a walk work taking, since the view from there is quite good, and the tower itself is very beautiful (not as nice, perhaps, as Himeji Castle supposedly is, but I won&#8217;t be seeing that on this trip).<br />
We returned to the train to try some shopping. I had hoped to go to Dotombori, one of the major shopping and food districts in Osaka, but Jen&#8217;s energy level was so low (and we&#8217;d spent a lot of money over the last couple of days in various bits of non-JR transportation) that even considering going there was not really much of a consideration. Something else that will have to wait for the next time I come this way, I suppose.<br />
We ended up hitting part of Kita, a shopping area next to Osaka Station. There wasn&#8217;t much there. We thought of doing dinner, but due to a miscommunication, it wasn&#8217;t dinner that was of interest, but was just a thought. So it was back to Kyoto.<br />
We ate at Kyoto Station, partaking of gyoza (for Jen) and ramen (for myself) at one of the ramen shops on the 10th floor. (The station is big.) Following dinner, we headed back to the hotel. Jen really wanted to rest and draw. Being so early, I went back out.<br />
I walked down Kurasame St. to the Kyoto Tower, a rather unassuming edifice just north of Kyoto Station. It&#8217;s not particularly tall, but offered a decent view of downtown at night (although unlike the World Trade Center at Hamamatsucho in Tokyo, the interior lights are far too bright), and of the lights out at Kiyomizudera Shrine (which look very nice at night).<br />
I walked around the station again afterwards, taking some more pictures (but at night) before heading back to the hotel.<br />
On my way back, I popped into the Family Mart (a convenience store) to grab a snack. That&#8217;s when it hit me &#8212; I should find some milk for Jen. She&#8217;s desperately needed milk for a couple of days now, and most of the stuff we find just doesn&#8217;t cut the mustard. But at the Family Mart, I found something that apparently will do for now.<br />
The whole milk thing is just one of a few things that have not been ideal. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not complaining. Just that travelling with Jen has, at times, been a bit more of a challenge than I would have hoped for. We&#8217;ve had to cut short some things because, somehow, this 31 year-old can out pace his 15 year-old cousin. Osaka was a good example of this. I just hope that the milk we&#8217;ve found helps restore her energy so we can handle things like Nikko, Kamakura, and the various Tokyo excursions.<br />
[flickr]tag:osaka+japan+april+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+april+2004+&#8221;2&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">340</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
