<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>new years tea &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/new-years-tea/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:07:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The kids&#039; first New Years Eve</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-kids-first-new-years-eve</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years tea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, to be fair, Monkey is now 10, and Choo Choo is rapidly approaching 8. They&#8217;ve seen &#8220;new years eve&#8221; a few times, but they&#8217;ve been more the family-friendly type. Staying up to midnight is the new thing. The only time they&#8217;ve ever been up past midnight is because of travel, and that&#8217;s always been &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The kids&#039; first New Years Eve"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, to be fair, Monkey is now 10, and Choo Choo is rapidly approaching 8. They&#8217;ve seen &#8220;new years eve&#8221; a few times, but they&#8217;ve been more the family-friendly type. Staying up to midnight is the new thing. The only time they&#8217;ve ever been up past midnight is because of travel, and that&#8217;s always been a bit of a struggle.<br />
Last night, for the first time ever, they watched a clock tick from 23:59 of one year to 00:00 of another. Honestly, they fared better than I did.<br />
And that, my friends, is not a good sign.<br />
<span id="more-3618"></span><br />
Alex was working, so it was just the three of us. An &#8220;extreme cold&#8221; weather warning was on its third or fourth day (honestly, I&#8217;d lost track), where the ambient temperature was in the mid-minus-20s, before you tacked on the wind chill. The City of Calgary wisely cancelled their outdoor events, as did a number of other cities across Canada (including Ottawa&#8217;s somewhat-gut-punch cancellation of a final 150th event).<br />
Although the City still had their family indoor event (with a &#8220;ball drop&#8221; at 9pm), I didn&#8217;t feel like fighting the kids out the door, very bundled up, to wait for a C-Train downtown, to be too warm with too many other people (and likely way past the fire department&#8217;s safety limit), to cheer, and then come home again. So we ordered pizza and watched movies.<br />
At 21:50, I went to the internet and pulled up the live video feed of Times Square as they approached midnight EST. Without the glorious commentary of the various American broadcasters (NBC&#8217;s feed on YouTube was just the video), the event was pretty bland. Even Monkey had to ask:</p>
<blockquote><p>Wait. <em>This</em> is what people get all excited about? Just to go &#8220;woo hoo&#8221;? This is stupid.</p></blockquote>
<p>For years, I&#8217;d kinda wondered the same thing, silently. I mean, there&#8217;s a small part of me that would like to see Times Square at New Years for myself, just once, solely for the spectacle. But if NBC&#8217;s unaided feed was indicative of what it&#8217;s really like &#8230; maybe I&#8217;ll just watch at a distance and be happy with that.<br />
And, really, Monkey is right. We celebrate for what, exactly? Surviving the year? We roll a calendar just as winter has begun (at least in the northern hemisphere; I think those south of the equator have it way better, here), and still have months of freezing winds and ice to suffer through. And at the end of it, all we&#8217;ve really done is give us a few weeks of cursing ourselves for selecting &#8220;2017&#8221; from drop-down lists.<br />
None of the stupidity of 2017 has gone away. It&#8217;s still there, and will continue to still be there. It&#8217;s like having Biff Tanner banging us in the forehead, shouting &#8220;Hey! McFly!&#8221;. We still have to suffer through that.<br />
My resolution? As much as I suffer not having close contact with most of my friends, I think one of the things I must do this year is limit, or at least filter my social media. There&#8217;s too much negativity, and no matter how much I try to let it roll off, the stink remains and ultimately weighs me down. I find it no end of ironic that while my <a href="https://www.insights.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Insights</a> review says I&#8217;m not empathetic, the bullshit of the world eats away at my soul.<br />
But, as the saying goes, one day at a time. I spend too much worrying about my future, rather than the things I do today that will make that future unfold. So let&#8217;s focus on today, and let tomorrow come as it must.<br />
Which is what we did today: New Years Tea, which we&#8217;ve managed to avoid on New Years Day for a few years, largely due to Alex&#8217;s work schedule, and an apparent misunderstanding about Fairmont Palliser; until this year&#8217;s instance, we didn&#8217;t think the Palliser did afternoon tea at all. It&#8217;s no Banff Springs, and I really did want to do Chateau Lake Louise this year, but at least it&#8217;s New Years Day, which is the day I prefer to do this, not a couple of days before or after.<br />
What will tomorrow bring? I can guess, but that would be negative. Rather, I&#8217;ll just deal with it &#8230; <em>tomorrow</em>. Today, I write. Because that&#8217;s what I need to do to prepare my future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year&#039;s (Eve) Tea</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/12/new-years-eve-tea/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-eve-tea</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/12/new-years-eve-tea/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 05:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years tea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By tradition, our family does afternoon (or high) tea on 1 January, and thus far it has always been at a Fairmont hotel (which, frankly, does excellent afternoon tea). This year, almost exactly one year ago today, we had our tea as planned. But last week, we came to the realization that we could not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/12/new-years-eve-tea/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Year&#039;s (Eve) Tea"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By tradition, our family does afternoon (or high) tea on 1 January, and thus far it has always been at a Fairmont hotel (which, frankly, does excellent afternoon tea). This year, almost exactly one year ago today, we had our tea as planned. But last week, we came to the realization that we could not effectively hold to our traditional date, as Alex has an evening shift, and getting back from Banff in time was nigh-impossible without rushing.<br />
Local? The Palliser doesn&#8217;t start until 2pm, which makes rushing just as much a problem. And no-one else in Calgary seems to be open on New Years Day. For afternoon tea, that is.<br />
And it wasn&#8217;t for a lack of looking. I even went to my internet compatriots for suggestions. I got the name of nearly every tea house in Calgary, but no others that served <em>afternoon tea</em>. It seems harder than it should be&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3400"></span><br />
Eventually, I came to terms with the fact that we wouldn&#8217;t be starting the new year with tea, so much as celebrating the new year with tea &#8230; just a little bit earlier.<br />
Early also meant leaving Calgary at 9am for our day&#8217;s trip into the mountains. It was cold &#8212; 17 degrees below zero &#8212; and snow and hoar frost covered everything between our home and the mountains. It was wonderfully dream-like, in every way a &#8220;magical&#8221; winter should be.<br />
By the time we arrived in Banff, the temperature had risen to a mere half a degree below zero (not an uncommon thing). Traffic was light, bordering on non-existent, and it was an easy trip up to the Upper Hot Springs. For the first time in probably over a decade, the spring was gushing hot water, rather than the usual trickle we&#8217;ve normally seen. Likely a result of the torrential rains we experienced last June, and a heavier snowpack, the springs are once again dependent on natural sources.<br />
We arrived in the pool barely 30 minutes after the pool opened for the day, which meant it was much emptier than I&#8217;ve experienced in more recent visits. It also meant the girls needed only admonishing for splashing, rather than having to pull them out of the pool entirely for annoying everyone.<br />
Bathed and dressed, we headed to the Banff Springs, where Alex and Choo Choo went to get our noon table, while Monkey and I parked the car. Our table was window-side, which I&#8217;d hoped for, allowing us a wonderful view down the Bow River valley.<br />
Now, the hard part with doing afternoon tea, or any relatively nice outing that involves manners, with young children is allowing them to act their age, with restraint. Monkey has some difficulty, but generally understands; Choo Choo, on the other hand, is a bit of a handful. Alex and I have to sit opposite each other so we can properly tag-team.<br />
That said, the girls did surprisingly well. They didn&#8217;t go so much for some of the fancier desserts (Monkey, inexplicably, refused to eat the multilayer chocolate cake slice on her plate), they ate without disaster, and drank almost with their pinkies out. But as one might expect, patience has its limits, and they couldn&#8217;t sit still forever.<br />
We zipped down to Bow Falls, which was frozen save for a two metre-wide gush of whitewater. The rest of the river was partially open, though heavily ensconced in thick ice, a point that was made to us while watching five people rather lacking on common sense, who got very close to the river&#8217;s edge without the ice breaking. We had our phones prepped for 911, just in case. The girls made &#8220;ice cream&#8221; from rocks, sand, and pine cones on a low rock wall.<br />
We tried to walk about town. We honestly thought we could spend a couple of leisurely hours wandering about, window shopping and otherwise sight-seeing. The girls, however, were done. Beyond done. That was clear after the first shop (a toy store, which may have aggravated the issue), and the parental patience ran thin, quickly. We were on the road by 4pm, the girls sound asleep before we were out of the Banff townsite limits.<br />
Next year &#8212; which is tomorrow, lest we forget &#8212; we have the same issue with Alex&#8217;s work schedule. We&#8217;ll likely do the same trip. And hopefully next year, we won&#8217;t wear ourselves out so quickly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/12/new-years-eve-tea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3400</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year&#039;s Tea, 2013</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/new-years-tea-2013/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-tea-2013</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/new-years-tea-2013/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 05:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years tea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Photo by Geoff S. Every year, so far able to be said to be &#8220;like clockwork&#8221;, we have Afternoon Tea on New Year&#8217;s Day. So far, every time has been at a Fairmont hotel (three times at the Banff Springs, once at the Hotel Vancouver), and I don&#8217;t suppose that tradition is likely to change &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/new-years-tea-2013/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Year&#039;s Tea, 2013"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2013/01/new-years-tea-2013/gingerbread-banff-springs/' title='Gingerbread Banff Springs'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Gingerbread-Banff-Springs-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignleft wp-image-3375" alt="Gingerbread Banff Springs" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/8334219425/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Every year, so far able to be said to be &#8220;like clockwork&#8221;, we have Afternoon Tea on New Year&#8217;s Day. So far, every time has been at a Fairmont hotel (three times at the Banff Springs, once at the Hotel Vancouver), and I don&#8217;t suppose that tradition is likely to change any time soon. Though we&#8217;re definitely needing to branch out to other Fairmonts, and my sights are definitely set on the Empress in Victoria.<br />
This year&#8217;s event was quieter, being just the four of us. Whereas last year we had more guests than the combined attendance of all previous NYTs, we intentionally kept it light and simple.<br />
In fact, this year&#8217;s annual Tea almost didn&#8217;t happen.<br />
<span id="more-3207"></span>Monkey is now 5, and she&#8217;s doing what five year-old kids usually do: test their parents, find the holes in their armour, and attack mercilessly until they collapse in a pile of weeping sorrow. (Honestly, it&#8217;s a wonder that the human race has survived, given children&#8217;s propensity to drive their parents nearly to genocide&#8230;)<br />
Add this developmental stage to the delirium brought on by the new toys at Christmas and &#8230; well, &#8220;fire and gasoline&#8221; doesn&#8217;t really bring out the volatile situation, but you can get an idea. Adjustments have come in various forms (and is still on-going); one of them was a proposed cancellation of the annual Tea. We were more than a little concerned about behaviour not just in a restaurant, but in a High Tea environment.<br />
I didn&#8217;t want to cancel it, even though I was the one who proposed it. I love New Year&#8217;s Tea. I love Afternoon (or High) Tea, and have had the luxury of having in several different countries, now. I was not looking forward to <em>not</em> going, and it actually hurt to suggest that we shouldn&#8217;t go.<br />
Nevertheless, Monkey availed herself to recant (some of) her behaviour, which gave us enough faith to believe that we could make this work. (Choo Choo, not yet 3, has some education before her as well, but being young and painfully cute, has a way of getting away with things more readily.) So, we hurriedly packed up, and pressed out for Banff late this morning.<br />
The first day of the New Year was bright and sunny, with the temp just below zero. Snow was still covering everything, and while the sun had melted the snow from the pine trees in most areas, there were still the stereotypically winter-white patches on the fringes once we got into the Rockies, in places the sun could not reach.<br />
Banff was busy, busier than I can recall for any previous trip, but busy in a way that lent a wonderful energy. I would have loved to have gotten out of the car and walked up and down Banff Ave. a bit, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that we were in a hurry. Despite leaving early enough, we somehow managed to arrive with only minutes to spare for our reservation.<br />
Sadly, we were not near a window &#8212; a first for us, and I think affected the kids a bit; they were a bit antsy to eat. The waitstaff was typically wonderful, and we were quickly set up with our teas, and confirmed the trays that were to come out.<br />
The egg salad croissants didn&#8217;t sit well with either of the kids, nor did the watercress (though that didn&#8217;t surprise me in the slightest). Peanut butter and jam were gone in seconds. Monkey loved the (absolutely delectable) creme brulée, but Choo Choo couldn&#8217;t really get into it. In fact, Choo Choo didn&#8217;t really eat much of the stacks, except for the scone (lathered in strawberry jam). Monkey ate, or at least tried, everything, and even had a second scone.<br />
But the antsiness continued, and it was clear before long that Choo Choo wasn&#8217;t going to sit still for much longer. Monkey, for her part, did exceptionally well.<br />
We headed out, and then up Sulphur Mountain to the Upper Hot Springs for a dip in the pool. It was, like the rest of Banff, quite busy, but not uncomfortably so. The water, however, was very comfortable, and lovely to rest in. We stayed no more than 15 minutes, mostly due to Choo Choo making a rather sudden dash across the shallow kiddie portion of the pool, aiming for a ladder into the deeper section. (One mother near me commented: &#8220;Wow, she&#8217;s fast!&#8221;) The swim was over.<br />
Choo Choo, the Great Fighter of Nap Time,  was asleep before we got back on the highway for home.<br />
I think this year will be the closest we ever come to not having New Year&#8217;s Tea, barring an emergency of some kind, as this will be the last year that I have wavering faith in my children&#8217;s behaviour. Next year, Monkey will be 6, and a perfect angel (right, Monkey??), and Choo Choo, though 3, will be learning much from her sister on how to behave well (right, Choo Choo??).<br />
I needed today. I honestly did. The drive out of Calgary alone was worth it, as was the time in the mountains, however short it was. I ain&#8217;t saying I&#8217;m ready for this year to begin yet &#8212; I&#8217;ll be writing &#8220;2012&#8221; for a while, I&#8217;m sure &#8212; but we at least got it off to a good start.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/new-years-tea-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3207</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
