<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>westjet &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/westjet/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 17:51:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A funny thing happened on my way home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 17:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Ed. Note: I&#8217;ve stripped out a bit of unnecessary bit at the beginning, and it was suggested that I sanitize it for sensitive eyes&#8230;] So last week, I was huddled with my mom back in Oakville, Ontario. No, I didn&#8217;t publicize this because &#8212; and utterly no offense meant to anyone &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A funny thing happened on my way home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[Ed. Note: I&#8217;ve stripped out a bit of unnecessary bit at the beginning, and it was suggested that I sanitize it for sensitive eyes&#8230;]</em><br />
So last week, I was huddled with my mom back in Oakville, Ontario. No, I didn&#8217;t publicize this because &#8212; and utterly <em>no</em> offense meant to anyone &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to see anyone but my Mom (and by extension, my sister and her family).<br />
The story here isn&#8217;t the journey to Oakville, or even the events in Oakville. This is about my trip home to Calgary.<br />
<span id="more-3182"></span>To maximize all the time I could get with Mom, I booked an early morning departure from Calgary, and the last possible flight home. The last possible flight departed from Toronto (as normally scheduled) at 21:45, via WestJet (I don&#8217;t fly Air Craptastic anymore, unless I have <em>literally</em> no other option). This meant I could do visiting, and have a (mostly) relaxing flight back.<br />
Murphy, it seems, stowed away in my luggage.<br />
First off, there was a heavy snowfall warning in Calgary yesterday. This normally leads to massive delays (and cancellations) at the airport &#8212; hell, even <a href="http://www.calgarysun.com/2012/06/14/storms-stall-flights-at-calgary-airport">a good thunderstorm can screw things up for hours</a>. So I started watching the (online) arrivals board constantly, looking for problems.<br />
(Side note, airports <em>and</em> airlines: Honestly, get your mobile support for your websites figured out. I want to <strong>RELOAD</strong> a page frequently, not resubmit a <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> form. Also: checking a flight status should always be prominent on your mobile home page. ALWAYS. And yes, <a href="http://calgaryairport.com">calgaryairport.com</a>, you need a mobile version. Badly.)<br />
The day, however, seemed to go well in that respect, and the worst that happened was a posted 30 minute delay on my flight, because the equipment in use was inbound from Cancun (and presumably incurred a delay there). Half an hour is annoying, not brutal.<br />
Cathy was very kind to drop me off at the airport (in lieu of a taxi); I had her drop me off early so I could get some more work done while waiting for the plane (I also knew she wanted to get home and relax herself, and the earlier she was home, the better). I had hoped to hang out in a bar, notably the Mill St. Brewery, which has a brewpub at Toronto Pearson.<br />
Problem: Mill St.&#8217;s pub is in Terminal 1. WestJet flies from Terminal 3. I wasn&#8217;t keen on hopping terminals, just in case the flight got bumped to a different plane, and the times changed. That left Fionn McCool&#8217;s, an &#8220;Irish&#8221; pub just beyond security. I use the term &#8220;Irish&#8221; only in the sense that the term is what&#8217;s used to set expectations &#8230; every single one of which McCool&#8217;s missed. As I commented last night, <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271422493133262848">the place was grossly lacking in authenticity</a>.<br />
The beer seemed half-strength in every possible meaning, and they somehow produced <a href="https://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271427759346180096">sweet potato fries without any discernible flavour</a> whatsoever. Now, given, I was officially sick (exactly where I&#8217;d obtained said illness is a matter for pointless debate), so yes, I could chalk that up to dulled sense, I suppose. But I can&#8217;t, because I knew damn well I could taste the &#8220;spicy mayo&#8221;, which was &#8230; well, I dunno what was in it, and I&#8217;m not sure I want to. Saving grace, at least <a href="https://twitter.com/sowrey/status/271428334095826944">the staff there was so unorganized</a> that I didn&#8217;t have to pay for the fries.<br />
The plane for our flight didn&#8217;t arrive until nearly 20 minutes after time we were supposed to <em>depart</em>. It was another 40-45 minutes (honestly, I stopped keeping track) until we boarded (I half-expected WestJet to just cancel the flight and reschedule for the morning).<br />
My highlight of the night? WestJet&#8217;s satellite TV. Discovery Channel. Three hours of <em>MythBusters</em>. I&#8217;m somewhat ashamed to say I passed out for about 30 minutes of one episode. (I&#8217;d been up since 6am; I was exhausted.)<br />
We landed in Calgary just after 01:00 MT, taxied to the terminal, and headed down to get our bags. The moment I hit the baggage claim &#8212; the carousel hadn&#8217;t even started yet &#8212; I was on the phone with the Alberta Motor Association (our provincial branch of the CAA), to arrange for someone to come and unlock the car so I could go home.<br />
Oh, right, I didn&#8217;t get to this part yet. Lemme rewind a couple days.<br />
On Monday, it was realized that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Allen and Jean (who&#8217;d come out to help Alex with the kids while I was gone) needed a way to get to the airport.</li>
<li>The process in which I&#8217;d driven to the airport, and deposited the keys with left luggage so Allen could pick up the car when he arrived in Calgary, had worked splendidly.</li>
<li>It would cost about $120 for two taxi rides (Allen and Jean to the airport; myself home).</li>
<li>Wouldn&#8217;t it make sense to do another car exchange? (Even with a $10/day parking fee.)</li>
</ol>
<p>Well, there were some logistical issues. Notably: left luggage closes at 23:00, and I wasn&#8217;t (originally) due until midnight, thus making key exchange difficult to the point of impossible. (Well, without running fear of theft, anyway.)<br />
The major problem was how to get into the car. I needed a key. After some back-and-forth, it was decided to mail the key to me in Oakville. Well, not so much &#8220;mail&#8221; as &#8220;least expensive couriered option possible&#8221;, since an overnight package for a mere <em>car key</em> would have been &#8212; <em>wait for it</em> &#8212; nearly $80. Which is a bit much. End result: two-day package with Canada Post, which &#8212; in theory &#8212; had enough time to arrive.<br />
Now, I have to say &#8220;in theory&#8221; because that requires Canada Post to actually <em>deliver</em> the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> thing. Which, <em>three days</em> later, they still haven&#8217;t. The tracking information says it&#8217;s only been accepted in Calgary. So far as we know, it <em>still hasn&#8217;t left the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> city of origin.</em><br />
EPIC. FAIL.<br />
Realizing this at 13:00 MT on Wednesday, we started Plan B. Which, oddly enough, was not to just take a taxi (which was my original preference, as I figured I&#8217;d be dog tired by the time I got in, and struggling with a car wasn&#8217;t on my list of things I wanted to do). Instead, I figured this was an excellent time to do something I&#8217;d been seriously considering for a while (but hadn&#8217;t done), and sign up for AMA again. We&#8217;d let our old membership expire when we moved to Costa Rica, and driving around with two kids was starting to worry me about having a car problem. (I&#8217;d had one before &#8212; thankfully solo &#8212; which was my first regret for not having the membership.)<br />
$90 later, I had a membership number, and a backup in case the key didn&#8217;t show. Which, as of 19:00 ET last night, it still hadn&#8217;t. (As of 09:30 MT today, <em>it still hasn&#8217;t</em>.)<br />
I called AMA as soon as I could because I figured it&#8217;d be a long wait, especially with all the snow. The agent confirmed that: roughly an hour and a half, but they&#8217;d seen calls answered in as little as 55 minutes. Either way, I had a while to wait.<br />
I got my bag, found a bench, and tried to occupy myself doing things that didn&#8217;t involve using my iPhone, because I needed the battery to hold its charge long enough to get the call and meet with the AMA truck.<br />
(Side note #2: My iPhone&#8217;s battery went <em>way</em> longer in Oakville than it does in Calgary. What the <strong>[CENSORED]</strong> is up with that, Rogers??)<br />
The call came 26 minutes later. I was actually shocked. It was an automated call saying the truck would arrive in 10 minutes. So I grabbed the bags, bundled up for the -14 degree weather, and went to go find the car. Which, as my father-in-law had stated, was pretty much where I&#8217;d left it a week earlier. (How&#8217;s that for good parking karma?)<br />
The truck arrived about 10 minutes later, as promised. The first words out of the driver (whose name, regrettably, I don&#8217;t think I ever got) was: &#8220;Is that a 2003?&#8221;<br />
We have a 2006 Jetta TDI. It&#8217;s a decent car. (Read: Not a &#8220;great&#8221; car. It works. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d recommend it as a purchase. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d buy another one.) But apparently, Jettas are some of the hardest cars to get into, notably because of the security systems and the electronic locks, and 2003&#8217;s are particularly dicey. The driver, conferring with his AMA experts (who seem to know damn near everything), determined that the 2006 shouldn&#8217;t be too bad, and we should be able to open it. So, yay, we&#8217;re off to the races.<br />
Or so we thought&#8230;<br />
Getting the jimmy in the door wasn&#8217;t too hard. After that &#8230; well, the driver was stumped as to why the locks weren&#8217;t disengaging. If you&#8217;ve never seen a door jimmy, these are pretty interesting things. It&#8217;s basically a sturdy steel wire shaped with a big U, with a bent end and a metal tab that looks not unlike a guitar pick. The U part lets the tab duck under the window (which is assumedly raised, &#8216;cuz why else would you need someone to open the damn door), and then with some deft twisting, you press the tab into the door lock button, and presto! the door opens.<br />
Except that it didn&#8217;t.<br />
And wouldn&#8217;t.<br />
No matter what the guy did, the door just sat there, laughing at him. And worse, he <em>had</em> to get the door open, because he needed his tool back, and you <em>can&#8217;t remove the tool if you can&#8217;t open the door</em>.<br />
Did I mention that it was well after 02:00, -14 with a northerly wind, with lots of blowing snow? And this guy had frostbitten hands? (And my gloves were not meant for that cold.)<br />
We huddled back in the truck, letting the blasting heat warm us up a bit. The guy hopped on the radio to discuss other options.</p>
<ol>
<li>Break the window. Thanks, but no thanks. I did not want to pay untold (large) sums of money for a new window. I&#8217;d rather wait for the key to be returned, and pay the extra days to get it out of the lot.</li>
<li>Get a locksmith to break in. See above, but even moreso on the &#8220;no&#8221; side, merely for expense alone.</li>
<li>Tow the car to a dealership and let them get into the car. Still involves a lock, see above notes for cost.</li>
<li>Try the longer tool again?</li>
</ol>
<p>In addition to the jimmy was a long (also very sturdy) metal rod that could be squeaked through the door (with an inflatable &#8220;jack&#8221; to move the door over a little), in hopes it could do a better job. The first one (he had two) hadn&#8217;t really done that great of a job, and had little effect. But after a pep talk, and a bit of hunting to find the &#8220;bigger&#8221; rod, we decided for one last shot before calling it a night. Early morning. Way too tired to really know which is better&#8230;<br />
Anyway&#8230;<br />
Bigger rod inserted (no euphemisms, please), and more fishing, pressing, hoping, and attempting to shine the light in the right place.<br />
POP!<br />
Two grown men, shouting like high school football players. That&#8217;s what you would have seen at 02:50 in the Economy Lot of the Calgary Airport Authority, just next to the #8 pole. Holy <em>crap</em>, were we ecstatic!<br />
Swearing profusely, I managed to dig the key out of the trunk (I had to pull down one of the seats; the narrowest one, of course) and use the flashlight app on my phone (so glad I have one, and why isn&#8217;t this a built-in feature?) to retrieve the key that was, of course, as far away as it could possibly be from me. The car, realizing that the game was finally up and there was no more point in resisting, started without complaint.<br />
The tool was removed, hands shook, bags loaded, car scraped (mostly) clean of the snow and ice, and home headed towards.<br />
Hmm.<br />
I titled this &#8220;A funny thing&#8230;&#8221;, didn&#8217;t I?<br />
Oh well&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/11/a-funny-thing-happened-on-my-way-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our first family flight</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-first-family-flight/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=our-first-family-flight</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-first-family-flight/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 21:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I remember the excitement as a kid on those early mornings where we got up to rush to the airport to fly somewhere. It was a hurried affair that I simultaneously loved and loathed. While most of me vowed to never deal with such mornings as I grew older, I think some small part of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-first-family-flight/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Our first family flight"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember the excitement as a kid on those early mornings where we got up to rush to the airport to fly somewhere. It was a hurried affair that I simultaneously loved and loathed. While most of me vowed to never deal with such mornings as I grew older, I think some small part of me always expected that one day, I would be guiding my children on similar mornings.<br />
Today, that small part got its moment in the limelight. Alex and I had not gotten to bed until well after 1am, having to finish packing, take down our Christmas tree (didn&#8217;t want a trying piece of highly-flammable timber being left inside), and making sure all was well with the house. (Oh, and dealing with a sick Monkey. Choo Choo got more sleep than the rest of us, combined.)<br />
And yet, we were off and running in under an hour. Not bad, eh?<br />
<span id="more-2814"></span>We cabbed it. Although it&#8217;s usually cheaper to drive and leave the car in one of the lots, we found that our trusty Jetta has a severe aversion to the cold and doesn&#8217;t like to start when it&#8217;s below -15 C. The last thing we needed to deal with was a frozen car upon our return.<br />
WestJet still remains one of the easiest airlines to fly, in my opinion. It was a simple check-in, few questions, no hassles, and a comfortable flight. Our last flight as a family, prior to Choo Choo&#8217;s birth, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/12/the-trip-home/">was arriving in Canada just over a year ago</a>. It had been an arduous, fairly stressful event and it still rang loudly in my mind. Thankfully, this jaunt &#8212; a mere hour &#8212; was over almost as soon as it started.<br />
It was good to be back in British Columbia again, some three years after my last visit. It was cold and wet, typical for the Lower Mainland in winter, but fresh and green &#8212; almost a much cooler version of Costa Rica, actually. Grandpa and Granny met us at the gate &#8212; Monkey raced to hug them &#8212; and we whisked off to the Aicken Homestead almost immediately. Well, with one sidetrip, where Granny had to pick up the World&#8217;s Largest Gift Basketâ„¢, which summarily buried me.<br />
Some things had changed, but the house was warm and welcoming, and the massive trees that grow on the property still the whispering stalwarts. It&#8217;s comfortable, here, and while it&#8217;s no beach on Hawaii, it&#8217;s hard not to relax. Which should make for an interesting juxtaposition, since I have to try and work a bit. We&#8217;ll see how it goes.<br />
Oh, speaking of which, there&#8217;s my email, now&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/12/our-first-family-flight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2814</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On my way home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=on-my-way-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 07:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/10/on-my-way-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me. It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On my way home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was definitely more expedient than most of the ones I&#8217;ve seen. That said, it was still a lovely ceremony.<br />
<span id="more-910"></span>I followed Tamara most of the day, her unofficial tied-to-the-hip photographer. Hair, make-up, nails, ceremony preparation, and post-professional pictures, before all heading off to dinner. I was fortunate enough to be treated almost like the wedding party without actually being one of them. It was nice to be considered in such a way, especially when it wasn&#8217;t really place.<br />
Yes, Tamara cried. So did I. (I cry at every wedding.) It&#8217;s hard not to when things turn out that well. The wedding chapel at the Mandalay Bay might be a bit &#8220;assembly line&#8221;-ish, but it&#8217;s really a nice way to have weddings. It&#8217;s definitely not your stereotypical Vegas chapel. Not an Elvis to be seen.<br />
Following the ceremony and the post-professional pictures, we all went to Chinois at the Forum Shops. It&#8217;s a Wolfgang Puck restaurant. Very tasty. Our &#8220;private room&#8221; was a great balcony overlooking the mall itself. It wasn&#8217;t loud at all, and much rejoicing was had.<br />
But now I stand in Maccaran International, awaiting my flight home at 2:10. Yes, that&#8217;s 02:10, as in AM, after midnight. I land in Calgary just before 6, then head right into work. Yes, I&#8217;m insane. But you already knew that.<br />
So to the newly-minted couple, I offer only my best hopes and wishes for life, love, and happiness. The minister was right &#8212; there is no gambling in love. There are no &#8220;ifs&#8221; or &#8220;in case of fires&#8221;. There is compromise and understanding, but love has a way of making that almost easy. May your remaining days in Las Vegas be full of fun and rest (you guys need it), and we all look forward to seeing you in Calgary.<br />
Congratulations my friends. And thank you for letting me be a part of your day in the sun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We have a travel-safe baby</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=we-have-a-travel-safe-baby</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 00:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/24/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve had the luxury of travelling many places of the last few years. Of those times, I&#8217;ve been on more than a few planes that were exhibit to babies that did not travel well. And by not travelling well, I mean they cried. A lot. Loudly. Ear-piercingly. My biggest fear is that we would have &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "We have a travel-safe baby"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had the luxury of travelling many places of the last few years. Of those times, I&#8217;ve been on more than a few planes that were exhibit to babies that did not travel well. And by not travelling well, I mean they cried.<br />
A lot. Loudly. Ear-piercingly.<br />
My biggest fear is that we would have one of those children. Loud. Ear-piercingly. So instead of casting disapproving glances at others, we would be the recipients of such withering glances as to kill off entire forests.<br />
<span id="more-864"></span>I held out hope that if there was one gene I could pass onto my offspring, it would be the ability to travel without much concern.<br />
So this weekend, we flew out to Maple Ridge to visit with family. (Alex&#8217;s family, that is. Oakville will have to come later.) Alex and the wee one are here for about a week and a half. I&#8217;m here only until tomorrow. But the first trip out was a joint affair. It had to be &#8212; just in case.<br />
Packing was a little rushed at the end, mostly because everything had to be tied around a final feeding at home. (Everything is ultimately tied to either feeding or sleeping, and schedules be damned.) Although late leaving the house, we managed to get to the airport pretty zippily, and I dropped off Alex and our assorted stuff at the terminal, before whipping over to the Park &#8216;n Fly to drop off the car. (Yes, we should take a taxi, but for what they charge, it&#8217;s just easier to leave the car.)<br />
I was back in less than 10 minutes, which caught Alex off-guard, as she didn&#8217;t expect me that quickly. Turns out I wasn&#8217;t needed for check-in. But I did prove somewhat useful in bagging up the Bugaboo to go into oversize baggage. Then we joined the longest security line I&#8217;ve ever seen for Gate D.<br />
Twenty-eight minutes to spare, we opted for Subway to tide us over until we got to the Lower Mainland. The wee one was mostly asleep in the Bjorn, much to our collective relief. So far, no issues. (I even managed to take the kid through the metal detector in the Bjorn, and it didn&#8217;t set off the alarm!)<br />
A last change, and we boarded our flight. WestJet seemed to put everyone with babies in the same area. For better or for worse, it seemed. No squawk, no fuss. So far. As we began taxiing, Alex started to breastfeed. Although the recommended procedure is to hold your child until after takeoff, there was enough squirming to suggest hunger. The squirt was out like a slow base runner before we even got to takeoff, and remained asleep for a good 30 minutes.<br />
In fact, the only sound she made was one whine as we started descent &#8212; not even anything major. She was genuinely hungry (having had very little on the way up). We hit ground, slowed, hit the terminal, and waited for everyone to leave. Not a sound, except a bit of cooing.<br />
Allen was waiting for us at the security doors, and would not let us pass until he&#8217;d kissed his grandchild. Then it was picking up the bags and off for Maple Ridge.<br />
While this is but a single case, and a very ideal one at that (the Calgary-Abbotsford run is barely over an hour), I&#8217;m holding out a lot of hope that our child will be a good traveler. Given that some of our family is a four hour flight away, and we want to travel to other places (we&#8217;re already in early stages for a Europspecial handlinge trip in April), a good travelling baby will help us a lot.<br />
Now we just need her to learn a few languages&#8230; starting with English.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">864</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2004 23:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/10/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day. And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind. Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day.<br />
And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind.<br />
<span id="more-348"></span>Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years ago, it hurt to have him leave. When Therese and Stuart moved to Montreal, it was hard to handle. But as I stood in the doorway of the train today, I looked back at my friend &#8212; my brother &#8212; and wondered when I will see him again.<br />
There is never enough time. Too many things happening, and too much distance separating us. I miss living with Chris. I miss the knowing glances and mouthed expressions we could give each other that conveyed meaning on a level only we knew.<br />
But such is life. Life is change, life is motion. It has to continue, lest life stop.<br />
Chris didn&#8217;t come to the airport with us, but Kaz was kind enough to guide us. When we arrived, we&#8217;d found that our flight time had changed. We had originally been booked for an 18:35 departure, but had been rescheduled for a 15:30 departure &#8230; or so I&#8217;d thought. The boards read a 17:15 departure, so I began to wonder if Air Canada had changed the times on us again, and not informed us. In retrospect, I think we&#8217;re okay, but I&#8217;m not 100% on that yet.<br />
Normally, a chance in flight times wouldn&#8217;t worry me. But I have to catch a flight in Calgary to take me to Kelowna, and I can&#8217;t afford to miss that flight. At the time, I started to worry. I had based my flight from Calgary on the changed (and perceived) time of 15:30. If we were now leaving Japan later, I might not make my Kelowna flight.<br />
Either way, we were at the airport far too early to determine what was going on, so it was just a matter of waiting. Putting the bags into storage (we had almost two hours to wait until we could check in), we went in search of lunch.<br />
One of the restaurants offered beef don, or a relative facsimile thereof. Jen was dying for beef, so this is where we went. Kaz and I had more traditional Japanese meals. It was a way of using up the remaining 2,000 yen I still had. (As it turns out, not such a wise move, since we had to pay to get the bags back, which was 1,500 yen.)<br />
We did a bit of shopping. Well, looking around, anyway. The only thing we really needed to buy still was a bottle of sake for Uncle Mike. But Terminal 2 really didn&#8217;t offer anything particularly interesting. And as we had time to kill, anyway, we went over to Terminal 1.<br />
I finally figured out why I&#8217;d been so disoriented when we arrived two weeks ago. Last year, I came in at Terminal 1 (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]), which I think is a lot nicer than Terminal 2. It was quite clear when we got close enough to see inside.<br />
We returned to Terminal 2 to check in. This is when we got another nasty bit of news: Jen and I were not sharing the same flight coming from Vancouver to Calgary. We had set it up that way so we didn&#8217;t have to worry about the flight. In fact, there supposedly weren&#8217;t any available seats at all on the flights and we didn&#8217;t really have reservations. I urged them to correct that sitation, but the best we could get was two flights over three hours apart. This is something I&#8217;ll have to sort out in Vancouver.<br />
Once checked in, we had to start heading to the flight. Kaz walked us to the security gate, where we had to say goodbye to her. Kaz and Jen had grown close (mostly as a result of yesterday&#8217;s rather interesting shopping spree). Kaz is my best friend&#8217;s wife. I don&#8217;t know her nearly as well as perhaps I should, but if she&#8217;s able to capture his heart, I know I will miss her as much as I miss him.<br />
The flight boarded only a few minutes later than scheduled, but far in advance of us departing the gate. The flight isn&#8217;t completely full, so is rather comfortable. Hopefully, the flight will be a short one, so we don&#8217;t have to sit down for too long.<br />
Jen and I chuckled a bit at the first movie. Not just because it is a funny movie, but because it was very appropriate for all the Japanese/English mishaps we&#8217;ve had throughout our trip.<br />
&#8220;Lost in Translation.&#8221;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
The plane arrived more or less on time. We hustled from the plane, bypassing many of the passengers (they were taking the escalators, we took the adjoining stairs) and getting into the immigration line. We had to go through Canadian Immigration in Vancouver before heading to Calgary.<br />
This was the only time &#8212; *only* time &#8212; throughout the entire trip that someone asked my relation to Jen in an official capacity. I had legal documents on me that stated that I was Jen&#8217;s legal guardian, but never had to show them to anyone. Even the clerk at Immigration didn&#8217;t ask to see them, but said that I might have to show them.<br />
I never had to.<br />
We had to collect our bags and go through Customs (which amounted to them taking our form of Declaration, not even saying &#8220;thank you&#8221;) and check them in again for our connecting flight.<br />
It was the connecting flight that was a bit of an issue. As you might recall, we found out at Narita airport that Jen and I were not on the same flight. This had me mildy irked, because we were supposed to be on the same flight. It&#8217;s not that I didn&#8217;t trust Jen to get back to Calgary on her own, but I was supposed to be her legal guardian, and wanted to make sure she got back to her parents.<br />
Fortunately, the flight I was on was not completely full, and the Air Canada clerk was reasonably certain that Jen would be able to get on the flight. She set Jen up as stand-by, and even checked her bag to Calgary (so even if Jen didn&#8217;t make it, her bag would). With that, we went off to our gate.<br />
I got pulled over at security again. I always seem to get pulled over in North America. It&#8217;s all my freaking electronics. Japan didn&#8217;t care. Maybe they&#8217;ve got better technology. I mean, they&#8217;ve got vending machines that will take bills upside down, backwards, and probably crumpled beyond recognition. They&#8217;ve gotta have better scanning machines than we do.<br />
At the gate, after giving the clerk a few minutes, we asked if Jen could get on the flight, and if it was possible if we could sit together. The clerk, originally seeming a little harsh, turned out to be quite congenial, and settled our last hurdle quite easily.<br />
At that point, I called Aunt Brenda. (I had my cell phone with me for in-Canada communications upon my return.) I let her know we were on the 12:00 (PST) flight from Vancouver, getting into Calgary around 14:30. She was quite happy to hear we&#8217;d be home soon, and said she&#8217;d meet us there.<br />
The flight was quite hot. Unlike our A340 plane, our little A320 was quite warm, even with the air vents cranked all the way open. But it didn&#8217;t really matter. Soon, we&#8217;d be at home. Thankfully, the flight went quickly (that happens when you sleep for half of it &#8230; or all of it, in Jen&#8217;s case), and soon we were exiting Gate A to the awaiting arms of Uncle Mike, Aunt Brenda, and Nana.<br />
Now, you&#8217;d think at this point that I&#8217;d be somewhat relieved to unload the responsibility for handling Jen back to her parents, right? Not really. It was at that point that I realized that Jen hadn&#8217;t really been that hard to handle. Aside from having to curb her manga-buying sprees, and encouraging her to see more things (which was more trouble than I would have thought), she was very easy to get along with. But then, we already had a good relationship.<br />
Jen immediately became a chatterbox, telling Brenda and Nana about the trip &#8212; almost entirely randomly-selected portions &#8212; while Mike and I exchanged a few thoughts about my perspective. All this while waiting for the bags to come out. Then it was back to their place to unload.<br />
Now, dear reader, this is where this tale should end. But it doesn&#8217;t. While Jen&#8217;s journey was over, mine still had a bit left to it. I had another flight to catch. I&#8217;m now in Kelowna. Why would I be coming to Kelowna? Two words:<br />
David Bowie.<br />
Remember when I said that if David Bowie was returning to Canada anytime soon that I&#8217;d go to see him? (See [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]].) I wasn&#8217;t kidding. A couple of months ago, during my only sick day of the year (so far, anyway), Tamara had burst into my room in a near state of ecstacy because David Bowie was playing in Kelowna. In an auditorium that holds only 5,000 people.<br />
Naturally, we were going.<br />
This was after I&#8217;d booked my flights to Japan and back, and had Jen booked in. This meant I had to catch another flight from Calgary to Kelowna. With WestJet, not a particularly huge deal. (The flight cost about as much as the ticket to David Bowie, at least before adding on all those ridiculous taxes.)<br />
I passed out in my chair on the plane (an aisle seat) mere moments after doing up my seat belt. I vaguely remember the word &#8220;juice&#8221;, and awoke only when the plane slapped the tarmac at Kelowna. I dozed until the plane finally stopped. I was soon met by my roommate Tamara, her boyfriend Dan, and her friend Andrea. (They&#8217;d driven out earlier in the day.)<br />
Our first stop was the White Spot, a BC-favourite for restaurants. Not one of mine (don&#8217;t really care for the place), but it was food and it was cheap. That was enough for me. Then it was to the hotel (the Royal Anne Hotel, situated in beautiful downtown Kelowna, a mere block from the lake, and four blocks from Prospera Place, the site for tomorrow&#8217;s David Bowie concert) to dump the bags.<br />
We went bar-hopping, in search of something fairly decent. The sad part is that most of Kelowna&#8217;s downtown has either really seedy biker bars (read: strip clubs, and we all know how much I like those places) or yuppie pubs. We weren&#8217;t thrilled by any of them. We finally gave up around 21:00 and went back to the hotel.<br />
I shaved off two weeks&#8217; worth of beard (much to my delight &#8212; the damn thing was driving me crazy) while Tamara and Andrea watched &#8220;Princess Bride&#8221; on the TV. Dan had already passed out. The four of us were asleep before the movie was over (and we only came in halfway-through).<br />
God knows I needed the rest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying home to Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=flying-home-to-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2004 22:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/27/flying-home-to-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I woke earlier than usual &#8212; about 8:45 or so. Craig was still up, but not nearly as tired as when he&#8217;d scared the bejezesus out of me. Turning down his offer of a beer (for Craig, this was still the end of the day), I got a glass of orange juice. Craig and I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Flying home to Calgary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke earlier than usual &#8212; about 8:45 or so. Craig was still up, but not nearly as tired as when he&#8217;d scared the bejezesus out of me.<br />
Turning down his offer of a beer (for Craig, this was still the end of the day), I got a glass of orange juice. Craig and I took the opportunity to have a chat about his career. I guess I forced the issue. I&#8217;m worried about him. I don&#8217;t know Craig as well as perhaps I could &#8212; he&#8217;d family, but aside from a few visits, I don&#8217;t know him even remotely as well as I should for a brother-in-law. For what I do know, though, Craig works too hard. I know the desire, though. I know what drives him, what pushes him forward. I had that drive once. It&#8217;s died off in recent months, mostly due to recognition of my own faults.<br />
<span id="more-330"></span>Nothing really came of the conversation, not that I thought anything would. I can only hope, though, that perhaps he&#8217;ll settle into a more regular schedule that will allow him to have some quality of life. At least more than he has now.<br />
Mom arrived about 30 minutes after I called her to take me back to her place. I had to finish fixing her computer. Norton Security had to be removed because it was blocking functionality. I installed just Norton Anti-Virus instead, which seemed to cooperate significantly better than the full suite. It installed well, and everything seemed to work. With that in place, I started up the defragmentation program to help speed mom&#8217;s computer up.<br />
By that time, Cathy had arrived at mom&#8217;s, off early from work, and the three of us went for lunch at Mexicali Rosa&#8217;s, one of a chain of Mexican-themed restaurants. Apparently, there were a couple of them in Ottawa, back in the day I used to live and work there. Cathy told me of them, but I honestly couldn&#8217;t remember any of them. Either way, I was in the mood for Mexican.<br />
The food was good, but the sangria was lacking. In fact, I was a tad disappointed, especially since I&#8217;d raved about how good sangria was to Cathy. I&#8217;ll have to make an effort to find really good sangria out here, so that when Cathy and Craig come out here for our cousin Pam&#8217;s wedding in September, I&#8217;ll be able to show them something really tasty.<br />
Following our lunch, we did a driving tour out to Port Credit. A few things had changed. A new strip mall complex at the corner of Southdown and Royal Windsor caught me by surprise. Even more surprising was the redevelopment of the St. Lawrence Starch grounds was extremely impressive, and certainly out of the range of most ordinary people. My mother couldn&#8217;t hope to afford one of them, although they are nice.<br />
The defrag was still running when we got back. I can only assume because it hadn&#8217;t been run in a very long time. But I wouldn&#8217;t be able to see it finish, as I had to get to the airport. I had a flight back to Calgary to catch. I bade mom goodbye, and headed to Cathy&#8217;s house to collect my things.<br />
I remembered why I don&#8217;t like Toronto traffic. On the way to the airport, I bore witness to the nastiest traffic jams on the westbound lanes of both the 403 and the 401, neither of which we were in. (Though Cathy would have to be heading in that direction after dropping me off.) I am so glad I walk to work, and drive as rarely as possible.<br />
Things had changed at the airport. Terminal 1 is no more. In the redevelopment of the GTAA, and the construction of the new terminal, the old was swept away. It was there when I was in Oakville last October (see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion]]), but since then was torn down. Soon, Terminal 2 will follow suit, and only the new terminals will remain.<br />
As I sat waiting for my flight to board, an announcement came over the PA. Apparently, there was a weather advisory for Calgary. There was a chance that we might not arrive in Calgary &#8212; we could get diverted to Kelowna.<br />
I didn&#8217;t see this as a particularly bad thing. At the very least, I&#8217;d get a good story out of it. Besides, I had relatives there that I could call upon if I were really stuck in a bind. But I also figured that because Calgary&#8217;s weather literally changes in a matter of minutes, the odds of me not making it to Calgary were fairly slim.<br />
End result: the flight was about half-full. I had a row to myself. We got snack bags two at a time. (We were flying WestJet, which means no meals. Not that I mind &#8212; a nice ham and swiss from Tim Horton&#8217;s fills the void quite well.) Aside from the three French guys in front of me (who seemed barely out of their teens, despite being well into their 30s), I had a very pleasant flight.<br />
Except for landing in Calgary. As we approached for landing, I had glanced out the window to see where we were. I saw what I thought was the sun setting far off in the distance (though it seemed far too late for that), or perhaps the moon in an odd position. In reality, it was the lights of Calgary shining through the fog that seemed to hug the ground.<br />
I suppose that as we decended through the clouds, I should have been a little frightened. Flying by instrumentation is fine, but visions of Die Hard 2 kept coming to mind. The last thing I really needed was to slam into the ground at far too fast a rate of decent. I didn&#8217;t think about it too much, though. Aside from a harder-than-usual landing, the approach wasn&#8217;t really that bad &#8212; even if the clarity at ground level couldn&#8217;t have been more than the height of the air traffic control tower.<br />
As I arrived home, I realized that I felt relaxed. There&#8217;s a certain clarity that comes with a vacation, even one as busy as the one I&#8217;d just had. I actually felt good about my time off. Perhaps I&#8217;ve been a little too critical of work lately. Maybe things aren&#8217;t as bad as I think they are. I know I&#8217;ve overcomplicated my life as of late, so maybe it&#8217;s something I need to work on.<br />
Who says New Years resolutions have to happen at New Years?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying to Montreal to visit friends</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2004 22:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/20/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I honestly couldn&#8217;t wait for 5:00 to come this morning. Today is the start of my first break longer than a long weekend in almost a year. I&#8217;ve been working away on my job, barely taking time off, slaving through one of the hardest Christmases I can remember, and wondering whether anyone&#8217;s really noticed. I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Flying to Montreal to visit friends"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I honestly couldn&#8217;t wait for 5:00 to come this morning.<br />
Today is the start of my first break longer than a long weekend in almost a year. I&#8217;ve been working away on my job, barely taking time off, slaving through one of the hardest Christmases I can remember, and wondering whether anyone&#8217;s really noticed.<br />
I won&#8217;t even mention my lengthy list of non-work activities.<br />
<span id="more-323"></span>I&#8217;ll be quite happy to leave my job, my house, even my life behind in Calgary for a week and forget for a while that I&#8217;m Geoff Sowrey and have any responsibilities whatsoever. I&#8217;m *so* looking forward to this.<br />
I arrived at the airport just after 6:00 and immediately got into the WestJet check-in line. Despite all of Air Canada&#8217;s attempts to shut down the smaller airlines, WestJet continues to pack &#8217;em in. Some people were off to Vancouver, some off to Edmonton, and some off to Toronto. Others to parts unknown. Me? I was off to Montreal.<br />
Why Montreal? Well, as you might recall (see [[Friends move away to Montreal]]), my friends Therese and Stuart moved there a few months back. Since then, they&#8217;ve established themselves, bought a home, and prepared for the arrival of their first child (currently monikered &#8220;Kicker&#8221;) who appears at the end of March.<br />
The flight was easy. I&#8217;ve flown far too much for my own good. I&#8217;ve flown around North America, across the Atlantic, and across the Pacific. After a flight to Japan, flying a few hours to Hamilton and a bare hour to Montreal after that is practically a milk run.<br />
I spent most of the flight (both legs) reading. Normally, it&#8217;s magazines, specifically my favourite &#8212; Wired. This time was different. This time, I was reading <em>Clan of the Cave Bear</em>, loaned to me from Kristen. It&#8217;s a fascinating novel, describing the life of a cro-magnon woman who comes to live with neanderthals, and the differences they face with the integration of the woman into their clan. I&#8217;m not sure how accurate it is from an anthropological perspective, but it is still quite an interesting read.<br />
But then, I&#8217;ve always been a fan of science.<br />
I arrived at Pierre Trudeau International Airport (previously known as Dorval Airport) about 10 minutes ahead of schedule, despite running late coming into Hamilton. As soon as I was out in the lobby, past security, I pulled out my cell phone to let Stuart know that I was in town, and was in the process of finding my way downtown. Dorval is on the isle of Montreal, but is quite some distance from the downtown core.<br />
Finding the bus stop for the #204, and finding the change I needed for bus fare ($2.50), I awaited the arrival of the bus to take me to Gare Dorval. There, I would either switch to another bus (the #221) or to an AMT train, either of which would take me into downtown Montreal and the Metro system.<br />
Dorval Station is a bare kilometre from the airport. You can see it clear as day, and it looks like you can walk from one to the other (it&#8217;s a little difficult because there are no sidewalks that I can see, and it&#8217;s mostly highway in that area). It took me a few minutes to figure out what my best options were, but luckily for me, it turned out that the train was the fastest way to get downtown. And the system allowed me to upgrade my bus ticket with a mere $0.75 addition ticket.<br />
If only Calgary were that intelligent.<br />
Montreal is an interesting place for languages. It skates the thin line of the two official national languages, and incorporates countless others. It is without a doubt the most multicultural city in Canada, at least in my opinion.<br />
What brought this into clear view was when I was trying to buy my new ticket. It was because a man at the top of the stairs, awaiting the train, suddenly asked:<br />
&#8220;Excuse moi &#8212; quelle heure et il?&#8221;<br />
For those of you who don&#8217;t know French (or even the Quebecois dialect), this is how you ask what time it is. This beckons back to my days of taking French in school. And despite many years of not taking French, I was able to immediately reply:<br />
&#8220;Deux heures et huit minutes.&#8221;<br />
I was beside myself. How the heck was I able to do that? How the heck was I able to even remember how to interpret what he&#8217;d said? Either way, I wasn&#8217;t about to object, because it meant that for a few precious moments, it meant that someone who spoke only French thought I could understand them.<br />
Hey, it happens.<br />
The train arrived about 30 minutes later. Montreal&#8217;s AMT system had originally inherited most of its equipment from GO Transit &#8212; the locomotives and the original passenger cars. To be honest, that&#8217;s what I expected to see. So needless to say, I was a tad disappointed to see a Genesis-class locomotive, and a set of somewhat flashy passenger cars.<br />
I boarded the train and took a set along the bench (the car has seats of two on one side, and a long bench on the other), with the six other people on the car. At that time of day, the train was mostly empty.<br />
I was reminded of my last train trip into Montreal when I was with the CBC (see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train, Montreal]]). I even tried to spot landmarks and figure out where I was. But before long I realized that I wasn&#8217;t on the rail line I thought I was on. VIA trains run on the CN line, whereas AMT trains seem to run on the old CP line.<br />
Before long, the train reached Gare Lucien L&#8217;Allier, which is the terminus for the AMT line I was on. From there, I would have to turn to the Metro. But first, I needed to find a bathroom, which proved a lot more difficult than I had thought &#8212; the one near the station was closed due to renovations.<br />
I ended up walking through the Bell Centre, the new home for the Montreal Canadiens in search of a toilet. The path wound around the south side of the Bell Centre and then down a hall that looked like a walled-in side of a railway station. Funny that, because it *was* a railway station &#8212; Gare Windsor.<br />
Windsor Station was CP&#8217;s Montreal hub for 100 years. It was where countless thousands started their journeys west into fame, fortune, ignaminy, and/or poverty. Today, it is little more than a room attached to the former headquarters of Canadian Pacific (some offices are still there, but there is little else), and trains haven&#8217;t arrived at that station since Lucien L&#8217;Allier took over at the terminus of the line, and the Bell Centre severed the corridor connection.<br />
Returning to Lucien L&#8217;Allier, I found my way deep into the labyrinth of stairwells to the Metro tunnels. My instructions, having arrived in downtown, where to go to the Peel station, and find a way to kill time for a few hours. I love the Metro, and I love riding it, but killing that much time isn&#8217;t easy.<br />
Reading. After patrolling the stores of three malls that interconnect downtown, that&#8217;s pretty much all I could find to do in the last hour of waiting. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, that&#8217;s fine with me. But I did feel a little peculiar sitting on a bench while the security staff walked by, wondering what I was up to.<br />
Stuart called about 17:15, letting me know that he was on his way to pick up Therese, and would be picking me up not long after. I gathered my things and headed up to the Famous Players theatre (on the upper floors) to await the call. I would meet up with them across the street, throwing my bag in the back seat of their Jetta, and taking off down St. Catherine into chaos of downtown Montreal.<br />
We chatted about my trip in, but before long settled into the regular banter that has defined the last 15 years of our relationship. We continued this as Stuart weaved in and out of traffic, and through neighbourhoods until we arrived at their townhouse, in the Point St. Charles area of Montreal.<br />
Their home is a new development, built in a two-unit construction to look and blend in with the older units on either side. It&#8217;s exceptionally nice. Two storey, plus basement, three bedroom, two bathroom, all open-concept on the main floor. The basement has a den/office, and a workshop the previous owner used to completely rebuild the interior (for example, all the doors, while standard-size, are custom-built). The decoration is immaculate. I have to say, I was envious. I wish my place looked that good.<br />
Therese is eight months pregnant at this point, which was a huge part of the reason I wanted to come out. I wanted to see them one last time before they become parents. I needed to have that moment with them, and just them. This far along in her pregnancy, Therese gets tired a lot more easily (when you pack on 40 pounds of kicking parasite, let&#8217;s see how well you do). This evening, Therese felt well enough that we could go out and explore a little.<br />
We ended up in the Verdun area, which is &#8220;west&#8221; of where Stuart and Therese lives. We were scooting along Wellington St., looking at the various restaurants that Therese and Stuart had eyed for a few months, but hadn&#8217;t had time to visit. So finally, we ducked into one place, which we discovered was Peruvian, and endulged ourselves in food and conversation.<br />
And it felt good. Not just that I got to eat for the first time in hours, but because I got to spend time with my friends, whom I love dearly.<br />
Not ending the evening too early, we headed over to the local video store and rented <em>Spellbound</em>, which is a documentary of the American spelling bee championships (an odd thing to have, to be sure). A couple six-packs of beer certainly made Stuart and I feel a lot better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-to-montreal-to-visit-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">323</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
