<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>fairmont hot springs &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/fairmont-hot-springs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>2012, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2012-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2012, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an unfulfilled burning need to travel, it&#8217;s truly a wonder I got out of bed in the morning.<br />
So it wasn&#8217;t with any reservation that 2012 walked out of my life on Monday night, yet it still managed to leave me rather depressed. Sadly, 2013 woke me up looking already a lot like 2012, so I&#8217;m not sure if I&#8217;m able to look at this new year with much hope yet. Instead, I suppose I shall have to try harder to make things work more my way.<br />
This not to say that I &#8220;didn&#8217;t like&#8221; 2012. It&#8217;s hard not to like an entire year in one&#8217;s life, especially one that brings so many new things to learn and experience. I just wish it hadn&#8217;t been so darned painful&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3208"></span><br />
Like I said, 2012 was a busy, busy year. So there&#8217;s no way to know if I&#8217;m going to miss anything, because I did a pretty lousy job of documenting it. I can only hope that through extracting details from Twitter, Facebook, Flickr, and my blog, that I can stir enough memories to get this all straight.</p>
<ul>
<li>Experienced our first New Year&#8217;s Tea not at the Banff Springs</li>
<li>Learned that my youngest, Choo Choo (no more than 2), was a lot smarter than I thought she was &#8230; and she only got smarter (and more defiant)</li>
<li>Saw far too few friends for far too short a time</li>
<li>Worked a lot, but not painfully so &#8212; I still had a (family) life outside of it. YAY FOR BALANCE!</li>
<li>Developed a vicious cold that led to &#8212; no word of a lie &#8212; pulled rib muscles. Owie.
<ul>
<li>Had my first chest x-ray, taken by &#8212; drum roll, please &#8212; my wife, Alex!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Discovered that Monkey loves shrimp, especially at dim sum</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t go to dim sum nearly enough</li>
<li>Had some fairly steep automobile expenses (block heater for the Jetta, and a new car for Alex)</li>
<li>Renewed a mortgage for the first time ever (instead of selling the house)</li>
<li>Continued hating, loathing, and despising having to deal with the Facebook API</li>
<li>Went through the agony, grief, despair, anger, bargaining, and acceptance of a major home renovation, as we redid our kitchen (and subsequently, floors and bathrooms)
<ul>
<li>I do so love our kitchen, though&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Found my cooking skills steadily improving
<ul>
<li>Need to watch more cooking shows, and figure out some different techniques</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Broke my little toe. Why do the little bones always hurt more?</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time ranting about how badly our Federal Government seems to want to drive Canadians to be not Canadian (specifically through bills C-11 and C-30, the ever-present Big Telco lobbies, revisiting the abortion laws, and Rob Anders)</li>
<li>Disposed of my giant water jug container of coins (6,400+ of &#8217;em)</li>
<li>Realized that building a &#8220;mobile&#8221; site is a pointless exercise, and that the design needs to adapt for all devices &lt;&#8211; my professional epiphany of the year</li>
<li>Lived (very basically) out of my contractor&#8217;s rental home for a month while our home was being torn apart</li>
<li>Celebrated Choo Choo&#8217;s 2nd Birthday</li>
<li>Cancelled TV at home, and went to internet-only for video content (still a work-in-progress)</li>
<li>Saw the original cast of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em> on stage</li>
<li>Had my first ambulance ride, my first shot of morphine, and my first (and thankfully last) bout of appendicitis
<ul>
<li>Also had a sponge bath; nowhere near as much fun as it sounds</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw <em>Avenue Q</em>. Hurt myself laughing.</li>
<li>Tried not to laugh when Monkey decided to cut Choo Choo&#8217;s hair. I failed.</li>
<li>Learned that I cannot work from home, without breaking my children&#8217;s hearts</li>
<li>Showed my children the &#8220;hole in the sun&#8221; as Venus transited our star &#8212; I think Monkey started to understand heliocentrism&#8230;</li>
<li>Exited the year wondering how RIM/Blackberry is still a going concern, and why Microsoft hadn&#8217;t fired Ballmer</li>
<li>Went to Fairmont Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Oakville</li>
<li>Went to Banff</li>
<li>Aaaaand that&#8217;s it, folks. Depressingly boring year for travel.</li>
<li>Turned 40. Or as I like to call it, &#8220;4, with an extraneous zero&#8221;.</li>
<li>Watched in real-time (delayed by 7 minutes) as Curiosity landed on the surface of Mars using the single most insane landing procedure ever conceived</li>
<li>Monkey became a 5 year old. I&#8217;ve been a parent for over <em>five years</em> now. And the world has not fallen apart (entirely). Who knew?</li>
<li>Tried to stop drinking coffee. Boy that was dumb.</li>
<li>Reminisced about being with the CBC TV 50th Anniversary project 10 years ago</li>
<li>Took Monkey to her first day of kindergarten; oddly, I didn&#8217;t cry</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that our family cannot operate without a second car</li>
<li>Made jam for the first time, and I shall do it again!</li>
<li>Made tomato sauce and tomato paste from scratch; there&#8217;s a reason they&#8217;re cheaper to buy in cans, sadly.</li>
<li>Made a &#8220;perfect&#8221; prime rib. Now I need to make it again.</li>
<li>Figured out how to make gluten-free stuffing for turkey (just need to tone down the spices a bit, as I discovered at Christmas)</li>
<li>Used a roto-tiller for the first time. Sadly, it had very dull blades, so using it hurt. A lot.</li>
<li>Felt my gut in my stomach as a man stood on the edge of the stratosphere. Then he jumped.</li>
<li>Somehow acquired strep</li>
<li>Got taken down, not by the strep, but by the stupid antibiotics I took to get rid of the strep. Go figure.</li>
<li>Had a very long night of trying to get my frozen, snow-bound car out of the airport parking lot.</li>
<li>Had a vicious cold knock me down for two days (minor flu?)</li>
<li>Got a re-learning of high school physics when I tried to vacuum up a box of baking soda. (Try it yourself, if you dare.)</li>
<li>Rode the new West LRT on the first day! Love that I take a train to work, now.</li>
<li>I saw <em>The Hobbit</em>. Yes, I liked it.</li>
<li>Had a minor outpatient surgery that didn&#8217;t exactly jingle my bells; made for an uncomfortable Christmas</li>
<li>Got an iPad mini for Christmas from my company. Had to admit that the Mini is actually a good idea.</li>
<li>Got (and installed) a Nest thermostat. I can&#8217;t stop fiddling with it.</li>
<li>Finally went sledding for the first time in two years.</li>
</ul>
<p>That brings me to the end of the year. So: busy, interesting, painful, trying, educational, somewhat wistful, and definitely productive. We&#8217;ll see what 2013 brings.<br />
I just hope it means no more trips to hospitals&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3208</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 2.5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-2-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 2.5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, kids, this vacation is certainly having some ups and downs. I&#8217;m taking that as a good thing, by the way, since without variation things can get a little dry. That&#8217;s also a joke, incidentally &#8212; &#8220;dry&#8221; isn&#8217;t a concern around here. It&#8217;s rained every day so far (we have thunderstorms as I&#8217;m writing this), and not far away, flooding is so bad that highways are being washed out.<br />
<span id="more-3121"></span>Yesterday started looking like it might rain, though it didn&#8217;t. That allowed us to bolt up the side of the mountain for a chance for you two to go in the bouncy castles. Sadly, only one of the three was set up, as they were all very wet (the one you were in was still a bit damp). It was so wet, and the clouds threatening a downpour so badly that we couldn&#8217;t decide whether or not to buy a day pass. Thankfully, the two attendants decided to let you two bounce anyway, as they didn&#8217;t get the other two castles set up until much later.<br />
We went for a snack afterwards: hot chocolate for both of you, along with (shared) slices of banana bread and devil&#8217;s food chocolate cake. After our snack, we all headed back to the S7 house for our lunch: Grandpa&#8217;s chili.<br />
Choo Choo went for a nap, Monkey went out with Mommy and Tia Nicole. It was quiet around the house for a little while.<br />
I attempted to make dinner. With a mostly-frozen chicken. The stupid heat-proof dish shattered, the chicken hadn&#8217;t thawed as expected, and I was thoroughly disgusted with my lousy attempt. We ended up having to order from a new restaurant nearby (that happens to make a fire roasted chicken with fries that is strongly reminiscent of those from a chain named for Alps-bound edifices).<br />
Post-dinner was our hot springs soak. Monkey, you&#8217;re getting better at swimming, but you&#8217;re still somewhat hopeless without a floatation device. We need to practice on your doggy paddle. And, I should also add, you finally took to the hot pool (which was significantly hotter than when Mommy and I had gone the night before). Choo Choo, on the other hand, could have just stayed there for hours.<br />
Sadly, that trip also put both of you well past your bedtimes; Monkey, you didn&#8217;t get to bed until nearly 22:00, which is dangerous for your overnight rest (as it stands, it wasn&#8217;t that good). But I can safely say Choo Choo had it worse.<br />
Laryngotracheobronchitis, to be exact. You picked it up yesterday morning, the wheezing very prominent. We had hoped it would pass, but it just got worse. So bad that a couple of times you woke up screaming &#8212; which wasn&#8217;t actually screaming, as you couldn&#8217;t really do much other than gasp and emit a raspy squeak. At 4:00, Mommy and I packed you into the car, and we were off to the hospital &#8230; nearly 30 kilometres away.<br />
The trip to Invermere was a bit difficult. I was anxious to get you there quickly, Choo Choo, but with dawn only just starting to dawn, it was still very dark, and light patches of fog randomly appeared. In any urban setting, I might not think twice about it &#8212; on Highway 93/95, which has a constant animal warning, I was more than a little worried about going too quickly.<br />
Ironically, I nearly hit the damn deer sitting in the middle of an Invermere street, less than 100 metres from the hospital, because I&#8217;d stopped watching for them.<br />
Invermere Hospital is small. Really small. The outer doors were locked, and we had to get buzzed in. Then we were met by the entire hospital night staff: Two Registered Nurses and a Practicing Nurse. A grand total of 12 emergency beds, and 8 overnight beds. We were the only ones there, so we had the entire hospital focused on you, Choo Choo. A far cry from the busy-ness of the Calgary hospitals.<br />
The Practicing Nurse almost immediately said &#8220;croup&#8221;, which is a nasty condition that stems from an infection of your vocal chords. Sadly, in small kids, it causes a tight constriction, leading to the wheezing and barking cough. That led to a phone call to the admitting desk &#8212; at some other remote location &#8212; and another call to the on-call doctor.<br />
In the meantime, we were whisked away to Bed #4 &#8212; as unoccupied as every other bed &#8212; where you got to lay down with a warm blanket. You were scared, Choo Choo, and I don&#8217;t blame you. There were two very nice ladies fawning over you, and you were somewhere you didn&#8217;t recognise at all. Then, to make things worse, you had some drops to drink (an oral steroid to help with your larynx), and then they put a mask over your face to help give you some ventalin to help you breathe.<br />
You really didn&#8217;t like that mask. It didn&#8217;t matter that it was painted to look a bit like a doggy, you just didn&#8217;t want it there, you didn&#8217;t want the mist, you just wanted it off. You cried. And I don&#8217;t blame you one bit. You were given a box of apple juice and two Digestive cookies for when you got it off, and stickers to put on while the mist did its work.<br />
When the doctor arrived, a very nice man I might add, he proceeded to do a quick check, and then took you and Mommy for a quick stroll outside to let the cool air help you breathe.<br />
I asked the nurses about the hospital, and learned how small it was, that we were in the &#8220;shoulder&#8221; season, between the high points of winter (dislocated shoulders and broken bones from the ski hills) and summer (not detailed, but I presume similar given the tendency for people to switch from one seasonal downhill activity to another).<br />
Finally, we left, thanking everyone for all their help. You munched on ice chips and your other cookie until we were back in Fairy-mont. We all went right back to bed &#8212; I curled up with you until you were asleep again &#8212; and managed to get some more rest.<br />
Breakfast was late, activities were (sadly) largely aborted. We managed to get in a short swim before eating lunch. Choo Choo went back down for a nap (in an effort to try get back to regular sleep patterns), and Monkey and I went for a (short) craft session, making Wiggly Worms.<br />
Monkey, you&#8217;ve been making cupcakes with Granny, and watching Wall-E. That&#8217;s where we are right now. Mommy just got back from a much-needed massage. Grandpa and Tia Nicole are in Invermere. The afternoon and evening are ahead of us; we shall see what comes.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-2-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vacation 2012, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=vacation-2012-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 05:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kids, You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours. We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230; We started &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Vacation 2012, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kids,<br />
You&#8217;re both sleeping right now. Soundly so. You&#8217;ve both had a big, exciting day, and I&#8217;m frankly amazed you made it as long as you did. You normally don&#8217;t pack this much into a few days, let alone a few hours.<br />
We&#8217;ll see how you do for the next few days&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3119"></span>We started early, all of us up before 7:00 this morning. I&#8217;d packed for our trip last night (and we&#8217;ve since determined that Daddy sucks at remembering certain important things), but we still had some last-minute things that had to be done at the last minute (turning off computers, internet, turning down the hot water heater, to name a few), and the packing of the last few things. I then packed the car &#8212; in the rain, I might add.<br />
Then we bolted to Sunterra for breakfast. This is our Saturday tradition. Every Saturday, we&#8217;re there when they open at 8:00 to have a good, hot breakfast that will usually keep us going for a few hours. (Well, most of us. Mommy&#8217;s current diet means she has to bring her breakfast with her, and it&#8217;s just never enough.) After breakfast, we did a tiny bit of shopping, and we headed out to North Glenmore Park.<br />
Today was the Race for Pace. This was a charitable event to raise funds for the Pacekids Program, which helps disabled kids. Amber, our next-door neighbour, informed us of the event, and it seemed like it would be a lot of fun. Y&#8217;know, in the rain.<br />
I joke, I joke! It didn&#8217;t rain &#8230; that much. It did rain, but nothing like when we woke up, which was a fair pounding. The rain had let up during breakfast. That said, the park was very wet, the ground very soggy, and we all got reasonably damp. Except in spirits. Once the two of you got your superhero capes, you were off like gangbusters. We did the 1 km Superhero race (Mommy and Monkey completed it; Choo Choo and I cheated a bit, only because you&#8217;re a bit of a slow walker, still, Choo Choo), which ended in a crowd of cheers, and medals on your necks.<br />
You played games and won prizes, too! The best was a &#8220;game&#8221; that originally started as an inflatable pool filled with shredded paper, in which were buried toys for kids to find. But it quickly evolved to a game where the kids threw around clumps of shredded paper (both in/out of the pool, and at each other), and pretty much ignored all the toys that were supposed to be &#8220;won&#8221;.<br />
After some slices of the 100th Anniversary Calgary Stampede cake, we headed back to the car, buckled in, and headed back to Sunterra (which, in our defence, was on the way out of the city) to get Choo Choo some diapers (which we&#8217;d forgotten to buy when we were there), hooked up the in-car DVD player (Kiki&#8217;s Delivery Service was the first movie up), and then hit the road.<br />
It rained.<br />
It rained off and on pretty much the rest of the day, really. It&#8217;s raining right now. It&#8217;ll be raining tomorrow. I really hope it stops raining.<br />
Anyway, we stopped in Canmore, rather than our usual habit, which is Banff. Mommy found a nice restaurant she could eat at, which turned out to be a wonderful place with good food, and colouring books. You two and I had grilled cheese sandwiches (mine also had ham, salami, and dill pickles, mind you) while Mommy had a spinach salad.<br />
We tried to find a playground afterwards, but it didn&#8217;t work out so well &#8212; the nearest one was further away than we&#8217;d planned. But we did find a toy store to stop at for short while.<br />
Finding Nemo was the next movie up, which carried us through Banff National Park, and well into Kootenay National Park. Choo Choo, you finally fell asleep as we approached Highway 93, and stayed asleep for about an hour, waking up at the Lodge, where we&#8217;ve often stopped for a short break. (In this case, it was a rather urgent potty break.)<br />
The rest of the trip went as it usually did &#8212; not anywhere near as fast as we&#8217;d like it to go. But soon we were out of the mountains, much to Choo Choo&#8217;s relief (your ears were apparently hurting), and turning south towards what Choo Choo had started to call &#8220;Fairy-mont&#8221;. (My spelling, of course.)<br />
After the obligatory stop in Invermere for groceries, we blasted to Fairy-mont, and checked in at the Mountainside Villas, barely minutes before Grandpa, Granny, and Tia Nicole arrived. We got the keys to our &#8220;new&#8221; house for this year, S7. Normally, we&#8217;re in B6, but it wasn&#8217;t available this week (this week being a traded week, since the timeshare schedule this year put us into Monkey&#8217;s first week of Kindergarten). S7 and B6 are similar, but there are notable differences. For this week, however, I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll be fine.<br />
The both of you ran amok around the house, running up and down stairs, jumping on beds (you&#8217;re still mystified at the Murphy bed; you have no idea where the bed keeps disappearing to). We had dinner (though both of you failed to eat much), you read some stories, and after a significant amount of struggle, we got you both to bed, both still far too excited to be here, and both passing out within minutes of hitting the pillow.<br />
Mommy and I made a run to the hot springs afterwards, and put some more thought into what we&#8217;ll do this week.<br />
Y&#8217;know, if it ever stops raining.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/06/vacation-2012-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3119</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2004 04:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/04/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest star hire had backed out &#8212; an extremely disappointing turn of events. I wouldn&#8217;t talk to Cory about it until late in the afternoon.<br />
We were gone before 8:00. (We were to have left at 6:00, then 7:00, but last night&#8217;s arrival in Fairmont pushed us even later.) Allen was in Jean&#8217;s Honda Civic, Alex and I in Alex&#8217;s car. I drove while Alex read &#8220;Why I Hate Canadians&#8221;. Today&#8217;s lesson? Canada&#8217;s cast system, more formally known as how poorly we treat Indians. It&#8217;s a hard thing for a Canadian to admit that we don&#8217;t treat everyone fairly and equally. For a country known as being &#8220;nice&#8221;, we treat our aboriginal peoples very poorly. We&#8217;ve marginalized, forcibly contained, abducted and tried to convert them, even poisoned them with disease. And yet after 400 years, they&#8217;re still who they are.<br />
<span id="more-382"></span>A lot of people think Indians have it easy here in Canada &#8212; pay no taxes, live on welfare, do what they please when they want. Lest we forget that we made them wards of the state &#8212; they *have* to live this way, because there is no other way for them to live. We never gave them a chance.<br />
(Incidentally, this is a view I&#8217;ve long held, and the book has since backed up. Ferguson is definitely a socialist who supports equal rights, nationalism (he rather dislikes the ill-guided attempts of Quebec separatists), and believes the monarchy should take a hike.)<br />
When we arrived in Golden, right behind Allen&#8217;s car, we headed to the Humpty&#8217;s on the Trans-Canada Highway for breakfast. I&#8217;d never been to Humpty&#8217;s before, having always viewed it as a lower-end sort of place to obtain a meal. My opinion of that hasn&#8217;t changed (the state of the bacon alone held me to that perspective).<br />
The weather yo-yo&#8217;d constantly from the time we left Fairmont until we arrived in the Lower Mainland. It was cloudy, rainy, spittling, sunny, warm, foggy, and windy all at various times (and varying combinations) throughout the trip. Alex seemed to get the bulk of the bad weather from Golden to Revelstoke.<br />
I read &#8220;Mythic Journeys&#8221; aloud. I disagreed with some of the interpretation, and wasn&#8217;t too thrilled with the depth &#8212; quite often, there was more commentary than story. It doesn&#8217;t make for great reading.<br />
We stopped in Revelstoke for drinks and snacks, and once again changed drivers. We stopped barely five kilometres past Revelstoke to make reservations at the Three Valley Gap hotel, which is a bit of a landmark in the area, and one of Alex&#8217;s favourite locations to be. (It&#8217;s a long story, which I&#8217;m going to forego with repeating here.) We&#8217;ll be stopping there on our way back.<br />
Off to Kamloops we went. We would have driven straight through, had we not also come across Craigellachie (&#8220;cray-GAL-ah-kee&#8221;), which was where the last spike was driven on the Canadian Pacific Railway in 1886. There&#8217;s not much there other than a cairn, bearing stones from every province and territory, and a stone from Craigellachie, Scotland, where most of the original directors of the CPR hailed from.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long. Just enough for a couple of photos, and a chance to mock some idiotic 20-something tourists from Ontario. They were being typical of that age: stupid. Though I never remember being quite so dumb that I would have inspired someone else to think of me: &#8220;Look at me, I&#8217;m an idiot!&#8221;<br />
Pulling into Kamloops about an hour later, running almost on fumes, we headed for the ABC Country restaurant on the junction of the Trans-Canada and Highway 5A. When we went inside, I realized that it was the same restaurant where Greg and I had eaten breakfast four and a half years before, when he helped me move from Vancouver to Calgary (see [[Left Vancouver, Job, and Girlfriend for New Start in Calgary]]). This time, thankfully, I wasn&#8217;t doing anything even remotely traumatic.<br />
Alex took over for the last stint of driving to Ruskin (a hamlet next to Maple Ridge, BC), where her father lives. The trip was much shorter than I had expected &#8212; for some reason, I thought the distance from Kamloops to Hope was much longer than we experienced. Mind you, the distance from Hope to Highway 11 seemed almost as long. (It didn&#8217;t help that we got stuck in traffic.)<br />
Dairy Queen made a call to us as we pulled off the highway. We&#8217;d been dying for a Blizzard since half-way down the Coquihalla Highway, but had missed the turn-off in Hope. Fortunately, the one on Highway 11 would suffice &#8230; even if some of the patrons were a little strange.<br />
Continuing up Highway 11, across the Fraser River (and getting a dirty look from a police officer at a radar trap for going a little too quickly), we turned west on Highway 7. Another 15 minutes, and we arrived at the farm &#8212; Allen and Jean&#8217;s new home, built on the former location of Alex&#8217;s grandparent&#8217;s home.<br />
We got a tour almost as soon as we were in the house. It&#8217;s an impressive structure. It looks unassuming from the outside, but there is much hidden under the covers. First and foremost, it&#8217;s a green building. It&#8217;s made with the most energy-efficient materials available, has radiant heating in the floors, recycling wood for the flooring upstairs, low-wattage lights, and nice, large windows to allow sunlight to come in during the winter.<br />
But the best feature was found tucked away, behind the garage: geothermic heating. This is the créme de la créme of cool (or heat, depending on what season you&#8217;re in). Because the house is built on an acreage, there is sufficient space to build this. (I could probably do this in Calgary, but I shudder to think at what cost.) A space about 25 feet wide, 80 feet long, and about seven feet deep was dug out behind the house and filled with long spiral tubes, and partially filled with clay. The tubes are then filled with a vicous liquid which tranfers heat in and out of the house. The system also hooks into the hot water tank to cut down on the energy needed to keep the water hot.<br />
The end result? Theoretically, a lower energy bill. If Allen has his way, he&#8217;ll also build a windmill to generate some additional electricity, and maybe even cut his BC Hydro bill to zero.<br />
A dream worth shooting for, indeed.<br />
Alex and I ducked out for a quick tour of the yard. The acreage isn&#8217;t huge (about 6.2 acres), with the main property lot about 200 feet on both sides, and then extending about 30-50 feet into the woods and down to the creek. The landscaping potential of this place is amazing &#8212; I have great dreams of a staircase and deck space down at the creek level. Now I just need to convince Allen that it&#8217;s a good idea.<br />
I pitched the tent (Alex and I are sleeping outdoors) under four great cedar trees on the east side of the house. The ground underneath is spongy from decades of cedar leaves and soil growth. Tonight, we will sleep well.<br />
I certainly hope so, because although today&#8217;s trip was outstanding, it really wore me down.<br />
[flickr]tag:craigellachie+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">382</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fort Steele and Cranbrook</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2004 04:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/03/bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No-one told me that we were doing any surprises this weekend. &#8216;Course, then it wouldn&#8217;t be a surprise, would it? Allen (Alex&#8217;s father) took Jean (Alex&#8217;s stepmom) down to Cranbrook so she could catch a flight out to southern Ontario for a wedding. This meant the condo was quiet for a number of hours. That &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fort Steele and Cranbrook"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No-one told me that we were doing any surprises this weekend. &#8216;Course, then it wouldn&#8217;t be a surprise, would it?<br />
Allen (Alex&#8217;s father) took Jean (Alex&#8217;s stepmom) down to Cranbrook so she could catch a flight out to southern Ontario for a wedding. This meant the condo was quiet for a number of hours. That meant we didn&#8217;t get up until late. I love sleeping in.<br />
<span id="more-381"></span>Before the major adventure of the day, Alex and I took a fairly brisk walk down to the giftshop on the Highway. Alex is seeing an old friend of hers while we&#8217;re in Maple Ridge, and she wanted to have a gift of some kind. I got caught up in a book on backroads in Southern Alberta, which accurately placed all the rail lines with access roads. I almost had to buy it.<br />
Following our lunch (leftovers from last night&#8217;s pork roast), we piled into Jean&#8217;s car (a little red two-door Honda Civic) and headed towards Fort Steele. But before we headed out the door, Alex turned to me and told me to bring my nice clothes with me. As far as I knew, we were going to Fort Steele, and then to the Canadian Museum of Rail Transportation in Cranbrook. Unless there was something she wasn&#8217;t telling me, which obviously there was, there wasn&#8217;t any reason for me to bring my nice clothes. My Suspicion Alarm was going off quite loudly.<br />
The trip down to Fort Steel was quite nice, at least for a section of highway that I&#8217;d never been down before. (I suppose if I went down it more than once, the drive would get a little, well, boring. It took about an hour to get to Fort Steele.<br />
Fort Steele was originally an outpost of the North West Mounted Police back in the 1880s. It was small, and key to the expansion of the Kootenays. It fell victim to the typoid epidemic of the late 1880s, which the Fort (and townsite) never fully recovered from. It became a ghost town for many years before the BC government turned it into a park. Now it&#8217;s a tourist attraction complete with some original buildings, some reconstructions, and a couple of imports for good measure.<br />
One of the imports is the small narrow-guage railway that ferries visitors along a mile or so stretch of track, pulled by an old logging camp locomotive from Chemainus, number 1077. When I first saw it, you couldn&#8217;t have convinced me that it was a Canadian locomotive &#8212; it just didn&#8217;t look like one. It certainly wasn&#8217;t either Canadian National or Canadian Pacific, which more or less meant American. It never occurred to me that it might be something else. Fortunately, a plaque on the hogger&#8217;s side told the story. It also explained the presence of the British passenger car that was the third part of the short train (probably because it was the only passenger car the museum could get that ran on that gauge).<br />
We hummed and hawed at the entrance, deciding whether or not we wanted to go in. Alex wasn&#8217;t sure, Allen didn&#8217;t seem to mind, and I was just following their lead. I wanted to go in, but at $10.50 a pop, wasn&#8217;t about the press the matter. Finally, though, we decided, forked out the fee, and in we went.<br />
I can only assume the grounds aren&#8217;t too far off from what had once been here. The old fort was reconstructed, but was likely very close to what had once been there. The interior of the soldier&#8217;s barracks looked reasonably accurate (given that I have no particular memory of what it could have originally looked like), and downright inhospitable. The interior of the officer&#8217;s quarters were luxurious by comparison, and further reinforced the tradition of class separation within the British military (police, or otherwise).<br />
We encountered some ill-mannered sheep (one of which sounded like it was belching constantly), highly-tempting candies, a few other guests (I accidentally uttered &#8220;geseundheit&#8221; to a German family), a few horses, and the various staff in costume and personna (including one group who were holding an etiquette lesson for the women). Otherwise, the grounds were fairly deserted, and some of the exhibits were closed. I can only assume, as it was a Friday, that it was either due to the weekday (possible) or the blatantly bad weather that has been plaguing this region of the country all summer (in my view, far more likely).<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay too long, and headed back towards the car. But not before I got a couple of pictures of the train, and got some ice cream with Alex.<br />
And so we resumed our trip south to Cranbrook, eventually ending up at the Canadian Museum of Rail Transportation. I&#8217;ve always wanted to go there, ever since I heard about the exhibits the museum had. And now that they&#8217;d moved to a new location with new facilities, I wanted to go even more. This, little did I know, was part of the surprise.<br />
CP 2816 had arrived only minutes before us, having brought people to Cranbrook from Fernie (about 100 kilometres away) at a cost of $200 per person (assumedly a charitable donation to the museum). I had worried that perhaps the surprise might be a ride on the train. While I would most certainly love the experience, that cost was unconciably too high.<br />
The surprise, as it turned out, was dinner. At the Museum. Specifically, the gala opening of the museum, held in the Royal Alexandra Hall. I had completely forgotten about the dinner and the event. I had mentioned to Alex that we should see the hall, but Allencame up with the idea that it would be nice for us to attend. Little did I know.<br />
And a gala it was. Just because we were in Cranbrook didn&#8217;t mean that we didn&#8217;t see people dressed in their finest for the event. This, I can only assume, was the sort of thing people remember. This was a chance to eat in the Royal Alexandra Hall, formerly the café of the Royal Alexandra Hotel in Winnipeg, one of Canadian Pacific&#8217;s Hotels. It was demolished in 1971, but not before a wise husband and wife preserved the interior of the hall for future generations. It sat in storage for 25 years before news of the museum&#8217;s goals caught their ear. They donated the whole thing, and it took over two years to reassemble it. The work isn&#8217;t entirely done yet, but he results so far are breathtaking.<br />
Equally breaktaking was the eight course meal (we only make it through six, having to leave early because of our hour and a half trip back to Fairmont). We sat at a table with five other people, all of whom were from the area. They were delightful, telling us their histories, the history of the museum, the history of the hall, and many of the reasons why living in Cranbrook was such a joy. Admittedly, it&#8217;s not the first place I&#8217;d ever think to move to, but I could see some of the appeal.<br />
Our menu was derived from the menus of the Royal Alexandra&#8217;s history. They were prepared using CP Hotel&#8217;s own rules. The meal was exquisite, even if prepared only by local Heidi&#8217;s Restaurant:</p>
<ul>
<li>Course #1: Savoury Canapes: proscuitto, quail eggs, smoked salmon, sardine, shrimp, portabello mushrooms (1948 menu), served with champagne</li>
<li>Course #2: Salad of Lettuce and Orange (1913 menu), served with apertif wine; the salad was far more intricate than the menu suggests</li>
<li>Course #3: Soup: Consomme Brunoise Xavier (1948 menu); a very tasty light beef broth with fresh vegetables added just as the soup was served</li>
<li>Course #4: Palate Cleanser: Pineapple Sorbet (1922 menu); pineapple ice with small chunks of frozen pineapple, simple yet clean</li>
<li>Course #5: Entrée: Duck with apple sauce (1948 menu), with new potatoes, French green beans Amandine (basically, wrapped with bacon), and a baked half tomato with spices; served with two glasses of red wine</li>
<li>Course #6: Dessert: Mocha slice with chocolate éclair glace (1965 menu); served with dessert wine</li>
<li>Course #7: Fruit &amp; Cheese Plate: Austrian smoked Gruyere, Swiss  Emmentaler, Roquefort, Canadian Cheddar, Italian Provolone, cantaloupe, honeydew melons and grapes, with walnuts &amp; almonds</li>
<li>Course #8: Tea or Coffee (with shots of Kahlua or Bailey&#8217;s, if desired)</li>
</ul>
<p>It hurt to leave so early, but it was best we left. Most of the others were staying in town, and it simply wasn&#8217;t an option for us to stick around. We had to get up early to drive out to Ruskin, and we had a 90 minute drive a head of us.<br />
Was I surprised? Darn right I was, and quite happy about it, too! But not as surprised as that deer we almost hit on the way back.<br />
[flickr]tag:fortsteele+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr] [flickr]tag:cranbrook+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-steele-cranbrook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">381</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs and Kootenay National Park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2004 04:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/02/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s nothing quite like waking up to the sound of lawnmowers. Rousing, yet entirely annoying. We started the day off with a mom saver. This is generally a breakfast meal, though I suppose you could just as easily use a version of one for any meal of the day. The breakfast one we had consists &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs and Kootenay National Park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s nothing quite like waking up to the sound of lawnmowers. Rousing, yet entirely annoying.<br />
We started the day off with a mom saver. This is generally a breakfast meal, though I suppose you could just as easily use a version of one for any meal of the day. The breakfast one we had consists of eggs, cubed bread, cream cheese (cubed, or something similar), some spices, and thrown in the oven to cook for 45 minutes. Throw on some maple syrup on top, and it&#8217;s pretty tasty. There&#8217;s also a ham and cheese version that I&#8217;m dying to try some time.<br />
<span id="more-380"></span>Showered and ready for the day, we decided that we weren&#8217;t heading off anywhere in particular until after lunch. This was a bit of a surprise to me, since we didn&#8217;t finish breakfast until almost 10:00. To wait only a mere two hours before lunch seemed awfully short. But then, Alex seems to have an insane metabolism &#8212; one I can&#8217;t even begin to hope to keep up with.<br />
So instead of heading off to Kootenay National Park for our hike, Alex and I decided to go for a little walk. The Mountain Villas of Fairmont Hot Springs (where Alex&#8217;s parents have a timeshare) are built around the Fairmont Creek, which is the outflow of the hot springs. The creek has been modified a bit over the years, mostly to accommodate the resort, but still flows into the Columbia River.<br />
We hiked over to the creek, not far from the condo, and started to walk up its shore. But the inviting burbling of the creek soon drew us to its side, and in Alex&#8217;s case, into the creek itself. (Had I been walking with my flip-flops, I would have followed Alex in. As I was wearing my hiking shoes, that wasn&#8217;t bloody likely.) We went up the river (and in the river) until I was driven out due to lack of dry walking space. Naturally, this was when Alex lost one of her flip-flops (which she later recovered).<br />
The creek bed isn&#8217;t like a regular creek &#8212; pebbly, with small stones, algae, and fairly free-flowing. This creek had a beige &#8220;liner&#8221; that the water coursed over and around, the result of years of mineral deposits. (It looks like someone poured concrete all along the creek bed to smooth out the bottom.) The minerals caked on tightly to anything and everything. Trees and branches that had fallen into the water were blended in with the creek&#8217;s bed, making it hard to tell where the tree ended and the creek bed began. Rocks in the creek created little pools of water. Being so warm, the pools were very tempting to sit in.<br />
About three-quarters of the way up the creek from where we started, we came to a waterfall. The mineral deposits up above created a chute, causing the water to fall further out into a large pool before cascading down terraces into the creek itself. It was a great place to sit and relax.<br />
Eventually, we found ourselves at the hot springs pool. We stayed only long enough to check out the price and the times before heading back.<br />
We arrived in time for lunch &#8212; leftover macaroni and cheese, with a Greek salad. I find Greek salads to be an interesting anachronism for me: while I love the taste, I can&#8217;t stand either olives or the raw tomatoes found in them. I am very good at eating around things I don&#8217;t like.<br />
Naturally, this preciptated a rather interesting conversation about picky eating habits. I hate olives, raw tomatoes (though I can eat about anything made with cooked tomatoes), sour cream (I&#8217;m sorry, but it&#8217;s *sour* &#8212; that just seems wrong to me), yogourt (I can&#8217;t anything with a &#8216;y&#8217; and a &#8216;g&#8217; in its name, but freeze it and I&#8217;m a happy camper), and I&#8217;m not fond of mushrooms (although as a kid, I used to eat cream of mushroom soup as if my life depended on it). We&#8217;ll forego with the more obvious stuff, like liver&#8230;<br />
Until the beginning of this year, Alex says she was far worse.<br />
Following lunch, Alex, her father, and I all headed out for Kootenay National Park, and the Juniper Trail. This is a fairly short (three kilometre) hike that runs from Highway 93 (just inside the south edge of the park), down into the valley, up the other side, and around over to Radium Hot Springs. You have to hike back to the start of the trail on the highway.<br />
The weather was cool and overcast, with the odd spot of rain. But nothing too serious. It didn&#8217;t take long for Alex to shed her sweatshirt, with Alex&#8217;s dad not far behind. I rolled up my sleeves and unzipped my fleece, but never took it off. I&#8217;m a big fan of regulating temperature, rather than having to rapidly adapt to it.<br />
Along the way, we saw part of a waterfall, mountain goats, a few other brave souls on the trip, the valley seen from the top of the trail (which must be gorgeous on a sunny day), and lots and lots and lots of trees and rocks &#8230; and water.<br />
We headed into Invermere to make a stop at the used bookstore (Alex really needed to see what she could find), and to get food for dinner. I had offered to cook. On the menu tonight was apple walnut-stuff pork loin, garlic mashed potatoes, and grilled asparagus. The loin split part-way through cooking, I didn&#8217;t have beer for the potatoes, and I didn&#8217;t cook all the asparagus. But otherwise, the meal wasn&#8217;t half bad.<br />
I do feel like I&#8217;m trying to show my worth, and this was part of it. Let&#8217;s be honest &#8212; these are Alex&#8217;s parents. I need to prove that I&#8217;m not some yutz. To be honest, I think I&#8217;ve done that, or at least am well on the way, and the meal seems to have been a cap.<br />
Before it was too late, Alex and I made use of the hot springs. The facility is huge, many times larger than Banff&#8217;s springs. It&#8217;s the size of an Olympic swimming pool, divided into three parts. A little over half of it is a general swimming pool, with some lanes so people can can do laps. That section is about 32 degrees (Celcius, of course). There&#8217;s another section with two diving boards, also 32 degrees. Then there&#8217;s the hot section, which varies from about 36 degrees to over 40 degrees, depending on where you sit in the pool.<br />
We arrived at about 21:15, about 45 minutes before the pool closed for the night. It was quite full of patrons, most likely taking advantage of the lowered rate in the last hour of operation. It wasn&#8217;t so full that we couldn&#8217;t get around. We lounged, I even took a dive (although I was very tempted to do a cannonball). We were out of the pool in about half an hour, having had enough heat for one night.<br />
[flickr]tag:fairmonthotsprings+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kootenay+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-kootenay-national-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">380</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Calgary to Fairmont Hot Springs</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2004 04:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/01/bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I so wanted to get my butt out of the office, almost from the moment that I was alerted to the problem on MBUSA.com&#8217;s live server. There&#8217;s nothing like trying to diagnose the cause of a homepage failure when you&#8217;re not really sure what happened. Most of my day was like this. Going from one &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Calgary to Fairmont Hot Springs"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I so wanted to get my butt out of the office, almost from the moment that I was alerted to the problem on MBUSA.com&#8217;s live server. There&#8217;s nothing like trying to diagnose the cause of a homepage failure when you&#8217;re not really sure what happened.<br />
Most of my day was like this. Going from one hot spot to another, barely getting enough time to wolf down some lunch. By the end of the day, I had to make sure that I wrapped up dialogue on three separate projects, ensure that the process was moving on two more, finish a proposal to Danny Sullivan for presentation topics for the next Search Engine Strategies conference, and write a rather lengthy email to about a dozen people to make sure they have some inkling about what the heck I&#8217;ve been doing for the last couple of weeks.<br />
Care to take bets that things will still go to hell in a handbasket tomorrow?<br />
<span id="more-379"></span>I ducked out from work at around 16:15 (I would have left 15 minutes earlier, had I not been so pressed to get everything done before I left), and bolted for home. I gathered the remainder of the things I didn&#8217;t pack last night (toiletries, bathing suit, camera, and a change of nice clothes), burned two CDs, shaved, and awaited Alex&#8217;s arrival.<br />
We&#8217;re taking our first actual vacation together. Alex has been planning this for months. Alex&#8217;s father and step-mom have a timeshare condo in Fairmont Hot Springs, a small town about 30 kms south of Radium. (Both of these are in British Columbia.) We would spend a couple of days there, then head off to their house in Maple Ridge, BC. A couple of days there, then back through Three Valley Gap, returning to Calgary on the 8th.<br />
Leaving my house at just after 17:45, we headed first to Market Mall to get something to eat before hitting the road. The mall just reopened with new stores and renovation. It&#8217;s extremely nice. A little too nice, maybe.<br />
A quick bite, and we were off towards Banff (Bamf!). We started off listening to one of two CDs I had brought along (compliations of Blue Rodeo and some Country songs &#8212; relax, none of the Country was actually mine; I will listen to Country, but I don&#8217;t know if I could buy any), but we soon switched to reading a book.<br />
Yes, a book. This is a habit Alex and I started on our return from Kananaskis a number of weeks ago (see [[Canada Day in Banff National Park]]). While I drove, Alex read &#8220;Why I Hate Canadians&#8221; aloud, a task she continued on our trip to and from Edmonton last weekend (see [[Surprise weekend in Edmonton]]). This time, it was my turn, so I read &#8220;Mythic Journeys&#8221;, which is a book that takes the myths of old and relates them to how humanity exists in the modern age.<br />
It should be a fascinating book. Sadly, it&#8217;s not. In fact, it&#8217;s not only a little dull (the analysis of the fables is usually longer than the stories themselves), but the sentence structure is quite difficult. It&#8217;s almost like trying to read Yoda at times. It&#8217;s like the authors decided to try and make themselves sound more educated. (It was probably written by university professors, or by people who wanted to be professors.)<br />
We stopped in Banff (Bamf!) to fill up on gas and acquire some beverages. (All that reading aloud was drying my throat out.) We stayed only long enough to do what we had to, and resumed our drive west.<br />
I switched from the Myth book to one of Patricia Cornwell&#8217;s, &#8220;From Potter&#8217;s Field&#8221;. It&#8217;s a murder mystery. Much more fascinating reading, I must say, mostly because I can actually get into the characters when reading them aloud. I love reading parts by one character, Marino, because he loves saying &#8220;Yo&#8221;. I imagine he says it like Sylvester Stallone.<br />
Not far past Banff (Bamf!) is Highway 93, which heads south to Radium, where is joins with Highway 95, which goes between Golden and Cranbrook. We would head towards Cranbrook. Along the way, we&#8217;d hit Radium (Radium Hot Springs is the main feature on the sign off the Trans Canada), Invermere (where our favourite ex-patriot jerk, Jude, originally hails from), and also Fairmont Hot Springs, our destination.<br />
Overall, the trip from Calgary to Fairmont is about 300 kilometres. It takes a bit longer than three hours, though, due to the winding roads and varying speed limits. Side trips, such as Market Mall and Banff (Bamf!) also tend to slow things down a bit. The trip was interesting, mostly because I&#8217;d never been in this neck of the woods before. So I had no idea where we were or how long it would be until we got where we were going.<br />
As I&#8217;ve said before many times, that&#8217;s all part of the adventure.<br />
We passed through a string of bad weather from the moment we left Calgary. From about 18:30 (the time we left Calgary) until about 22:20 (the time we got to Fairmont), we went from good to bad to rainy to good to foggy to rainy to stormy. It was raining in the last 50 kilometres.<br />
We didn&#8217;t see much of Radium, as it was quite dark when we rolled through. We stopped only once as we headed towards Fairmont (a red traffic light). It&#8217;s a small little place, a bit less prominent than I had expected. But then, it&#8217;s tucked inside Kootenay National Park, so I suppose size does matter.<br />
I called Alex&#8217;s dad as we started to pass out of Radium, just to let him know where we were. We would have called earlier, but by the time Alex suggested that we do so, we were well out of cellular range.<br />
With our stuff stowed away in our little room in the condo, we finally began to unwind a bit. The four of us &#8212; Alex, Allen (Alex&#8217;s dad), Jean (Alex&#8217;s stepmom), and myself &#8212; chatted away and had ice cream and peaches.<br />
I already feel away from the ordinary.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-calgary-fairmont-hot-springs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">379</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
