<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>temples &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/temples/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 14:46:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Nara is neat</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nara-is-neat</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 14:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/18/nara-is-neat/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last time I was in Japan (a little over a year ago), I&#8217;d wanted to go to Nara. I&#8217;d quite a bit about it, but just hadn&#8217;t gotten the chance to go. So when we planned this out, and happened to be spinning through Japan on our way home, it was a very fortunate &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Nara is neat"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last time I was in Japan (a little over a year ago), I&#8217;d wanted to go to Nara. I&#8217;d quite a bit about it, but just hadn&#8217;t gotten the chance to go. So when we planned this out, and happened to be spinning through Japan on our way home, it was a very fortunate happenstance that both of us wanted to be there.<br />
Nara, as it turns out, is a very neat little city. Make no mistake, this is most definitely no town. But it doesn&#8217;t feel large. At least, if you&#8217;re within the &#8220;walled&#8221; portion. (I&#8217;m not sure if there&#8217;s an actual wall, but that&#8217;s what it looks like on the maps we&#8217;ve seen.)<br />
<span id="more-583"></span>Our trip there was an adventure and a half. First, shinkansen to Shin-Osaka, Nozomi-class. (There are three classes: Kodama, Hikari, and Nozomi. Although JR Rail Pass holders aren&#8217;t allowed on Nozomi, the cost to buy a ticket isn&#8217;t much different (maybe 300 yen) between them. And you save almost an hour.) Originally, we were to go to Kyoto, but Amy convinced me to go all the way to Shin-Osaka. Once there, we switched to a local train to Osaka station, then to a regional train that took us all the way out to Nara. From the moment we got off at Shin-Osaka, all the way to a taxi that we finally climbed into in Nara, we stood. My feet were KILLING me.<br />
We&#8217;re staying at a ryokan, a small traditional Japanese guest house. Apparently, it used to be a geisha house. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s Japanese geishas, or American geishas. (What&#8217;s the difference? A proper Japanese geisha is an entertainer. Their job was to placate and entertain powerful men who paid very highly for the services of a geisha. Despite beliefs, Japanese geishas were not prostitutes, unlike the American geishas. These were introduced by the U.S. Government after World War II as an effort to keep American soldiers from &#8220;disturbing&#8221; the Japanese people. These were prostitutes dressed up as geishas, and called as such for the exotic overtones.) I&#8217;d like to believe the house was a Japanese one. It&#8217;s nothing fancy &#8212; a pair of mattresses, a couple of chairs, and a noisy air conditioner. Toilets and showers are communal, but there doesn&#8217;t seem to be anyone around.<br />
Nara is full of temples. Aside from being a former capital (many Japanese cities seem to hold this title), this is still a religious centre. Thankfully, most of the neat stuff was in walking distance of the ryokan. (For the record, though, our &#8220;walking distance&#8221; is probably a lot further than some people&#8217;s definition. We&#8217;ve walked a <em>lot</em> in this trip.)<br />
Starting off at a pond near the Five Storied Pagoda, we found a healthy collection of turtles. Then we wandered through the Pagoda area and were introduced to the deer. Nara deer are &#8230; odd. They&#8217;re small, not as small as the ones on Miyajima Island near Hiroshima, but certainly smaller than the ones in Canada. They&#8217;re defined as &#8220;semi-wild&#8221;, meaning that while they are wild animals, they tolerate interaction with humans quite well. (Although there are a lot of signs telling you to be careful and not to enrage the deer.) It&#8217;s stuff like this that reminds me why many tourists in Banff (Bamf!) are told not to get too close to the elk.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03745.JPG" alt="Pond o' Turtles" width="300" /></a><br />
We were distracted by a rather nice park on the way to Tennoji Temple. Aside from the wonderful Japanese stone lanterns, the biggest attraction we saw was the botanical garden. Apparently designed off various literal works, the garden contains a wonderful collection of plants, arranged into very beautiful pockets of splendour. Of particular interest was a small red deck built over a lilypad-covered pond. The pond was home to a school of carp, which a trio of elderly photographers were taking turns snapping pictures.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03746.JPG" alt="Botanical Garden" width="300" /></a><br />
Tennoji Temple is quite impressive. Like other buildings I&#8217;ve been to that claim it&#8217;s &#8220;the largest wooden building in the world&#8221;, it&#8217;s big. Really big. And impressive. There&#8217;s a large Buddha that sits inside, sheltered by the building. Interestingly enough, the building is smaller than it once was (fire reconstruction), and the temple itself is smaller, having been reduced by similar damage.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03747.JPG" alt="Tennoji Temple" width="300" /></a><br />
We walked around through various alleys and laneways (Nara has many that are very picturesque. You&#8217;ll see something interesting down nearly every road, it seems.)<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03748.JPG" alt="Nara Cultural Hell" width="300" /></a><br />
Amy finally found some Japanese yarn. I thought she was going to have kittens when she found it. She couldn&#8217;t decide, either.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03750.JPG" alt="Yarn, yarn, everywhere..." width="300" /></a><br />
I&#8217;d glad to have finally been to Nara. It&#8217;s a nice little place. If you&#8217;re thinking of coming to Japan, give it a thought. It&#8217;s an easy trip from Osaka &#8230; so long as you&#8217;re not carrying all your bags with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">583</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In the House of Mao</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/in-the-house-of-mao/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-the-house-of-mao</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/in-the-house-of-mao/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2005 06:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/02/in-the-house-of-mao/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chalk up another notch on the Dead Communist Leader Tour. Today, Amy and I decided to keep things light, since our train leaves tonight for Shanghai. On the list of things to hit: Mao Ze Dong&#8217;s Mausoleum, and the Lama Temple. But first, the House of Mao&#8230; When Mao finally kicked the bucket in the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/in-the-house-of-mao/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "In the House of Mao"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chalk up another notch on the Dead Communist Leader Tour.<br />
Today, Amy and I decided to keep things light, since our train leaves tonight for Shanghai. On the list of things to hit: Mao Ze Dong&#8217;s Mausoleum, and the Lama Temple. But first, the House of Mao&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-561"></span>When Mao finally kicked the bucket in the 70s, he was well into this 90s, something the Chinese are quite proud of (and probably cigarette companies, too, since he chain-smoked something fierce). When Mao died, they couldn&#8217;t simply bury him. He was (and still is) a driving force in Chinese life. So they built him a mausoleum. A big one. Nay, a gigantic one. One that rivals the size of small office buildings. All to house the not-really-decaying body of Mao.<br />
To keep this in perspective, I&#8217;ve also been to Lenin&#8217;s Mausoleum. (That was 16 years ago.) It&#8217;s very small, by comparison &#8212; maybe 10&#215;10 metres. This place is easy 100&#215;100 metres. And four or so stories tall. There&#8217;s considerably more security around it than at Lenin&#8217;s tomb, even during the Soviet era.<br />
<a><br />
<img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03645.JPG" alt="Mao's Mausoleum" width="300" /><br />
</a><br />
Because of all the shady people about, and because we couldn&#8217;t find lockers to stow our stuff so we could go inside, Amy and I took turns. Amy went first, because I&#8217;d already seen a dead commie. When I asked her how she felt when she got back, her immediate response was &#8220;respectful&#8221;.<br />
My turn. I had to stand in a line for about 10 minutes before they took a batch of about 40 people around the corner and inside the perimeter to see Mao. You pass by a small booth that sells fresh flowers to lay within the mausoleum building (though it&#8217;s interesting to note that the flowers are &#8220;laid&#8221; in a different room than Mao himself). Then up a set of stairs and into doors that wouldn&#8217;t be any different than an office building&#8217;s. Complete with revolving doors that can&#8217;t really be used all that often.<br />
The atrium features a larger-than-life white marble sculpture of Mao, seated facing north. This is where some kind of trough exists for placing the newly-purchased flowers. (A cynic might suggest that the flowers are collected and taken to the booth for resale.) The line winds around the atrium to the left (east), down the side of the building, then back to the centre to enter the mausoleum chamber. In the centre of the chamber is the Big Guy himself. There&#8217;s a glass wall that separates you from him, and several soldiers standing on guard. Mao is contained within a glass sarcophagus, his body draped in what looks to be a Soviet flag. (The hammer and sickle are a symbol of the people, though it would seem more appropriate to use the Chinese flag &#8230; that&#8217;s just me.)<br />
After being hustled through the Room of Mao, you enter into &#8230; a souvenir shop. No, I&#8217;m not kidding. I wish I were making that up. In fact, from the inside of the building all the way until you reach the perimeter again, it&#8217;s all Mao kitch. It&#8217;s tackiness on a level I can&#8217;t even begin to understand. The Soviets were never like this &#8212; Lenin&#8217;s tomb was a simple thing &#8212; even now, the Russians treat it with respect. (Although it&#8217;s said Lenin will be buried in St. Petersburg before too long.)<br />
Seeing Mao was interesting, but not so much as all the grandeur surrounding it. People still worship the man (inasmuch as the officially Communist state allows worship), gathering in lines readily, half of whom buy flowers, for a man most never met and even more whom weren&#8217;t even alive during his tenure as Chairman. The legacy lives on&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/in-the-house-of-mao/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">561</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Mongolia</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=adventures-in-mongolia</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2005 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mongolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulaan baatar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/25/adventures-in-mongolia/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.) Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Adventures in Mongolia"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.)<br />
Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up that somehow manages to sway us (which I doubt will happen), then Mongolia will be <em>the</em> thing on the trip. Also without question, we would heartily recommend coming to Mongolia (and soon, before the rest of the world discovers how cool this country is) and signing up with Nomadic Journeys. They take far too good care of you.<br />
<span id="more-550"></span>Our campsite was about 300 km west of Ulaan Baatar &#8212; a trip that takes six hours. Most of the roads in Mongolia were built back in the 1950s by the Russians and Chinese &#8230; and haven&#8217;t really received any major attention since then. Needless to say, if you&#8217;re not driving something well-built, you don&#8217;t be driving it too long &#8212; the roads will turn them to pulp. We drove in a small Russian-built jeep without seatbelts. Our driver, Lasaa (assuming I&#8217;m spelling his name correctly) is an expert driver, and avoided the majority of the disasters of the road. That meant driving all over the road, including the shoulders.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03595.JPG" alt="The scenery as you drive in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
It&#8217;s an interesting commentary when the dirt roads that sometimes parallel the highway are better than the highway.<br />
When we arrived at our camp (which appeared rather suddenly), we found three gers, tents used by the Mongolian nomadic people. They&#8217;re wood-framed, built in a circle with a sloped conical roof. The entire frame is covered with felt and canvas. They&#8217;re ridiculously comfy, even in the heat we experienced. Amy and I were the only tourists there &#8212; we&#8217;re the first of the season at that location. There were two nomadic families across the valley.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03596.JPG" alt="Our ger camp" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03597.JPG" alt="Just to prove I was there" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03598.JPG" alt="The all-important toilet; which, thankfully, did not stink" width="300" /></a><br />
The first day there was a laid-back one: hiking up the adjacent mountain (Amy to half-way; I couldn&#8217;t resist the surge to the top). Meals were in the middle ger. The second day took us on a hike north through the valley, passing a family of domesticated camels, and through a mountain pass to a small Buddhist temple on the other side (Lasa met us there to drive us back). The temple has but a single nun (not even a monk, so far as we could tell) and a museum curator, who showed us around. There&#8217;s ruins there from a previous building destroyed when the Soviets ran amok through Mongolia in an attempt to stamp out all religion.<br />
To give you an idea of how unspoiled this place is, when we wandered around the ruins, we found fragments of Buddha statues and artwork still in the dirt. That&#8217;s how few tourists have been here. (Even though there is a &#8220;card shop&#8221;.)<br />
After lunch, we visited a small lake featuring kites, ducks (that sounded like frogs), and horses. Beautiful scenery, too. Then it was a visit over to one of the nomadic families to see how they live. Truth be known, they live pretty well. The gers are so comfortable, most nomadic families choose to live in them instead of permanent shelters. It&#8217;s also necessary as many families have to move (up to four times a year) to keep their herds of animals fed and watered. We petted baby sheep and goats. One tried to milk me by banging it head repeatedly into my groin. I mean, honestly, do I look like a goat?? After dinner, Amy and I dragged Ganaa (our guide/translator) up the side of a sand dune to watch a sunset. We were treated to a rather strange spectacle when we returned as the nomadic family tried to get their herd into a small corral for milking time.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03599.JPG" alt="Down by the bay (but no watermelons grow)" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03601.JPG" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03602.JPG" alt="Inside a nomadic ger" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03603.JPG" alt="Sunset on top of a sand dune" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03606.JPG" alt="Our driver, Lasa, with a baby goat" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03607.JPG" alt="Not nearly as noisy as you think it should have been" width="300" /></a><br />
Our third day marked a trip to Kharakorum and Erdene Zuu, the former being the ancient capital of Mongolia, and the latter being the monastery that still operates there. Three hours on bumpy roads. Beatiful buildings, though. Amazing part of it was that we were among the first tourists there that day &#8212; most of those in attendance were there for the ceremony marking the first 15 days of summer, which was the monks chanting the entire day. The fact we could walk around the museum temples unimpeded by a single tourist was &#8230; very zen.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03608.JPG" alt="The temples of Erdene Zuu" width="300" /></a><br />
The weather on the morning of our fourth day was unbelievable. The wind that had started the night before had given rise to rain, blowing sand (you couldn&#8217;t see the dunes &#8212; a mere kilometre away &#8212; for the clouds erupting from them), and eventually snow as we rolled to Hustai National Park, 95 km from Ulaan Baatar.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03610.JPG" alt="Crappy weather on the road" width="300" /></a><br />
Hustai is a preserve that hosts the only wild population of tahki &#8212; the Mongolian wild horse. It was reintroduced here in the early 1990s, and has grown to over 200 horses in 14 small herds. (That, and an insane number of marmots.) It was freezing as we got our glances at a distance, but they were neat to see. We stayed in Ger #7 at the Hustai Tourist &#8220;Resort&#8221;. (About 20 gers, a couple of permanent buildings, and a &#8220;restaurant&#8221; serving food so lacking in flavour, I&#8217;d describe it as a gastronomic vacuum.)<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03611.JPG" alt="The ger camp at Hustai National Park in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
I woke up about 3:00 this morning in a big shivering ball. Our fire had gone out and the temperatures had plunged. Needless to say, I&#8217;m a little tired as a result. Even once I was more bundled up (and I was beginning to think that long underwear wasn&#8217;t a good idea to bring!), my brain ran crazy with ways of trying to rekindle our dead fire. Note to self: always bring matches in the future when going to places that need fires.<br />
We returned to UB today and made a beeline for the Gobi Factory Store. Gobi is the major manufacturer of cashmere goods, at least in Mongolia. I knew of them before coming, but hadn&#8217;t really thought that this was the place. It really was a factory store, too &#8212; the store was attached to the Gobi factory. Prices were decent, although the place was mobbed by some very unruly and rude French tourists.<br />
The real prize, however, was not the completed fabrics. It was cashmere yarn, which Gobi does <strong>not</strong> sell in their stores. And Amy could not leave Mongolia without it. To get it, Ganaa went through the most amazing display of digging that I&#8217;ve ever seen. It took 90 minutes, including walking deep into the Gobi factory to find the yarn storage room to select the spools, but we walked away with 2.3 kilos of it. Amy&#8217;s happy, to say the least. But I&#8217;ll leave that portion of the story to her. It&#8217;s a doozy.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03614.JPG" alt="Cashmere yarn at the Gobi Factory in Ulaan Baatar" width="300" /></a><br />
After that, we visited the Bogd Khaan&#8217;s Summer Palace in the south part of the city. It&#8217;s nice, but poorly maintained. Some of the treasures inside are wonderful, but it wasn&#8217;t worth the 5500T it cost for me to take pictures (even though that&#8217;s only about US$5). After Erdene Zuu, it was hard to look at the Summer Palace and think it was wonderful.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03615.JPG" alt="The gates of the Bogd Khan's Summer Palace" width="300" /></a><br />
And so we leave Mongolia for China. Our plans have changed a bit, there. We&#8217;re hitting only Beijing, Xi&#8217;an, and Guangzhou (only because it&#8217;s right next to Hong Kong, and after the train from Xi&#8217;an, we won&#8217;t be up to crossing the border right away). Then it&#8217;s into the Hong Kong area, first with Macau, then HK proper. Why the cutting back? Too much running in and out of places has made us weary, and after hearing a few too many horror stories, we&#8217;re not sure that we&#8217;re even going to like China that much. But we shall see&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">550</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A little scoot around Ulaan Baatar</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2005 13:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mongolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulaan baatar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/20/a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We arrived early this morning. We were up by 5:00, but only arrived an hour later or so. After a sort-of-nap (couldn&#8217;t sleep), we were picked up by our guide (again; she&#8217;d also taken us to the hotel from the station) and shown around the city. First up was Sukhbaatar Square &#8212; a large open &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A little scoot around Ulaan Baatar"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We arrived early this morning. We were up by 5:00, but only arrived an hour later or so. After a sort-of-nap (couldn&#8217;t sleep), we were picked up by our guide (again; she&#8217;d also taken us to the hotel from the station) and shown around the city.<br />
First up was Sukhbaatar Square &#8212; a large open area in front of the Mongolian Parliment. It&#8217;s sort of like Red Square, but is named after a man who is credited with being the hero of Mongolia, who led the armies who finally pushed China out of &#8220;outer Mongolia&#8221; and declared an independant Mongolia. He died mysteriously (insert obligatory conspiracy theory here) and is buried at the north end of the square in a mausoleum. Unlike Lenin and Mao, however, you can&#8217;t get in to see him.<br />
<span id="more-549"></span><a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03593.JPG" alt="Sukhbaatar Square" width="300" /></a><br />
Then it was over to the Gandantegchinlen Monastery, the largest in Mongolia and also the main one. It&#8217;s relatively old, though a lot of it (like most of the monasteries in Mongolia) were ransacked by the Soviets under the guise of socialism. There&#8217;s an 80-metre statue in the largest building in the complex to replace the one the Soviets stole and melted down into bullets.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03594.JPG" alt="Gandantegchinlen Monastery" width="300" /></a><br />
Then it was off for a cultural presentation of song, dance, and music, including Mongolian throat singing. (I swear I sound like that some mornings!)<br />
Tomorrow, we&#8217;re off for the back country for some &#8220;camping&#8221; (ger camps, though we&#8217;re not sure what to expect). Needless to say, we won&#8217;t be posting for a few days &#8212; I doubt there&#8217;s internet way out there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/a-little-scoot-around-ulaan-baatar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">549</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Da svidanya Rossiya</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/da-svidanya-rossiya/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=da-svidanya-rossiya</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/da-svidanya-rossiya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2005 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulan ude]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/18/da-svidanya-rossiya/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, we&#8217;ve reached the end of our time here in Russia. Tomorrow morning, early, we&#8217;re off to Mongolia. And a 10+ hour border-crossing, so we&#8217;re told. It&#8217;s simultaneously a horror story and a quest of patience, so it seems. After we arrived last night, literally 10 minutes into being in our new hotel room, the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/da-svidanya-rossiya/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Da svidanya Rossiya"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we&#8217;ve reached the end of our time here in Russia. Tomorrow morning, early, we&#8217;re off to Mongolia. And a 10+ hour border-crossing, so we&#8217;re told. It&#8217;s simultaneously a horror story and a quest of patience, so it seems.<br />
After we arrived last night, literally 10 minutes into being in our new hotel room, the phone rang. It was &#8220;Helga from St. Petersburg&#8221;. Being more than just a little out of it, I assumed Helga was our tour operator, and was arranging our tour for tomorrow. She said she would be in the hotel, and we could meet her in the &#8220;cafeteria&#8221; (more like a bar with food). This was great since she had our train tickets to Ulaan Baatar, and would give us the details for our tour to the Datsun &#8212; the Buddhist template near Ulan Ude.<br />
<span id="more-546"></span>We walked into the cafe (as it&#8217;s referred to) about 20 minutes later only to find, much to our deep surprise, Helga &#8212; the woman we&#8217;d met in St. Petersburg whom we&#8217;d tried very desperately to avoid. (Helga had originally asked for all the details of our trip so she could tag along with us, not wanting to do the trip alone. We weren&#8217;t particularly happy about that, since we&#8217;d spent so much time and effort planning to this as a duo &#8212; not a trio.) This was not the surprise I&#8217;d wanted.<br />
Since Helga had some of the information we needed, we opted to talk with her until she left for her homestay, some distance from the Hotel Geser. Why did she have all this information? She ran into the tour guide we were using, and had signed up for the same tour to the Datsun.<br />
The trip out today was quite nice, actually. Ulan Ude is in a steppe valley, which is wide, expansive, and fairly flat. It&#8217;s dominated more by <em>dacha</em> (small cottages). Otherwise, short grasses and free-roaming animals (cows, goats, horses) which are &#8220;owned&#8221; by the local buryat inhabitants. The region we&#8217;re in is named for them: Buryatia. They&#8217;re an offshoot of Mongolian society, who&#8217;ve decided not to be nomadic and settle permanently.<br />
The result of the Mongolian influence in this area brings the Buddhism, which is what we&#8217;d planned to see today. <a href="http://www.stupa.org.nz/stupa/russia.htm">Ivolginsky Datsun</a> dates back only to 1947, when Stalin (of all people!) allowed limited religious practices for recognized minorities, such as the buryats.<br />
On the 30 km drive out to the Datsun, our guide Ilyena (I believe that was her name) attempted to explain the history of Ulan Ude, the general environment around us, and the basics of Buddhism. All of which Helga continually interrupted with questions &#8212; some decent, but mostly inane. And annoying, since Ilyena was continually put off her speech, and found it difficult to continue. Thankfully, Amy and I have a good understanding of Buddhism, and had read much about the area through our guidebooks.<br />
The Datsun itself is quite interesting. Because it was built only a little over a half century ago (and even then, the main temple burned down just before it initially was to open), most of the buildings are reminiscent of Soviet construction: big and stolid. Yet there is still a blending with Buddhist stylings, with all the statuary and stupas one would expect to find. Though here, they&#8217;re made of concrete and not wood or stone. The insides of the temples, though still Buddhist, borrow concepts from Russian churches (such as windows and high ceilings), a result of Russian influences on the Buryats when they tried to settle in the area.<br />
There were few other tourists there than ourselves, so we had a fairly easy time getting around. Although Ivolginsky Datsun is the centre for Russian buddhism, it&#8217;s not heavily visited at all times. There are strong ties here with both Mongolia (which is a very powerful buddhist centre, so I&#8217;ve learned) and, of course, Tibet.<br />
On the way back, we got to ask Ilyena a few questions. Well, to be most specific, Amy and I got to ask a few questions &#8212; Helga wouldn&#8217;t let up. To the point where she was outright challenging Ilyena about the differences between hardships under Soviet rule versus Helga&#8217;s post-war upbringing in the late 1940s &#8211; early 1950s. It was enough for me to bite my tongue &#8212; hard &#8212; and not suggest that Helga put a cork in it. It&#8217;s enough to ask questions, but an entirely different thing to disrespect your hosts by suggesting their troubles in life are trivial.<br />
We finally ditched Helga, and picked up our train tickets for tomorrow, and went off to explore the rest of Ulan Ude. Admittedly, there isn&#8217;t much else to see in this city, save for two museums that aren&#8217;t easy to get to. Across the road from our end-point was a nice opera theatre that looked almost like it had been plucked out from Spain. Next door to that was the Mongolian Embassy.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03587.JPG" alt="Mongolian Embassy in Ulan Ude and the opera house" width="300" /></a><br />
Down the road (to the south) was the GUM department store and market &#8212; of which there wasn&#8217;t much. However, there were <strong>delectable</strong> blinni &#8212; which are crepe-like packages filled with (in our case) cheese and ham. The pedestrian mall took us down to a recently-renovated church, before we walked back towards our hotel, and the world&#8217;s largest Lenin head.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03589.JPG" alt="Big dead Lenin and head and I" width="300" /></a><br />
Why is the world&#8217;s largest Lenin head in Ulan Ude? Got me. I can see it from this computer. It&#8217;s <em>HUGE</em>. It&#8217;s at least two storeys tall. The body, if there were one, would tower over Ulan Ude. Vlad-zilla!<br />
We&#8217;re preparing for tomorrow&#8217;s trip. Not just with supplies (food and water), but also mentally. Mongolians like to smuggle things across the border, and we need to be prepared for the possibility that they might try to muscle their way into our compartment &#8212; which we bought all the seats in to prevent us getting caught with smugglers.<br />
Either way, the next time you hear from us, we&#8217;ll be in another country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/da-svidanya-rossiya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">546</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kamakura</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kamakura</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 23:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/07/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We were up a little earlier than the previous few days, so we could catch a good train out to Kamakura, our excursion for the day. Kamakura is a small town south of Tokyo, about an hour and three-quarters away from Yotsukaido. From 1192 to 1333, Kamakura was the feudal capital of Japan. There are &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kamakura"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were up a little earlier than the previous few days, so we could catch a good train out to Kamakura, our excursion for the day.<br />
Kamakura is a small town south of Tokyo, about an hour and three-quarters away from Yotsukaido. From 1192 to 1333, Kamakura was the feudal capital of Japan. There are no signs of its previous governmental past today, but the marks of its present status as a religious centre are very clear. The area is peppered with no less than 84 shrines and temples. Less than Kyoto, but Kamakura is a much smaller area.<br />
<span id="more-345"></span>We had outstanding timing this morning, arriving at the Yotsukaido station mere moments before the train to Zushi arrived. The Zushi train comes only once an hour. It comes from Narita Airport, and runs the full length of the Sobu / Yokosuka line. Had we not caught the Zushi train, we&#8217;d have had to take a local to Chiba and change there for a Zushi train.<br />
Originally, I thought we&#8217;d have to change trains at Zushi and take a local to Kamakura. But as luck would have it, the map I&#8217;d looked at wasn&#8217;t particularly clear, and we could take that train all the way to Kamakura without changing once.<br />
We had to stand all the way into Tokyo before we could sit down for the rest of the trip. Jen snoozed, even I caught a few minutes of additional sleep. We got off at the small station of Kita-Kamakura, which the guide book recommended as the starting point for the walk.<br />
First on the list was the Engakuji Temple. A facinating little walk, the temple was considered second among the five great zen temples of Kamakura. Accented by stands of cherry trees, the grounds even featured a new building under construction. Unfortunately, we couldn&#8217;t get close enough to see what it looked like.<br />
We walked from there down to Kenchoji Temple. First among the five great temples, this was a temple I did on my own. Jen had her fill of temples after the second one, and decided that she wasn&#8217;t visiting any more without good reason. While I was at first very disappointed to hear that, I could certainly understand her perspective. I remember thinking that there were far too many churches and cathedrals when I was in the Soviet Union (see [[Behind the Iron Curtain: My Trip to the Soviet Union, Touring Odessa]]).<br />
The approach to the temple was lined with cherry trees, and the interior was laid out with a zen perfection that we had not seen before. I almost found it quite annoying that I could not wander around a while longer and find more things to see. Such as it was, however, I didn&#8217;t want to keep Jen waiting too long.<br />
I know that Jen was a little tired of all this wandering around small towns, seeing the same shrine over and over again. But the point of travelling is to see the country you&#8217;re in. And that&#8217;s hard to do when you don&#8217;t want to see it. It&#8217;s even more hard when one of you wants to see it, and the other does not. I promised to avoid any more temples unless they were really interesting, until we got to the Great Buddha.<br />
I managed to keep us walking, eventually reaching the main downtown of Kamakura. The main road through downtown has a cherry tree-lined walkway down the middle, dividing the two lanes of traffic. I can only imagine how wonderful it must look like at night.<br />
We arrived at the Kamakura station. There, we took the Enoden Line to Hase, on a small, old single-tracked tram line. This brought us much closer to the Great Buddha, saving us a bit of a walk. Although it is nice to have nice, warm weather, walking around in at least 20 degree weather gets a little uncomfortable after a while.<br />
The walk up to the Kotokuin Temple (home of the Great Buddha) was nice, marked with a few shops and restaurants. Prices for similar items climbed the closer you got to the Buddha, of course. We perused a bit as we climbed.<br />
The Great Buddha was created in 1252 by sculptors Ono-Goroemon and Tanji-Hisatomo. This massive structure was cast in bronze (in several large sections) and housed in a massive temple. In 1498, a massive tsunami reached the heights of Kotokuin temple, destroying the wooden structures but leaving the 13.35 metre-tall, 121 ton structure intact. Since the tsunami, the statue has been exposed directly to the elements.<br />
It is an impressive structure. Despite its massive size (and weight), the statue doesn&#8217;t really look all that large. It&#8217;s an impressive design that takes something so large and make it seem a little more inviting. Its peaceful stance (in the traditional buddha sitting pose) brings on similar feelings in those who visit it. It&#8217;s with no surprise that the Great Buddha is one of the main attractions at Kamakura.<br />
Having taken in the grandeur of the Buddha, we headed back towards the Hase tram station to return to Kamakura station. But instead of taking the tram, we opted to walk the 1.7 km (this was Jen&#8217;s suggestion, not mine). We had half-thought that we might be able to find something to eat along the way. Much to our surprise, most of the stores and restaurants appeared to be closed. It seemed completely contrary to normal logic for a tourist-rich location.<br />
Finally, we reached a short pedestrian mall that led us down to the Kamakura JR station. After getting a quick snack at a food stand of sorts, we caught the first Narita Airport-bound train. That would take us all the way back to Yotsukaido without having to change trains.<br />
We left Kamakura at 15:18, and arrived in Yotsukaido at 17:00. That left us plenty of time to hit the toy store near the station. We&#8217;d gone in very briefly last night before coming home, but had to leave early because the store was closing. This time, we had plenty of time to peruse.<br />
Perhaps too much time. As we came out of the store, the bus we needed to catch pulled away. And following with the completely inconsistent nature of the bus schedule, the next wouldn&#8217;t appear for almost an hour and a half.<br />
So we walked back to the apartment.<br />
Mind you, we had no real way of knowing whether or not Kaz was actually home. We had tried to get a hold of her a couple of times, but with no answer, we didn&#8217;t know if she was actually home. As it stands, she had only come home not long before we arrived, as a convenient happenstance. She had been out with her friend, who would be spending the night with us.<br />
Kaz was very kind to make us dinner, flavoured pasta. Kaz and her friend watched a &#8220;Friends&#8221; DVD (a show that I cannot particularly stand) translated in to Japanese. I sat and wrote my journals, while Jen watched, waiting until she could get access to the Playstation to continue playing &#8220;Devil May Cry 2&#8221;.<br />
Finally, just after 23:00, Chris appeared for the first time since Sunday. We won&#8217;t get much time with him today, so hopefully, we&#8217;ll make the most of it now, so we can have some time before we leave for home.<br />
[flickr]tag:kamakura+april+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kamakura/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">345</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (still)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2004 23:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/06/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The alarm went off early. Earlier than usual, anyway. Jen was still sleeping, so I thought I&#8217;d let her sleep a bit longer. But at 9:00, I got her going. Unforunately, Jen started off with a killer headache, so she didn&#8217;t move very quickly. Compound to that a very irregular bus schedule and not being &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (still)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The alarm went off early. Earlier than usual, anyway. Jen was still sleeping, so I thought I&#8217;d let her sleep a bit longer. But at 9:00, I got her going.<br />
Unforunately, Jen started off with a killer headache, so she didn&#8217;t move very quickly. Compound to that a very irregular bus schedule and not being able to catch a limited express to Tokyo wound up pretty much killing the point of today&#8217;s journey &#8212; going to Nikko.<br />
<span id="more-344"></span>Nikko is about 50 minutes north of Tokyo by shinkansen. We neeed to get to Nikko in enough time to look around, and still get back at a reasonable hour. Problem: the first shinkansen was at 13:16, which would get us to Nikko (including the time on the local train) at almost 15:00, far too late to be useful for us.<br />
Instead, I thought a different plan might be in order: a tour of Tokyo. So off on the Yamanote line to Hammamatsucho to catch one of the Hato Bus tours. This is the same thing Chris and I did last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Tsukiji Fish Market]]), and I thought that the commentary might be better for Jen than me trying to explain things as we either walked too much or whizzed by on the train (on which Jen loves to sleep).<br />
Initially, Jen wasn&#8217;t too keen on doing it, but with a little encouragement (and me paying the fare), things were arranged. I am slowly starting to have issues with motivation. Jen really wanted to come to Japan, but in the last few days, I&#8217;m having trouble getting her to want to go out and do things. Sometimes, I think all she wants to do is sit back and play video games at Chris and Kaz&#8217;s. And I really hate having to say things like: &#8220;you didn&#8217;t come to Japan to play video games&#8221;. I&#8217;m hoping this is just because of Jen&#8217;s headache today.<br />
The bus tour was the same as the one we&#8217;d taken last year, starting off at the World Trade Center, then out to the Imperial Palace (via the Ginza district), out through Akehabara to Asakusa Kannon Temple, and then a boat cruise down the Sumida River. I think the order is different than last year, and the stop at the Imperial Palace was different.<br />
Also different were the guides. The guide for our bus was missing at the time the tour started, so one of the guides had to take our group in addition to his. The way this guy talked reminded me of Mr. Chen from &#8220;Big Trouble in Little China&#8221; with his odd humour and speaking manner.<br />
Tokyo was hazy again, so we couldn&#8217;t see too far. No chance of seeing Mt. Fuji from the top. Soon, we were back down at the bottom and on our way to the bus. There we met our tour guide, Rika.<br />
Rika knew English quite well, but had an odd speaking manner. Unlike most people speaking English, Rika&#8217;s annunciation sounded like the earlier generations of computer synthesized speech: choppy construction, inflection in the wrong parts of the speech, and the odd bit of mispronounciation. Otherwise, her English was inpeccable. (Except when she tried to tell us that people hang out their clothes to &#8220;disinfect&#8221; rather than &#8220;dry&#8221;.)<br />
The tour was busy. There were at least five groups running through at the time, including ours. One particular group appeared to be school kids from the United States. We weren&#8217;t sure if they were there on some kind of field trip or on an exchange. They were a bit annoying. Like how gnats are annoying. Luckily, they weren&#8217;t with us.<br />
Our bus was thankfully light on the load, and all adults. We had a multicultural group, with people from the United States (both coasts), Switzerland, Sweden, Argentina, Mexico, and Peru.<br />
We stopped at a different part of the Imperial Palace Plaza than last year, which was the uninteresting part. The double bridge entrance has more to see, the side next to the East Gardens is kinda dull.<br />
Off to Asakusa and the Nakamise shopping arcade. Last year, this wasn&#8217;t a huge issue. This year, I think every tour bus in Tokyo had delivered people there, in addition to the countless regular tourists. &#8220;Crowded&#8221; is an understatement.<br />
Trying to follow Rika proved to be a problem, not just because she was shorter than the average crowd height, but trying to get through the throngs of people proved to be a challenge. Even having to elbow our way through everyone, we finally arrived at the temple mostly intact as a group. Everyone else who didn&#8217;t join the group were out in the shopping arcade.<br />
Rika gave us the quick tour of the temple, how it was built and how it worked. Then we were cast to the winds for 25 minutes, at which time we needed to be at the boat dock. Jen and I started down towards the arcade, but just barely outside of the actual temple grounds, we were sidetracked by the smell of fried noodles and chicken yakatori. Both of us were hungry enough that we sat down for a quick meal.<br />
Then it was a quick walk down the arcade, bypassing all the stores, almost running the last little bit to the boat dock. The boat trip down the Sumida River was the same one we did last year, so there really wasn&#8217;t much new for me. The fact that the cruise was also full of people certainly didn&#8217;t make the cruise particularly exciting. We just enjoyed a lazy trip down the river, periodically taking a bit of chop as a result of the incoming tide.<br />
We arrived at the Himeda Pier, hopped the bus, and headed back to Hammamatsucho. Once there, Jen and I headed back to Tokyo and then onto Chiba. Along the way, Kaz and I exchanged messages, discussing possibilities for dinner. Chris was still at work, we wouldn&#8217;t see him again for a while, so it was just us for a while.<br />
We tried to get on an NEX at Tokyo, but without success. Although our passes supposedly work on the NEX, we couldn&#8217;t get on the train because there didn&#8217;t seem to be any cars with unreserved seats. We got on a regular rapid train instead.<br />
We met up with Kaz at Chiba station, and headed off in search of the 100 Yen store, just above Yodobashi Camera. Jen had thought of finding some things there to take back for friends and family. But Jen disappeared almost as soon as I rounded a corner. I found her in the toy store next to the 100 yen plaza.<br />
She&#8217;d found a hoodie (sweatshirt with a hood) for Full Metal Alchemist. To say she was excited was putting it mildly. So excited that I actually couldn&#8217;t resist buying it for her. Mostly because she couldn&#8217;t afford to buy it for herself.<br />
Purchases in hand, we headed off in search of dinner, specifically sushi. It didn&#8217;t take much to direct them to the sushi restaurant under the railway tracks. Yep &#8212; the same one I went to the first night I was in Japan a year ago. The three of us picked off what we wanted as it came around on the conveyor, supplementing with a couple of ordered items, such as shrimp tempura, singed salmon, and Jen had a huge bowl of miso soup.<br />
Completely full, we rolled out and headed back to Yotsukaido. It turns out Chris was unable to join us tonight &#8212; he&#8217;s back at his old place packing up the remainder of his things. Hopefully, we&#8217;ll see him tomorrow night.<br />
[flickr]tag:japan+tokyo+april+2004+&#8221;6&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:japan+chiba+april+2004+&#8221;6&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Nishi Honganji Temple</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2004 23:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/01/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we experienced what can only be the most terrifying thing I&#8217;ve ever experienced. The earthquake hit around 7:30, and shook the entire room. Jen and I leapt from bed, and I dragged her into one of the doorways &#8212; supposedly the safest place to be during an earthquake. The rumbling continued for a good &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Nishi Honganji Temple"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, we experienced what can only be the most terrifying thing I&#8217;ve ever experienced. The earthquake hit around 7:30, and shook the entire room. Jen and I leapt from bed, and I dragged her into one of the doorways &#8212; supposedly the safest place to be during an earthquake. The rumbling continued for a good 30 seconds (not that I was timing, but it was certainly a long shake) before things settled down a bit. I don&#8217;t know how often Kyoto gets an earthquake, but apparently even our modest little ryokan can handle the stress.<br />
April fool! Had you going, didn&#8217;t I? No, there wasn&#8217;t an earthquake. Quite the opposite, actually. It would have taken an earthquake to get Jen out of bed.<br />
<span id="more-339"></span>Breakfast showed up at the regular time, which was still far too early for Jen. She was quite tired with the events of the last couple of days, and certainly with all the hiking we did yesterday. Add to that the prospect of fish, tofu, and non-western foods for the first meal of the day really didn&#8217;t jump start her any. Still she did her best to try and eat the things put before her.<br />
However, Jen was so tired that she practically begged to go back to sleep. I remembered (if only vaguely) what it was like to be 15, travelling abroad, and always being tired (see [[Behind the Iron Curtain: My Trip to the Soviet Union, Touring Odessa]]). So I let her go back to sleep, and took the opportunity to go wandering to yet more temples, specifically the Higashi Honganji Shrine, located about two blocks north of the JR Kyoto Station.<br />
I walked from the hotel, partly to kill time, but also so I could see what else was on the way down from the hotel. It&#8217;s a bit of a hike, and I wasn&#8217;t in any huge rush. There wasn&#8217;t much to see, outside of watching people, so I was content to speed my arrival at the temple.<br />
It&#8217;s an old temple, originally built in 1602 (it&#8217;s a split from the Nishi Honganji temple, which is about a kilometre to the west). The temple was rebuilt in 1895, during the Meiji Reformation, and those buildings are the ones we see today. Among the massive structures is the largest single wooden structure in the world, the Founder&#8217;s Hall. It&#8217;s size is hard to put into words, other than &#8220;massive&#8221;. The amount of time, effort, skill, and lives it took to build something of this size is just mind-boggling. The details are intricate, and the layout gorgeous. I just wish I could have seen a service here.<br />
Continuing south, I arrived at the JR Kyoto Station. I took a quick detour over to the Kyoto Central Post Office, partly so I could mail some postcards home, but also so I could get some more money from my bank account. I love the post office in Japan &#8212; it just makes so much sense.<br />
The JR Kyoto Station building is immense. It&#8217;s really hard to understand just how large this thing is until you&#8217;re standing in it. The main area is a concourse for passengers and some shops. A few restaurants and food stands are in a space on the second level, set towards the northern end of the main area. From the main floor all the way up to the ceiling (about 11 floors up) is open space. Huge amounts of open space. It&#8217;s enough to make an agoraphobic freak out.<br />
I snapped pictures from the south side of the main space, riding up several flights of the escalator to get the right angle. At the top, I took the Sky Walk (a bridge running under the ceiling out to the north side of the main space). I could feel my knees beginning to quake as I reached the top of the esclator (I have a mild fear of unsafe heights that I regularly try to challenge). But the Sky Walk is so strongly built that there is no real way to see how far down it is.<br />
Finally prying myself away from the architecture of the station building, I returned to awaken Jen from her slumber. Awake barely 20 minutes, I had timed my return quite well. It was time for the adventure of the day: Mt. Hiei.<br />
The northeast corner of Kyoto has been known as the &#8220;Devil&#8217;s Gate&#8221;, a fear that it would let in demons to destroy the city. The gate is guarded, however, by Enryaku-ji, a temple that at its height had over 3,000 buildings and spanned the entire mountain area. Today, it&#8217;s a little smaller, but is so important to Bhuddism in Japan (the temple area is regarded as the Mother of all Japanese Bhuddism) that it is now a UNESCO World Cultural Asset.<br />
This is what Jen and I wanted to see (although when we left this morning, we thought there was an actual &#8220;Demon Gate&#8221;, as we&#8217;d misunderstood the text in the travel guide), and set out to find it.<br />
The first step was to take a subway to the Kaisan Sanjo station, where we switched to the Kaisan Railway. Reaching the end of that line, we then switched to the Eizan Railway, and took a single-car train to Yase-Yuen, at the base of Mt. Hiei, a picturesque little area. Then it was onto a cable car, a single-car train pulled up by a cable, and finally a rope-way &#8212; what North Americans would call a cable car &#8212; to the top of the mountain.<br />
This was when we had our first bout of confusion. The ticket machine bore no English instructions, and the staff were unable to help. A sign on the wall seemed to indicate that for 1,640 yen, we could get round-trip tickets up on the cable car and ropeway. But for 1,700 yen, we&#8217;d get something else. But it was the something else I couldn&#8217;t understand. Figuring that it was something we&#8217;d probably need, we got the extra value package.<br />
The cable car departed 15 minutes later. It&#8217;s an odd vehicle, clearly for use on mountains. The grade is at least 15%, if not much more, and requires a vehicle built such that the floor is stepped, like bleachers, as it runs up the curves on the side of the mountain. The single track bulges only right at the middle of the run, when the two cars pass one another (one up, one down), strung together like the counterweights on a grandfather clock.<br />
At the top of the cable car, we switched to the ropeway, transportation I&#8217;m more familiar with. Another five minutes, and we were at the top. We were so glad we&#8217;d decided not to hike the trail.<br />
At the top, we walked around the Mt. Hiei Gardens, which we weren&#8217;t too particuarly interested in. We passed by a sign leading us to Enryaku-ji, but didn&#8217;t realize at first that was what we were looking for. (Doh.) Instead, we ended up at the north entrance to the Gardens.<br />
We figured out that our extra value package included access to the gardens. We felt it best to give it a whirl and see what we could find. Unfortunately, we were far too early in the season (Mt. Hiei can get quite cold &#8212; there&#8217;s even a (really lame) ski hill up there) for the gardens &#8212; there were only just beginning to flower.<br />
The view from the top of the mountain is amazing. You can see Kyoto (despite all the haze) and Otsu, a largish city that sits on the eastern side of Mt. Hiei, on the shores of a large lake. But otherwise, there wasn&#8217;t much up there worth looking at.<br />
Jen decided we needed to take a bus to get to what we wanted to find. When one finally showed up, we hopped on, and almost by fluke, ended up at the To-Do (or East Area) of Enryaku-ji. After paying the modest fee (assumedly to help maintain the grounds and provide for the monks who live and work there), we entered to take a look.<br />
Unlike the other shrines we&#8217;d seen over the last couple of days, To-Do was almost completely deserted of tourists. It was gloriously delightful. And a bit chilly. When we&#8217;d left downtown Kyoto, it was almost 19 degrees. It was barely 10 on the mountaintop, and with the breeze, Jen was a bit cold. I was lucky enough to have long sleeves, but it wasn&#8217;t helping much.<br />
We toured the complex, looking at the Dai Ko-Do, the Konpon Chu-Do (the Centra Main Hall, originally built in 788), and the Monju-ro. But by that time, Jen was heading towards hypothermia, and even I was a little too chilly for comfort. We decided to head home.<br />
As we were mostly on the &#8220;other side&#8221; of the mountain, we thought we&#8217;d take the cable car on that side down to the bottom, a but to the JR Otsu Station, the train back to Kyoto, and then subway back home. This proved a little more difficult when we thought more about cost (the travel portion of this day pretty much blew the bank on our regular travel patterns) and convenience. So we thought about the bus.<br />
We hiked almost a kilometre trying to figure out our travel options. The bus was the next, and almost last, choice. We were so cold and tired that we were willing to take the next bus, no matter where it went. As it stands, back up to the top of the mountain. This wasn&#8217;t so bad, as we could then use the rest of our round-trip ticket to get back down the mountain, and then take the reverse route back to our hotel.<br />
We rested only long enough to prepare for our next shot out. Again, back to Teramachi to find a sweatshirt Jen has seen last night, but hadn&#8217;t purchased at the time. When we got there, we were dismayed to find out that the store was sold out. We would spend another half-hour trying to find it at any other stores. Jen would end up settling for a t-shirt.<br />
Dinner was much needed, so we wanted towards the river area, and found a restaurant called Katsukura. It looked interesting because it looked like it had breaded pork, and because it offered something we hadn&#8217;t seen anywhere else: English menus.<br />
(Okay, yes, there is a certain appeal t having to negotiate with your server to try and get something you might like to eat. I actually find that a lot of fun. But after last night&#8217;s rather disappointing tempura, I felt it better to make sure we were going to get something good.)<br />
Katsukura&#8217;s speciality is pork, in various preparations (but usually breaded). Dinner there usually consists of pork, rice, miso soup, pickles (although we didn&#8217;t get any), and oolong tea. Simple, yet tasty. Really tasty. Really, really, really tasty. Katsukura cooks a mean pork cutlet, I have to say, and their prawns are over eight inches in length. The sauces they provide for dipping really accentuate the flavours.<br />
Wrapping up dinner, we patrolled the arcades again (third night in a row) for anything new. Jen attempted to win a prize with one of the games, but unfortunately had to give up after she ran out of coins.<br />
We returned to the hotel, deciding that we both needed to relax for the night. It&#8217;s been a long couple of days, and with all the fresh mountain air, we could use the chance to rest.<br />
Tomorrow: Osaka.<br />
[flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+april+2004+&#8221;1&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-nishi-honganji-temple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">339</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Kiyomizu Temple</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2004 23:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/31/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was up long before I&#8217;d planned to be up. I&#8217;d wanted to try and sleep a bit more to get rest for the long day of walking ahead, but my body said it was time to rise, and so it did. Besides, the racket of Kyoto on the move outside the window pretty much &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Kyoto Kiyomizu Temple"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was up long before I&#8217;d planned to be up. I&#8217;d wanted to try and sleep a bit more to get rest for the long day of walking ahead, but my body said it was time to rise, and so it did.<br />
Besides, the racket of Kyoto on the move outside the window pretty much precluded any additional sleep.<br />
<span id="more-338"></span>I took a much needed shower and changed into something a little more comfortable. As Jen took her turn to use the bathroom, our breakfast showed up. Like last night (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto]]), we had a dish that we cooked at our tables (short, personal-sized platforms for our eating enjoyment). Unlike the luscious duck of last night, this morning featured three large cubes of unflavoured tofu.<br />
Oh joy.<br />
Tofu is not really one of those foods I particularly enjoy on its own. It&#8217;s bland and the texture is not particularly appealing. Fortunately, that was offset by the other foods, including sweet scrambled egg, pickles, some potatoey thing, rice, and my personal favourite, miso soup (a *good* use of tofu).<br />
Jen had some difficulties eating her breakfast. But she did a far better job than I ever did at her age.<br />
Bags in hand, we went off in search of our daily adventure. Today, it was shrines, specifically the Higashiyama area on the eastern side of Kyoto. The walk, about six or seven kilometres long, takes you to several of the most popular shrines in the city. It&#8217;s not within walking distance from the ryokan, so we had to take a subway part of the way.<br />
We got off at Gojo station on the Karasuma line (about a kilometre down from the hotel), and walked over to Higashiyama-ku, the area of the city we were going to be exploring. The walk took about 20 minutes. We walked until Gojo St. (Gojo-dori) effectively ended at what turned out to be Nishi-Otani Mausoleum, a rather interesting, albeit somewhat quiet, little place. Realizing this wasn&#8217;t the start of the walk, we exited and suddenly found ourselves in the middle of a massive graveyard.<br />
A pathway wound us through the cemetary, eventually bringing us out at the exit to the Kiyomizu Temple. This was the start of our excursion. Walking up a large flight of stairs through a massive temple gate, we found ourselves at the admissions booth (it seems all the shrines have an entrance fee, presumably to offset the costs of maintenance), and entered the complex.<br />
Kiyomizu is one of the most beloved temples in all of Japan. This is mostly due to one of the bodhisattvas(images of Bhudda) that is enshrined here. It attracts huge numbers of people, even during the middle of the week. (There are many large parking lots for bus tours, assumedly solely for the purpose of bringing people to this area.)<br />
We walked around the grounds (the entrance and exit are situated along a path that takes you through the temple grounds so you can experience most of the site), and came back out almost exactly where we&#8217;d come in from the cemetary path. From there, it was down into Teapot Lane, the main path from the central road arteries to the temple.<br />
Teapot Lane is so named for the countless stores that sell, well, teapots. And tea cups, and sake cups, and fans, and curios of almost all types. We found a replacement mug for Jen (having lost hers the day before in a taxi mishap), and a new handkerchief with Hello Kitty. I almost bought a dozen gorgeous teacup sets, each time reminding myself that I don&#8217;t have that much money to play with (although the thought was very tempting).<br />
We found a gift for Nana in one of the stores. Mike and Brenda had told us to find something very nice for Nana that she could put on her wall. It&#8217;s a Japanese fan, hand-painted, and mounted in a wooden frame with a glass cover. To make sure it was good, I fired a note off to Brenda (it was about 20:00 Calgary time) through my keitai (Japanese cell phone that also does email). About 20 minutes later, I had my response: go for it.<br />
I love modern technology. I just wish we could have phones (and services) just as good as the ones here back in Canada.<br />
We wandered down Teapot Lane until we reached the turn for the alley towards the next temple. By this point, however, we needed lunch, so continued a little further. Finding a small noodle shop that offered tempura udon, we broke for a meal, followed by a dessert of gelato and fresh cream wrapped in a soft tortilla-like cone. Very tasty, though very fattening, I&#8217;m sure.<br />
Returning to the alley, we headed off in search of the Ryozen Kannon Temple. Due to a somewhat vague map, ended up at the Yasaka Pagoda by mistake. Luckily, someone had enough foresight to put up maps to help out misguided tourists such as ourselves. The signs might be only in Japanese, but the pictures are universal.<br />
By the time we reached Maruyama Park (a wonderful public space filled full of cherry trees), I heard a lot of &#8220;are we there yet&#8221; from Jen. I could hardly blame her &#8212; even my feet were beginning to hurt a bit, but I really wanted to see the shrines. Over the next three days, we have to do the Imperial Palace (and hopefully, a couple of other shrines), Mt. Hiei, and Osaka. So I&#8217;m trying to cram in as much as possible, given the circumstances.<br />
We breezed through Maruyama Park, to find ourselves at the gates to Chion-in Temple, a rather impressive structure with huge stone steps that lead up the side of the hill. Getting up was a workout onto itself. Getting down was another challenge. Most people were taking one step at a time. Jen nearly ran down them, almost reminding me of Sen&#8217;s accidental running down of the stairs in Hiraro Miyazaki&#8217;s &#8220;Spirited Away&#8221;, only with a little more control.<br />
Jen said it was all about how you ran down. Apparently, one of her basketball tryouts at school had a competition to run down stairs as fast as you could, something Jen did particularly well. She claimed that running down was the hard part &#8212; it was the easiest time to trip. Going up stairs is easy.<br />
As if the gods had heard Jen&#8217;s little challenge themselves, she suddenly slipped jogging up a short flight of steps on our way out, slamming the top of her shin (just below the knee) into one of the stone steps. We both had a good laugh at Jen&#8217;s misfortune, mostly because of the timing.<br />
Little did we know, however, that Jen&#8217;s injury was more than a simple bruise. When we stopped briefly at Shoren-in Temple (the next temple along the walk), Jen realized that she had cut herself, and was bleeding (thankfully, not too badly). This is not unknown to Jen, who has several scars of various interesting origins all over her body. It seems that being accident-prone runs on the Tisdale side of the family.<br />
We arrived at the Heian Shrine area, much to Jen&#8217;s delight. We took a short break to watch a baseball team practice amongst themselves before we went into the shrine area. Admittledly, I&#8217;ve seen better. The shrine at Narita (see [[My Trip to Japan, Daihonzan Naritasan Shinshoji Temple]]) comes immediately to mind as a good example.<br />
Nevertheless, we (or rather, I) took pictures of the courtyard. The shrine buildings are scaled-down versions of the first Imperial Palace built in 794 AD (though the shrine was built in 1895). Although very nice-looking, aren&#8217;t particularly special. We (or rather, I encouraged Jen to join me as I) entered the shrine&#8217;s gardens for a look-see.<br />
Listed as being &#8220;outstanding&#8221;, I expected a bit from the gardens. I was less than impressed with the layout, the rear, between the shrine&#8217;s rear wall and the outer wall, was almost non-existant, and while the east side was quite nice, it was a far cry from the Hama-Rikyu Gardens I saw in Tokyo last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park]]).<br />
We headed back to the entrance to the Heian area, expecting to take the #5 bus to Kyoto Station. But due to a lack of instructions (or clarity at the bus stop), I thought it better to take the subway. Our feet were sore, but the distance short. We quickly got our tickets (accidentally leaving behind a half-finished bottle of Coke), and headed to Kyoto Station.<br />
The reason for going there was to check out a manga store (&#8220;manga&#8221; refers to serial Japanese comics and all the associated toys and cartoon shows/movies) that we thought to exist there. Turns out, however, that the manga store was in fact a shop dedicated to Tezuka Productions, the company that creates Mighty Atom (known as &#8220;Astroboy&#8221; in North America). Jen was a little disappointed in the result.<br />
We tried, instead, to hit the Yen Shop across from the station, thinking that it was a 100 Yen Shop, the Japanese equivalent of a dollar store. It wasn&#8217;t. So we thought to try a comic store also in the building. It was a library, not a store. A comic *library*? Only in Japan&#8230;<br />
We arrived back at the hotel to take a bit of a break and rest up a bit. Jen needed a shower, and I was pretty tired, myself. We lazed around the room for a while before deciding that a run back over to the Tenamachi area was in order, as was a run out to dinner.<br />
Stopping at the front desk to drop off the key, the clerk we were getting to know fairly well (he used to live in Vancouver) suggested we go to a restaurant called &#8220;Uneme&#8221;, not far from the hotel. We were hungry, but were interested in first hitting the clothing stores and comic book shops on Tenamachi Road.<br />
Comics in hand (clothing stores will have to wait), we found Uneme, right where the clerk said it would be. While not the most outrageously good food I&#8217;ve ever had, it was interesting. The meal included an appetizer of gobo (shredded carrot, beef, and a Japanese root combined with soy sauce and sugar) and fish eggs (not my favourite thing on their own), followed my grilled meats and vegetables on a skewer. Jen then had tempura, and I had sashimi.<br />
And more sake. For both of us. This is something that, admittedly, concerns me a bit. Jen&#8217;s developed a taste for this stuff. In itself, I&#8217;m not worried. Jen seems to have a great deal of control (she doesn&#8217;t like having too much), and the alcohol doesn&#8217;t have a lot of effect. Still, I wonder how badly Aunt Brenda&#8217;s going to give me heck when we get back.<br />
Back to Tenamachi. (Seeing a pattern here?) Most of the stores were closed by now, so there wasn&#8217;t much for us to do except video games. Then it was back to the hote, first stopping at the Lawson&#8217;s for snacks.<br />
But now it is time for rest. It&#8217;s been a long day&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+march+2004+&#8221;31&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-kyoto-kiyomizu-temple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">338</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 22:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiroshima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miyajima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/29/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.) It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.)<br />
It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. Twenty-four degrees is just uncomfortable. We rose, repacked our bags, and prepared for the trip to Hiroshima. Neither of us were particularly hungry, so would skip breakfast. Chris called to inform us of the paper shinkansen schedule, which we&#8217;d found out about the night before.<br />
<span id="more-336"></span>One thing the schedule had shown was the difference in shinkansen trains.There are three different types running between Tokyo and Hakata: Kodama, Hikaru, and Nozomi. Kodama shinkansen are local trains, hitting every station on their runs. Hikaru shinkansen are limited, hitting only some of the stations. Nozomi shinkansen are express, and run between only a few stations. Nozomi trains are the only ones that will run all the way from Tokyo to Hakata. The others terminate roughly half-way.<br />
We came to Toyohashi on a Kodama, but we left on a Hikaru. (We can&#8217;t take a Nozomi, as the rail pass doesn&#8217;t cover those trains.) It took us to Shin-Osaka, where we switched to another Hikaru that took us to Hiroshima.<br />
Getting a seat on the shinkansen wasn&#8217;t as easy as I&#8217;d hoped. I figured that when we got to Shin-Osaka, getting prime seats on the next Hiraku would be as simple as being the first in line. Except that when we got to Track 20 (no, there aren&#8217;t 20 shinkansen tracks &#8212; the track we were on just happened to be the last in the series of all tracks at the station), the lines were already quite full. Luckily, we still got good seats, although we were quite crammed in with our backpacks and day bags.<br />
It&#8217;s odd. On weekends, getting a seat is surprisingly easy on long-distance trains, when you&#8217;d figure most people would be travelling. But during the week, the seats are packed to the point of standing-room only, when people would normally not be travelling. This is an odd country&#8230;<br />
Jen slept most of the way between Toyohashi and Shin-Osaka, and between Shin-Osaka and Hiroshima. I did, too, opting for some much-needed rest. The last couple of days had taken their toll on me, and a short nap was much welcomed. Although I haven&#8217;t been here long, I&#8217;m already adapting to the Japanese way of riding the trains &#8212; fall asleep just enough to rest, but not enough that you don&#8217;t hear the call for the next station.<br />
Disembarking at Hiroshima, we went in search of lockers. The idea was to ditch our bags and lug around only our day bags. Sadly, the only lockers we could find weren&#8217;t large enough to store the big bags, so we were forced to continue with those. Instead, we put away some of the stuff we didn&#8217;t want to carry.<br />
Once outside, we found streetcars that would take us to the Atomic Bomb Dome. This is one of the major tourist spots of Japan, and is so well-featured that many signs bear the name. Even signs at the streetcar made it clear that you could take the streetcar to the Hiroshima Bomb Dome for 150 yen. It was almost too easy.<br />
Easy enough for us to realize that either we left our bags at the station, went to the dome, and then came back before going to Miyajima, or we took our bags with us, and then continued on the streetcar to the Miyajima ferry. We oped for the latter.<br />
The streetcar ride down was easy, requiring little more than to obtain a ticket, and wait for the station to appear. Once I realized that there was a digtal sign that read off station names in English, it was impossible to miss the dome. That, and the station stop is barely 100 metres from it. Very hard to miss.<br />
The Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome is the former Hiroshima Prefecture Industry Promotion Hall, barely 100 metres from the hypocentre of the blast. It has come to symbolize the destructive power of the atomic bomb, and is a constant reminder of what happened at 8:15, 6 August 1945.<br />
It was a strange moment for me. I&#8217;ve read all about the atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima. I&#8217;ve read about the reasons for and against it. I&#8217;ve heard the debates and listened to the stories. It&#8217;s something to have a perspective on the event, but it&#8217;s entirely another to witness the actual building &#8212; or what&#8217;s left of it. Aside from excavations following its destruction, and some preservation work to keep it intact, the dome remains untouched from when it was destroyed nearly 60 years ago.<br />
As Jen and I walked taking photos, a little elderly woman came up to her and flashed a small sign that read: &#8220;Would you like to receive prayers for happiness?&#8221; I didn&#8217;t know this at first, because all I found was this tiny woman holding her hand up towards Jen&#8217;s bowed head. A little confused for a moment, another elderly woman came up to me and flashed a similar sign. Jen and I were blessed, in a way, to allow us to have a much happier day.<br />
Taking a photo of the two women, they directed us to the Peace Memorial Park, surrounded by the Ota-gawa River, the shores lined with sakura &#8212; cherry trees just entering full bloom. We could hardly pass that up.<br />
On the other side, we found more monuments to the tragedy of the a-bomb attack. One was a peace bell, the supports built of concrete, from which was suspended a traditional shinto bell. The chain used for the bell&#8217;s clapper had a metal origami crane. This is significant because next to the bell are several transparent plastic observation booths filled with hundreds of thousands of paper cranes, offered in peaceful remembrance of 6 August.<br />
Further into the park is the eternal flame, near the Peach Arch. Looking through the Peace Arch towards the flame, you can see directly to the dome. The Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum is past the Peace Arch, but we didn&#8217;t go there. Instead, I followed Jen over to something she saw off to one side. It was a concrete wall, inside of which looked like a clock surrounded by a bed of broken bricks.<br />
It was the top of the Hiroshima National Peace Memorial Hall for the Atomic Bomb Victims. The clock is a skylight into the middle of musem, and is fixed at the time of detonation, 8:15. The bricks were excavated from the Atomic Bomb Dome.<br />
Deciding that it might be an interesting thing to see (and because it was free), we headed down into the entrance. (The museum is underground.) Inside, we were handed English pamphlets, and directed down the walkway, which spirals further down into the earth. Every 20 feet or so, there is a glass panel with text about World War II and the atomic bomb and its affects on Hiroshima.<br />
The perspective is interesting. This should be the Japanese perspective. This is their view of (what is basically) an attack of unwarranted scale. But they&#8217;re not accusatory, not disdainful. The presentation is factual, and appeals to visitors to campaign against the use of nuclear weapons.<br />
At the bottom, you enter a huge round room. At the top is the skylight you see at ground level. Directly under the skylight is a fountain, also in the shape of the 8:15 clock. The water is offered as a consolation to all those who died begging for a drink. On the walls are the names of the neighbourhoods destroyed by the bomb, their proximity to the floor indicating how close they were to the hypocentre. Around the upper third of the room is a 360 panoramic view of the destroyed Hiroshima, as seen from the hypocentre, recreated with 140,000 hand-carved tiles. One tile for each person who died.<br />
Leaving the room, you come to a display of some of the victims. Each of the pamphlets accesses one of 9,606 photographs of a victim through a computer. Mine accessed the record of a 48 year-old woman by the name of Masayo Kubota. Suddenly, it wasn&#8217;t just a piece of paper. This was a real person.<br />
Sobered quite a lot by the museum, it was quite strange to come to the surface to be confronted by the sounds of a bustling metropolis (Hiroshima is quite large), the laughs of playing children, and the chatter of a people who most likely don&#8217;t think about the events of 6 August on a regular basis.<br />
Stopping briefly at the Tourist Information Office for a map and a drink (green tea slushie, anyone?), we continued back to the streetcar station to head down to Miyajimaguchi station, to catch the ferry to Miyajima.<br />
A note for anyone going from Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome to Miyajima. As soon as you can switch to the JR Sanyo line, do so. The trip by streetcar, although nice, is very long.<br />
At Miyajimaguchi station, I called the ryokan in Miyajima to let them know we were catching the next ferry to the island. (They offered a pickup service, and we were to call ahead.) The conversation was a bit difficult due to the language barrier, but the person I was speaking with had obviously taken the trouble to learn enough English to make herself understood.<br />
The ferry trip over was short, only about 10 minutes, and we were soon waiting out in front of the ferry station for our ride to the ryokan. A small white bus appeared in view, and an enthusiastic employee beckoned us to join him for a drive.<br />
The speed limit in Miyajima seems to be about 20 km/h. This guy was doing at least 60 in most places, narrowly missing people and other cars in his mad dash to get to the ryokan to drop us off. The ride, though confusing, was enough to make Jen and I suddenly wish that we didn&#8217;t have to go to Kyoto tomorrow (we have reservations, so don&#8217;t have much of a choice) and stay here a while longer.<br />
Hold on, you&#8217;re probably looking at that &#8220;ryokan&#8221; word and are wondering what that is. We&#8217;re staying at what&#8217;s called a ryokan &#8212; it&#8217;s a type of Japanese hotel. We&#8217;re at the Momijiso ryokan, which sits in the middle of Momijitani Park, up the hill from the town/village of Miyajima. In fact, the ryokan is on the way to the ropeway to the top of the mountain.<br />
Mimijiso is the only building in sight. (Mind you, with the forest, it&#8217;s hard to see the next ryokan down the side.) It&#8217;s also a cafe for travellers going up and down Mt. Meisen, a focus of religion in the area &#8212; there are many shrines at the top of the mountain. The isolation is glorious.<br />
We were greeted at the door by what I can only describe as the house matron, a wonderful elderly woman whom I can only assume was the one I had talked to earlier. She guided us to our room, ushered us in, and immediately served us maple leaf-shaped cakes (filled with red bean paste) and two cups of very strong green tea. She told us that dinner was at 18:30, and that breakfast was at 8:00 tomorrow morning.<br />
We had time to kill, so leaving most of our bags behind, Jen and I went to explore the town of Miyajima. The town centres on the shrine, which sits in a tidal area at the shoreline. Just offshore is a torii, a huge red gate that is the symbol for Miyajima. There are shrines all over this part of the island.<br />
One of the other symbols of Miyajima is the maple leaf. Not the same as the Canadian maple leaf, but a Japanese maple. (Jen described it as looking like a marijuana plant.) During the fall, apparently the entire area turns a bright red from the changing leaves. The symbol is found in everything from the cakes, cell phone (kaitei) baubles, markers on the roads and sewer grates, signs, and various tourist trinkets.<br />
As Jen and I walked around, we came realize that we really liked Miyajima. I might have trouble tomorrow when it comes time to leave. Jen and I might not want to get on the boat. I really wish I could change the reservation in Kyoto so we could stay another day. The architecture here is quaint and simple, the people nice, and the lifestyle laid back. And walking around in the park is a joy.<br />
Deer are everywhere. Miyajima has countless deer. They&#8217;re small, about the side of a large dog. And completely unafraid of humans. They probably eat a little too much from humans, so have no qualms about coming up to you for food. Jen refused one, and it whined.<br />
We wandered down to the shrine and torii, up to the pagoda, around the town and through the countless gift shops (my only complaint of Miyajima &#8212; it&#8217;s almost like an amusement park at times, though at least some of the stores aren&#8217;t too tacky), before arriving back just in time for dinner.<br />
The cooking was &#8230; exquisite. We were told it was mostly fish. The &#8220;appetizers&#8221; were sashimi (locally-caught whitefish, sea breem, and the most succulent tuna I&#8217;ve ever had), traditional sunomuno, and some egg thing that I can&#8217;t even begin to describe. Then it was a cooked piece of sea breem (that blew me away), rice, miso soup, pickled roots, and finally fresh strawberries and melon.<br />
Following dinner, Jen and I went exploring again. With all the tourists gone, it was easier to move around, and much quieter. The deer had gone to sleep. We took pictures of the torii (now lit up for night), walked around the town, and explored a few roads we hadn&#8217;t been down.<br />
I need a tranquilizer for Jen, though. She gets quite hyper.<br />
We returned for about 21:00, since the ryokan closes down around 21:30 for the night. Which was fine with us, since both of us were quite tired. It&#8217;s been a long day, but a very good one.<br />
I think those prayers worked, because tonight, Jen and I are very happy.<br />
[flickr]tag:toyohashi+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr] [flickr]tag:hiroshima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:miyajima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">336</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
