<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>narita &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/narita/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2004 22:53:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2004 22:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/26/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept like crap. And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh? It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept like crap.<br />
And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh?<br />
<span id="more-333"></span>It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel companion, I&#8217;m Jen&#8217;s legal guardian for the next two weeks (I&#8217;ve got the documents to prove it). I&#8217;m responsible for her safety, her well-being, and certainly to some extent, her life. I have to make sure that all is taken care of so there&#8217;s little concern about what will happen or where we will go.<br />
The Kyoto guest house worries me a bit. The map I have isn&#8217;t horribly clear. I&#8217;ll have the chance to review the map when we get to Chris&#8217; place later &#8220;today&#8221;. But there&#8217;s also the cell phone that I supposedly reserved, but never received confirmation on. I hope we can get that, because it will be very handy for communication. That, and I&#8217;d hate to get charged for something I never got to use.<br />
Getting to Chris&#8217; is actually the least of my worries. Even though Chris was generous in sending me a &#8220;refresher&#8221; map to guide me around Yotsukaido (Chris won&#8217;t be meeting us when we get there &#8212; he&#8217;ll already be off to Toyohashi), I&#8217;m pretty sure of my memory of the area. Then it&#8217;s just a matter of catching the correct trains on Saturday to get us to Tokyo, then to Toyohashi, on time so we can catch a shuttle bus.<br />
I think once I&#8217;m in Toyohashi, I can relax a bit.<br />
Although I was awake before 6:00 this morning, I didn&#8217;t rise until 6:30. I proceeded to shower and dress, while Brenda made us all breakfast. Maggie (the dalmatian) was going insane &#8212; she knew something was up because of the activity and the bags being packed. Fried eggs, sausages, hashbrowns, and cheese bread toast.<br />
Then it was off to the airport. Brenda drove, Mike ran shotgun, while Jen and I sat in the back. It was a quiet ride up. There seemed to be a lot of anxiety in the car. Not that I noticed &#8212; I was telling myself over and over that this wasn&#8217;t a big deal, and being responsible for more than just myself was not a problem.<br />
Sooner or later, I hope to start believing it.<br />
Security was an issue. Normally, I breeze through it. Every so often, they ask to turn on my camera or start my Minidisc player. But this time, I&#8217;m carrying wedding presents for Chris and Kaz from friends back home. I had packed a few of them in my carry-on. And that&#8217;s what they wanted to look at.<br />
Specifically, it was the juicer that Karen and Mark were sending. It had never dawned on me that it could be a problem. It was extremely light, so I figured it was plastic. But what about blades, or some moving part? I hadn&#8217;t actually <em>seen</em> the juicer &#8212; Karen and Mark had already wrapped it. But security wanted to. I had to open it.<br />
My hands were shaking. I couldn&#8217;t let them confiscate it. I <em>needed</em> to take this, and had no-one else who could get it from me. For a moment, I forgot about Jen.<br />
I realized quickly why security wanted to see this thing. Although it had no moving parts or &#8220;sharp&#8221; edges, the outline on the x-ray machine really must&#8217;ve set off some alarms. It&#8217;s shaped like a tripod: three legs that rise not quite vertically, in a slight curve, towards a central node. The node rises from the union of the three legs to a roughly egg-shaped and -sized pod. The pod has the grooves common with hand-operated juicers. The whole thing is one-piece aluminium. And thankfully, not a threat.<br />
With that, we headed to the gate to wait for our plane to arrive, deboard, restock, and for us to get on. While we left a little late, our arrival in Vancouver should be roughly on time.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
We&#8217;ve about five hours to go before we land at Narita. So far, we&#8217;ve had lunch (ravioli), watched one movie (&#8220;Master and Commander&#8221;) and are most of the way through a second (the classic &#8220;Roman Holiday&#8221;, with Gregory Peck and Audrey Hepburn). I fell asleep not far into the second movie, owning to what I can only describe as sudden, inescapable exhaustion.<br />
But it&#8217;s what I needed. Earlier, I was stressed out. I wasn&#8217;t rested, I wasn&#8217;t ready. I wasn&#8217;t looking forward to arriving in Japan. You could almost say I was scared.<br />
Not now. I&#8217;m looking forward to it. I think the nap was all I needed. I&#8217;m awake, alert, and eager. This is going to be fun. Best part is, the usual headwind going in this direction isn&#8217;t as strong, so we&#8217;re moving at a faster clip than usual, arriving about a half hour earlier. This is a good thing.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if Jen is excited or terrified. Apparently, she was talking her head off yesterday, repeatedly saying she wasn&#8217;t excited. (Riiiiight.) Jen&#8217;s been pretty quiet, though. Her usual half-giddiness is almost non-existent, and hasn&#8217;t said much since we left the house earlier this morning. She claims she&#8217;ll be excited once we get there. We&#8217;ll see.<br />
A little under five hours to go&#8230;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Our flight arrived even earlier than predicted, which was fine with me. It was good to get off the plane &#8212; my back was beginning to give me some trouble, and my feet were dying to be used. Sitting down for nine and a half hours really isn&#8217;t my cup of tea.<br />
We came in at a different point in the airport than I had come into last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]) &#8212; a completely separate building for Terminal 2. (This is a really flipping huge airport.) We even had to take a short shuttle ride from one building to the next.<br />
Immigration was about the same as last year, but a little quicker. This time, I didn&#8217;t have to explain myself to the clerk. I had the immigration form filled out correctly, so there was no questions about what I was doing. Jen passed through with equally as little trouble.<br />
Customs was a little more trouble than I would have liked (the clerk wanted to look at a few too many things in my duffle bag), but we passed through again without much affair.<br />
And before we knew it, we were in Japan. There were three things I needed to do before we left for Yotsukaido: Get more money from the Post Office ATM, pick up the rented cell phone, and pick up our rail passes.<br />
The Post Office was easy &#8212; I vaguely knew were it was. The desk for G-Call (the company we were renting the cell phone from) was a little harder to find. The information desk didn&#8217;t quite understand, so we ended up on the third floor before being directed to the first floor. But we found the place. The clerk spoke just enough English to understand most of what I was asking, but not enough for me to understand him.<br />
It&#8217;s amazing what you can communicate with hand gestures.<br />
Cell phone in hand, we then went to the JR Office to get our passes. Took a little while (the people in front of us were very good at monopolizing time), which was fine, as we&#8217;d missed the 16:04 train to Yotsukaido, anyway. As soon as we&#8217;d done that, Jen promptly proceeded to lose her mind.<br />
Jen had spotted a couple of the infamous Japanese vending machines while we were running the quick errands. Now she was in full vending machine glory. She had to personally inspect each and every machine in sight. She kept apologizing for the exuberant (if perhaps a bit odd) behaviour. No big deal as far as I was concerned &#8212; it was all a good laugh for me.<br />
I went through the same thing last year.<br />
Jen immediately bought a can of hot tea, which she found to her surprise (and partial dismay) to be actually hot. (It was very warm, but not discomforting.) Can in hand, we headed off in search of a train.<br />
The JR platform was, in stereotypical Japanese fashion, spotless. Jen was thoroughly fascinated by this. But no more so with the continued abdunance of vending machines. By the time we got on the train at 17:04, she had four cans, one of which was mine.<br />
The trip to Yotsukaido was fairly easy. Upon arrival, we headed over to the Yotsukaido ALS school (where Chris works) to grab a key for his apartment. After a quick conversation with his coworkers, Jen and I were off to the apartment.<br />
Chris called while Jen was showering. He suggested I call Tony and make arrangements to get together with him the following day for our trip down to Toyohashi. Made sense to me. So while Jen dried and dressed, Tony and I worked out a couple of details for tomorrow.<br />
The next order of business? Food. We needed food. Luckily, I know where the Mos Burger is around here, thanks to Kaz showing me the first night I came to Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]). Jen had a hamburger.<br />
Hey, at least it wasn&#8217;t McDonald&#8217;s!<br />
Home again (following a quick run to 7-11 for green tea ice cream), we settled down for a well-deserved rest. Not counting a couple of cat naps on the plane, we haven&#8217;t slept in almost 24 hours. Hopefully, jet lag won&#8217;t be a big deal this time around.<br />
It&#8217;s good to be back.<br />
[flickr]tag:narita+march+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Trip to Japan, returning home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-going-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=trip-to-japan-going-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-going-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2003 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/05/06/trip-to-japan-going-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I finally arrived home from my stint with the CBC so many months ago (see [[Home for a rest]]), I was happy to be back. It will be nice to be home after my trip to Japan, even though it&#8217;s sad to leave it so soon. When I arrived almost two weeks ago, I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-going-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Trip to Japan, returning home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I finally arrived home from my stint with the CBC so many months ago (see [[Home for a rest]]), I was happy to be back. It will be nice to be home after my trip to Japan, even though it&#8217;s sad to leave it so soon.<br />
When I arrived almost two weeks ago, I had no idea what to expect. There were a lot of questions, intrepidation, excitement, and desire. The fear would not last long, and I certainly got a healthy dose of adventure. But there is simply too much to see and do in Japan &#8212; you could visit for a year and before you could see enough to be satisfied.<br />
<span id="more-280"></span>We woke just after 10:00. Well, *I* woke up just after 10:00 &#8212; Chris and Kaz had been cooing at each other for a while before that. There was no hurried rush &#8212; there was only one activity on the schedule: going to the airport.<br />
But first, I had to pack. I had to pack all my junk &#8212; old and new &#8212; into my cavernous backpack and figure out how I was going to take the remainder of my new-found knickknacks. Luckily, years of moving myself around have taught me that there are many ways to pack things. Even carrying back more than I came with (I ended up with a box with all the plates and all but one of the paper lamps, and the bag from the Raumen Museum with the bowl and a small assortment of candies), it was far from an impossible task.<br />
Just heavy.<br />
Showering while Chris and Kaz ran to the post office (and mailed the package Tushar had asked me to mail in Japan), I finished packing save for my toiletries bag and the Japanese candy I would obtain shortly afterwards at the 7-11.<br />
12:30 rolled around, and it was time to head to the train station. The train to Narita Airport comes only once an hour, and I wasn&#8217;t too keen on missing it. The day was becoming warm and sticky, and lugging a backpack that weighed almost as much as Kaz only made it more difficult. (I&#8217;m told there&#8217;s snow in Calgary, so maybe that&#8217;ll help keep me warm.)<br />
Kaz accompanied me to the airport &#8212; she didn&#8217;t have to, but I very much appreciated it. (Usually when Kaz doesn&#8217;t need to come with me and does, I inevitably end up needing her to help me with the language.) Chris paid the minimum to see me off from the station. He had to work today, and couldn&#8217;t come to the airport.<br />
The train arrived right on schedule, and it was time to say sayonara to my best friend again. In some ways, it was like we&#8217;d never been apart, and in others, an eternity since I last saw him. Hopefully, it won&#8217;t be another eternity until I see him again.<br />
The exit procedure at the airport is rather interesting. Once you exit the train, you have to pass through a baggage inspection station. I have no idea what exactly these people do. They checked my passport (and Kaz&#8217; ID card), glanced fleetingly at my bags, and waived us on. It was then up to the check-in counter.<br />
At the check-in counter, I had to put my backpack through an x-ray machine prior to checking it. The officers asked to inspect it, which I half-expected. (I have a camera, a travel tripod, a large stack of manga books, and a few other things thrown in there that would give off some really weird readings on an x-ray. I helped the guard rifle through my things, without having to completely unpack my very carefully-packed bag. He was soon satisfied and I went to obtain my ticket.<br />
Bag checked, boarding pass in hand, Kaz and I proceeded to wandering through the airport&#8217;s stores to kill a little time. I was earlier than I needed to be, so going through security right away would have meant a lot more time to kill on the other side. I found out one interesting thing: I bought my camera in the right place (the airport, as you could expect, as a lot more expensive).<br />
Wandering around, we found our way to the Observation Deck, a fenced terrace that overlooks the international departure planes and runway. It would be my last picture of Japan.<br />
I decided it was time to go through security. If I had to clear US Customs in Japan, it could take me over an hour. (I didn&#8217;t know if the US had the same customs arrangement with Japan that it does with Canada. For the record, it doesn&#8217;t.)<br />
The security check was a breeze. Nothing checked. I collected my things and headed to Immigration. Kaz looked down on me as I descended the escalator. I bowed deeply, and disappeared into the bowels of the airport.<br />
Immigration was stupidly fast. The officer merely tore out the rest of the disembarkation card, stamped my passport, and waived me on. They weren&#8217;t even that busy.<br />
The flight left on time. I felt a twinge of regret as the plane headed skyward. Not regret for things I did or didn&#8217;t get to do &#8212; only that the experience was ending so soon.<br />
As the ground below began to disappear under the clouds and haze of the mid-Spring Japanese day, I began to feel like I was waking from a vivid dream. You know that period when you&#8217;re starting to wake up, when things aren&#8217;t really clear? Where you drift in an hour of clarity before waking up completely? That&#8217;s what it felt like.<br />
That&#8217;s where I am now. Thirty-four thousand feet above the Pacific, watching the sun set behind me. (I don&#8217;t want to watch the in-flight movies. They&#8217;re pretty poor choices.) I&#8217;ll be sleeping off and on for a few hours, waking only briefly in San Francisco before returning to Calgary. It is almost 18:00 in Yotsukaido, but the day is far from over.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
We arrived in San Francisco a little behind schedule, but nothing too serious. Well, not too serious for anyone staying in San Francisco. If you had a connecting flight, say to Calgary, then you had a problem. This was the problem Ayo and I faced. Ayo was rapidly becoming my new best friend. I had first noticed him standing on the train station platform in Yotsukaido. (He was probably the only other black person in Yotsukaido.) I saw him again at the airport, and again in line for my flight.<br />
Then I accidentally elbowed him in the back of the head putting my bags in the overhead compartment.<br />
As it turns out Ayo and I have pretty much mirrored our trips. In fact, he was on the same flight out of Calgary. (He spent a couple of days in San Francisco before going to Japan.) We took the same train to the airport, the same flight to San Francisco, and the same flight to Calgary. And we found out at the same time that we were going to be running very quickly through the airport to make our connecting flight.<br />
We didn&#8217;t even have an hour and a half. And according to the video we&#8217;d seen on the plane, we had to pass through immigration, collect our bags, pass through customs, and then recheck our bags, passing again through security before we could make our next flight. Based on my experiences with going through American airports, particularly Kennedy (see [[Behind the Iron Curtain: My Trip to the Soviet Union, Touring Helsinki and Heading Home]]), I wasn&#8217;t particularly hopeful.<br />
Immigration was easy. But my backpack was not forthcoming. In fact, Ayo, myself, and a couple of others had to wait almost 20 minutes before a page came over the PA system. Apparently, because we were connecting to flights so soon after arriving, our bags were automagically transferred to our connecting flight. Would&#8217;ve been nice if they&#8217;d told us that before we&#8217;d blown 20 minutes waiting.<br />
Customs was easy without my large bag. Security was another issue. Although there wasn&#8217;t any huge lineup, my camera bag was searched because of all the weird things I&#8217;ve got packed in there. It&#8217;s typical, but nothing really unusual. A couple of minutes, and I was through.<br />
Despite all the rushing, Ayo and I arrived at our gate to find that our flight was delayed. Figures. So we entertained ourselves discussing what kind of weather we were going to get when we got to Calgary. The first weekend we were away, Calgary got 60cm of snow. According to the fancy display with our flight information, it was -1 Celsius and snowing. A far cry from the 27 degree weather we&#8217;d had at Odaiba just a couple of days ago.<br />
The flight was late leaving (no surprise there). A couple of short hours later, we pulled into Calgary terminal. I was in the home stretch. It was just a matter of immigration and customs. I have yet to have a problem there. Bags in hand, I grabbed the first bus home.<br />
Am I happy to be home? Yes and no. It&#8217;s always nice to be home, but Japan was such a great place to be that it&#8217;s hard to leave it behind so soon. I could live there very easily. It&#8217;s an unbelievable safe place, it&#8217;s clean, and it&#8217;s an interesting place to be. Chris made a good point about Japan life: even the mundane daily tasks of Japanese life are interesting to Westerners. We don&#8217;t do them. It would probably be true in reverse, too. When the mundane things become interesting, it&#8217;s hard to be bored.<br />
This adventure is over. Disaster notwithstanding, I&#8217;ll visit Japan again. Next time, though, I&#8217;m going to see more of the country. So much to see, so little time (and money).<br />
[flickr]tag:narita+may+2003+airport@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-going-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">280</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
