<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>surprise &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/surprise/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend at Tabacon</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-at-tabacon</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend at Tabacon"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active Arenal volcano, and dinner and a splash at the <a href="http://www.tabacon.com/">Tabacon Hot Springs</a>.<br />
At the time we&#8217;d been there, it was highly magical. We&#8217;d seen lava (in the form of red-hot tumbling rocks) rolling down the side of the mountain, the clouds of steam rolling through the trees illuminated by the carefully-placed lights. It was something to behold.<br />
Ever since then, Alex had wanted to go back. Rack up Surprise Weekend in Costa Rica #3.<br />
<span id="more-1096"></span>We left Saturday just after lunch, taking a route up through Naranjo, Cuidad de Quesada (also known as San Carlos), and then angling west through La Fortuna. This was not exactly an ideal route, since it&#8217;s a national highway &#8212; despite the insane amount of curves present in the road &#8212; which means a lot more (slow) truck traffic.<br />
We arrived around 16:30 (it&#8217;s about a 3-3.5 hour drive, albeit a very nice drive) and checked in right away. A nice room (with air conditioning), two on-site <a href="http://www.cafebritt.com/">Cafe Britt</a> stores (one in the hotel, the other in the hot springs facility), and a couple of very nice restaurants.<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+hotel+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was when we found out how expensive Tabacon can be. Although the room rate for the weekend wasn&#8217;t too bad (technically less than the one at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/">Ylang Ylang</a>), it does not include any meals (whereas Ylang Ylang covered breakfast and dinner). A $75 buffet bill said that we were in for a pricey weekend.<br />
That&#8217;s the first myth of Tabacon &#8212; very nice hotel, but far too-expensive food for the quality that you get. The second myth is that the hot springs open at 8:00 in the morning. Which is true &#8212; they do, but you&#8217;ll find the water levels in the river are practically non-existent, as the water is diverted to fill the swimming pools, which starts around 9:00. So you can&#8217;t really use the hot springs until at least 10:00.<br />
On Sunday, we went out for an excursion to find a butterfly farm (Alex had promised Mi Pequeña Niña that we&#8217;d go see butterflies). We had to drive to the south side of Lake Arenal to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>, which took us on a very picturesque journey around the volcano. Which &#8212; apparently a sign of good luck &#8212; was mostly free of clouds for once. Many photos were taken.<br />
[flickr]tag:arenal+volcano+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The Butterfly Conservatory is near the end of a very rough road, off of a bumpy and rocky gravel road, off of another dirt road. (Driving back onto pavement after all that was a joy.) It sits atop a hill that provides &#8212; without question &#8212; one of the finest views of the Arenal volcano. This would be an exceptional place to take pictures at night during an eruption, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that driving there in the dark is a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢.<br />
The tents that contain the butterflies are down in a valley (a former cattle ranch turned into a reforestation project, after it was realised that putting cattle on volcanic soil is also a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢), which pretty much eliminated all breeze, and turned it into a bit of a boiler. Everyone was sweating profusely. But the butterflies were in significantly larger numbers than at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/">Spirogyra</a> &#8212; and some species that we hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+butterflies+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Luckily, we&#8217;d gained a tour guide part-way through the second (of four) butterfly tent, who not only showed us the butterflies and their names (given her limited English and our even more-limited Spanish), but also played with Mi Pequeña Niña while Alex and I snapped pictures). Sadly, I never did get her name, so all I can say is &#8220;Thanks, whomever you are!&#8221;<br />
Butterfly Conservatory also has a little frog habitat with some of the native Costa Rican frogs. Our guide was kind enough to bring the non-poisonous ones to the front of their enclosures so we could see them more closely. Otherwise, it would have been a bit hard to see them at all.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+frogs+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Naturally, Alex and I visited the hot springs whenever we could &#8212; what else would be the point of staying at Tabacon if we didn&#8217;t? Alex also took advantage of the five-star spa there, and hasn&#8217;t stopped talking about it yet. (I have to admit, it does sound wonderful.)<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+waterfall+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Even MPN got a chance to try the hot waters, while Alex was at her massage. Yes, I took my daughter into 39 degree Celsius water. And she loved it. I tried her in the cooler pools first, just to make sure, but when I slowly put her into the hot pool, it must&#8217;ve felt like heaven for her &#8212; she splashed around like a seal. The bridge overlooking the pool was soon filled with spectators. We might as well have been the featured attraction at Sea World.<br />
This is normal, by the way &#8212; it&#8217;s rather absurd the amount of attention MPN attracts down here.<br />
Monday being a holiday in Costa Rica (Independence Day), we took a leisurely return Monday afternoon, going through San Francisco and San RamÃ³n instead of San Carlos and Naranjo. This is the route that we had travelled (in the other direction) 3.5 years ago with Interbus on our way to Arenal. But Alex and I didn&#8217;t remember a thing, something we feel pretty guilty about. Alex claims that it was culture shock at the time. I think I can live with that.<br />
We stopped only twice &#8212; once to feed MPN (and have a Coke), and another at a gift shop we&#8217;d stopped at with Interbus 3.5 years ago. The only other place in the area that we knew of. It was weird because we didn&#8217;t really recognise it, but we did remember it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2862455883(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Sadly, this weekend cost a lot more than I&#8217;d budgeted for, so we&#8217;re not likely to do anymore long-distance trips for a while. (Besides which, we&#8217;re out of long weekends until Christmas). Of course, there&#8217;s still stuff around us for day trips, so stay tuned for more adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pwned</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/pwned/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=pwned</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/pwned/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 14:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/31/pwned/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning, the Blue Business Unit (aka the Mercedes-Benz USA team) decided to prank the Gold Business Unit (aka the Rolex team). Toilet paper &#8212; hundreds of rolls &#8212; over everything. Silly string. Blue streamers. And randomly-attacked items with Saran Wrap. Call it petty jealousy, call it bravado, call it a need for decorating our &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/pwned/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Pwned"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This morning, the Blue Business Unit (aka the Mercedes-Benz USA team) decided to prank the Gold Business Unit (aka the Rolex team). Toilet paper &#8212; hundreds of rolls &#8212; over everything. Silly string. Blue streamers. And randomly-attacked items with Saran Wrap.<br />
Call it petty jealousy, call it bravado, call it a need for decorating our space without input. We still got pwned.<br />
<span id="more-852"></span>I would offer only one suggested to Blue. Run and hide.<br />
[photopress:_MG_7894.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7898.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7899.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7901.jpg,thumb,pp_image]<br />
But Dan got it worse. Much worse.<br />
[photopress:_MG_7902.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7903.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7904.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_7905.jpg,thumb,pp_image]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/pwned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">852</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise birthday weekend in Revelstoke</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 16:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelstoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/07/17/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend, it was my turn to be surprised. And surprises came in droves. Sunday was my 34th birthday. I find it a little hard to believe that I&#8217;m actually that old. I always figured when I was in my 30s, I&#8217;d be more &#8230; mature. And yet I find myself being more immature with &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise birthday weekend in Revelstoke"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend, it was my turn to be surprised. And surprises came in droves.<br />
Sunday was my 34th birthday. I find it a little hard to believe that I&#8217;m actually that old. I always figured when I was in my 30s, I&#8217;d be more &#8230; mature. And yet I find myself being more immature with each passing year. I guess I&#8217;m holding to my pattern &#8212; 18 years old, with a heap of experience. For now, I think that&#8217;s a good thing. Experience helps, and one can&#8217;t get too mature. You lose all the fun, after all!<br />
<span id="more-441"></span>I sprinted home from work. I can bike home now almost as fast as I used to drive. I can&#8217;t quite figure out how I&#8217;ve done that, but I can&#8217;t really complain, either. It&#8217;s a good thing. Except that damned 8th Street hill. It&#8217;s just evil. It&#8217;s not as bad as other hills in town I have to say, but it still sucks the life out of you.<br />
Following a shower, Alex packed me in her car, and off we went. Destination unknown. Quite literally. This weekend was my chance to be surprised. I don&#8217;t ask questions, though &#8212; I prefer to try and guess to myself. The process is usually pretty simple elimination. I can eliminate quite a large number of things without much effort. Alex, of course, knows this. So she makes sure to keep me guessing.<br />
Our first stop was Banff. Dinner. Nothing serious. Kind of an eat-and-run thing. The Wolf Street Grill completely ignored us, so we tried some Japanese place a couple of blocks away. (The sign out front, in Japanese, solicited a great deal of laughter from Japanese tourists. I&#8217;m now dying to know what it says.) We ate quickly before heading back to the car and our exit.<br />
Although we ended up making one side-trip into Abomindable Sports. Sandal-searching. And I found something &#8212; Tevas. My previous pair of leather sandals was Teva, and I rather like them. I wanted something that wasn&#8217;t leather, though, since I wanted to be able to use these in wet conditions (among other things). Tevas ain&#8217;t cheap, though. But they fit, and they don&#8217;t hurt. That&#8217;s a tough thing to overcome sometimes. Tevas it was&#8230;<br />
We continued past Lake Louise and the Icefields Parkway turnoff (much to my relief), then over the Big Hill into Field, BC. Passing Field, we headed into the valley towards Golden. I was trying to figure out where we were going, and constantly drawing a blank. There was a faint hope that it had something to do with 2816, since I knew she was in the neck of the woods during the weekend. But beyond that, I hadn&#8217;t a clue.<br />
It seems that finally someone had the sense to start work on the Trans Canada highway east of Golden. It&#8217;s been a mess there for decades, and is generally difficult to go through. The hills are steep, the road windy, and there are a number of 40 km/h corners. The new section that they&#8217;re building, so it looks, will create a massive fly-over to reduce the cornering and hopefully twin the lanes. It&#8217;ll be a few years until it&#8217;s open though &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of work to do.<br />
Being the master of deception that she&#8217;s becoming, Alex really threw me off with a visit to the 7-11 in Golden before going a mere two blocks to the Travelodge for our motel room for the night. I had no idea what was going on. Thoroughly stumped.<br />
The next morning we were back on the road, following a brief stop at the Humpty&#8217;s for breakfast, we continued west. Why we were going to Revelstoke, I had no idea. We stopped briefly at the railway museum (but didn&#8217;t go in &#8212; next time, I need to actually go in there). I had heard about a trip from Revelstoke to Golden with 2816, and thought that maybe that&#8217;s what we&#8217;d gone there. (Alex had mentioned that we needed to be &#8220;there&#8221; for 13:00.) We hopped back in the car, though, and continued south.<br />
Now I was stumped. I have no idea what&#8217;s south of Revelstoke. As it turned out, not much &#8212; we were on the wrong road. We ended up having to double-back to the Trans Canada and continue west. I was beside myself with confusion. Where the hell were we going?<br />
Three Valley Gap. That&#8217;s when the surprise revealed itself. As we took seats in the restaurant there, there were settings for four, not two. Someone was going to meet us &#8212; but who? I couldn&#8217;t think of anyone who lived in the area. And that&#8217;s when Allen and Jean appeared. The sneaky trio (apparently mostly Jean&#8217;s doing) had completely orchestrated the charade.<br />
The four of us had a lovely (long) lunch, followed by a transfer of inheritances that Allen and Jean had brought from Ruskin. We&#8217;ve now got some of Christena&#8217;s things that she&#8217;d left to Alex. Oddly enough, with no planning at all, they seem to fit with our house.<br />
Naps were next. Well, for three of the four of us. Not yet being tired, I went wandering with my camera. I was lucky enough to catch a west-bound coal train (the Canadian Pacific line runs right past the hotel), though I botched the timing and the train&#8217;s a bit blurry. Things to remember for the next time I try that. Fortunately, the other trains I shot don&#8217;t move.<br />
Three Valley Gap is the oddest place you&#8217;ll ever see. It&#8217;s very much a work in progress and comes complete with a variety of antiques, including five former passenger cars from the Canadian National and Canadian Pacific railroads (and technically VIA, but they&#8217;re ex-CN/CP). Included is the Eatonia, Sir William Eaton&#8217;s private railway car. Most are in poor condition, not being maintained at all and restoration seems not to be a consideration. They do make for interesting photography, though.<br />
I found the group in the main garden wandering about. We gathered, piled into Jean&#8217;s car, and drove out to Revelstoke for dinner. Our first stop sounded good on paper. But the rather angry dog and very unassuming appearance of the restaurant suggested we go elsewhere. This led us up a long windy road to the Glacier Lodge, about a stone&#8217;s throw from the Revelstoke Dam on the west side. A massive log hotel built in 1999, and apparently a great place for dinner.<br />
It was an outstanding dinner. Miso-marinated salmon encrusted with sesame and ginger. It was a powerful but tasty meal. Alex had a lamb shank done Moroccan-style, but became more intrigued with the joint she found in the meat than actually eating it. This tortured poor Boulder, one of the wilderness guide&#8217;s two dogs. He wasn&#8217;t allowed on the patio, but the proudly displayed bone was too much for him to handle. When the waitress scolded Boulder, I suggested that she scold my wife instead for being a tease.<br />
Night photography was marginally successful. The biggest success was capturing an east-bound sulphur train, the lights creating glowing lines across the frame and glinting across the water.<br />
I was woken with a &#8220;Happy Birthday&#8221;. The goal was to try and chase 2816 from Palliser to Calgary. Alex would be on her first train chase. But first, we had to have breakfast. We met up with Allen and Jean &#8230; and a few presents.<br />
Sometime in the next while, the group of us will go to Washington and ride the dinner train. That was my present from Allen and Jean. Very nice of them. Alex surprised me with a painting of the York Railway station, circa 1930s/1940s. The kicker is that I sort of knew that she&#8217;d bought <em>something</em> when we were there, but had been told I couldn&#8217;t look at it. Never even thought about it after we got back from England and had since forgotten about it. It was a very welcome surprise.<br />
The Empress had left Revelstoke heading east around 8:00. We passed her arriving at the MacDonald tunnel entrance heading into Roger&#8217;s Pass. In theory, we could have started the chase there. But I wanted to get to Palliser before her to set up, and I knew that the construction traffic would slow us down a bit.<br />
We stopped at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a light snack and teas. As expected, the construction did in fact slow us down. I kept a weather ear out for the train, trying to make sure it wouldn&#8217;t get past us. We arrived at Palliser and took up a position and waited. And waited. And waited.<br />
2816 was supposed to leave Golden at 13:00. At first, I believed that she was just behind schedule. Freight trains get priority in most cases, so it was concievable that a delay would put her off. But 90 minutes somehow didn&#8217;t seem right. Before long, I came to believe that, somehow, she&#8217;d gotten in front of us. Perhaps in Golden, when we were at the Tim&#8217;s. Heartbroken at having to give up on what should have been a great chase, we headed east without train pictures in hand.<br />
As it turned out, we were ahead of 2816. The delay was long, and had we stayed for another 10 minutes, we&#8217;d have gotten the picture. My friend Graham was there not long after we&#8217;d left. I missed a train. Me. The Trainstalker. I feel so ashamed. It put a bit of a downer on my birthday. It seems really trivial, I know, but I just hate missing trains! It was my own fault, though, a lack of patience and too much indecision did me in. Otherwise, it was a good 34th birthday.<br />
Another year older. Hopefully a bit wiser. And perhaps a lot richer. Last year, I wasn&#8217;t married. Next year &#8230; who knows?<br />
[flickr]tag:threevalleygap+birthday+2006@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-birthday-weekend-in-revelstoke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">441</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend at Bow Lake</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/07/10/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go. We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend at Bow Lake"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go.<br />
We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different.<br />
<span id="more-440"></span>This weekend was grossly delayed, though. This year has been quite busy with a multitude of things to do and see. As such, we&#8217;re several months behind schedule on surprises. To make sure I don&#8217;t follow too far behind, I felt something particularly nice was important. That&#8217;s how we came to Bow Lake in Banff National Park and Simpson&#8217;s Num-Ti-Jah Lodge.<br />
We went up on Saturday, the first weekend of the Calgary Stampede. In fact, because it&#8217;s Stampede time again, it gave us the opportunity to have a hearty Stampede breakfast in our neighbourhood. I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s a homeowner&#8217;s group specifically, but someone definitely has their act together. We came across the same breakfast a year or two ago (admittedly I can&#8217;t remember which) and thought that it would be neat to attend. Little did we know that we&#8217;d be living there. The group puts on a mean breakfast.<br />
We then started the long drive out to Bow Lake. Only I knew where we were going, so it did raise the constant question: &#8220;Where are we going?&#8221; That was usually tied with: &#8220;When will we get there?&#8221; The gaps in between were punctuated with &#8220;How far are we going?&#8221;, &#8220;Are we going to [insert place name here]?&#8221;, and &#8220;Would Asia like going to [insert place name here]?&#8221; (That last one is a nod to a previous spoiled Surprise Weekend where I was caught off-guard with the [[Surprise weekend in Edmonton|mention of my oft-misbehaved cat]].)<br />
Thankfully, I&#8217;m very good at not answering questions like this. In order, the answers might sound like this: &#8220;Somewhere&#8221;, &#8220;Before we go to bed&#8221;, &#8220;As far as we need to&#8221;, &#8220;We might be going there&#8221;, and &#8220;Possibly, but I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;d enjoy being caged in the car for more than five minutes&#8221;. (Asia hates going to the vet, which only takes 10 minutes.)<br />
Our first stop was Banff. Not for any real reason other than we had to eat lunch. Our favourite place, the Old Spaghetti Factory, has finally lost its charm. A couple of years ago, they changed their recipe for the bread. It&#8217;s not bread anymore, it&#8217;s some conglomeration of bread-like powder. And the Italian salad dressing is &#8230; I don&#8217;t know how to describe it, but it ain&#8217;t the same. The quality has slumped overall, which is probably to recoup some of the costs on their otherwise reasonably-priced meals. It will likely be the last time I eat there. Considering we&#8217;ve already written off Starbucks, who knows how many more places will end up on the banned list&#8230;<br />
We did a little shopping (I can&#8217;t say for what, though) and I searched for sandals. As of yet, I&#8217;ve found nothing. But then I&#8217;m a picky sandal person, so it&#8217;ll probably take a while. Hopefully not too long, though &#8212; I need a second pair, and soon.<br />
Returning to the car, we headed back to the Trans Canada and continued west. This brought a return of questions regarding our destination, and a wad of non-commital responses. About 40 minutes later, we turned up Highway 93 (the Icefields Parkway part of it, of course). This brought about a specific direction of questions. It&#8217;s about three hours to Jasper, and there isn&#8217;t much in between. Alex wasn&#8217;t too keen on being in the car that long. While not giving away anything truly important, I swore that we wouldn&#8217;t be long until we got there. Well, except for one thing:<br />
I&#8217;d totally forgotten the name of the place we were going.<br />
Thankfully, when the sign came into view, it wasn&#8217;t too hard to realize that we&#8217;d arrived. The cat, as it were, was finally out of the bag.<br />
Room 24 overlooks Bow Lake, facing roughly south. The view is spectacular. They key is big and old, tied to a horseshoe so you don&#8217;t lose it. No fancy electronics here. When we entered the room, we had our Romantic Package waiting for us. In all honesty, I&#8217;d totally forgotten about it. A bottle of champagne and chocolate-covered strawberries all served on a flat rock. Decadent, most certainly.<br />
Being late in the afternoon, we wandered around looking at the natural splendour of the area before going to dinner. One downside were all the bugs. Not mosquitoes, but flies of somekind. Mildly annoying. That and the American tourists who wanted to know about Calgary, yet seemed to &#8220;know&#8221; all the answers. Can&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn &#8217;em&#8230;<br />
Num-Ti-Jah is known for an amazing kitchen. The reputation is well-deserved. The food there is outstanding, if a tad over-priced. (I will freely admit that the Lodge as a whole is expensive. This is not your average stay at a Holiday Inn &#8212; this is on the order of a Fairmont, but at a log-cabin appearance. In all honesty, it&#8217;s worth it. Especially if you&#8217;re there for the nature. If you just want a room, you can go many places that are a lot cheaper. But if you want to hit the trails right after an excellent sleep and a killer breakfast, there isn&#8217;t much better.<br />
Which is pretty much what we did the following morning. Following breakfast, we checked out and packed the car. Tying my car keys to a loop in my pants, we headed off on the 4.5 km trail to Bow Glacier Falls. (As a point of note, bear bells or jingling keys do very little. Bears apparently have no better sense of hearing than humans. So if you think you can hear a bear bell past a couple of hundred metres on a flat plain &#8212; let alone in the forest &#8212; you can imagine how easily you&#8217;d run into a bear. The recommendation is to make a lot of noise. Apparently, that&#8217;s what helps most.<br />
The hike took us about an hour, depositing us at a glacial valley. It&#8217;s bleak, cold, wet, and utterly gorgeous. There&#8217;s just something inspiring about the sheer rawness of an area that has barely any vegetation, where snow probably fills the area metres deep during the winter. Where few humans tread (indeed, we saw only two couples in the area) there is much to be seen.<br />
Returning to the car, we found that a storm was brewing at the south end of the Bow Valley. It seemed that there was a massive storm going over the mountains, probably heading right for Calgary. Indeed, a fair amount of rain and golf ball-sized hail wreaked havoc in the north of Calgary (the south seemed to be spared) later that day.<br />
We ate a bag lunch (courtesy of Num-Ti-Jah) before taking a leisurely drive back to Calgary, managing to avoid getting the Mini hailed on a second time.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603434328282[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend in Edmonton</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-edmonton</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2004 04:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/08/22/surprise-weekend-edmonton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend in Edmonton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a while since our last surprise weekend (see [[Surprise Visit to Drumheller]]), but not for a lack of wanting. We&#8217;ve been that busy. Either Alex has had to work (the joys of working in the medical community) or we&#8217;ve both been traveling. This weekend was the first one we&#8217;d had to get away.<br />
It was a bit of a special one, but for no other reason than we&#8217;d barely seen each other in almost three weeks. I was away in San Jose for a conference (see [[Search Engine Strategies Conference 2004 San Jose, Calgary to San Jose]]), followed immediately by the Calgary Dragon Boat Festival (see [[2004 Calgary Dragon Boat Festival]]), and then Alex was off in Ontario for a week and a half. So I had to plan this weekend&#8217;s getaway so we&#8217;d have some time to ourselves.<br />
<span id="more-378"></span>That&#8217;s the tricky part, actually. I had a devil of a time finding something quasi-romantic, yet equitable, and that wouldn&#8217;t put a major dent in my wallet. Easier said than done when you consider that it&#8217;s high season out here for tourism. So I decided to go some place somewhere unconventional for tourism. The sort of place that doesn&#8217;t immediately come to your mind as a destination. (It is, at least at this end of Alberta, even considered a punishment by some.)<br />
Edmonton.<br />
It&#8217;s a large city, with interesting things, comfortable hotels, and a wee bit of shopping. (Yes, that&#8217;s a joke.) I&#8217;d only ever been there three times before (once on my Trans-Canada tour in 1997, again with the Rocky Mountain Rail Society in October 2001, and then with the CBC almost a year later). In those three times, I&#8217;d barely seen anything of Edmonton, so this was a chance to see &#8230; well, more than I had. Now all I had to do was keep Alex in the dark as to where she was going.<br />
That&#8217;s a lot harder than it sounds. Alex wanted to know &#8212; who doesn&#8217;t want to know what a surprise is? Be damned if she didn&#8217;t really dig for it, too. In fact, Thursday night, she kept at me for nearly two straight hours of questioning. She was persistent, and sometimes really sneaky when composing her questions. I was quite proud of myself for not supplying the answer, while not lying about the destination.<br />
But everyone has their Achilles heel. Mine is Miao-Yin.<br />
Alex took a turn of what was supposed to be silly questioning, where she asked if the cat would like where we were going. Would the cat enjoy the view? Would she like to drive? What about if she wanted to stop and get out for a while? Hey, maybe she could take us out for dinner one night! It was supposed to be in fun, but I got stuck on the more serious side: namely, the cat wouldn&#8217;t survive the trip down the block without me going insane from her yowling, let alone the three hour drive to Edmonton&#8230;<br />
Insert a long string of emphatic expletives here. Because that&#8217;s what spewed out of my mouth immediately after &#8212; letting the cat out of the bag &#8212; I said where we were going.<br />
So that piece of the surprise was divulged the night before. Doh. But Alex didn&#8217;t know where we were staying, or why she had to bring a nice outfit. And those I kept quite tightly under wraps.<br />
Despite leaving Calgary a little later than I&#8217;d planned Friday evening, we arrived in Red Deer before 19:30. Hunting for a restaurant downtown (and turning up empty), we ended up at the White Spot. (Not my first choice of places for dinner, but it holds a particular place in Alex&#8217;s heart from when she was younger.) It took everything I had not to mock our waiter, obviously a student from Red Deer College, either trying to be an actor or a radio personality, and failing miserably. His schmaltzy shtick dripped of goofiness, despite an obvious desire to be taken seriously. I know more than a few people who would have talked back to him in the same manner.<br />
I&#8217;d never arrived in Edmonton from the south before. Fortunately, signs weren&#8217;t too hard to follow to downtown, and the road was actually familiar from the time the CBC crew had taken a shuttle bus to the train station &#8212; surprisingly, I still remembered it. The hard part was then finding the hotel. Despite having the address, the grid system actually confused me rather than helped. Alex was rhyming off building names or companies, starting at the names of hotels before slipping into ones like banks, insurance companies, restaurants, and the YMCA. Finally, I found the Westin, and we pulled in.<br />
Why the Westin? One reason: The Heavenly Bed. I spent a weekend in one during a prison term in Cincinnati (see [[Live from Cincinnati, Surviving Memorial Day]]) and haven&#8217;t forgotten it. Given how much Alex and I hadn&#8217;t seen each other, and Alex&#8217;s less-than-stellar trip to Ontario, I felt that perhaps a really comfortable stay would help. It certainly couldn&#8217;t hurt&#8230;<br />
We checked in on a very auspicious weekend. In addition to the Fringe Festival (an annual event in Edmonton), there was also the Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival (Topmade sent the Dragoneers, and Sang and Colette were also paddling for Crew Yahoo of the Calgary Dragon Boat Club), the Jazz Festival (I think), the 100th Anniversary of Edmonton, and the coup de grace, being held at the Westin, the National Bodybuilding Championship.<br />
Be still my beating heart.<br />
After waking up quite late the following morning (we were both quite content to stay in the Heavenly Bed), we went in search of breakfast. A flip through the phonebook was a bit frustrating due to the lack of options. Eventually, we decided on the Denny&#8217;s, about 12 blocks from the Westin. It would have been a nice walk, had it not been cold, windy, with a spattering of rain mixed in for flavour. We cut through the mall downtown to save ourselves from the chill.<br />
The Denny&#8217;s was packed. But it was also one of the only eateries that we could find in the area that serves breakfast, at least from judging by the line-up inside. It took nearly a half hour to get a seat for two. It would take about the same amount of time to actually get our breakfast once ordered.<br />
While we waited, we babbled nearly incoherently about whatever kept coming to mind. (Hey, we had almost three weeks of events and trivial crap to catch up on.) While we chatted, a semi-familiar silhouette passed through my peripheral vision, heading into the washroom.<br />
Me: &#8220;I think that&#8217;s Mo!&#8221;<br />
Alex: &#8220;Mo? Topmade Mo?&#8221;<br />
Me: &#8220;Yeah&#8230; it *is* Mo! And there&#8217;s Byron, and Arnold!&#8221;<br />
The Topmade Dragoneers were in town (the aforementioned Edmonton Dragon Boat Festival), and some of the team had apparently decided to grab a meal at Denny&#8217;s in between the races. (The Edmonton Festival, unlike it&#8217;s Cowtown counterpart, is planned very well. It also had the sense to judge teams by the times they logged racing, not by some idiotic point system &#8212; Calgary Festival organizers, take note!)<br />
Arnold was surprised by our appearance:<br />
&#8220;You&#8217;re the last two I expected to see here!&#8221;<br />
Yeah, I know, what the heck does that mean? I was wondering that, slightly miffed. It wasn&#8217;t like we didn&#8217;t enjoy ourselves paddling. I&#8217;m rather looking forward to it next year. Actually, if anything, I&#8217;m miffed that I&#8217;m not getting the club updates (they were looking for volunteers this weekend; not that I&#8217;d have been able to go even if I had got the notice). We promised to drop by later on.<br />
We trudged out into the rain following our meal, and decided to take a shortcut through Grant McEwan Community College, just across the street. (Partly because it&#8217;s an interesting-looking building, but also because it was warm and dry.) The college campus is situated on the old Canadian National rail yard that used to run through downtown Edmonton (well, what is now downtown Edmonton &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t downtown when the yard was built). With the yard relocated to the north end of the city, the lands were freed up for other uses. The $16 million parcel of land was donated to the College, which then built its main campus.<br />
The College&#8217;s namesake, Grant McEwan, is a man of considerable distinction. Alex and I didn&#8217;t really know who the man was. Thanks to an exhibit in the main lobby, we found out that the Honourable Mr. McEwan was a Professor and the Director of the School of Agriculture at the University of Saskatchewan, a magazine editor (and prolific author), a Calgary alderman and a three-year Mayor of our fair city, became an MLA for Calgary and was elected the Liberal Party leader, became the Lieutenant Governor of Alberta for eight and a half years before going into semi-retirement. He never slowed down, however, and continued humanitarian work until his death in 2000 (at the age of almost 98).<br />
There are times when you simply can&#8217;t avoid feeling humbled.<br />
We ended up having to dive back into the rain, thoroughly unable to avoid it. We trudged through the Farmer&#8217;s Market before finally finding our way back to the mall we&#8217;d cut through earlier in the morning. We did some window shopping (I ended buying a new fleece jacket, mostly because I hadn&#8217;t come properly prepared for the weather) before returning to the hotel. We napped. It was great.<br />
Dinner was a surprise I managed to keep on tap, though Alex guessed the destination by some of the clues I had let out (but by then, I didn&#8217;t mind) &#8212; Fairmont&#8217;s Hotel MacDonald, about a block from the Westin. Specifically, the Harvest Room. I was told this was one of the best restaurants in town, and I wanted to take Alex there. I even wore a suit and tie for the affair.<br />
Oh, one thing I need to point out. While we were preparing for dinner (mainly me ironing my clothes), we listened to the radio. Much to our surprise (and near shock), we came across 92.5, known as Joe FM. Now this might sound a little weird &#8212; why would I identify a radio station, you might ask? It&#8217;s a sister station of 96.9 Jack FM. Same commercials, same commercial voice dude, but it just didn&#8217;t sound right. Even the slogan was different: Playing &#8230; Anything! (In Calgary, it&#8217;s &#8220;Playing &#8230; what we want!&#8221;) Yet another reason why Edmonton and Calgary don&#8217;t get along.<br />
I have to say that I was mildly disappointed with the experience. The hotel itself is nice, but the Harvest Room lacked the old-world quality you often find in the older Fairmont hotels (most notably the Banff Springs). The food was well done, but I felt I&#8217;d had better meals here in Calgary, and much &#8220;lower-end&#8221; restaurants. I also felt the service wasn&#8217;t quite to the level I&#8217;d expect for Fairmont. (Or more importantly, a Canadian Pacific Hotel.) Such as it is, the meal was wonderful, as was the company. Next time, though, I think we&#8217;ll go somewhere else.<br />
By the time the meal was done, it was nearly 20:00, so we opted for a dip in our hotel&#8217;s hot tub (it was a little chilly outside). After a cold beverage in the bar, we headed for bed. Despite really doing nothing, we were both quite tired.<br />
Awaking late again the next morning, we rose, showered and packed, while watching the Olympics. I haven&#8217;t watched much of it this year (partly due to the time change), but what little I have seen kind of annoys me. And it&#8217;s not he performances, it&#8217;s all the media.<br />
C&#8217;mon folks, it ain&#8217;t about the medals. So what if Canada isn&#8217;t getting that many this year? Big deal! Our athletes are out there, competing, and doing a pretty good job, all things considered. Are they gonna bring home the bacon? Maybe, but will the world end if they don&#8217;t? Probably not. Just let them compete without all the additional pressure &#8212; they went there to represent Canada, not be bad-mouthed by us.<br />
Checking out, we drove (as it was raining even harder Sunday morning) for Denny&#8217;s. No-one from Topmade was there that time, so we ate in relative anonymity. We headed back to our hotel&#8217;s parking lot, though, to go down to the festival area to see our friends and team-mates.<br />
We arrived just in time for the Sistership tribute. This is something they do almost every festival (they didn&#8217;t do it in Calgary, for some reason). It&#8217;s in tribute to those lost to breast cancer. Sistership is a club whose members are all cancer patients, past and present.<br />
Passing by the boards, we found the scores of the previous day. Topmade Dragoneers had done quite well, and were ranked up with EDBC and Jetstart (from Toronto). One of the others under the tent commented that the first race was going to be a good one. Alex and I would not wait to see it, as we were cold and wet, and really not wanting to stick around in the weather.<br />
Finding Topmade&#8217;s tent, we found Sang and Collette inside. We chatted for a while before following them down as they went to get something to eat. We left them at the food vendors and returned to the car. We were off&#8230;<br />
&#8230;to West Edmonton Mall. The largest mall in the world. The megalopolis of merchandising.<br />
It&#8217;s a weird place, if you&#8217;ve never been. Parts of it make sense. But then you run into Galaxyland (formerly known as Fantasyland), which is the midway there. Rides that you would normally see at the Calgary Stampede, PNE, or CNE are permanent showcases there. Even the infamous rollercoaster on which people died a number of years ago. It&#8217;s loud. It&#8217;s hard to believe you&#8217;re in a shopping mall.<br />
And then there&#8217;s the ice rink, the water park, the indoor golf course, the submarines, and the model of the Santa Maria.<br />
Oh, and lest we forget the over two decade-old design? That place is in *serious* need of a facelift. (It also didn&#8217;t help that the glass roof leaks, probably due to that nasty hailstorm and flooding of a couple months ago.)<br />
Considering its size, the mall wasn&#8217;t that bad for crowds &#8212; we had little or no trouble getting around. Well, except for size &#8212; the mall is huge, after all. I was disappointed to see that Sega Playdium had closed down. Considering the other attractions in the mall, however, I could understand.<br />
After about four hours, we&#8217;d had enough, and it was time to head home. Alex tried to cross-stitch as we headed out of town, but eventually switched over to reading for a while (reading to *me*, I might add) to take a break.<br />
We stopped again in Red Deer for dinner, this time going to Boston Pizza for, well, pizza. Nothing outlandish, we split a small (10&#8243;) between us, which was just perfect. Then it was back on the highway in the rain, drizzle, and fog, before arriving back at Alex&#8217;s shortly after 21:00.<br />
The weekend was good, despite the weather. Edmonton isn&#8217;t exactly the vacation destination I had thought it might be, but then we didn&#8217;t see much of it either. Next time, we&#8217;ll have to go somewhere else, though. Someplace less urban.<br />
And if you&#8217;re looking for hints here, Alex, you&#8217;ll have to try harder than that!<br />
[flickr]tag:edmonton+august+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/08/surprise-weekend-edmonton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">378</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise Visit to Drumheller</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-drumheller</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2004 03:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drumheller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/06/28/surprise-weekend-drumheller/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come. The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise Visit to Drumheller"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come.<br />
The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is a &#8220;Jerks BBQ&#8221;, you might ask? The group of people that I work with most around the office are The Jerks. Effectively, we&#8217;re mostly web developers. Why &#8220;Jerks&#8221;? Well, we have a rather odd term of endearment around here: &#8220;JERK!&#8221;. Hence, we&#8217;re Jerks.<br />
<span id="more-363"></span>This was only the second barbecue I&#8217;ve had since I bought the house (see [[My Housewarming Party]]), and was a far cry from the housewarming audience. Suddenly, I remember why I only have these barbecues once in a while &#8212; they&#8217;re a lot of work.<br />
For example, I was up late putting together the fixin&#8217;s for the barbecue, specifically hamburgers and potato salad. I didn&#8217;t want to buy pre-made burgers (they taste like crap, and you really don&#8217;t know what goes into those things). I decided to make everything. Wanna know what went into them? I can&#8217;t give you quantities (I made it up as I went), but it went like this:<br />
Hamburgers<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
&#8211; medium ground beef (you need the fat for flavour)<br />
&#8211; beer (specifically Big Rock Traditional)<br />
&#8211; caramelized onions<br />
&#8211; garlic (lots of it)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; cumin<br />
&#8211; rosemary<br />
&#8211; thyme<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; seasoning salt<br />
&#8211; oregano<br />
&#8211; chipotle powder (adds a great kick)<br />
Potato Salad<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
&#8211; roasted potatoes (with coarse salt, olive oil, and rosemary)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; olive oil<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; balsamic vinegar<br />
&#8211; scallions<br />
&#8211; red, orange, and yellow peppers<br />
Everything was ready for when my guests arrived Friday after work &#8230; about 20 minutes before it began to rain. At first, it only rained a little. Soon, it was raining a lot. Apparently someone had decided to ignore my purchase order for a nice, sunny evening. We ended up cramming into the kitchen and living room. Still, a good time seemed to be had by all, which is all I really wanted.<br />
Pat and Scott were the last two to roll out the door, shortly before 22:30. That gave me time to go over to Alex&#8217;s. Which was important for activities the next day&#8230;<br />
&#8230;starting with the Inglewood Festival, and the pancake breakfast. We were originally going to walk from Alex&#8217;s, but when she found out that her sister had a layover in Calgary on her way back to Vancouver, the plan changed to driving. Though we walked from the south side of the Zoo to Inglewood.<br />
The breakfast was put on as part of the festival, but I think also for the footrace runners so they could eat after their event. The food was quite good (there&#8217;s nothing like greasy spoon flapjacks and Spolumbo&#8217;s sausage), and we were serenaded by local group, The Wake Ups.<br />
We did a quick circuit of the various stalls (many still setting up) before running back for the car, and heading up to the airport. Sadly, we would not see Nicky that day, as she had only 40 minutes between flights, and I gather the staff felt she wouldn&#8217;t have enough time to see anyone. We headed back down to downtown.<br />
Originally, the intent had been to go back to Inglewood. To go easy on parking, we stopped at the Calgary Zoo, planning to walk from there. But we soon found ourselves at the entrance to the Zoo. We had the option of going around, or going in. Suddenly, the Zoo seemed so much more appealing.<br />
It was a perfect day to see the Zoo. I&#8217;d only been there two times before, and both times were cold and nasty, and not all the animals were really active. This time, we were tripping over them &#8212; especially the flock of peacocks that seemed to be running around the grounds (including peahens with their peachicks). And then there were all the kids. Hundreds of &#8217;em. They were almost as interesting as watching the monkeys.<br />
We started off in the dinosaur section. This is little more than a static display and a garden, with some dinosaur sculptures thrown in for accent. They&#8217;re not the best models, perhaps, but for a portion of the zoo, it&#8217;s not too bad. Then we were off in search of elephants, bears, monkeys, horses, and tigers before we had to stop for lunch. After eating a fresh Spolumbo&#8217;s sandwich (albeit a little pricey), we were off to Africa (to see hippos, giraffes, zebras, ostriches, lions, gorillas, more moneys, bongos, several species of birds), the botanical garden to see various plants and the butterflies (which even after three times, have been very light in numbers), then over to Australia.<br />
The Australian section (which until this weekend I didn&#8217;t even know existed) included kangaroos (which didn&#8217;t move much), one of the roaming peacocks, and a building full of oddities from Down Under. Part of the building is dedicated to &#8220;Creatures of the Night&#8221;, a rebranding for the nocturnal section.<br />
Inside there, it&#8217;s dark. Really dark. You almost feel like squinting, it&#8217;s so dark. In there, you find things like a little fox with REALLY big ears, wallabies, and of course, bats. Lots of bats. But my favourite thing was a little mouse-sized creature, the name of which I currently forget. This little marsupial zipped along at high speed, and could crawl up the surface of a vertical pane of glass. (Apparently, sweat glands in its feet create suction.) It was quite an experience.<br />
Then it was off through the Canadian Wilds. Nothing particular here, just the usual cougars, lynxes, moose, ducks (but they&#8217;re everywhere, so you can&#8217;t avoid them), bison, wolves, caribou, owls, hawks, porcupines, deer, elk, and goats. Y&#8217;know &#8212; the same stuff you see every day on your way to work. (Sorry, that&#8217;s a bit of an in-joke for us Canucks.) That concluded our Zoo visit, and it was time to get on with the day.<br />
A quick stop at London Drugs retrieved photos that Alex has been taking for the last couple of months. One of them was of her bedroom wall, which she painted milk chocolate brown. Prior to painting it over completely, she&#8217;d drawn a large heart, inside of which she wrote: &#8220;AA + GS&#8221;. Although I&#8217;d known that she drew something on that way, she wouldn&#8217;t tell me what was there until I saw the photograph.<br />
Have I mentioned that I love this woman?<br />
Collecting our things, it was time for the surprise (it might take a while, but you knew I was going to get to it eventually). First off was dinner. For that, we tried to find Mother&#8217;s Pizza in Beddington Town Centre. However, it appears that the store front is currently hidden under the mask of renovation. I only hope it makes a return. We ended up at the Boston Pizza, instead.<br />
From there, we headed out towards Deerfoot Trail, and then north. You need to understand that, at this point, I had no idea where we were going. In &#8220;return&#8221; for the surprise I pulled on Alex in Banff (see [[Jazz Up Your Weekend at the Banff Centre]]), Alex wanted to take me somewhere mysterious. Her &#8220;clue&#8221; had been misinformation, to throw me off the scent. I had guessed Kananaskis. As we drove north on Deerfoot, I assumed that she was taking a very circuitous route.<br />
When we turned east onto one of the many regional highways at the north end of Airdrie, I put Kananaskis off to the side. I soon thought it might be Irricana, though I couldn&#8217;t imagine why. When we passed it on Highway 9, I tried to think of something else. When we passed Beiseiker, there weren&#8217;t many options left. Alex was trying to convince me it was Saskatoon. While this was the same route I&#8217;d take when we&#8217;d moved Nana to Calgary (see [[Moving Nana from Prince Albert to Calgary]]), the drive out is a little long. I felt it safe to assume she was trying to distract me from our destination: Drumheller.<br />
Though when we first pulled into the downtown core, I had second thoughts. Alex passed by most of the hotels, and started taking South Dinosaur Trail away from downtown! (It&#8217;s all industrial park out there.) It wasn&#8217;t until she crossed over the railway tracks and pulled into the Newcastle Inn that the surprise was fully exposed.<br />
The Inn is a small place, with about 12 rooms. It looks sort of like your grandmother&#8217;s place, but with an extra fridge in the kitchen, and a bathroom for each bedroom. Family photos adorn the walls. The Inn was mostly empty when we were there, save for the owner, and two other couples (who seemed to be in the basement). It was certainly comfortable enough for us for the night.<br />
We checked in just before 22:00, dumped our bags, and headed out for a short walk. Which ended up being a long walk (about 30 blocks) to the 7-11 and back. The night was cool, but not uncomfortable. Many small homes, and a few with firepits (we smelled a little like smoke by the time we got back). The unmistakeable scent of prairie-bound small town was just the sort of thing I needed to clear the head.<br />
The next morning, woken up by the other guests who had decided to eat their breakfast on the patio outside our window &#8212; the first ones to do so since the Inn opened &#8212; we ate our breakfast on the patio next to the kitchen. Cereal, toast, and a little fruit salad. We showered, dressed, packed up, and headed out for the adventure of the day.<br />
Our first stop was at the Tourist Information Centre. Why? Originally, to find the local TD Canada Trust, of which there is none in Drumheller. Every other bank is there, just not the TD. While we were there, we felt it necessary to do the tacky tourist thing, and climbed the World&#8217;s Largest Dinosaur.<br />
The 26.2 metre (85 ft.) tall structure is a massive version of a tyrannosaurus rex (or something similarly nasty), about 4.5 times the life-sized versions found in a museum not too far away. It&#8217;s not nearly as life-like, but that&#8217;s part of the charm. The internal structure is steel, though aside from the stairs it&#8217;s hard to tell &#8212; the inside is a plastic &#8220;tunnel&#8221; lined with fossil reproductions.<br />
The tunnel ends at the dinosaur&#8217;s jaws, where you peer westward over the town of Drumheller. It&#8217;s a pretty neat view, especially with the teeth in the way. Alex and I got a great view of the city, and the children playing in the water park just beneath the dinosaur.<br />
Then it was off to the real thing &#8212; the Royal Tyrell Museum. It&#8217;s been a while since the last times that I&#8217;ve been there (see [[Kathryn comes for a visit]], [[Touring Alberta, Calgary Stampede, Columbia Icefields, Lake Louise, Banff (Bamf!), Drumheller]], and [[A Boys Night out in Calgary, Drumheller, Banff (Bamf!), and Star Wars]]), and it was good to be back and see it again. Especially with someone who really wanted to see it because of personal interest.<br />
If you might remember, Alex is an x-ray technician, which means she spends a lot of time with bones. That, and her degree in science, leads to a lot of questions. For example, there&#8217;s a skeleton of a lambeosaurus (duck-billed), that showed a lot of spines from the tail bones. This puzzled Alex, as did the series of long bony-looking lines running the length of the spine between the shoulders and the hips. Before, I&#8217;d not have thought twice about this. Alex, however, is very good with anatomy, and knew this wasn&#8217;t right. A passing staff member told us the long bony structures were fossilized tendons (who knew?) and the tail spines were to create the thickness of the tail.<br />
We tried to take our time, but we ended up only taking a couple of hours. One thing about visiting museums off and on &#8212; you see different things upon subsequent returns. That&#8217;s what made it so interesting. I suspect the air conditioning also hasted our movement, since even for me, it was a little chilly.<br />
We ran out to the hoodoos east of downtown for a quick photo stop. Since I was there last, the Royal Tyrell has taken over management of the area, and created paths for people to walk on, trying to keep people from prematurely destroying the hoodoos. A bold and very noble initiative, since you don&#8217;t have to pay for the privilege of seeing them. So kudos to the Tyrell!<br />
With that, we headed back towards Calgary. We stopped at Horseshoe Canyon for a look-see. This meant a lot of climbing. Once we hit the valley floor, Alex was off like a shot, feeling a need to run up and down the slopes. For a while, I thought I was the dog that no-one wants, and was trying to ditch me out in the middle of nowhere. Fortunately, I managed to not fall too far behind.<br />
The trip back was into the setting sun. The excitement of the two days hit me, and for a short period of time, I slept. Soon, we were back in Calgary. We finished our weekend with a simple Greek meal at Santorini. Along the way to the restaurant, we were confronted by a friendly cat who stirred a few old memories in Alex, of a cat she&#8217;d had as a little girl. I had to take a picture for her.<br />
Now it&#8217;s my turn for planning the next surprise. I&#8217;m not sure what to do just yet, but I&#8217;ve got &#8220;It&#8217;s a Small, Small World&#8221; playing in my head&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:drumheller+june+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">363</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to throw a surprise party (and not get caught)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2004 22:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/27/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise parties are one of those great little joys in life. While I&#8217;ve never had one thrown for me, I&#8217;ve thrown a couple myself. They&#8217;re not the easiest things to do, to be certain, but they are definitely some of the most fun. What makes a surprise party so good? If you&#8217;re the host or &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to throw a surprise party (and not get caught)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surprise parties are one of those great little joys in life. While I&#8217;ve never had one thrown for me, I&#8217;ve thrown a couple myself. They&#8217;re not the easiest things to do, to be certain, but they are definitely some of the most fun.<br />
What makes a surprise party so good? If you&#8217;re the host or planner, it&#8217;s from the giddiness that forms from knowing what will happen. If you&#8217;re the guest of honour (or the victim, depending on your point of view), you get the joy of knowing that people have planned something just for you. It&#8217;s a special feeling &#8230; or rather, I would hope that it is (not actually knowing myself).<br />
I&#8217;m going to speak to the planners, which I assume is why you&#8217;ve come to this page. (If you think someone is planning a surprise party for you and are trying to find out if it&#8217;s true, I can offer no hints here. If they&#8217;re following these suggestions, you won&#8217;t know until it&#8217;s too late.) You&#8217;ve got a hard task ahead of you, but it is a rewarding one if it&#8217;s done right.<br />
At all times, you need to remember who is in control: you. Everything that happens is because of you. If you lose control, don&#8217;t expect things to go off without a hitch. You can delegate, but you need to know that those you&#8217;ve delegated to are trustworthy and reliable. Otherwise, your intended surprise might end up a dud.<br />
There are some basic rules you should follow to ensure that your party goes well and without hitches. Above all, you don&#8217;t want to get caught in making the preparations, and spill the beans to the indenting surprisee.</p>
<ol>
<li>Secrecy are the first and second words</li>
<li>Separate and isolate communications</li>
<li>Better to over-involve than under-involve</li>
<li>Inform clearly and explicitly</li>
<li>Know what&#8217;s going on at all times</li>
<li>Be mindful of what you say</li>
<li>Cover your tracks</li>
<li>Make sure you have a backup plan</li>
</ol>
<h3>Secrecy are the first and second words</h3>
<p>The first rule of the Surprise Party is: you do not talk about the Surprise Party. The second rule of the Surprise Party is: <strong>you do not talk about the Surprise Party</strong>.<br />
You never know who&#8217;s around and don&#8217;t think for a second that the six degrees of separation is a myth. So idle chatter about a surprise party is not a wise idea. Similarly, you should always make sure that any communications you send are to specific people, be it by phone, email, or IM. Never send things by post (unless you&#8217;re certain there is no way information could leak), by fax (it&#8217;s out in the open), or leave voicemails on residential lines (especially if the intended victim lives there).<br />
Swear everyone to secrecy. This means they cannot discuss it with anyone else except you. And ideally, unless they&#8217;re involved with the planning or execution, they shouldn&#8217;t need to. The less anyone talks, the less chance of the wrong people finding out. As the WWII saying goes: Loose lips sink ships.</p>
<h3>Separate and isolate communications</h3>
<p>As alluded to above, you need to make sure your communications lines are clear and isolated. This cuts down on crosstalk chatter and sidebars, which are guaranteed to cause problems.<br />
When you talk to people, talk to them individually. This is best because you get immediate feedback, and there&#8217;s no question about whether or not they understand what is being asked of them. If you have to do discussions with a group, make sure each person acknowledges what you have said and/or asked. The last thing you need is ambiguity.<br />
Make sure your communications are direct &#8212; never make public statements. If you have to send out invitations, make sure that they&#8217;re received in a private manner (e.g. the office, through email, talking on the phone). Never leave messages where others can see or hear them, especially if it&#8217;s the person you&#8217;re surprising.<br />
Finally, don&#8217;t communicate unless you have to. Updates are fine, but don&#8217;t randomly send out information until you&#8217;re ready to do so. This lessens the change of leaks.</p>
<h3>Better to over-involve than under-involve</h3>
<p>On the flip-side of secrecy is an inadvertent foul-up due to conflicting plans. The best laid plans can go to pot in mere seconds by the actions of someone who is not privy to the surprise party. So when you&#8217;re planning, make sure that everyone within the sphere of influence knows what is going on. They don&#8217;t have to be invited, just need to know that they can&#8217;t foul things up.<br />
Naturally, you can&#8217;t cover for everything. There are always things that you simply can&#8217;t plan for. (For that, see &#8220;Make sure you have a backup plan&#8221;.) Consider it as an 80/20 rule. You can cover 80% of all possible actions with relative ease. The remaining 20% are a lot riskier and difficult, and might not interfere with your plans, anyway.<br />
You need a list of culprits. Some will be invited, some not. The list of invitees is up to you, but they still need to be informed:</p>
<ul>
<li>friends</li>
<li>significant others</li>
<li>co-workers</li>
<li>teammates</li>
<li>housemates</li>
<li>roommates</li>
<li>spouse</li>
<li>parents</li>
<li>siblings</li>
<li>aunts and uncles</li>
<li>cousins</li>
<li>nieces and nephews</li>
<li>uncle&#8217;s cousin&#8217;s roommate&#8217;s older brother&#8217;s girlfriend&#8217;s dog</li>
</ul>
<p>Okay, that last one was a bit much, but you get the point.<br />
Really consider who you&#8217;ve got on your list. Each of these people will have contact on a regular basis, and could introduce plans that could thoroughly foul up anything you&#8217;ve got going.<br />
Family is particularly important, especially if the party does not directly involve family. Family is the single most powerful thing for some people, and is the reason why your intended guest might decline your casual invitation to spend time with their parents. So if you&#8217;re throwing a party, make sure the family knows what&#8217;s going on.<br />
Plan big. Get as many people as you can. Sure, you can throw a small surprise party, but why bother when you can have a big one? Besides, you can get a much louder yell out of more people.</p>
<h3>Inform clearly and explicitly</h3>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve got your key list of people, make sure you give details. Tell them everything they need to know: time, place, reason, attire (if any specifics are desired), and who the other people are.<br />
Make sure that you get accurate contact information for each person, and ensure that it&#8217;s secure (e.g. that no-one else might inadvertently overhear something they shouldn&#8217;t). You might have to employ one or more of your intended invitees to help out if you don&#8217;t know enough people up-front.<br />
Don&#8217;t be vague at any time. Once you have the details, make sure they&#8217;re broadcast to everyone else. Make sure everyone else knows the details, so there&#8217;s no question. People need to make sure that they arrive at the surprise location before the unsuspecting target(s) arrive. There&#8217;s nothing worse than a surprise with only a few people.</p>
<h3>Know what&#8217;s going on at all times</h3>
<p>Know your details, and know them cold. Make sure you can answer any question about the party or the plans if asked, without having to refer to notes (unless it&#8217;s something esoteric). It&#8217;s a bit of work, but it&#8217;s easier when you&#8217;re running around trying to organize things.</p>
<h3>Be mindful of what you say</h3>
<p>In short, you have to learn to lie.<br />
This is particularly important if you&#8217;re the one doing the planning, and the person you&#8217;re surprising is close to you (spouse, significant other, friend, family). If you want to conduct a surprise, you need to make sure you don&#8217;t tell them anything accidentally.<br />
You also have to make sure they don&#8217;t suspect anything. This is the hard part. Humans are inquisitive by nature. If you have a look of &#8220;something&#8217;s up&#8221;, the other party will immediately suspect something. You have to be able to look someone square in the face and say: &#8220;No, honey, I have no idea what you&#8217;re talking about.&#8221;<br />
Be able to avoid the topic. If they want to plan something for the same time that you&#8217;re planning the party, allow them to do so. This will keep them occupied and they will not expect anything than their plans. Defuse the plans as necessary by canceling reservations (while informing of the real plans), or deferring purchases as long as possible. If necessary, go to a backup plan and use some of the invitees to construct a &#8220;just in case&#8221; scenario to distract.</p>
<h3>Cover your tracks</h3>
<p>Never leave your plans lying around, even if you live alone. Chances are, someone will see what you&#8217;re doing, and if it&#8217;s the wrong people, it&#8217;s game over. Hide them in drawers (under locks, if needed) or in password-protected files. Delete messages once you see/hear them. Jot down only the most crucial notes.<br />
Create distractions. This is the same technique magicians use to make a ball disappear before your eyes. Make fake plans that will keep someone on their toes. You can even create real plans designed to take the person away from what&#8217;s going on, only to bring them back to the surprise to unfold.</p>
<h3>Make sure you have a backup plan</h3>
<p>No plan is ever perfect. So long as you deal with humanity, you must expect something to go wrong. Be it discovery of the plans, suspicion of a surprise, a sudden illness, disappearance of the subject (hey, it&#8217;s been known to happen), or transportation failures, make sure you&#8217;ve got something in your back pocket to save the day.<br />
Some things you can plan for. If the gig is up, and you&#8217;ve got a few hours before the surprise is planned to go off, admit to a surprise. Just not *the* surprise. Grab a couple of friends and set them up at a different location. Do a small surprise there. Have them all need to leave for different reasons (when in reality, they&#8217;re all going the same place you will be going), and then head to the actual surprise.<br />
Some things you can&#8217;t. If the gig is up less than an hour away, you might pretty much be screwed. At that point, you might have to resort to the worst thing you can do: ask that they act surprised when they enter the room, if nothing else than for the benefit of everyone else.</p>
<h3>A few suggestions</h3>
<p><strong>The Home Surprise Party.</strong><br />
This is an easy one, if planned well. Ensure that a trusted person has the keys to the house or apartment. Make sure everyone arrives at least an hour ahead of schedule for decorations, etc. Make sure all cars are parked away from the home. Set a window of 10 minutes before you arrive with the subject so that no-one comes in. If you can, call ahead with a pre-defined ring (twice, and then twice again) to set a &#8220;five minute warning). Lights should be off (or in whatever expected state they should be in), and all evidence (especially shoes) should be hidden.<br />
<strong>The Office Surprise Party.</strong><br />
A little more difficult, but often the most fun. Call the person away from their desk (get a manager to call them into a closed office or another floor or building) for 30 minutes. Decorate their desk, string lights and streamers, set out snacks and cake (if possible). Get the manager to walk them back to their desks such that it would be difficult for them to see what is about to happen until it&#8217;s too late. This works best in environments with actual offices or tall-walled cubicles.<br />
<strong>The Central Location Surprise Party.</strong><br />
Sometimes, due to size, you&#8217;ll need to hold a surprise party at a restaurant or hotel ballroom. These are harder, since you might draw immediate attention. The trick is then to give the person a reason to have to go there. In the case of a restaurant, you can go under even the most simple reason: lunch or dinner. Make sure you have reservations for all the guests, and make sure the restaurant knows that it&#8217;s a surprise party. Ballrooms are much harder, since they have special purposes. You can play it by going to a hotel&#8217;s restaurant, and go into a different room. If it&#8217;s a community hall, say you were asked to pick something up.</p>
<h3>Abort! Abort! Abort!</h3>
<p>Okay, let&#8217;s face facts. This could go wrong. You might not actually succeed. There are a million things that can go wrong, and you might get to the point where you have to pull the plug and abandon the attempt.<br />
First off, don&#8217;t panic. Secondly, don&#8217;t feel bad. And thirdly &#8212; and most importantly &#8212; don&#8217;t tell the Surprisee. EVER.<br />
There&#8217;s a couple of reasons for this. You (or someone else) might try to surprise them again. There&#8217;s no sense in tipping off your potential victim by telling them &#8220;oh, well, we tried, but it didn&#8217;t work&#8221; &#8212; they might thing you might try again. And if you do, the surprise might not be as effective.<br />
But most notably &#8212; I think, anyway &#8212; telling someone runs risk of actually hurting their feelings. Not for the failed effort, but because it might be something they really, really wanted. Finding out that you came close to having a wonderful surprise, but it won&#8217;t happen is &#8230; well, it&#8217;s really hard to learn, and it can be very depressing. This is not something you want your surprisee to go through.<br />
So, yes, you may have to just suck it up. You tried, it didn&#8217;t work, and aside from those who you&#8217;d already talked to (and you should make sure they know why it&#8217;s aborted), no-one else <em>needs</em>  to know. In the end, it&#8217;s better for all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>297</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">458</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Practical Jokes Around the Office: Wrapping a Desk</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/12/practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/12/practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2003 22:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/12/22/practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is an Old Klingon proverb that says: &#8220;Revenge is a dish best served cold.&#8221; It is very cold in December. (Well, when we&#8217;re not chinooking, anyway.) Several months ago, I fell victim to an attack. Not a physical or verbal attack &#8212; a water balloon attack (see [[Critical Mass Reckless Summer Reunion]]). This was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/12/practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Practical Jokes Around the Office: Wrapping a Desk"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is an Old Klingon proverb that says: &#8220;Revenge is a dish best served cold.&#8221;<br />
It is very cold in December. (Well, when we&#8217;re not chinooking, anyway.)<br />
Several months ago, I fell victim to an attack. Not a physical or verbal attack &#8212; a water balloon attack (see [[Critical Mass Reckless Summer Reunion]]). This was orchestrated by the Delichte brothers, Jason and Darren. (I&#8217;m still not sure how I became the focus of their attention. I&#8217;m not sure if I should be honoured or horrified.) I certainly owe them a special &#8220;thank you&#8221; for that particular event, and one day, when I find something appropriate, I shall.<br />
But first things first.<br />
The water balloon attack could not have been pulled off without inside information, namely my boss, Allard. As you know, I tend to carry cameras with me. The Delichtes made sure I was camera-free by having Allard make sure that my cameras were at a safe distance. He did it very well, too &#8212; I had no idea that I was being set up. At least not until a line of water bombers appeared on the hill above the volleyball courts.<br />
As the sayings go: One good turn deserves another; no good deed goes unpunished; eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth; wrong me, do I not revenge?<br />
For the last few months, I&#8217;ve been plotting and scheming, trying to think of something good to pull off. The trick, of course, is so that the person at the receiving end has no knowledge what is to befall them, yet can do nothing about it once it&#8217;s happened. Not as gruesome as Poe&#8217;s &#8220;The Cask of Amontillado&#8221;, but certainly something that when seen, will provoke the appropriate feeling of &#8220;he got me&#8221;.<br />
Such it was that in a moment of brilliance (or drunken stupidity, they&#8217;re pretty much interchangeable), it came to me. I would give Allard a nice, gift-wrapped present.<br />
His desk. And everything on it.<br />
I wish I could take credit for this little idea, but I must confess that Chris had mentioned it around the time we were replacing Teak&#8217;s files with several cubic feet of candy (see [[Revenge is Sweet]]). But no-one had acted on it around here, so it was left as a possibility. And with Allard taking a couple of days off for the Christmas holidays, I was presented with a prime opportunity for revenge.<br />
Yesterday, I made a little trip out to Costco, to acquire a few rolls of cheap(er) wrapping paper. I didn&#8217;t know exactly how much I&#8217;d need, but the desks aren&#8217;t that small (Allard has an end unit, which means vertical surfaces), and while his desk isn&#8217;t even remotely as cluttered as mine, there are still a number of things that require wrapping.<br />
I arrived at the office around 19:00. I needed to make sure that there was no-one else around on the second floor. My goal was to complete the task without anyone knowing who it was. I wanted the mystery effect to last at least a few days (Allard won&#8217;t be back until the 29th), and because Allard arrives so early in the morning (before most of the people on this floor), I wanted the effect to be seen before he &#8220;opened his gifts&#8221;.<br />
The first thing I did was take reference photographs. I needed to know (roughly) where everything was so I could put it back in a wrapped state. Then came the fun part: wrapping. I started with the aisle-facing side of his desk &#8212; it was the easiest thing to do, and a good place to start. It didn&#8217;t take long, but admittedly, didn&#8217;t really leave me with a sense of accomplishment. I still had a long way to go.<br />
I got bogged down in the details. The table legs are not straight cylinders &#8212; they are slightly arched, and taper quite a lot towards the top; the shelving racks are like blocky shovels, which do not wrap easily (or nicely). It was 21:45 when I came to the realization that I needed help, or be up all night.<br />
For the record, I would love to give credit where credit is due. I would love to stay who it was who loaned two hours of their time to my task, as strange (and draining) as it was. However, in the interests of preventing any form of retribution, they will remain nameless. But their help was invaluable, and definitely prevented me from staying too late. They left shortly before midnight.<br />
I continued working until everything had at least some wrapping paper around it: the desk, side table, filing cabinent, phone (wrapping the cord was no fun), the monitor and monitor stand, the laptop dock, the keyboard, mouse and mousepad, more books than should be allowed on a desk, the chair, the light post, and his nameplate.<br />
Everything was put back in the place it had been originally found. Cables were plugged back in. Ideally, everything should be exactly as it was before &#8230; just covered with wrapping paper. There are even bows on a few things. (I had toyed with using ribbon, but in retrospect, I&#8217;m glad I didn&#8217;t. That&#8217;s a little more detail than I really care to think about.)<br />
Towards the end, admittedly, I was getting a little sloppy. My back was killing me, I was hot, tired, and desperately wanting to go to bed. But I finished, leaving the chair perhaps a little less wrapped than I would have liked. Around 1:45, I finally packed up my things, cleaned up the evidence, and made for home.<br />
I skipped gym this morning &#8212; I needed the rest. After the &#8220;workout&#8221; I&#8217;d had moving things around and wrapping, I figured I&#8217;d had enough exercise for a while. (Yeah, I&#8217;m stretching. I&#8217;ll do cardio all week to make up for it.)<br />
A couple of people were already in the office when I arrived. It didn&#8217;t take long for word to spread. People were taking notice. Even the less-than perfect wrapping job was being lauded. And if nothing else, the smiles have been worth all the time and money.<br />
After all, if you can&#8217;t get a good laugh out of revenge, why do it at all?<br />
[photopress:dsc01758.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01760.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01766.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01767.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01768.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01771.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01776.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01777.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01778.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01779.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01780.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01781.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01782.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01783.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:dsc01784.jpg,thumb,pp_image]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/12/practical-jokes-around-the-office-wrapping-a-desk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">312</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revenge is Sweet</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/11/revenge-is-sweet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=revenge-is-sweet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/11/revenge-is-sweet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2001 17:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2001/11/26/revenge-is-sweet/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the temperature falls to -21 degrees with the wind chill, and the sky dumps 15 centimetres of snow on the ground, that&#8217;s when a young man&#8217;s fancy turns to&#8230; Revenge. Some months ago, Chris&#8217; and my collective birthday to be exact, our friend Teak decided that he would give us each a small token &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/11/revenge-is-sweet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Revenge is Sweet"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When the temperature falls to -21 degrees with the wind chill, and the sky dumps 15 centimetres of snow on the ground, that&#8217;s when a young man&#8217;s fancy turns to&#8230;<br />
Revenge.<br />
Some months ago, Chris&#8217; and my collective birthday to be exact, our friend Teak decided that he would give us each a small token of &#8230; well, sugar. Specifically, a lunchbox full of it. When I opened my little gift, candy spilled all over my desk. How he managed to get the candy in there and the lid shut is beyond me&#8230;<br />
Needless to say, when word of Teak&#8217;s birthday came roaming around, Chris and I started thinking. Initially, it wasn&#8217;t anything mean or nasty, but then Chris joked about getting even with Teak for the months of sugar. (I still have some of mine.) It wasn&#8217;t too long before the joke turned serious, and it was time to execute.<br />
Step 1: The plan.<br />
This was perhaps the easiest part. The basic principle was sound: Get one of Teak&#8217;s desk-side cabinets (they&#8217;re a little over two feet tall, about one and a half feet deep, and a foot and a quarter wide &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a ruler, so these are estimates). Empty it. Then refill it. With candy. The trick, of course, was to do it when Teak wasn&#8217;t around (he&#8217;s been in the office late a lot, so working around that was a bit tricky).<br />
Step 2: The supplies.<br />
Sugar. And lots of it. In short, a trip to Costco, about the only place we can get such huge quantities of glucose goodness without completely breaking the bank. There&#8217;s a lot to consider when buying for a stunt such as this. You don&#8217;t want full-sized chocolate bars &#8212; they&#8217;re too big. Halloween ones would have been perfect, but those haven&#8217;t been in the stores for almost a month. You also have to be careful not to get too much of one thing. For example, too many M&amp;Ms, although perfect for something like this, means you need more of them. Also, you want variety.<br />
This meant we had to carefully choose our ammunition. I wish I&#8217;d remembered to bring the list of things we bought, but it&#8217;s along the lines of:</p>
<ul>
<li>Four boxes of sour gummies (including cherry and watermelon flavours)</li>
<li>Two small tubs of more sour gummies</li>
<li>One tub of marshmallow rats (yes, rats)</li>
<li>One large tub of sugar lollipops</li>
<li>One small tub of Chupa Chups (lollipops)</li>
<li>One box of Blue Whales (gummies that taste like those blue freezies)</li>
<li>A couple packages of marshmallow peaches</li>
<li>Two huge bags of M&amp;Ms (peanut variety)</li>
<li>Two bags of Jelly Belly jelly beans</li>
<li>One container of candy necklaces</li>
<li>One tub of Double Bubble gum (the ones with Bazooka Joe comics)</li>
<li>Three boxes of chocolate and caramel Rice Krispie squares (about the healthiest thing we threw in)</li>
<li>One large bag of Werther&#8217;s (sp?) caramels</li>
</ul>
<p>There&#8217;s probably more, but we were having too much fun shopping for this stuff.<br />
Step 3: The prank.<br />
I was in the office again this weekend, partly because I had some work to do, partly because I&#8217;m overhauling my personal website (coming soon to a URL near you), and on Sunday, because I had to know when Teak wasn&#8217;t here anymore.<br />
Around 6:30pm, I took a short trip upstairs. First good news: Teak wasn&#8217;t there. Second good news: Neither was anyone else. Best good news: The poor fool had left his cabinet unlocked. A little after 7:00, Chris called to say he was ready to have fun. I whipped over to the apartment, picked up my roommate and brother in mischief, and returned to the office.<br />
The security guard was puzzled to say the least when we walked in with two huge boxes overflowing with packages of candy. We went upstairs to the Creative Services floor, and found that the lights were still off. (I&#8217;d turned them off when I&#8217;d inspected the floor earlier.)<br />
The first thing we had to do was clean out his cabinet &#8212; the lower part, anyway. Teak had a lot of files, which would of course get in the way when trying to empty the various tubs, boxes, and bags. Fortunately, there are other cabinets which weren&#8217;t in use. A simple transfer, and we were on our way.<br />
Almost &#8230; first, we had to line the lower bin with waxed paper. We didn&#8217;t want to make a total mess.<br />
Then came the fun part &#8212; filling the drawers. Taking several containers, we started pouring. Mind you, this isn&#8217;t some random thing &#8212; you have to do it carefully. You don&#8217;t want to make a parfait of candy &#8212; you want a nice, even dispersion. We had to mix a few times to get the right distribution. But the end effect looks &#8230; nasty, actually, and the smell&#8217;s quite powerful.<br />
Filling the lower drawer, we proceeded to the upper drawer (filling it with mostly small stuff, including M&amp;Ms, and finally the top bin (which sits under the seat), also nice and full. The surprising part was that we&#8217;d had leftovers. We&#8217;d originally thought we didn&#8217;t have enough, and worried that the joke would only be partially realized. But &#8217;tis better to have too much and do the job right than not have enough and do a half-assed job.<br />
[flickr]photo:4336923348[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4336177183[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4336176767[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4336176305[/flickr]<br />
The final touch was on Teak&#8217;s computer. Like most of our Designers, he has two monitors (one is usually for seeing the artwork, the second for all the tools). Chris made up two images that were placed on the backgrounds of each of the monitors. One read &#8220;Sugar is sweet.&#8221;, the other &#8220;Revenge is sweeter.&#8221;<br />
I couldn&#8217;t stop giggling the entire time. I so wanted to put up a camera and videotape Teak&#8217;s arrival this morning. I so wish I could have seen the look on his face.<br />
Ah well, all&#8217;s well that ends well. At least until Teak tries to up the ante. If he&#8217;s smart, he won&#8217;t &#8212; starting an arms race with us is &#8230; foolish.<br />
All I can say is: There&#8217;s always room for&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/11/revenge-is-sweet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">167</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
