<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kelowna &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/kelowna/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 23:18:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Driving home from Kelowna</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/driving-kelowna-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=driving-kelowna-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/driving-kelowna-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2004 23:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/12/driving-kelowna-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a very long time since I&#8217;ve been on a roadtrip. And although it was only one-way, I didn&#8217;t mind it at all. I flew into Kelowna, but I drove back with Andrea, Tamara, and Dan. Andrea had driven the three of them out on Saturday, and I got the distinct feeling she wasn&#8217;t &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/driving-kelowna-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Driving home from Kelowna"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a very long time since I&#8217;ve been on a roadtrip. And although it was only one-way, I didn&#8217;t mind it at all.<br />
I flew into Kelowna, but I drove back with Andrea, Tamara, and Dan. Andrea had driven the three of them out on Saturday, and I got the distinct feeling she wasn&#8217;t looking forward to the drive back. Understandably so &#8212; it&#8217;s an eight-hour drive. Unless you&#8217;re in a really comfortable vehicle (such as a RoadTrek), long-distance driving can be excrutiating. And nowhere more frustrating than the Trans Canada Highway between Kamloops and Banff.<br />
<span id="more-350"></span>Why there? Most of the highway is two-lane &#8212; one in either direction. Aside from the odd passing lane, you have to wait until there&#8217;s a break in the traffic to get around all people staring at the scenery, driving at a snail&#8217;s pace. At least the highway from Banff to Calgary is divided four-lane. Much easier to handle.<br />
Anyway, we started off this morning at the IHOP, having failed to get breakfast at it yesterday. Bellies packed with food, we loaded up with snacks and beverages, and headed north on Highway 97 to the Trans Canada. It had been nearly four years since I was last in the Okanagan (see [[Download Overload, the Critical Mass Kelowna Getaway in Westbank]], and my memory of driving in and out was either via Merritt (see [[Canada Day in Kelowna, Winery Tours, and Penticton]], for example) or back in 1997, when I drove to Kelowna with my friend Gerry. I didn&#8217;t remember much of the trip with Critical Mass, having watched movies most of the way there and back.<br />
Driving is an excellent way of seeing the valley, though I imagine the Okanagan Wine Train (now sadly defunct) would be even more spectacular, going places the roads do not. I looked around periodically, or peered at my copy of &#8220;The Hobbit&#8221;, which I&#8217;m finally reading. (Yes, I&#8217;m 31 and have never read any J.R.R. Tolkien. So sue me.)<br />
When we got to Revelstoke, we stopped for gas, a pee break, and a chance to stretch. At that point, I offered to give Andrea a break from driving. She was quite willing to give up the wheel for a while, since she was getting sore from having to keep pace (or pass) traffic. Something I would soon learn myself&#8230;<br />
Andrea&#8217;s car, a VW Jetta, is manual. This is why I had to offer to drive, and not Tamara or Dan. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I didn&#8217;t mind, but the manual is a little different than mine. Took me a little bit to get used to it. But soon, I was handling it like my Mini. Which was actually a problem. My Mini handles corners a little better than the Jetta. I took a corner or two a tad wide, and a bit too fast. We were trying to get home in good time (I didn&#8217;t go any faster than Andrea already had, so I didn&#8217;t feel particularly guilty about it), and being stuck behind some yahoo motorhome with a passenger handing out the window during the run through the Kicking Horse canyon east of Golden &#8212; that&#8217;s right, moron, you know who you are!! &#8212; wasn&#8217;t our piece of cheese.<br />
I found myself succumbing to highway hypnosis after a while. It wasn&#8217;t until we hit the divided four lane of highway east of Lake Louise that I relinquished the wheel back to Andrea. I fell asleep in the front passenger seat until we were inside Calgary city limits. I was that tired.<br />
Home was a bit cool, though it was 18 degrees outside. Miao-yin was happy to see us, only because it meant someone was actually going to feed her. Lots of mail, a couple voicemail messages, but otherwise, the house was the same as it had been when I&#8217;d left almost three weeks ago. Tomorrow, I go back to work.<br />
Sigh. I&#8217;m already wishing I were back in Japan.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/driving-kelowna-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">350</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Bowie plays Kelowna Prospera Place</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2004 23:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/11/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We all woke at about the same time. I was awake, though eyes closed, when I heard Tamara and Andrea whispering. I joined into the conversation, joined shortly thereafter by Dan. At that point, there wasn&#8217;t much reason to stay in bed, so I called first shower (I hadn&#8217;t had one since getting up &#8220;yesterday&#8221; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "David Bowie plays Kelowna Prospera Place"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all woke at about the same time. I was awake, though eyes closed, when I heard Tamara and Andrea whispering. I joined into the conversation, joined shortly thereafter by Dan. At that point, there wasn&#8217;t much reason to stay in bed, so I called first shower (I hadn&#8217;t had one since getting up &#8220;yesterday&#8221; in Japan).<br />
The plan had been to go for dim sum for breakfast, at the Chinese restaurant across the road. Not being open until 11:30 proved to be a bit of an issue, however, so we opted for breakfast #2: IHOP. Unlike Calgary, there is an International House of Pancakes in Kelowna. And we weren&#8217;t the only ones who knew that. The lineup was clearly out the door, and not just by a few people. It would be a long wait before we got breakfast if we&#8217;d stayed. We opted for the much shorter lineup at a nearby Perkins.<br />
It felt good to not eat Japanese for a change.<br />
<span id="more-349"></span>Having thoroughly packed ourselves full, we returned to the hotel and went for a walk down by the lake shore. We&#8217;d been trying to figure out what to do, and headed for a boat ride on the Fintry Queen, a stern-wheeler ship that runs out of Kelowna. As we would find out, it runs during the tourist season, which we weren&#8217;t in. The ship was closed down, and not operating. We turned instead to the boardwalk, and slowly walked our way north along the lake, past the condos, rounding the park, turning around only when we got to the estuary marsh. We walked back passing Propera Place (where David Bowie would play later in the day).<br />
We started to look for a patio. We thought that we&#8217;d take advantage of the great weather (it was warming up very quickly) and sit out in the sun with a drink or two. Turned out to be harder than we thought. Unlike Calgary and Vancouver, which open patios at the first hint of a warm day, Kelowna&#8217;s stayed closed. We ended up at the Earl&#8217;s, instead. Not my first choice, but it wasn&#8217;t too bad.<br />
Back at the hotel again, we were desperate for something to do. While Tamara, Andrea, and Dan perused the various pamphlets and brochures in a pair of racks in the hotel&#8217;s entrance, and searched the Internet. I took the opportunity to use a local call to give my relatives a ring.<br />
Uncle David answered the phone, which I thought a bit surprising &#8212; I&#8217;d fully expected him to be on the golf course. Temporarily put down by a cold and a wrist injury, he was reduced to merely watching the Masters game on TV. Not the best way to get a golf fix, but it would have to do. We talked for a bit about the trip to Japan, the things we&#8217;d seen, and how much Jen had apparently liked the experience. We got onto the topic of what we were doing before the concert, and soon, we had our destination for the afternoon.<br />
Knox Mountain is just north of downtown Kelowna. It&#8217;s not too high a rise, but is high enough that you can see quite a distance from the apex lookout. Almost the entire city if Kelowna is visible (some parts are blocked by trees and/or parts of the mountain). It&#8217;s an old mountain, having long since been worn down by the glaciers that were up to 7,000 feet thick in the area that now supports Kelowna. Now the mountain features many coniferous trees and a lot of daisies.<br />
Having done our tour of the mountain, we headed back to the hotel to prepare for the concert. Well, Tamara and Andrea were preparing. Dan and I were pretty much set to go. I ended up falling asleep on my cot. Not sure if it was jet lag, exhaustion from all the wandering around, or both. But it was a rest I needed.<br />
When I woke, it was dinner time. We hoped to eat with enough time to get there before the concert actually started (last time, we were a tad late &#8212; see [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]]). After a quick discussion, it was off to Earl&#8217;s again. No dice &#8212; the stable was full. We looked at a place called Cattle Country, but the prices were a little out of our range. Luckily, we could get into The Keg. However, despite our fortune in finding a restaurant, we had issues with the slow service, and ended up having to eat quickly and set a quick pace to get to the concert.<br />
Once again, the opening act was already on stage. We didn&#8217;t consider this a huge deal, since we weren&#8217;t really there to see them. To be honest, we&#8217;d never even heard of The Polyphonic Spree before. Quite an odd band &#8212; there are 25 members, including a nine-person choir, harpist, flautist, trombone, trumpet, two percussionists, bass and guitar, lead singer, and two keyboardists (one of whom plays the therimin). They call themselves a pop choir. I wouldn&#8217;t use the word &#8220;pop&#8221; to describe the music, though. It&#8217;s very melodic and very different. Out of our group, I think I was the only one who liked it, though.<br />
During the break, I got a chance to know some of our neighbours. The couple sitting next to me were a bit older (the guy, whose name I&#8217;ve already forgotten, commented that he was glad not to be the oldest one there &#8212; he couldn&#8217;t have been older than late-30s), and very excited to see David Bowie. But they didn&#8217;t hold a candle to Tannis. She sad in the row ahead of me. I had thought I was pretty gung-ho for coming off a plane from Japan and coming out to Kelowna for a concert I&#8217;d already seen.<br />
Tonight is Tannis&#8217; sixth David Bowie concert since January. She went to the Calgary concert, and also the ones in Winnipeg, Edmonton, Vancouver, and Seattle. Tonight is her last, though, having run out of both money and vacation time. But she was just as excited to see him this time as the first time. She epitomized the ideal &#8220;fan&#8221;. (Thankfully, not to the extremity of the freak in the bunny suit, a perfect example of someone taking it too far. She was staying at our hotel, too.)<br />
Prospera Place is small &#8212; it&#8217;s a large community ice rink. It seats no more than 5,000 people. It&#8217;s got one level of seating, not counting the floor (where we sat). The place is so small that the stage set had to be slightly reduced. No-one seemed to have any idea what possessed David Bowie to play there.<br />
You wouldn&#8217;t hear any of us complain.<br />
The music changed on the sound system, and Tannis went crazy. Even I knew what it meant &#8212; no-one else around us did &#8212; this was the beginning of Bowie&#8217;s stint onstage. The lights dimmed, and the video showing the animated version of the band appeared on the video wall. It faded to video of the band, as the members walked on. The delay between the band entering onstage and starting the first song was much shorter than before &#8212; &#8220;Rebel Rebel&#8221; was soon starting, and as they&#8217;d probably practiced almost endlessly, David walked up the microphone just as he needed to start singing.<br />
Andrea and I were on the left side of the stage, in the fifth row. (Tamara and Dan were in the eighth row, on the other side of the floor.) While our seats sound wicked, I actually prefered the seats we had at the Calgary concert &#8212; at least I didn&#8217;t have some completely unanimated gorilla standing in front of me.<br />
I have to say that the Kelowna crowd was FAR more laid back than the one in Calgary. On the slower songs, they all sat down (as did Andrea &#8212; I think Tannis and I were one of a handful who stayed standing; Tamara and I would later comment that we should have stayed in the fifth row, with Andrea and Dan in the eighth &#8230; oh well), there wasn&#8217;t nearly as much jumping up and down, and not as much singing as I had expected. There was, however, a lot more pot than in Calgary (hey, we are in British Columbia). I should point out, however, that Andrea and I were among the youngest ones in our area&#8230;<br />
The playlist had changed since Calgary, much to my delight. The second song up was &#8220;Modern Love&#8221;, one of my all-time favourites, and the song that got me hooked on Bowie in the first place. (He never did play &#8220;Space Oddity&#8221;, but I think I can live with that.) At this show, David dug out the oldies, playing a few songs I&#8217;d never heard before. He also changed up the beginning to &#8220;Let&#8217;s Dance&#8221;, to the point where I didn&#8217;t initially recognize it. If nothing else, the song selection just further proved Bowie&#8217;s artistry.<br />
He also continued his habit of joking around, especially with &#8220;China Girl&#8221;. Unlike last time (see [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]]), Bowie didn&#8217;t make us sing. Instead, he tried to sing the whole song in Chinese. (Apparently, he&#8217;s done this &#8212; it appears on a DVD.) He made it two verses before stopping, unable to remember how the rest of it went. He restarted with the original English version.<br />
The concert was much more intimate than Calgary&#8217;s, with David making lots of jokes with the audience (starting off with &#8220;What&#8217;s with &#8216;Kamloops&#8217;, anyway?&#8221;) and ribbing Kelowna about its history. He even brought out a little plush representation of Ogopogo, and started comparing it to the Loch Ness Monster. He claimed it wasn&#8217;t much to talk about, being only four inches long, fuzzy, and wearing a bowtie. He even pointed out the freak in the bunny suit. He nodded to Tannis &#8212; I think he was actually looking for her.<br />
A little shorter than Calgary&#8217;s show, the Kelowna show was notably louder. (Although when it came to the &#8220;Wham, bam, thank you, ma&#8217;am&#8221; part in &#8220;Suffragette City&#8221;, you couldn&#8217;t really hear the audience.) My ears rang well into the night, and long after I went to bed.<br />
I thought it was a great concert, though I have to admit it lacked the energy I felt in Calgary. Might have been partly because of the crowd, or perhaps because I&#8217;d already seen him. I&#8217;m still glad I went, though, because it was great to see him perform again. If he comes around in the not-too-distant future, I might go. But I won&#8217;t feel quite as much need as I have before.<br />
[flickr]tag:davidbowie+kelowna+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2004 23:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/10/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day. And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind. Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day.<br />
And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind.<br />
<span id="more-348"></span>Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years ago, it hurt to have him leave. When Therese and Stuart moved to Montreal, it was hard to handle. But as I stood in the doorway of the train today, I looked back at my friend &#8212; my brother &#8212; and wondered when I will see him again.<br />
There is never enough time. Too many things happening, and too much distance separating us. I miss living with Chris. I miss the knowing glances and mouthed expressions we could give each other that conveyed meaning on a level only we knew.<br />
But such is life. Life is change, life is motion. It has to continue, lest life stop.<br />
Chris didn&#8217;t come to the airport with us, but Kaz was kind enough to guide us. When we arrived, we&#8217;d found that our flight time had changed. We had originally been booked for an 18:35 departure, but had been rescheduled for a 15:30 departure &#8230; or so I&#8217;d thought. The boards read a 17:15 departure, so I began to wonder if Air Canada had changed the times on us again, and not informed us. In retrospect, I think we&#8217;re okay, but I&#8217;m not 100% on that yet.<br />
Normally, a chance in flight times wouldn&#8217;t worry me. But I have to catch a flight in Calgary to take me to Kelowna, and I can&#8217;t afford to miss that flight. At the time, I started to worry. I had based my flight from Calgary on the changed (and perceived) time of 15:30. If we were now leaving Japan later, I might not make my Kelowna flight.<br />
Either way, we were at the airport far too early to determine what was going on, so it was just a matter of waiting. Putting the bags into storage (we had almost two hours to wait until we could check in), we went in search of lunch.<br />
One of the restaurants offered beef don, or a relative facsimile thereof. Jen was dying for beef, so this is where we went. Kaz and I had more traditional Japanese meals. It was a way of using up the remaining 2,000 yen I still had. (As it turns out, not such a wise move, since we had to pay to get the bags back, which was 1,500 yen.)<br />
We did a bit of shopping. Well, looking around, anyway. The only thing we really needed to buy still was a bottle of sake for Uncle Mike. But Terminal 2 really didn&#8217;t offer anything particularly interesting. And as we had time to kill, anyway, we went over to Terminal 1.<br />
I finally figured out why I&#8217;d been so disoriented when we arrived two weeks ago. Last year, I came in at Terminal 1 (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]), which I think is a lot nicer than Terminal 2. It was quite clear when we got close enough to see inside.<br />
We returned to Terminal 2 to check in. This is when we got another nasty bit of news: Jen and I were not sharing the same flight coming from Vancouver to Calgary. We had set it up that way so we didn&#8217;t have to worry about the flight. In fact, there supposedly weren&#8217;t any available seats at all on the flights and we didn&#8217;t really have reservations. I urged them to correct that sitation, but the best we could get was two flights over three hours apart. This is something I&#8217;ll have to sort out in Vancouver.<br />
Once checked in, we had to start heading to the flight. Kaz walked us to the security gate, where we had to say goodbye to her. Kaz and Jen had grown close (mostly as a result of yesterday&#8217;s rather interesting shopping spree). Kaz is my best friend&#8217;s wife. I don&#8217;t know her nearly as well as perhaps I should, but if she&#8217;s able to capture his heart, I know I will miss her as much as I miss him.<br />
The flight boarded only a few minutes later than scheduled, but far in advance of us departing the gate. The flight isn&#8217;t completely full, so is rather comfortable. Hopefully, the flight will be a short one, so we don&#8217;t have to sit down for too long.<br />
Jen and I chuckled a bit at the first movie. Not just because it is a funny movie, but because it was very appropriate for all the Japanese/English mishaps we&#8217;ve had throughout our trip.<br />
&#8220;Lost in Translation.&#8221;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
The plane arrived more or less on time. We hustled from the plane, bypassing many of the passengers (they were taking the escalators, we took the adjoining stairs) and getting into the immigration line. We had to go through Canadian Immigration in Vancouver before heading to Calgary.<br />
This was the only time &#8212; *only* time &#8212; throughout the entire trip that someone asked my relation to Jen in an official capacity. I had legal documents on me that stated that I was Jen&#8217;s legal guardian, but never had to show them to anyone. Even the clerk at Immigration didn&#8217;t ask to see them, but said that I might have to show them.<br />
I never had to.<br />
We had to collect our bags and go through Customs (which amounted to them taking our form of Declaration, not even saying &#8220;thank you&#8221;) and check them in again for our connecting flight.<br />
It was the connecting flight that was a bit of an issue. As you might recall, we found out at Narita airport that Jen and I were not on the same flight. This had me mildy irked, because we were supposed to be on the same flight. It&#8217;s not that I didn&#8217;t trust Jen to get back to Calgary on her own, but I was supposed to be her legal guardian, and wanted to make sure she got back to her parents.<br />
Fortunately, the flight I was on was not completely full, and the Air Canada clerk was reasonably certain that Jen would be able to get on the flight. She set Jen up as stand-by, and even checked her bag to Calgary (so even if Jen didn&#8217;t make it, her bag would). With that, we went off to our gate.<br />
I got pulled over at security again. I always seem to get pulled over in North America. It&#8217;s all my freaking electronics. Japan didn&#8217;t care. Maybe they&#8217;ve got better technology. I mean, they&#8217;ve got vending machines that will take bills upside down, backwards, and probably crumpled beyond recognition. They&#8217;ve gotta have better scanning machines than we do.<br />
At the gate, after giving the clerk a few minutes, we asked if Jen could get on the flight, and if it was possible if we could sit together. The clerk, originally seeming a little harsh, turned out to be quite congenial, and settled our last hurdle quite easily.<br />
At that point, I called Aunt Brenda. (I had my cell phone with me for in-Canada communications upon my return.) I let her know we were on the 12:00 (PST) flight from Vancouver, getting into Calgary around 14:30. She was quite happy to hear we&#8217;d be home soon, and said she&#8217;d meet us there.<br />
The flight was quite hot. Unlike our A340 plane, our little A320 was quite warm, even with the air vents cranked all the way open. But it didn&#8217;t really matter. Soon, we&#8217;d be at home. Thankfully, the flight went quickly (that happens when you sleep for half of it &#8230; or all of it, in Jen&#8217;s case), and soon we were exiting Gate A to the awaiting arms of Uncle Mike, Aunt Brenda, and Nana.<br />
Now, you&#8217;d think at this point that I&#8217;d be somewhat relieved to unload the responsibility for handling Jen back to her parents, right? Not really. It was at that point that I realized that Jen hadn&#8217;t really been that hard to handle. Aside from having to curb her manga-buying sprees, and encouraging her to see more things (which was more trouble than I would have thought), she was very easy to get along with. But then, we already had a good relationship.<br />
Jen immediately became a chatterbox, telling Brenda and Nana about the trip &#8212; almost entirely randomly-selected portions &#8212; while Mike and I exchanged a few thoughts about my perspective. All this while waiting for the bags to come out. Then it was back to their place to unload.<br />
Now, dear reader, this is where this tale should end. But it doesn&#8217;t. While Jen&#8217;s journey was over, mine still had a bit left to it. I had another flight to catch. I&#8217;m now in Kelowna. Why would I be coming to Kelowna? Two words:<br />
David Bowie.<br />
Remember when I said that if David Bowie was returning to Canada anytime soon that I&#8217;d go to see him? (See [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]].) I wasn&#8217;t kidding. A couple of months ago, during my only sick day of the year (so far, anyway), Tamara had burst into my room in a near state of ecstacy because David Bowie was playing in Kelowna. In an auditorium that holds only 5,000 people.<br />
Naturally, we were going.<br />
This was after I&#8217;d booked my flights to Japan and back, and had Jen booked in. This meant I had to catch another flight from Calgary to Kelowna. With WestJet, not a particularly huge deal. (The flight cost about as much as the ticket to David Bowie, at least before adding on all those ridiculous taxes.)<br />
I passed out in my chair on the plane (an aisle seat) mere moments after doing up my seat belt. I vaguely remember the word &#8220;juice&#8221;, and awoke only when the plane slapped the tarmac at Kelowna. I dozed until the plane finally stopped. I was soon met by my roommate Tamara, her boyfriend Dan, and her friend Andrea. (They&#8217;d driven out earlier in the day.)<br />
Our first stop was the White Spot, a BC-favourite for restaurants. Not one of mine (don&#8217;t really care for the place), but it was food and it was cheap. That was enough for me. Then it was to the hotel (the Royal Anne Hotel, situated in beautiful downtown Kelowna, a mere block from the lake, and four blocks from Prospera Place, the site for tomorrow&#8217;s David Bowie concert) to dump the bags.<br />
We went bar-hopping, in search of something fairly decent. The sad part is that most of Kelowna&#8217;s downtown has either really seedy biker bars (read: strip clubs, and we all know how much I like those places) or yuppie pubs. We weren&#8217;t thrilled by any of them. We finally gave up around 21:00 and went back to the hotel.<br />
I shaved off two weeks&#8217; worth of beard (much to my delight &#8212; the damn thing was driving me crazy) while Tamara and Andrea watched &#8220;Princess Bride&#8221; on the TV. Dan had already passed out. The four of us were asleep before the movie was over (and we only came in halfway-through).<br />
God knows I needed the rest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">348</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
