<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>oakville &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/oakville/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>2012, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2012-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2012, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For me, 2012 was a bad year. Between a host of medical issues (brutal chest cough that led to pulled muscles, to appendicitis, to strep throat, a couple nasty colds-cum-killer flus, and a minor outpatient surgery), ridiculous amounts of stress, the ever-present struggle of being a parent to young children, a general malaise, and an unfulfilled burning need to travel, it&#8217;s truly a wonder I got out of bed in the morning.<br />
So it wasn&#8217;t with any reservation that 2012 walked out of my life on Monday night, yet it still managed to leave me rather depressed. Sadly, 2013 woke me up looking already a lot like 2012, so I&#8217;m not sure if I&#8217;m able to look at this new year with much hope yet. Instead, I suppose I shall have to try harder to make things work more my way.<br />
This not to say that I &#8220;didn&#8217;t like&#8221; 2012. It&#8217;s hard not to like an entire year in one&#8217;s life, especially one that brings so many new things to learn and experience. I just wish it hadn&#8217;t been so darned painful&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3208"></span><br />
Like I said, 2012 was a busy, busy year. So there&#8217;s no way to know if I&#8217;m going to miss anything, because I did a pretty lousy job of documenting it. I can only hope that through extracting details from Twitter, Facebook, Flickr, and my blog, that I can stir enough memories to get this all straight.</p>
<ul>
<li>Experienced our first New Year&#8217;s Tea not at the Banff Springs</li>
<li>Learned that my youngest, Choo Choo (no more than 2), was a lot smarter than I thought she was &#8230; and she only got smarter (and more defiant)</li>
<li>Saw far too few friends for far too short a time</li>
<li>Worked a lot, but not painfully so &#8212; I still had a (family) life outside of it. YAY FOR BALANCE!</li>
<li>Developed a vicious cold that led to &#8212; no word of a lie &#8212; pulled rib muscles. Owie.
<ul>
<li>Had my first chest x-ray, taken by &#8212; drum roll, please &#8212; my wife, Alex!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Discovered that Monkey loves shrimp, especially at dim sum</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t go to dim sum nearly enough</li>
<li>Had some fairly steep automobile expenses (block heater for the Jetta, and a new car for Alex)</li>
<li>Renewed a mortgage for the first time ever (instead of selling the house)</li>
<li>Continued hating, loathing, and despising having to deal with the Facebook API</li>
<li>Went through the agony, grief, despair, anger, bargaining, and acceptance of a major home renovation, as we redid our kitchen (and subsequently, floors and bathrooms)
<ul>
<li>I do so love our kitchen, though&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Found my cooking skills steadily improving
<ul>
<li>Need to watch more cooking shows, and figure out some different techniques</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Broke my little toe. Why do the little bones always hurt more?</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time ranting about how badly our Federal Government seems to want to drive Canadians to be not Canadian (specifically through bills C-11 and C-30, the ever-present Big Telco lobbies, revisiting the abortion laws, and Rob Anders)</li>
<li>Disposed of my giant water jug container of coins (6,400+ of &#8217;em)</li>
<li>Realized that building a &#8220;mobile&#8221; site is a pointless exercise, and that the design needs to adapt for all devices &lt;&#8211; my professional epiphany of the year</li>
<li>Lived (very basically) out of my contractor&#8217;s rental home for a month while our home was being torn apart</li>
<li>Celebrated Choo Choo&#8217;s 2nd Birthday</li>
<li>Cancelled TV at home, and went to internet-only for video content (still a work-in-progress)</li>
<li>Saw the original cast of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em> on stage</li>
<li>Had my first ambulance ride, my first shot of morphine, and my first (and thankfully last) bout of appendicitis
<ul>
<li>Also had a sponge bath; nowhere near as much fun as it sounds</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw <em>Avenue Q</em>. Hurt myself laughing.</li>
<li>Tried not to laugh when Monkey decided to cut Choo Choo&#8217;s hair. I failed.</li>
<li>Learned that I cannot work from home, without breaking my children&#8217;s hearts</li>
<li>Showed my children the &#8220;hole in the sun&#8221; as Venus transited our star &#8212; I think Monkey started to understand heliocentrism&#8230;</li>
<li>Exited the year wondering how RIM/Blackberry is still a going concern, and why Microsoft hadn&#8217;t fired Ballmer</li>
<li>Went to Fairmont Hot Springs</li>
<li>Went to Oakville</li>
<li>Went to Banff</li>
<li>Aaaaand that&#8217;s it, folks. Depressingly boring year for travel.</li>
<li>Turned 40. Or as I like to call it, &#8220;4, with an extraneous zero&#8221;.</li>
<li>Watched in real-time (delayed by 7 minutes) as Curiosity landed on the surface of Mars using the single most insane landing procedure ever conceived</li>
<li>Monkey became a 5 year old. I&#8217;ve been a parent for over <em>five years</em> now. And the world has not fallen apart (entirely). Who knew?</li>
<li>Tried to stop drinking coffee. Boy that was dumb.</li>
<li>Reminisced about being with the CBC TV 50th Anniversary project 10 years ago</li>
<li>Took Monkey to her first day of kindergarten; oddly, I didn&#8217;t cry</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that our family cannot operate without a second car</li>
<li>Made jam for the first time, and I shall do it again!</li>
<li>Made tomato sauce and tomato paste from scratch; there&#8217;s a reason they&#8217;re cheaper to buy in cans, sadly.</li>
<li>Made a &#8220;perfect&#8221; prime rib. Now I need to make it again.</li>
<li>Figured out how to make gluten-free stuffing for turkey (just need to tone down the spices a bit, as I discovered at Christmas)</li>
<li>Used a roto-tiller for the first time. Sadly, it had very dull blades, so using it hurt. A lot.</li>
<li>Felt my gut in my stomach as a man stood on the edge of the stratosphere. Then he jumped.</li>
<li>Somehow acquired strep</li>
<li>Got taken down, not by the strep, but by the stupid antibiotics I took to get rid of the strep. Go figure.</li>
<li>Had a very long night of trying to get my frozen, snow-bound car out of the airport parking lot.</li>
<li>Had a vicious cold knock me down for two days (minor flu?)</li>
<li>Got a re-learning of high school physics when I tried to vacuum up a box of baking soda. (Try it yourself, if you dare.)</li>
<li>Rode the new West LRT on the first day! Love that I take a train to work, now.</li>
<li>I saw <em>The Hobbit</em>. Yes, I liked it.</li>
<li>Had a minor outpatient surgery that didn&#8217;t exactly jingle my bells; made for an uncomfortable Christmas</li>
<li>Got an iPad mini for Christmas from my company. Had to admit that the Mini is actually a good idea.</li>
<li>Got (and installed) a Nest thermostat. I can&#8217;t stop fiddling with it.</li>
<li>Finally went sledding for the first time in two years.</li>
</ul>
<p>That brings me to the end of the year. So: busy, interesting, painful, trying, educational, somewhat wistful, and definitely productive. We&#8217;ll see what 2013 brings.<br />
I just hope it means no more trips to hospitals&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/2012-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3208</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIA Wi-Fi = No-Fi</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/via-wi-fi-no-fi/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=via-wi-fi-no-fi</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/via-wi-fi-no-fi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 00:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via rail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/12/28/via-wi-fi-no-fi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So I&#8217;m taking VIA from London to Oakville, saving Alex from another four hours of driving on Ontario&#8217;s highways. I&#8217;m sitting here with my trusty laptop trying to do some work, using the &#8220;Wi-Fi&#8221; service on-board. Except it doesn&#8217;t work. I can connect to the onboard gateway, no problem. It recognizes me and that I&#8217;ve &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/via-wi-fi-no-fi/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "VIA Wi-Fi = No-Fi"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I&#8217;m taking VIA from London to Oakville, saving Alex from another four hours of driving on Ontario&#8217;s highways. I&#8217;m sitting here with my trusty laptop trying to do some work, using the &#8220;Wi-Fi&#8221; service on-board.<br />
Except it doesn&#8217;t work.<br />
I can connect to the onboard gateway, no problem. It recognizes me and that I&#8217;ve been desperately trying to send and/or receive something. Anything in fact. It has my byte counts. What it doesn&#8217;t do is actually let me receive any data. So far, I&#8217;ve not even been able to pull up a Google search.<br />
I call false advertising! It doesn&#8217;t work, VIA &#8212; don&#8217;t tell me that it&#8217;s there if it doesn&#8217;t work. And it isn&#8217;t my laptop, as I know I can connect to virtually any wireless network I&#8217;ve ever seen. I can see yours but you won&#8217;t let me see anything else!<br />
Mind you, could be someone else on this train using up all the bandwidth for porn&#8230;<br />
(And if you&#8217;re wondering how on Earth I posted this despite not having any connectivity, I offer the simplistic Notepad + Copy &amp; Paste method.)<br />
<em>[Ed. Note: When we got past Brantford, it actually seemed to work, albeit not very well. I wouldn&#8217;t rely on VIA&#8217;s WiFi service for anything mission-critical, though it was still better than the next-to-nothing access I had with the CBC.]</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/via-wi-fi-no-fi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">592</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Merry Old London (Ontario)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-merry-old-london-ontario</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 03:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/12/27/in-merry-old-london-ontario/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We arrived last night, around 20:00 local time. A quick run through the airport, and we were tracking through the back country out to Janice&#8217;s place in Kintore. The house was cool (old farm houses tend to lack a lot of insulation or it mostly needs to be replaced) so Alex was a little chilly &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "In Merry Old London (Ontario)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We arrived last night, around 20:00 local time. A quick run through the airport, and we were tracking through the back country out to Janice&#8217;s place in Kintore.<br />
The house was cool (old farm houses tend to lack a lot of insulation or it mostly needs to be replaced) so Alex was a little chilly most of the time. We watched <em><a href="http://us.imdb.com/title/tt0479647/">Bon Cop Bad Cop</a></em> until around midnight or so (22:00 our time) before we were tired enough to go to sleep. I&#8217;d picked it up during what will be my last bout of Boxing Day sales. They&#8217;re hardly sales, since most of the prices (for the things I wanted) were still steep.<br />
<span id="more-591"></span>The cool house required several layers of blankets for warmth. I slept reasonably well. Alex didn&#8217;t, though more due to an inability to breathe. Janice&#8217;s house, in addition to being older, is much more humid (Ontario weather), dusty (due to age and size), and has two cats Alex&#8217;s immune system is unfamiliar with. End result: up much of the night.<br />
After giving up on trying to start Janice&#8217;s car, we got a lift from her neighbour back to the airport to pick up a rental car: a Dodge Calibur. We hadn&#8217;t asked for the Calibur &#8212; that&#8217;s what we were given. That&#8217;s what Enterprise defines as a &#8220;small car&#8221;. It&#8217;s certainly not the smallest thing on the roads, but it made for a comfortable ride out to Oakville. We figured it was a good chance to visit with family.<br />
Our first stop was at Burlington Mall to get Alex&#8217;s cousin Tara&#8217;s new baby a present. Then it was a 20 minute stop at Tara&#8217;s house before proceeding to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s. Tori was not in a mood to see us at all, and regularly ran away from both Alex and I. Turmoil is wreaking havoc with her, due to Craig working for the last several weeks in Windsor and Tori starting in day care so Cathy can go back to work.<br />
Our visit was too short, as always. We came in, chatted with Cathy and Craig, headed over to Mom&#8217;s for dinner for almost three hours, then were back on the road by 19:30 heading to London. Alex seems far more comfortable with driving in Southern Ontario than I am. Maybe I&#8217;ve become less tolerant of long-distance drives?<br />
Stopping briefly at Janice&#8217;s house again, we dropped off cat food and a new electric heating pad before heading off to the Quality Suites hotel in south London for the night. Alex needs her rest, and a room free of airborne irritants is important. Tomorrow, we join the rest of Alex&#8217;s family in St. Thomas for visitation. At some point, I&#8217;ve got to get back to Oakville for my flight home. Not sure yet how I&#8217;m going to do that&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/12/in-merry-old-london-ontario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meeting my niece for the first time</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/05/23/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spent most of last week in Critical Mass&#8217; Toronto office. I was there primarily to support our technical team, which hasn&#8217;t had the level of support from me that it&#8217;s been needing. So I went out to try and reestablish my presence other than &#8220;that guy in Calgary&#8221;. The trip was successful, though I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Meeting my niece for the first time"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent most of last week in Critical Mass&#8217; Toronto office. I was there primarily to support our technical team, which hasn&#8217;t had the level of support from me that it&#8217;s been needing. So I went out to try and reestablish my presence other than &#8220;that guy in Calgary&#8221;.<br />
The trip was successful, though I have yet to type up all my findings. That&#8217;s going to take a bit longer, as I&#8217;m sure to be put on the spot for a variety of must-do activities for this week. C&#8217;est la vie, though.<br />
<span id="more-437"></span>I didn&#8217;t return to Calgary with Paul on Thursday, though. I stuck around for the weekend, as I&#8217;d already planned to be in Oakville for the weekend. Back in January, my family expanded by one with the birth of my niece. Since then, Alex and I had tried to figure out when the best time was to go out and visit. As such planning tends to go, it was arduous, difficult, and ultimately it came down to picking a weekend and going. It would be barely over a week since returning from the UK and Ireland.<br />
Turns out it was the best thing for me. Returning from the UK wasn&#8217;t easy for me. As I discovered last year, it&#8217;s very easy to get into the travel groove. The constant stimulation is amazing, almost addictive. Coming down is ugly, often fettered with depression. The last thing I wanted to be dealing with is wishing I were somewhere else, when I need to concentrate on the here-and-now. So changing quickly from Calgary to Toronto actually turned out to be a benefit. Get some travel in me, but set me up for being home.<br />
Then there was seeing my neice for the first time. Cathy and Craig met me at the train station (literally next door to Mom&#8217;s condo) pushing around their daughter in a carriage to help her sleep. Small, adorable, and looking more like her father than her mother. It wasn&#8217;t until we got into the condo and she woke up that she first saw me.<br />
And immediately smiled.<br />
Now it could be argued that a child of her age (barely four months) does not have the ability to fully discern who she&#8217;s seeing or how specifically to react. I&#8217;m sure hundreds of reports have been written about the mental processes of a newborn, and that most of them strongly doubt the ability to recognize things definitively. But there&#8217;s also a case for the potential for genetic memory &#8212; that it&#8217;s possible to recognize features through genetic programming.<br />
It&#8217;s a thought.<br />
Meeting my niece gave me pause. Partly because I&#8217;ve never really been comfortable around babies, but because this is a new life in my family. Unlike all the other babies I&#8217;ve been around, she&#8217;s related to me. Not through marriage, but by blood. Genetically similar. It&#8217;s a different thing to see a cute baby, and then see a baby you&#8217;re related to. (And Mom thinks she looks like I did at her age. Cathy doubts it. I&#8217;m undecided.) But it&#8217;s a cool effect, too. You feel a certain amount of attachment to her.<br />
I held her only once while there &#8212; she still depends greatly on Cathy for support. And I tried to comfort her when they drove us out to the airport &#8212; she doesn&#8217;t like her car seat very much &#8212; but I&#8217;m not the fatherly type just yet. I felt bad, though. All that pain, and no way for me to remove it.<br />
Parenthood. The next great adventure. I wonder what it has in store for me, when it finally happens. I know I&#8217;ll never be ready for it, and it will change my life. I guess if nothing else, I worry mostly about failing at it. Only time will tell, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/05/meeting-my-niece-for-the-first-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 04:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/12/31/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day. So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day.<br />
So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 on the morning of 23 December, catching the end of a nasty two-day snowstorm. There&#8217;s poetic justice in this, somewhere.<br />
<span id="more-480"></span>Due to the weather, Cathy (wisely) opted not to come and get me at the airport. Instead, I took a limo (for the extra five dollars, it was worth the comfort) out to Oakville. Since Cathy had to go into work, and I didn&#8217;t have a key to her house, I went to Mom&#8217;s place instead. Cathy had already called her to let her know I was coming, before I called her to let her know I was coming.<br />
I made myself a light breakfast, and then let the red eye flight catch up with me, passing out in Mom&#8217;s bed with my jacket over my head to block out light and sound. Mom and I hung out for a while, then went and ran some errands, concluding with a very lousy lunch at the Tim Horton&#8217;s at the former Trafalgar Village (I have no idea what it&#8217;s called now). The place used to be a Burger King years ago, and was pretty lousy then, too.<br />
I eventually ended up at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s, dumping my things off before the four of us congregated at Mom&#8217;s again for dinner. Ribs, one of my favourites.<br />
During dinner, I decided it was time to let my family know that things were about to change for me. I stated: &#8220;Official annoucement time!&#8221; and declared that they not make any plans for 27 August 2005. This is the day Alex and I will be married. No-one was particularly surprised, and everyone seemed happy about it. This, of course, made me feel happy about it, because I was getting more than a little anxious about the whole thing. Blessings are what I needed most. The happiness I already had.<br />
&#8216;Twas the day before Christmas, and I had a few things left to do, most of which was buying a couple of last-minute presents (most notably for Craig, whom I was having trouble finding). This brought Cathy and I to Oakville Place, barely a kilometre from their house.<br />
Since Oakville Place was first built, I&#8217;d hated it. Originally, I disliked it because of the 100-odd stores in the mall, over 80 of them were dedicated to women&#8217;s fashions. For a teenaged boy, this was about as interesting as &#8230; well, a mall full of stores that had no interest to me. In later years, I came to revile it due to its marked resemblance to a two-storey strip mall. It was meant to look bright and wonderful, but its design left much to be desired.<br />
Recently, Oakville Place underwent a significant overhaul, culminating with a complete change of food courts (the old one is gone, a new, larger one is on the second floor in the new &#8220;wing&#8221;), several new stores (including &#8212; GASP! &#8212; an HMV), and a few other changes. The pit in the centre under the clock has been gone many a-year, but following it are the two fountains that used to exist at either end of the main section under the stairs. The stores are actually nicer than I remember (with a few exceptions), and it feels more like a mall than an oversized women&#8217;s fashion store.<br />
Dinner that night was not at Mom&#8217;s or at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s. For this, we would travel across town to Mark and Darla&#8217;s. This was the first time that I would see Mark and Darla&#8217;s home (completed; I saw it over a year ago &#8212; see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion]]). I hadn&#8217;t really seen them since Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding.<br />
Mark had invited us over for Christmas Eve dinner, which would be roast beef and yorkshire pudding (which Cathy would make, following the time-honoure recipe that came with the roast pans Dad bought in the States eons ago). This, I looked forward to. I *love* roast beef, especially when prepared by those passionate about it.<br />
Mark and Darla&#8217;s home is quite beautiful. Very tastefully decorated, and already full of the smells of dinner. We were a bit late in arriving, which meant that dinner was well on the way to being ready. Also in attendance were Julie and Dave, whom I hadn&#8217;t seen for almost as long as the last time I saw Mark and Darla. We settled into conversation before we were called to the dinner.<br />
The first round was a smashing corn chowder. That was followed by the roast beef, onions and parsnips, yorkshires, mashed potatoes, and peas. Dessert was a mousse cake from &#8220;La Petit Gateau&#8221;, which is either a really neat little pastry shop, or an in-joke about a supermarket that I never got filled in on. Either way, all was very tasty. Mark went all out.<br />
Even moreso when Cathy, Mom, and I recognized what Mark wore around his neck. When Mark was first going to Appleby College, it was Dad who had taught Mark how to tie a tie. When we were cleaning out Dad&#8217;s things after his death, Cathy had given Mark one of Dad&#8217;s trademark paisley ties. It was this tie that Mark wore over dinner. Given how the meal turned out, I would hedge to bet that Dad had shown up just to give a little advice.<br />
Following dinner was a game &#8212; Scene It. This neat little game includes a DVD that you use as part of the questions. Mark had played it before, but the rest of us had not. We split into four teams: Mark, Darla and Julie (Dave had gone to bed, a victim of a 38-hour day), Cathy and Craig, and Mom and myself. Owing to a series of fortunate rolls and good questions, Mom and I finished the game when the others were about half-way through. (I hate to say it, but they were up against a movie geek. I really wonder how Chris, Stuart, and I would fare against each other.) The others finished neck-in-neck.<br />
Cathy, Craig, and I would stay up a bit late that night, talking about generally nothing (Cathy blaring loud music) before we all went to bed.<br />
Mom arrived around 9:00 the next morning for Christmas day. Her only stipulation was that she wanted to be home before 13:00 to make the turkey. This would not be a problem. A new tradition was started with present unwrapping. In previous years, &#8220;Santa&#8221; (which was usually me) would hand out a present to each person, who would then unwrap it in turn. This year, Cathy and Craig instituted the &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; rule. Basically, they said &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; and everyone unwrapped. The 1-2-3s got progressively faster as the unwrapping progressed.<br />
Interestingly enough, most of the presents I got weren&#8217;t just for me &#8212; they were also for Alex. They included a picnic backpack (as opposed to a basket), a picnic blanket with inflatable headrests, a flashlight, and walkie-talkies. It wouldn&#8217;t be the only time I would regret Alex not being able to come out to Ontario. (She was at her father&#8217;s place in Ruskin.)<br />
Breakfast was a mom-saver: bread, eggs, cream cheese, and a lot of maple syrup. It cooked while we unwrapped. Mimosas washed it down well.<br />
Mom left just before 11:00 for home, while Cathy, Craig, and I wandered around the house. Hamilton Dave (formerly Scarborough Dave) arrived not long afterwards. He was joining us for dinner that night. The last time I&#8217;d seen him was at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding (see [[Cathy and Craig&#8217;s Wedding]]).<br />
The gifts kept coming. Dave received a clock from Cathy and Craig for his boat. In exchange, Cathy and Craig received heated cups for their car. This precipitated a test, where Craig took the remote thermometer, some hot water, and placed the mug in his car to see what would happen. (It works, for the record, but keeps the temperature rather than raise it.) Julie and Dave stopped by for a beer before heading onto other parts for the day.<br />
Dinner was at Mom&#8217;s. It seemed odd to be having dinner there, though I can&#8217;t really tell you why. Maybe because it&#8217;s not the house on Gatestone, where I&#8217;d had so many Christmas dinners before. Hopefully, Christmas dinner will be at our place next year!<br />
We got back and played Possumopoly (a parody of Monopoly based on the <em>Red Green</em> TV show). Craig is plain evil. We played until Dave pretty much passed out from all the beer.<br />
Boxing day was all about the board games. Cathy, Craig, and I played from noon almost all the way through until we went to bed. (It takes a long time to place the Ontario Trivia game.) More visitors passed through, including Mark and Darla. Walkie talkies were tested as Craig went out for supplies at the local convenience store. Pizza was our only other interruption.<br />
The next day, Mom and I went out for Greek for lunch. We then did a little shopping (including presents for Chris and Kaz &#8212; books on Canada, a subtle hint for him to move back). The party that night was the fifth (and hopefully final) wedding party for the two of them (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]] and [[Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba]]). I was literally the token white guy. Therese and Stuart couldn&#8217;t make it as they&#8217;d only arrived in town 10 minutes before the party started, and wanted to visit with family. Gerry was also in the area, but lines were crossed and our paths weren&#8217;t. I would miss out on Gerry&#8217;s presence this time around (Chris would catch up with him a couple days later).<br />
Oddly enough, none of these absences really bothered me &#8212; it gave me a lot of time to chat with Chris and Kaz. And joke with Kaz about being so cold. And I did get a chance to talk with Gerry the next morning.<br />
Chris, Kaz, and I met up with Stuart and Therese for dim sum the next morning. I picked up Chris and Kaz from Chris&#8217; parents&#8217; place, a rental while they wait for their new house to be built. It&#8217;s weird not seeing them in the house I knew. Weirder still was seeing Aidan, Therese and Stuart&#8217;s daughter. It&#8217;s still hard to believe my friends are reproducing. She&#8217;s a doctor (in psychiatry) and he&#8217;s an art director for a major ad firm. We&#8217;ve somehow all grown up. It&#8217;s kind of creepy, actually.<br />
Therese looked like herself again, assumedly due to the lack of a parasitic organism inside her. Stuart looked tired, but the new &#8216;do helped. Kaz wanted to smuggle Aidan back to Japan. We ate and talked for a long time. But eventually we had to part ways. I had to go home. I dropped Chris and Kaz at Clarkson station, not knowing when I&#8217;d see them next.<br />
I thought I&#8217;d done a great packing job, only to realize that I&#8217;d forgotten a few things. I had to steal a duffel bag from Craig to get it all home. Steak and Caesar salad &#8212; a Sowrey favourite &#8212; was my last supper before the flight. Despite a full, uncomfortable flight, Alex was waiting for me when I got back.<br />
I realized how much I&#8217;d missed her for the last few days. It was a realization that she is <em>The One</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">480</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying home to Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=flying-home-to-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2004 22:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/27/flying-home-to-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I woke earlier than usual &#8212; about 8:45 or so. Craig was still up, but not nearly as tired as when he&#8217;d scared the bejezesus out of me. Turning down his offer of a beer (for Craig, this was still the end of the day), I got a glass of orange juice. Craig and I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Flying home to Calgary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke earlier than usual &#8212; about 8:45 or so. Craig was still up, but not nearly as tired as when he&#8217;d scared the bejezesus out of me.<br />
Turning down his offer of a beer (for Craig, this was still the end of the day), I got a glass of orange juice. Craig and I took the opportunity to have a chat about his career. I guess I forced the issue. I&#8217;m worried about him. I don&#8217;t know Craig as well as perhaps I could &#8212; he&#8217;d family, but aside from a few visits, I don&#8217;t know him even remotely as well as I should for a brother-in-law. For what I do know, though, Craig works too hard. I know the desire, though. I know what drives him, what pushes him forward. I had that drive once. It&#8217;s died off in recent months, mostly due to recognition of my own faults.<br />
<span id="more-330"></span>Nothing really came of the conversation, not that I thought anything would. I can only hope, though, that perhaps he&#8217;ll settle into a more regular schedule that will allow him to have some quality of life. At least more than he has now.<br />
Mom arrived about 30 minutes after I called her to take me back to her place. I had to finish fixing her computer. Norton Security had to be removed because it was blocking functionality. I installed just Norton Anti-Virus instead, which seemed to cooperate significantly better than the full suite. It installed well, and everything seemed to work. With that in place, I started up the defragmentation program to help speed mom&#8217;s computer up.<br />
By that time, Cathy had arrived at mom&#8217;s, off early from work, and the three of us went for lunch at Mexicali Rosa&#8217;s, one of a chain of Mexican-themed restaurants. Apparently, there were a couple of them in Ottawa, back in the day I used to live and work there. Cathy told me of them, but I honestly couldn&#8217;t remember any of them. Either way, I was in the mood for Mexican.<br />
The food was good, but the sangria was lacking. In fact, I was a tad disappointed, especially since I&#8217;d raved about how good sangria was to Cathy. I&#8217;ll have to make an effort to find really good sangria out here, so that when Cathy and Craig come out here for our cousin Pam&#8217;s wedding in September, I&#8217;ll be able to show them something really tasty.<br />
Following our lunch, we did a driving tour out to Port Credit. A few things had changed. A new strip mall complex at the corner of Southdown and Royal Windsor caught me by surprise. Even more surprising was the redevelopment of the St. Lawrence Starch grounds was extremely impressive, and certainly out of the range of most ordinary people. My mother couldn&#8217;t hope to afford one of them, although they are nice.<br />
The defrag was still running when we got back. I can only assume because it hadn&#8217;t been run in a very long time. But I wouldn&#8217;t be able to see it finish, as I had to get to the airport. I had a flight back to Calgary to catch. I bade mom goodbye, and headed to Cathy&#8217;s house to collect my things.<br />
I remembered why I don&#8217;t like Toronto traffic. On the way to the airport, I bore witness to the nastiest traffic jams on the westbound lanes of both the 403 and the 401, neither of which we were in. (Though Cathy would have to be heading in that direction after dropping me off.) I am so glad I walk to work, and drive as rarely as possible.<br />
Things had changed at the airport. Terminal 1 is no more. In the redevelopment of the GTAA, and the construction of the new terminal, the old was swept away. It was there when I was in Oakville last October (see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion]]), but since then was torn down. Soon, Terminal 2 will follow suit, and only the new terminals will remain.<br />
As I sat waiting for my flight to board, an announcement came over the PA. Apparently, there was a weather advisory for Calgary. There was a chance that we might not arrive in Calgary &#8212; we could get diverted to Kelowna.<br />
I didn&#8217;t see this as a particularly bad thing. At the very least, I&#8217;d get a good story out of it. Besides, I had relatives there that I could call upon if I were really stuck in a bind. But I also figured that because Calgary&#8217;s weather literally changes in a matter of minutes, the odds of me not making it to Calgary were fairly slim.<br />
End result: the flight was about half-full. I had a row to myself. We got snack bags two at a time. (We were flying WestJet, which means no meals. Not that I mind &#8212; a nice ham and swiss from Tim Horton&#8217;s fills the void quite well.) Aside from the three French guys in front of me (who seemed barely out of their teens, despite being well into their 30s), I had a very pleasant flight.<br />
Except for landing in Calgary. As we approached for landing, I had glanced out the window to see where we were. I saw what I thought was the sun setting far off in the distance (though it seemed far too late for that), or perhaps the moon in an odd position. In reality, it was the lights of Calgary shining through the fog that seemed to hug the ground.<br />
I suppose that as we decended through the clouds, I should have been a little frightened. Flying by instrumentation is fine, but visions of Die Hard 2 kept coming to mind. The last thing I really needed was to slam into the ground at far too fast a rate of decent. I didn&#8217;t think about it too much, though. Aside from a harder-than-usual landing, the approach wasn&#8217;t really that bad &#8212; even if the clarity at ground level couldn&#8217;t have been more than the height of the air traffic control tower.<br />
As I arrived home, I realized that I felt relaxed. There&#8217;s a certain clarity that comes with a vacation, even one as busy as the one I&#8217;d just had. I actually felt good about my time off. Perhaps I&#8217;ve been a little too critical of work lately. Maybe things aren&#8217;t as bad as I think they are. I know I&#8217;ve overcomplicated my life as of late, so maybe it&#8217;s something I need to work on.<br />
Who says New Years resolutions have to happen at New Years?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/flying-home-to-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friends from university</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=friends-from-university</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2004 22:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waterloo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/26/friends-from-university/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pretty much keep with the trend, I woke late again. When I walked out of the bedroom, though, I found the door to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s bedroom open. Given the time of the morning, I assumed Craig would be asleep. I peered in to see if perhaps he had simply not closed the door. &#8220;Good &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Friends from university"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pretty much keep with the trend, I woke late again. When I walked out of the bedroom, though, I found the door to Craig and Cathy&#8217;s bedroom open. Given the time of the morning, I assumed Craig would be asleep. I peered in to see if perhaps he had simply not closed the door.<br />
&#8220;Good morning, Geoff&#8230;&#8221; a voice from behind said. I damn near had a heart attack.<br />
<span id="more-329"></span>Craig was still awake, playing solitaire on the computer in the third bedroom. He looked like hell, like he hadn&#8217;t slept in days. To some degree, it wasn&#8217;t far from reality &#8212; while Craig had been catching sleep, the schedule of his workload was certainly taking its toll. Craig was staying awake a while longer to try and reset his sleeping schedule. I remembered my days of looking like him, when I worked hours far beyond reason.<br />
Those are days I do not miss.<br />
I showered, shaved, dressed, and hopped in Craig&#8217;s car. I was off to Waterloo to visit more friends, and take a little trip down memory lane. That journey started before I even left Oakville town limits. I was amazed at the amount of construction that seemed to stretch endlessly. I hadn&#8217;t driven north on Trafalgar Road for quite some time, and my memory of farmland was replaced with subdivisions.<br />
I drove quickly, soon arriving at the 401, where I started my trip west. The first thing I noticed was the dramatic increase in truck traffic that now seemed to plague the highway. Back in the days I used to drive it to Waterloo, trucks averaged maybe 1/3 of the vehicles on the road. Now they numbered well over half &#8212; maybe as many as 2/3 in some places. The second thing I noticed, which I&#8217;ve noticed before, is that everyone in this province has slowed down far too much. No-one exceeds the speed limit anymore.<br />
The trip to Waterloo was quite uneventful. There were a few new things along the way, but mostly the scenery was as I remembered it. The only major difference was more construction where the #85 joins with King St. This was a hated junction for me, because the on-ramp and off-ramp were too close together, and probably caused too many accidents, hence the new overpass they were building.<br />
University Avenue wasn&#8217;t too different. There were a few things that had changed, mostly stores, but nothing really stood out any differently than it had from my university days. I pulled into the University of Waterloo campus, and went in search of a parking spot. My meagre memory told me there would potentially be spots in the parking lot wedged between the Davis Centre, Biology 2, and Engineering 3.<br />
Imagine my surprise to find a new building there.<br />
It was the first of several new things to find on campus. This was the long-awaited Environmental Engineering building, planned from when I was an undergrad. I would later find the new Co-operative Education building, a new student residence, and some changes to old buildings (such as the upgraded Engineering Lecture Hall). It wasn&#8217;t the same campus I had known, but it wasn&#8217;t far off.<br />
I met up with Kim outside the Davis Centre library. We headed off to the Campus Centre strip mall, adjacent to the Engineering buildings. We went to a new Persian restaurant that offered some rather interesting cuisine. Despite being fast food, I had a wonderful dish made of chicken in a pomegranate and walnut sauce.<br />
Kim asked for a ride to Conestoga Mall. She had a gift card to spend at the HBC stores, and Zellers was the nearest store she could get to. Without a car, she had no easy way to get up there (a bus takes forever), and me with a car, it all seemed like a good plan. Besides, I had nothing else better in mind to do.<br />
After sucking up all but the remaining $0.40 of her gift card, we headed back in the direction of the university. We got sidetracked by Chapters. Kim needed a guide book for Dublin, Ireland. She&#8217;s going there for a conference, proof that Kim not only knows what she&#8217;s doing in her line of study, but also that she knows how to save enough money to do it on her own.<br />
We headed back to the university, guidebook in hand, and did a little driving tour around the campus, so I could see what had changed. We even went over to the Columbia Lake Townhouses to view the expansion. And it&#8217;s quite an expansion &#8212; an entire new set of buildings, which are quite a bit more impressive than the ones I had lived in many years ago. I mentally wished that the new units are built better than the ones I lived in.<br />
We ended up parking in the south lot of the university, so Kim could show me her office and the pictures of her last trip to Ireland. Before long, though, I had run out of time and had to head back to Oakville. As far as I knew, I had to be back by 16:00 so Craig could go to work. It was already well past 15:00.<br />
I&#8217;d never driven so fast down a highway before &#8230; well, in Ontario, at least. The trip back was a little frustrating, mostly due to people cruising in the driving lanes. But I made excellent time, getting back to Trafalgar Rd. in a length of time that was exceedingly short. The plethora of trucks, however, caused me to miss my exit. As it turned out, it was a fortunate happenstance, since I got to take the much quicker 407 instead. Calling Craig to let him know I was running a little late, I found out he didn&#8217;t need the car until 17:30, which gave me ample time to not only vacuum out the car, but wash it, too.<br />
Not long after getting back to Cathy and Craig&#8217;s, my phone rang. It was Duncan, an old friend and roommate from university. We had made loose plans to meet up, and had more or less solidified them over the course of the day. We would join forces at the Jack Astor&#8217;s at Square One, at 19:30.<br />
The last time I&#8217;d seen Duncan was sometime in 1997, though I honestly can&#8217;t remember when. He was a roommate in my last year of university, the two of us having met a couple of years earlier in my first rhetoric class. We&#8217;d hit it off and have been friends ever since. Just before we&#8217;d moved in with each other (and another friend of mine, Mike), Duncan had met Marla, who was working on her Psychology Masters at the time. They were married last year.<br />
I arrived at the restaurant mere seconds after they did. Despite it having been almost eight years since I&#8217;d last seen Duncan, and even longer since the last time I&#8217;d seen Marla, I recognized them immediately. Duncan didn&#8217;t really look any different. Marla, however, had gained a little weight &#8230; about nine month&#8217;s weight, if you know what I mean.<br />
I know far too many pregnant people.<br />
None of us had eaten, so took a table, ordered some food, and began a 2+ hour conversation trying to catch up on most of a decade. It really brought to life the need to see old friends a little more frequently than I do. It made me wish that I&#8217;d seen my old roommate Scott when I&#8217;d been in Waterloo earlier in the day (but hadn&#8217;t thought about it until that point).<br />
Things I need to change. Too many people, and never enough time.<br />
We talked until Marla looked really tired. Considering that she was only two weeks from giving birth, I could hardly blame her. We parted ways, all of us wishing that we could have spent more time, and Marla wishing she could have had a beer.<br />
I returned home, the clock ticking louder than ever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/friends-from-university/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">329</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer repairs and financial advisors</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2004 22:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/25/computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I woke late again. I could get used to this. Mom came to pick me up after getting myself all cleaned up. We went down to her place, where I took the time to try and bring her computer up to snuff again. It seems that every time I&#8217;m out, I need to do something &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Computer repairs and financial advisors"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke late again. I could get used to this.<br />
Mom came to pick me up after getting myself all cleaned up. We went down to her place, where I took the time to try and bring her computer up to snuff again. It seems that every time I&#8217;m out, I need to do something to her computer. Sometimes it&#8217;s something simple. Other times, I spend a couple of days trying to get it to cooperate with me. Such was the case this day.<br />
<span id="more-328"></span>Mom&#8217;s computer was having virus problems. She didn&#8217;t have a virus, thankfully, but needed the software set up. The previous virus software was either outdated or broken. Either way, it was of no use. I decided the best thing was to load in the full Norton Security suite, to prevent things like spam, pop-up ads, viruses, and intrusions onto her system. It seemed like a good idea at the time.<br />
One thing about mom&#8217;s system, though &#8212; it&#8217;s Windows 98. It&#8217;s almost five years old. Installing new software into old operating systems is troublesome at best, disasterous at worst. Trying to install Norton Security onto Windows 98 tends more towards the latter.<br />
Installation finished just as mom and I had to go out for errands. Mom had a pedicure appointment at 13:00, and I had a meeting with my financial advisor at 14:00.<br />
Yes, I have a financial advisor. Why? Because I would like to be able to retire one day, and not worry about having enough money to live out to a very old age. And after my RRSPs took a serious hit when Telus nose-dived a couple years back, a professionally-managed system was of importance. This was a recommendation from my sister, who knows way more about this stuff than I do.<br />
Now, I&#8217;ve never met my advisor in person. She&#8217;s the same person who manages my mom&#8217;s account, and was the logical suggestion. I handled all my communications with Pat through email and fax. Until today, I&#8217;d never even talked to her.<br />
I was a little apprehensive when I got to the Assante offices. I wasn&#8217;t nervous to meet Pat, I just felt that perhaps the interior was a tad too flashy. The last thing I needed was for my money go to pay for a plush chair for someone else&#8217;s ass. Well, unless I bought it for them, anyway&#8230;<br />
Meeting with Pat was immensely good. Not only do I have a face to go with the name, but I have a certain clarity that goes along with having talked about options and possibilities with the person who is effectively managing my rather meagre fortune. I&#8217;m a far cry from being independantly wealthy, but I&#8217;d like to think that it&#8217;s achieveable. Although I do have a $35,000 buffer space which I should be filling as much as possible. In due time, of course.<br />
I left about 40 minutes later, feeling a lot better about being 65 many years down the road. In the more immediate future, though, I had to retrieve mom from her pedicure.<br />
Stopping briefly at mom&#8217;s to check on her computer (it was still doing a system check), we headed back out in search of dinner. Cathy, mom, and I would eat at Cathy&#8217;s tonight (Craig had to work, so I would make sure there were leftovers), and I was making dinner. If Cathy was going to put me up in her home and supply me with beer, the least I could do was make dinner once.<br />
Three racks of baby back ribs, some red potatoes, garlic, an onion, some asparagus, and a rather tasty whole wheat baguette (didn&#8217;t even know such a thing existed). Then it was off to Cathy and Craig&#8217;s to prepare the meal.<br />
Craig was still there. He looked a little tired, either from only having wakened recently or from not having slept well enough from previous day&#8217;s work. I feel sorry for his situation. There&#8217;s a certain amount of hard work that is needed in Craig&#8217;s line of work, and I certainly respect it. At the same time, though, I worry about his quality of life. He sleeps poorly, rarely sees his wife or his friends &#8212; certainly in the situation I&#8217;ve gotten myself into recently, I can&#8217;t really see that working for long.<br />
After dinner, mom headed home, and Cathy sat down to watch TV while I caught up on my Observer&#8217;s Logs. I probably would have ignored the TV were it not for the fact that it was the last episode of <em>The Bachelorette</em>.<br />
On a whole, I don&#8217;t like reality TV. It&#8217;s not really my sort of thing. They generally play to human misery at some level to make everyone else feel better. It&#8217;s not exactly what I call entertaining. I guess I&#8217;m more of a fan of fairy tale endings.<br />
Which brings me back to <em>The Bachelorette</em>. Every so often, I looked up, and watched a little bit of the show. It was down to two guys, neither of whom I remember the names of. All I know is that Cathy and probably most of the audience favoured one guy. Which of course meant that the girl had to choose the other (hey, you can&#8217;t have a perfect ending, y&#8217;know). So predictable, it was almost annoying.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/computer-repairs-and-financial-advisors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">328</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VIA Train from Montreal to Toronto</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2004 22:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[montreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[via rail]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/02/23/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Morning came early. (When your hosts have to get up early to go to work, you get up early, too.) The plan was simple: on their way to work, Therese and Stuart would drop me off at Central Station where, like when I arrived in Montreal, I would proceed to kill a couple of hours &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "VIA Train from Montreal to Toronto"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Morning came early. (When your hosts have to get up early to go to work, you get up early, too.)<br />
The plan was simple: on their way to work, Therese and Stuart would drop me off at Central Station where, like when I arrived in Montreal, I would proceed to kill a couple of hours before my train boarded (around 11:00).<br />
<span id="more-326"></span>I skipped breakfast yet again (this whole vacation thing leaves me feeling not so hungry as usual), and showered for the day. I packed up the things I had unpacked for Montreal (basically, my toiletries bag and a couple items of clothing), and waited until it was time for us to leave.<br />
Traffic in Montreal is pretty easy, at least by my standards. Other cities, such as Toronto and Vancouver, are near-nightmares in some areas. Calgary, of course, is laughable, but then I don&#8217;t drive in Calgary rush-hour anyway. It didn&#8217;t take long until we&#8217;d arrived at Gare Central. I hopped out, bade a fond farewell (it will be several months, at least, before I see them again &#8212; and next time, they will be full-bore parents).<br />
Central Station is/was the Canadian National Railway&#8217;s hub in the Montreal area, as Windsor Station was Canadian Pacific&#8217;s. I strongly suspect Central Station is a lot more recent than Windor Station &#8212; Windsor was built in the 1800s, while Central Station is more reminicent of the 1940s. It&#8217;s not the most attractive station, sadly &#8212; Gare du Palais, Toronto Union, Winnipeg Union, Pacific Central, and Waterfront are fore more appealing, at least in my eyes. But it&#8217;s a busy station &#8212; a couple of the AMT lines use Central Station as their main hub, it&#8217;s the main hub for VIA Rail east of Toronto, and Amtrak&#8217;s Adirondack train terminates at Central Station.<br />
I was rather amazed (and a bit dismayed) to find that Gare Central has no lockers. Hence, no place to put my bag away while I went off wandering. Le sigh. The thing isn&#8217;t really that heavy &#8212; about 18 lbs (according to WestJet&#8217;s baggage scale), but heavy enough that I don&#8217;t really want to lug it around everywhere.<br />
While trying to determine how to kill about an hour and a half of time, I realized that my body did in fact want to eat. I opted for what I think was a square cream cheese croissant. Odd, but still tasty. I relaxed a while, ate, and read my new book, <em>The Party Monster</em>.<br />
I eventually tired of sitting and went wandering. I headed into the various hallways that lead to the Metro, thankfully avoiding the CAW picket lines in front of CN&#8217;s headquarters (adjoining Central Station). It seems half of downtown Montreal is on strike for something. The Metro station didn&#8217;t really offer me any inspiration &#8212; I could go places, yes, but what did they offer me in the end? Deciding to head back, I realized that a map showed not only Gare Central, but also Gare Windsor. This was when I realized that they were merely a couple blocks apart.<br />
So off I went, in search of Windsor Station. But not so much for the station itself, but because like Central Station, the owning railway&#8217;s headquarters adjoined. Or rather, <em>were</em> adjoining. (Canadian Pacific relocated to Calgary back in the mid 1990s, but left offices in Montreal.) The buildings are original from the start of the CPR, and while there might not be much else to see, I had to take a look.<br />
There wasn&#8217;t much else to see. Not surprised, though a little disappointed, I returned to Central Station to await Train #61 for Toronto. It gave me a chance to buy some provisions for the trip: a sandwich, bag of chips, oatmeal chocolate chip cookie, and a bottle of Coke. Not one of them approved for my diet. But hey, I&#8217;m on vacation, like I could give a damn.<br />
The train boarded a little late, but not so much as to cause concern. Those of us going direct to Toronto and not riding in VIA 1 were herded to the sixth and last car of the train. Despite all being on one car, I managed to get two seats all to my lonesome. It&#8217;s nice when that sort of thing happens.<br />
The attendant started going through the car, informing people about the safety devices they were seated next to. Then, for reasons I don&#8217;t totally understand, she came to me and asked if I would come with her so I could learn how to open the doors. Needless to say, this was an odd thing to hear.<br />
Out of everyone in the car to receive the briefing on how to manually open the door, who gets called? Me, of course. Probably the only person in the car with an iota of railroad experience outside of the staff, who has any inkling about how this stuff works, or would want to find out in the first place.<br />
The standing rule, so I gather, is that one of the passengers must learn how one opens the LRC car doors so people can get out. It&#8217;s fairly simple, actually. Slide open the door, and flick a switch on the ceiling that will keep it from closing. Then go to one of the doors (one facing away from any other tracks, if at all possible), pull back on a lever that releases the door, pull the door open, and pop the catch over the stair well.<br />
I sat there, half-giggling to myself about the odds of that sort of thing happening to someone like me. I would suspect it&#8217;s pretty rare. The train pulled out and headed out from the labyrinth beneath Montreal and out into the daylight. You wanna talk odds? Complicate the above with what I saw next&#8230;<br />
Another VIA train, backing into Gare Central. The locomotive on the train was none other than VIA #6403 &#8212; the CBC locomotive (see the <a href="/index.php/category/cbc-tv-50th-anniversary-via-rail-train/">CBC Television 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train</a>), still dressed in it&#8217;s 50th Anniversary glory. The only thing that could have been weirder is if it had been the locomotive on my train (as it stands, we had one of the newer P42s).<br />
The train passed by Point St. Charles. Somewhere out there was Stuart and Therese&#8217;s house. I couldn&#8217;t see it, of course, but I knew it was in there, somewhere. If only that could be used as a flag stop on the line so I could get on or off. Oh well.<br />
Our first stop was at Dorval Station. While a physically separate station from the AMT station (VIA runs on the CN line, whereas the AMT runs on the adjacent CP line), it still marked my entry into Montreal &#8212; not counting the airport, of course. It would now mark my exit.<br />
As the train exited Montreal, I became acutely aware of something men are not supposed to have &#8230; biological clocks. Visiting with Stuart and Therese, and being witness to their impending parenthood, really began to make me think more about the things that might be lacking in my life. I&#8217;m 31. By this time, my mom was a mother. By this time, ancient humans were considered to be well into old age. I could actually hear my clock ticking. It&#8217;s hard to admit, but I want kids.<br />
The train was soon rocketting off towards Toronto. We had stops at Cornwall, Kingston, Guildwood, and Toronto Union. It would keep the trip blissfully short (only about four and a half hours, though we ended up coming in a little late) and quite nice. Although I was on the sunny side of the train, it wasn&#8217;t hard to catch a nap as the train&#8217;s motion lulled me into submission. Thankfully, the sound of bratty children didn&#8217;t let me sleep well. [Insert sarcasm here.]<br />
The train pulled into the Toronto Terminal Railway system, and suddenly everything was familiar again. Although I&#8217;ve only pulled into Toronto Union from the east a bare two or three times, the view is equitable with the one from the highway. You don&#8217;t miss much.<br />
Hopping off the train, I speedily bypassed the slower-walking passengers, and hurried into the GO Concourse to purchase my ticket to Oakville. A train was leaving in about 10 minutes, which was timed perfectly for me. Once on the train, I called mom and let her know that I was on my way. She would meet me at the Oakville station about 30 minutes later, and take me to Cathy and Craig&#8217;s.<br />
Upon arrival, I had a beer thrust into my hand. Now normally, I wouldn&#8217;t complain about that. However, it was Carlsberg Light. There are two problems with this. First, it&#8217;s a mega-brewery beer, which just their own nature, I don&#8217;t like. They generally have little flavour and aren&#8217;t worth the water they were brewed with. Second, and much more obviously, IT&#8217;S A LIGHT BEER. Blech.<br />
We chatted a while, discussing my trip, Montreal, Therese and Stuart (and Kicker), before heading out to dinner. Craig had to work that night, so we needed to go out before it was too late for Craig to eat. We opted for Milestone&#8217;s, which was part of the way there for him, and not too far for us.<br />
I haven&#8217;t had a meal at Milestone&#8217;s in years, and haven&#8217;t had their hot artichoke and spinach dip in years more. Theirs is the only one I like. Most other companies dump in huge gobs of sour cream or cream cheese, which ultimately ruins the flavour of both the artichoke and spinach.<br />
We had to be out of the restaurant by 21:00, as there was a private party taking over. Near as we could tell, it was a staff party. There didn&#8217;t seem to be anything more special to it. But I&#8217;m far from complaining &#8212; staff always needs to be recognized for the work they do. If you don&#8217;t recognize staff, you get disgruntled staff. And that&#8217;s not a good thing at all.<br />
Craig went off to work, Cathy and I returned to her place, and mom went home. And so began part three of my vacation. I hope the rest of this week goes nice and easy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/02/via-train-from-montreal-to-toronto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">326</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I want to go home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=wanna-go-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2002 06:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/14/wanna-go-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been on the road far too long. Last night was Thanksgiving dinner up at the cottage. Good food, family, friend (there was only one), and good times. Even better sleep, in my old bed (since co-opted for use in the loft). Mom and Cathy drove me down to the airport. We made a side &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I want to go home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been on the road far too long.<br />
Last night was Thanksgiving dinner up at the cottage. Good food, family, friend (there was only one), and good times. Even better sleep, in my old bed (since co-opted for use in the loft).<br />
Mom and Cathy drove me down to the airport. We made a side trip to see a rather uninteresting antique dealer in Gravenhurst. Aside from that and a couple of bathroom breaks, we made Pearson in a fairly good time.<br />
We grabbed a late lunch at Swiss Chalet. I checked my luggage after eating, and we switched to the bar.<br />
Even though I was at the airport, boarding pass to Calgary in hand, I didn&#8217;t really feel like I was going anywhere. I was in a bar with my family, as I&#8217;ve been (a few too) many times this year.<br />
Mom and Cathy were soon off for Oakville, leaving me to wait for my flight. (We left early to beat the returning weekend traffic. We left perhaps a little too early.)<br />
I waited at gate B20 for about an hour, reading Wired. Nothing out of the ordinary (at least for me, lately). Even when WestJet staff started yelling for passengers (the microphone to the PA system wasn&#8217;t working), there was no rush. For me, it&#8217;s all routine.<br />
I think I&#8217;ve actually travelled too much this year.<br />
But as I boarded the plane and took my seat, a feeling of reserved relief crept upon me. I&#8217;m going home. My month and a half abroad is ending in a few short hours. Tonight I will sleep in my own bed in my own home. I will see my cats. (Tomorrow, I&#8217;ll have to go back to my job &#8212; hey, it can&#8217;t all be roses.)<br />
I&#8217;m tired. Take me home. Please.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">249</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
