<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iona &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/iona/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Obligatory Vacation Recap</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-obligatory-vacation-recap</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british airways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glasgow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[st. alban's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=928</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the few minutes I have before I dive back into another conference session, figured I&#8217;d cover some of the items of our last vacation. This was a 2.5 week excursion mostly to Scotland, with a few days in England. Alex planned most of the trip, with me handling things like the transportation and hotels &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Obligatory Vacation Recap"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the few minutes I have before I dive back into another conference session, figured I&#8217;d cover some of the items of our last vacation. This was a 2.5 week excursion mostly to Scotland, with a few days in England. Alex planned most of the trip, with me handling things like the transportation and hotels to stay along the way. Overall, about a 50/50 split on the events et al.<br />
Sadly, at the end, it wasn&#8217;t a usual vacation. Until now, it&#8217;s always been either just me, or myself and Alex. Now there&#8217;s three of us, and the Wee One doesn&#8217;t have our stamina for travel and has a pseudo-schedule that needs to be followed from time-to-time.<br />
<span id="more-928"></span></p>
<h4>British Airways</h4>
<p>We flew BA from Calgary to London (via Heathrow). Air Canada &#8212; are you listening? These are the guys you should be looking to for level of service. Wow. Allow me to describe: We arrive at the plane along the jetway, with stroller (and babe) in hand. They tell us that they might not be able to bring the stroller on-board, but they&#8217;d let us know. They didn&#8217;t ask for seat or name &#8212; they figured it out on their own, checked the stroller, and gave us the claim ticket. They presented us with a small toy bag for the Wee One with a small stuffed plane for playtime. Free wine. Good (read: real) food. A feeling like people actually cared about the passengers&#8217; well-being. Excellent in-flight entertainment for that 8-9 flight. Sure, it costs a bit extra. But not so much that I wouldn&#8217;t even think twice about flying with them again &#8212; that&#8217;s a definite.</p>
<h4>Travelling with the Wee One</h4>
<p>Most people thought we were nuts for hauling our offspring to Europe. A seven hour time difference, air travel, trains, ferries, lots of packing and moving, and add an infant to all of that?<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/24/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/">I said it before</a>, but our kid rocks. Sleep on the flight out (sadly, not so much on the way back), adjustment to the timezone in two nights (by the third day, all was well), played a lot on the trains (although she did have trouble sleeping due to lack of space), and she didn&#8217;t keep us up at night even though we were all in the same room. It didn&#8217;t matter how many places we went or how many people wanted to hold her (the Wee One apparently is the cutest thing many Brits have ever seen, judging by the near-endless stream of comments we got).<br />
And hey, I got to spend 2.5 of constant time with my child! What on Earth could be wrong with that?<br />
About the only bad thing (if you could call it that) was one bad habit picked up by a three-week older infant, and now the raspberry has entered the vocabulary.</p>
<h4>Iona and the Iona Community</h4>
<p>This was our first stop. Iona is a small island off the coast of the Isle of Mull, which is in turn off the western coast of Scotland. (The nearest major port is Oban, in case you&#8217;re looking for a geographical reference.) The day we arrived, there was a viciously strong and cold north wind. We immediately regretted having arrived, but pressed on. The Community itself runs mostly out of the Iona Abbey, which is owned and operated by Historical Scotland. For a week, we were guests, and basically had free run of the place.<br />
That said, a week at a Christian commune (even an ecumenical one) takes a bit of a toll on the less- (or non-)devout. Although the people were wonderful &#8212; and I have to say that while I lamented the absence of meat in our meals, the things they can do with vegetables are stunning &#8212; I was happy to be on the road again for the mainland.<br />
It&#8217;s a very small island, so it&#8217;s (relatively) easy to get around on it. Though parts of it are very boggy, you can cross the island in about 30 minutes, and go the length in about three times that. Even the highest point on the island &#8212; Dun I &#8212; takes about 15 minutes to climb, if you take your time.<br />
It&#8217;s quiet, and it&#8217;s very dark at night &#8212; there are almost no street lights. It&#8217;s so quiet that doors mostly don&#8217;t have locks. The Abbey (technically-speaking) is open all the time.</p>
<h4>Oban</h4>
<p>I heard a few people trash Oban before I went there. But I have to say it&#8217;s a nice little town. It&#8217;s a good base for day trips, and there&#8217;s a lot to see in the area. You could easily stay there a week and not be bored. Given, the hotel we stayed at (Oban Caledonian) had some trouble &#8212; when you have to name the springs in your mattress due to the intimacy you&#8217;re getting with them, it&#8217;s time to replace the mattress. But I&#8217;ve stayed in far, far worse for much more money.</p>
<h4>Train Travel</h4>
<p>I love trains. Duh. You know that. So travelling all over the place on trains is generally not a problem. But I gotta say, someone has to change the rules that puts an end to the drunken football hooligans from spreading out all over the car, singing their songs and disturbing the crap out of everyone else, stinking the place up with their booze, and generally being belligerent. No, asshole, I&#8217;m not student. Unlike you, I have the good sense to travel responsibly, but there&#8217;s not enough luggage racks in the car for my backpack. That doesn&#8217;t give you the right to use it as a pillow or a reason to tell me off. (I also have the good sense to not say anything, since I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re looking for a reason to get into a fight.)</p>
<h4>Inverness</h4>
<p>I also had people tell me not to go to Inverness. Why, I have no idea. It&#8217;s a beautiful little city. The trip there north of Perth is gorgeous, with all the rolling hills. It&#8217;s the highlands there, and it&#8217;s the best way to see it all. Anyway, the city of Inverness is amazing. The River Ness seems almost Disney-esque in the way it cleanly cuts through town, with banks of green grass and the sprouting daffodils. Add to that the lovely old buildings, winding little roads, and the general hospitality of people (drunken football hooligans notwithstanding), you just can&#8217;t go wrong.</p>
<h4>Ramada Inverness</h4>
<p>Except for the Ramada Inverness. For the record, the location is excellent. But overall, I found their staff to be bordering on incompetent. There were a couple of shining stars, no question, but I kept running into people who couldn&#8217;t answer the most basic questions, such as telling me why I can&#8217;t make a long distance phone call. It drove me CRAZY. So sorry, Mom, I couldn&#8217;t call you on your birthday. I tried, really.</p>
<h4>High Tea at the Edinburgh Hilton Caledonian</h4>
<p>Just as good as we had the last time we were there. Outstanding service. Great food. Great tea. Just wish we could have been there longer. Such is life.</p>
<h4>York</h4>
<p>I finally got to spend some actual time in York. The last time we were there barely 5 hours, so didn&#8217;t see much of it. That said, I didn&#8217;t really understand the road map until well into the second day (I kept getting turned around) and even then still took wrong turns. Confusing, but I still love the place. I could easily do month-long stints there to do some photo essays: York at Night, York Minster&#8217;s Hidden Places, Up Close with the National Rail Museum, etc. Love it.</p>
<h4>York to St. Albans without going to London</h4>
<p>Big mistake. Too many switches, we missed a connection, and it&#8217;s too much movement. Going through London is out of the way, but it&#8217;s a lot easier.</p>
<h4>St. Albans</h4>
<p>I still love this little place. The last time, we swore we&#8217;d spend more time there the next time. But we ended up with not even 1 day again, sadly. One day, we will spend more time there. It&#8217;s a very nice place.</p>
<h4>Pictures</h4>
<p>Some are already <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/tags/scotland2008/">posted on Flickr</a>, and others will come once I get them all done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last full day on Iona</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/last-full-day-on-iona/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=last-full-day-on-iona</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/last-full-day-on-iona/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 13:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=922</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m back at the St. Columba Hotel again &#8212; the only place on the island with an internet connection, it seems &#8212; enjoying my last day here on Iona. The weather over the last few days has improved considerably, even though we had ice pellets again last evening. The last few days have been marked &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/last-full-day-on-iona/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Last full day on Iona"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m back at the St. Columba Hotel again &#8212; the only place on the island with an internet connection, it seems &#8212; enjoying my last day here on Iona. The weather over the last few days has improved considerably, even though we had ice pellets again last evening.<br />
The last few days have been marked with a variety of excursions, notably on what they call &#8220;pilgrimages&#8221; (the Community here, although ecumenial, is still devoutly Christian). The pilgrimage route here is so well-known it&#8217;s even published on maps. They tell you that it&#8217;s not a &#8220;hike&#8221; because that would remove all sense of the meaning behind the pilgrimage. It&#8217;s about going to the religiously significant places on the island.<br />
Talk about being the odd man out.<br />
<span id="more-922"></span>Anyway, the experience was good. The weather actually seemed to improve as we went along, even though I found that my supposedly water-resistent shoes are anything but. I ended up having to abort the full route, as the latter half treks through the distinctly boggy part of the island.<br />
Nevertheless, I have officially been to all four shores on this island. It&#8217;s less of a feat than it sounds, since getting to all four shores can be done in a matter of a day without too much effort. The island is very small, and except for the wet parts of the south end of the island, you can pretty much hit all four sides without a great deal of effort.<br />
I also trekked up Dun I (pronounced &#8220;dun-ee&#8221;), which is the tallest point on the island, about 103 metres. I&#8217;m convinced that it&#8217;s not actually a hill of stone, as is much of the island. I think it&#8217;s actually an ancient (and massive) heap of sheep dung from the plentiful flocks that roam the island. The herders have to put it all somewhere, right? I think the farmers have just passed it off as a &#8220;holy mountain&#8221; just to keep the tourists happy.<br />
(Yes, I&#8217;m kidding. If you&#8217;ve read any of this blog, you know enough not to take me seriously.)<br />
Tomorrow, we head back to Oban to overnight again before heading off to Inverness. Not really sure how all that will go, but I&#8217;m looking forward to the trip. I feel like I&#8217;ve been cooped up in the abbey far too long, and I need to see something new. Then it&#8217;s off to York, St. Alban&#8217;s, and home again.<br />
Then I&#8217;m off to San Francisco not even two days later. Oy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/last-full-day-on-iona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">922</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life on Iona</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/life-on-iona/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=life-on-iona</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/life-on-iona/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 15:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=921</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, we&#8217;re into Day 2 on our Iona Community experience. Thus far it&#8217;s been &#8230; well, chilly. The weather here is reminiscent of something we tried to leave back home. Only windier with the sea dampness to add to the chill. Walking about is a little hard right now, so I haven&#8217;t been much further &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/life-on-iona/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Life on Iona"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we&#8217;re into Day 2 on our Iona Community experience. Thus far it&#8217;s been &#8230; well, chilly. The weather here is reminiscent of something we tried to leave back home. Only windier with the sea dampness to add to the chill. Walking about is a little hard right now, so I haven&#8217;t been much further than the abbey itself.<br />
I suppose you gotta start somewhere, right?<br />
<span id="more-921"></span>So far, the Wee One has been a joy to travel with. The flight was trivial (compared to what we feared), and by third day had effectively adjusted to the time zone. (I think there might have been a faster change, had it not been for all the travelling on the second day.)<br />
The train trip from London to Glasgow on Virgin was wonderful and exceedingly prompt. We even arrived nine minutes early &#8212; Allen surprised us at the station. I hadn&#8217;t actually expected to see them until Oban. The Glasgow-Oban leg of the trip was very picturesque, although the Wee One was getting pretty darn cranky about the trip at that point and made sure the two-car train knew it.<br />
Oban is a nice place, but didn&#8217;t really get to see much beyond the esplanade and the Tesco. With luck, we might see a bit more of it on the way back. We will see.<br />
The Iona Community is an interesting thing. It operates at the abbey, so we actually become &#8220;residents&#8221; for the week we&#8217;re there. That includes serving food and cleaning. I got the bathroom floors. There&#8217;s also a priority on worship &#8212; I think I&#8217;m going to try hide in the library as much as possible.<br />
We&#8217;re always cold. The Abbey is 14th century, and fibreglass wasn&#8217;t really known at the time. Windows are single pane, and you always hear the wind. (The Library has gaps in shutters right to the outside.) Most everyone wears a jacket all the time. But the food is good and the people are very nice &#8212; they seem to have taken our child as a mascot of sorts, it seems. They rub for good luck. A mini Buddha.<br />
We&#8217;re here until Friday, then off back to Oban then on to Inverness. I hope I get to see more of the island, but the wind has to die down first. I&#8217;m losing ideas in the gusts&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/life-on-iona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">921</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Up-coming travel</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=up-coming-travel</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 20:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[england]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/22/up-coming-travel/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it. So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months. First, the family is off to Scotland &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Up-coming travel"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it.<br />
So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months.<br />
<span id="more-894"></span>First, the family is off to Scotland again. This time, more Scotland than England. And no Ireland. Allen and Alex want to visit Iona. A week on a small rural island with ancient churches. I can&#8217;t think of a better place for a photo essay, myself. Then off to the Inverness area (hello, Nessie!), through York for a couple of days (a <em>whole day</em> in the National Railway Museum!), then home again. That&#8217;ll be early April.<br />
And, yes, El Bebe is coming with us. Not sure how this is going to work &#8212; both Alex and I are a bit apprehensive about the time difference. Alex has trouble with the shift &#8212; I can only imagine how the wee one will handle it. We&#8217;ve heard that this is the best time to travel with children, so they (kind of) get used to it. But it does mean we can&#8217;t move at my preferred break-neck pace. Instead of going right to Iona, it&#8217;s going to take two days from the time we land. I can hack that, though.<br />
Next up is a business trip to Chicago, which is actually first in the list, coming up in the second week of February. The Technology Department leadership (which includes me) will be trying to figure out our long-term plans and aspirations. It&#8217;s going to be an interesting session.<br />
Finally &#8212; at least currently on the radar &#8212; is a weekend in Las Vegas. I&#8217;m going down for Tamara&#8217;s wedding. That&#8217;s the second weekend in March. I haven&#8217;t been there in 12 years, so this should make for an interesting experience.<br />
I can&#8217;t wait to get back on the road again!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">894</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
