<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>networking &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/networking/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 18:10:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Network Connection</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-network-connection</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 18:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something.   For me, it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Network Connection"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something.  <br />
For me, it&#8217;s music.  <br />
<span id="more-1148"></span>Feel free to sing along. I&#8217;m sure <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSFLZ-MzIhM">you know the tune</a>&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Where are there so many drops in our network<br />
Out into the internet?<br />
Our network is simple, really quite basic,<br />
But which I daily reset.<br />
So we&#8217;ve been told by our service provider<br />
We&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me.  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Who said that ATM was a good system?<br />
Bandwidth gets shared too far.<br />
All it takes is just one jerk to tie up the router<br />
And then you can&#8217;t send your TAR.  <br />
What&#8217;s so amazing &#8217;bout tech that&#8217;s so aging<br />
When fibre was just meant to be?<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me.  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">It&#8217;s down whenever it rains,<br />
I think it&#8217;s going to be tragic&#8230;
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">We&#8217;ve been promised fibre for over a month now,<br />
I hope it comes any day.<br />
Then we&#8217;ll surf the internet without an outage,<br />
And upload without delay.<br />
We&#8217;ll have our own servers and not be dependent<br />
On our Calgary family.  <br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me!  
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">La, la la lee la da do, la aw crap, the friggin&#8217; thing&#8217;s out again&#8230;</p>
<p>With apologies to Paul Williams, Kenneth Ascher, and Kermit the Frog.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web 2.0 Expo: Creating a Coherent Social Strategy for Buiness</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-creating-a-coherent-social-strategy-for-buiness/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-20-expo-creating-a-coherent-social-strategy-for-buiness</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-creating-a-coherent-social-strategy-for-buiness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 06:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oy. I can&#8217;t seem to get a decent connection to anything anymore. Too many people with wireless connections. They&#8217;ve got big-ass routers, but it ain&#8217;t helping. Gonna stay offline for reliability. Presenters: Charlene Li (Forrester Research), Josh Bernoff (Forrester Research) Seems to be partly about flogging their book Lots of companies coming into social, but &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-creating-a-coherent-social-strategy-for-buiness/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web 2.0 Expo: Creating a Coherent Social Strategy for Buiness"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oy. I can&#8217;t seem to get a decent connection to anything anymore. Too many people with wireless connections. They&#8217;ve got big-ass routers, but it ain&#8217;t helping. Gonna stay offline for reliability.<br />
<span id="more-935"></span>Presenters: Charlene Li (Forrester Research), Josh Bernoff (Forrester Research)</p>
<ul>
<li>Seems to be partly about flogging their book</li>
<li>Lots of companies coming into social, but how to handle this as a strategy</li>
<li>The focus on the technology behind Web 2.0 is on technology, which is often wrong (they have a slide on Web 2.0 approach-avoidance syndrome)
<ul>
<li>Tech changing so rapidly that it&#8217;s almost impossible to keep up to date and still keep a business focus</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Groundswell: A social trend where people use technologies to get the things they need from each other, and not from traditional institutions</li>
<li>Objectives [not technology] are the key to successful social strategy
<ul>
<li>Question isn&#8217;t about starting a community &#8212; it&#8217;s <em>why</em> you want to start a community</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Four step process to Groundswell:(done in order)
<ul>
<li>People (assess customer values)</li>
<li>Objectives (what do you want to accomplish)</li>
<li>Strategy (what relationship do you want to establish)</li>
<li>Technology (what do you have to use to make it all work)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Most of existing business operations already fit into groundswell objectives</li>
<li>Some basic-level sociam networking material (stuff we already know)
<ul>
<li>Communities will give you far more detailed (and more valuable) feedback on product ideas if you engage them</li>
<li>Branding widgets or posts signatures will help generate feedback</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Corporate blogging costs mostly about training people to act in the blogosphere</li>
<li>Keys to success
<ul>
<li>Start with customers (who&#8217;s out there, who are they, what do they need/want)</li>
<li>Choose a measureable objective (otherwise, you can tell if you succeed)</li>
<li>Line up executive backing (e.g. Michael Dell)</li>
<li>Romance the naysayers (bring them in and get them directly involved)</li>
<li>Start small, think big (can&#8217;t change the company overnight, so pick one thing to gain success)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Short presentation, seem to be asking for more time for Q&amp;A</li>
<li>Many of the questions seem to be asking about how to set things up
<ul>
<li>One point was: Who &#8220;owns&#8221; the internet at your company? Marketing? IT? Media?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>[flickr]tag:groundswell+web20expo@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-creating-a-coherent-social-strategy-for-buiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web 2.0 Expo: Community Building: Good, Bad, and Ugly</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-community-building-good-bad-and-ugly/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-20-expo-community-building-good-bad-and-ugly</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-community-building-good-bad-and-ugly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 05:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And the fun continues. Another morning at the conference, and another day of hard-core typing. I&#8217;m also up on Twitter now (le sigh), so you can get some notes as I go along. Presenters: Dawn Foster (Jive Software), Jeremiah Owyang (Moderator, Forrester Research), Bob Duffy (Intel), Kellie Parker (PC World and Macworld) Firefox crapped out &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-community-building-good-bad-and-ugly/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web 2.0 Expo: Community Building: Good, Bad, and Ugly"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And the fun continues. Another morning at the conference, and another day of hard-core typing. I&#8217;m also up on Twitter now (le sigh), so you can get some notes as I go along.<br />
<span id="more-933"></span>Presenters: Dawn Foster (Jive Software), Jeremiah Owyang (Moderator, Forrester Research), Bob Duffy (Intel), Kellie Parker (PC World and Macworld)</p>
<ul>
<li>Firefox crapped out while I was writing up some great real-time notes and lost everything. So I&#8217;m going to resort to a text editor and fix it all later. Some notes lost in this session, but hopefully I&#8217;ve remembered the broad strokes.</li>
<li>Twitter traffic appears to be killing bandwidth</li>
<li>This isn&#8217;t a presentation, it&#8217;s a panel. No pix for this one, folks.</li>
<li>Basic points:
<ul>
<li>Building communities is about people, not tools</li>
<li>Home roll, or use an existing service: Do both. You can&#8217;t expect people to just find you, you need to engage them to join and let them know that you&#8217;re there.</li>
<li>You have to put a face behind your company in the community. Setting up a Facebook page isn&#8217;t enough &#8212; someone needs to be there to be the face of the company. Especially important for blogs and/or Wikis. [Matt Cutts @ Google is a great example of this.]</li>
<li>You have to engage trolls directly to not let them run roughshod over your community. Things like: &#8220;We&#8217;re sorry you hate the colour red. We love the feedback, and will use it in our future development.&#8221; Also engage trolls with additional responsibility (e.g. follow up on a bug they&#8217;re complaining about, give them access to log and track the issue).</li>
<li>You are investing in people, not tools. You need to engage people.</li>
<li>Starting fresh is hard, and you need to bring people into the community. Can be done through hitting up evangelists, going through existing customers, setting up shop in other communities, and through blogs (etc.) to market the community</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How did Intel set up their community
<ul>
<li>Intel protects their brand very closely, but they&#8217;re also willing to take risks. That&#8217;s the basis for selling in the idea. But you have to lay down the methdology to ensure that communication backs up the brand.</li>
<li>Intel signed onto Slashdot to engage their customers directly in a forum that had been largely negative to Intel. Using their experts, they were able to start turning around opinion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: What&#8217;s the ROI?
<ul>
<li>Bob: You need to know what you were trying to do in the first place. What&#8217;s your objective? In our case, it&#8217;s affecting the conversation. If we can see a change in the conversation. If we see referal links, or organic search content, and increased logging and registration base, then we&#8217;re having affect. That&#8217;s the ROI.</li>
<li>Dawn: Looking at the participation in the community, the messages posts. Not about pageviews, but about action. Too many people use their community to generate leads. Not sure that&#8217;s the right way to be viewing it. Communities are more about awareness than purchase.</li>
<li>Kellie: We look at both pageviews and posts. Not everyone participates, so we need to see if the conversations are being read. If content is growing, but pageviews don&#8217;t grow, suggests that people might also be more efficient with the posts (e.g. not having to read more than one post to find what they want).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Do you need a dedicated person to this?
<ul>
<li>Dawn: In small companies, you probably can&#8217;t handle this sort of thing. But in large companies, or in cases where you have a large community, you would likely need a dedicated community manager.</li>
<li>Kellie: You can still have others contribute.</li>
<li>Bob: Company policy requires the business groups to have responsible bloggers (usually 4-5 per group) who can put out a few posts a week to ensure the community still runs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to you moderate the abusive language (without being accused of violating First Amendment)?
<ul>
<li>Kellie: Create a profanity list as part of your community standards, and make it in plain English. Refer to it often. Everyone (blogger or commenter) is held to it. You can say an argument is bullshit, but you can&#8217;t say a person is full of shit. Can also do moderation after the fact and clean up the mess if it&#8217;s out of hand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-community-building-good-bad-and-ugly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">933</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
