<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>weekend &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/weekend/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Torches and waterslides</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=torches-and-waterslides</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 04:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Torches and waterslides"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, it&#8217;d been over a month since the last time you swam in a pool, and I thought it high time we went for a swim. In fact, it was so overdue that I felt it was also a good time to go for a Surprise Weekend. And that&#8217;s a big deal, because it&#8217;s been almost a year and a half since our last one.<br />
Why so long? It&#8217;s been a number of things. First, I worked a lot, and too hard. It wore me down and I was almost always too tired to do things that we should have done. It&#8217;s a poor excuse, Monkey, and I&#8217;m sorry that it&#8217;s all I have to offer. Second, doing things in Costa Rica was always just that much harder than it really needed to be, at least when planning for us. You can only go to Arenal so many times, and getting to the coast never seemed to be as easy for us as it was for others. After a while, we planned all of our weekends, rather than letting one of us surprise the rest.<br />
Needless to say, I wanted to change things up a bit.<br />
<span id="more-2514"></span>We went to Edmonton, the capital of Alberta, and the home of the West Edmonton Mall. Once upon a time, long before you were born, West Edmonton Mall was the largest mall in the world. Now it&#8217;s only a measly #6 &#8230; though it&#8217;s still the largest in North America. We didn&#8217;t go to shop, though. You&#8217;re not a shopper. Not yet, anyway. We went there for the World Waterpark, which (depending on whom you ask) is the largest indoor waterpark in the world.<br />
For that, we piled in the car Friday afternoon, and set our course &#8230; northwest. This is because one of the requirements of a Surprise Weekend is to keep the others guessing. Or at least, that&#8217;s how I do it. Mommy goes insane trying to get me to tell her where we&#8217;re going. It used to be cute, but I think the next time we go somewhere, I&#8217;ve got about 60 minutes of leeway before she punches me.<br />
We took Stoney Trail, which is part of the new ring road that circles about 3/5 of Calgary, from Highway #1 in the west to Highway #2 in the north. (It was then that Mommy correctly guessed &#8220;Edmonton&#8221;, but I feigned ignorance &#8212; not a stretch for your father, I might add &#8212; for nearly three more hours.) From there, we drove to Airdrie, only for a quick stop at Tim Horton&#8217;s for a couple of steeped teas, a muffin, and a donut.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stop again until we got to Red Deer, which was where we had dinner. It was one of those unplanned things in life that gets you an historic moment you&#8217;ll soon forget about, only to remember years later. In 1988, Calgary hosted the Winter Olympics (something, it seems, Calgarians never stop talking about). That winter, the Olympic flame journeyed all the way across the country, running through my hometown of Oakville &#8212; I still remember the flame being run down Lakeshore Road. Mommy saw the flame when it got to Calgary.<br />
This year, Vancouver is hosting the Winter Olympics (sadly, we won&#8217;t be going), and the flame is making a long journey all around the country. On Friday, it ran through Red Deer, right in front of the Montana&#8217;s at the south end, which happened to be the place Mommy picked for us to eat. You and Mommy stayed inside, while I went out to watch the runner pass the torch to the next person. A short historic moment you won&#8217;t remember, and Mommy and I will likely forget until the next time we see it.<br />
Once we hit the road again, I told Mommy where we were going. That allowed her to relax a bit. We drove through the darkness, the stars overhead, heading towards the distant glow of Edmonton. (Seriously, Edmonton, we could see you from Red Deer. You have a light pollution problem.) We drove along the new #216 highway through southwest Edmonton until turning off on Stoney Plain Drive, and found our Holiday Inn Express.<br />
The room was nice, and we were all pooped from the long drive. Mommy, now nearly seven months pregnant, took one bed. You got stuck with me, Monkey. And while we&#8217;re on the subject, you are the most restless sleeper I&#8217;ve ever had the misfortune of sharing a bed with. You never stop moving around, and I can&#8217;t count the number of times you tried to sleep sideways, kicking me in the ribs. I&#8217;m amazed either of us got any sleep over the last two nights!<br />
The next morning, we tramped downstairs to the breakfast buffet, before packing up and heading over to the mall. Shortly after arriving, Mommy got a call from her friend Sandra, and decided to go and visit while you and I went to the waterpark. But first, we wandered our way down to the entrance, passing the sea lion entertaining what appeared to be special guests, and watched the lemurs play in the their enclosure.<br />
We managed to get our ticket from a nice couple who had gotten the tickets through work. At $10 off the cover price ($30), we couldn&#8217;t believe our luck! You and I got changed, and Mommy waited to see us at the viewing area. She commented that I should have left our backpack in the locker, so it wouldn&#8217;t get stolen. I didn&#8217;t think it was a problem, given all the other parents with their backpacks, bags, and strollers.<br />
Our first stop was the Dolphin Pool, a kiddie pool that barely came to your waist, but had three small waterslides. You didn&#8217;t take much encouraging to go up the stairs and go down your first ever waterslide. You&#8217;d been on big slides before, and I think you thought these would be the same. But suddenly, your bum slipped out from under you, and you were whizzed down the slide into the water below. You were a little stunned, but you still got up giggling.<br />
After a little bit, we went into the big pool &#8212; the one that looked like a beach, and had the waves. The last time you felt waves was last October when we&#8217;d gone to Playa Chiquita. Mommy and I still feel bad that we didn&#8217;t get to any more beaches after that, because that was the first time you really liked going to the beach. There&#8217;s no sand at World Waterpark, but you loved the waves.<br />
As we headed back to the Dolphin Pool, I realised that Mommy was right &#8212; the bag should have stayed in the locker. It was gone, as was the towel we&#8217;d rented. I didn&#8217;t panic, but I was pretty annoyed. It wasn&#8217;t so much that my phone and credit card were in there, it was more that it had all of your diapers. That, and it really made me feel nothing but disgust for people who would take something in such a family environment.<br />
We talked to the staff, and they said they would call security. They gave us an extra towel (you were shivering something fierce), and suggested that we also look around one more time. Thankfully, far away from where we&#8217;d originally placed our things, was the bag &#8212; towelless &#8212; sitting on the last chair of the back row of the deck chairs. Whether some &#8220;clever&#8221; thief had put it there in hopes we&#8217;d not look for it, or if some kid had moved it as a joke, I don&#8217;t know. But nothing was missing (insert a big PHEWF here). I called off the hounds, and immediately put the bag in the locker.<br />
Back to the pool, we went over to an area known as  Caribbean Cove, which is a large structure (I don&#8217;t know what else to call it) where you can climb, turn wheels, pull on ropes, lift handles, and generally just get utterly soaked. You didn&#8217;t like it quite as much the first time (more the second time), and we went back to the Dolphin Pool again.<br />
After a while, I convinced you to go on a waterslide, the only one I could take you down with me. Sadly, my choice of bathing suit appeared to be really bad, because we got stuck a few times on the way down. You giggled and cheered &#8220;whee!&#8221; anyway. The waterslide seemed to pique your interest, though, and back at the Dolphin Pool, you happily ran up the waterslide stairs, slid down, and repeated until it was time to go.<br />
It was almost 13:30 before we found a restaurant to eat at, and it was over an hour before we&#8217;d finished. (The service at Moxie&#8217;s, though apologetic, was borderline intolerably slow.) We headed out to the car, and back to the hotel so you could nap.<br />
For dinner, we went to one of the most Canadian of restaurants: Swiss Chalet. Given you run-in with chicken at lunch, we opted to order you a kid&#8217;s pizza. Mommy had a salad, which I was tempted to copy, but I got suckered into one of my old favourites, the quarter chicken. The Chalet Sauce hasn&#8217;t changed since I was a kid &#8230; nor had the decor of that particular location, from what I could tell. Our server was beyond amazing, however, and was an utter joy.<br />
You and I both reeked of chlorine, something you&#8217;re not familiar with, but thankfully a bath managed to get most of the stench off of you. I would have to wait until this morning&#8217;s shower to get the smell off of me. (That, and wrestle another night with you kicking me in the ribs.)<br />
After breakfast this morning, we went back to the Mall (&#8216;cuz, really, what else is there to do in Edmonton?), with the idea of going to Galaxyland. It&#8217;s an amusement park in the Mall (you&#8217;re going to find this hard to believe, but most malls don&#8217;t have rollercoasters), and has a play area exactly for kids your age. It&#8217;s only $6, and Mommy and I get to go in with you. And unlike everywhere else we&#8217;ve been, we get to climb with you, too (mostly because somethings are a bit too much for you at this age).<br />
You went in the bouncy room, trudged through the ball pit, climbed up and down the padded levels. I took you way up high to go down one of the slides. At first, I thought I might just send you down on your own, but thankfully I had enough sense to go with you &#8212; the slide was very dark inside. You seemed unimpressed with it. Your second slide you did on your own, which was far less of a success &#8212; I heard the distinct down of squeaking skin, and you came down feet-first on your belly. You weren&#8217;t happy at all.<br />
After a bit more playing, I took you on a small train that runs around Galaxyland. Despite being excited to go on, I think you were disappointed that you didn&#8217;t get to run the train. We went for lunch &#8212; you split a Mr. Sub sandwich with Mommy &#8212; and then hit the road for Calgary.<br />
As we drove home &#8212; you slept all the way to Red Deer &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t help but stare  wistfully  at the flatness that surrounded us. Driving in Costa Rica, it was exceedingly rare to see a flat area, as the country is so mountainous. Even rarer are long stretches of straight road. But up here, you can look around for 360 degrees and see nothing but a straight horizon, the road you&#8217;re travelling on disappearing way off in the horizon in a dead-straight line. I hadn&#8217;t realised how much I&#8217;d missed it.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long weekend of fun, Monkey. I hope you enjoyed it. We&#8217;ll be going back again, and I hope with each successive time, you enjoy it more and more. And hopefully, your sister will like going there, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/torches-and-waterslides/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2514</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend at Tabacon</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-at-tabacon</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend at Tabacon"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active Arenal volcano, and dinner and a splash at the <a href="http://www.tabacon.com/">Tabacon Hot Springs</a>.<br />
At the time we&#8217;d been there, it was highly magical. We&#8217;d seen lava (in the form of red-hot tumbling rocks) rolling down the side of the mountain, the clouds of steam rolling through the trees illuminated by the carefully-placed lights. It was something to behold.<br />
Ever since then, Alex had wanted to go back. Rack up Surprise Weekend in Costa Rica #3.<br />
<span id="more-1096"></span>We left Saturday just after lunch, taking a route up through Naranjo, Cuidad de Quesada (also known as San Carlos), and then angling west through La Fortuna. This was not exactly an ideal route, since it&#8217;s a national highway &#8212; despite the insane amount of curves present in the road &#8212; which means a lot more (slow) truck traffic.<br />
We arrived around 16:30 (it&#8217;s about a 3-3.5 hour drive, albeit a very nice drive) and checked in right away. A nice room (with air conditioning), two on-site <a href="http://www.cafebritt.com/">Cafe Britt</a> stores (one in the hotel, the other in the hot springs facility), and a couple of very nice restaurants.<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+hotel+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was when we found out how expensive Tabacon can be. Although the room rate for the weekend wasn&#8217;t too bad (technically less than the one at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/">Ylang Ylang</a>), it does not include any meals (whereas Ylang Ylang covered breakfast and dinner). A $75 buffet bill said that we were in for a pricey weekend.<br />
That&#8217;s the first myth of Tabacon &#8212; very nice hotel, but far too-expensive food for the quality that you get. The second myth is that the hot springs open at 8:00 in the morning. Which is true &#8212; they do, but you&#8217;ll find the water levels in the river are practically non-existent, as the water is diverted to fill the swimming pools, which starts around 9:00. So you can&#8217;t really use the hot springs until at least 10:00.<br />
On Sunday, we went out for an excursion to find a butterfly farm (Alex had promised Mi Pequeña Niña that we&#8217;d go see butterflies). We had to drive to the south side of Lake Arenal to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>, which took us on a very picturesque journey around the volcano. Which &#8212; apparently a sign of good luck &#8212; was mostly free of clouds for once. Many photos were taken.<br />
[flickr]tag:arenal+volcano+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The Butterfly Conservatory is near the end of a very rough road, off of a bumpy and rocky gravel road, off of another dirt road. (Driving back onto pavement after all that was a joy.) It sits atop a hill that provides &#8212; without question &#8212; one of the finest views of the Arenal volcano. This would be an exceptional place to take pictures at night during an eruption, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that driving there in the dark is a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢.<br />
The tents that contain the butterflies are down in a valley (a former cattle ranch turned into a reforestation project, after it was realised that putting cattle on volcanic soil is also a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢), which pretty much eliminated all breeze, and turned it into a bit of a boiler. Everyone was sweating profusely. But the butterflies were in significantly larger numbers than at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/">Spirogyra</a> &#8212; and some species that we hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+butterflies+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Luckily, we&#8217;d gained a tour guide part-way through the second (of four) butterfly tent, who not only showed us the butterflies and their names (given her limited English and our even more-limited Spanish), but also played with Mi Pequeña Niña while Alex and I snapped pictures). Sadly, I never did get her name, so all I can say is &#8220;Thanks, whomever you are!&#8221;<br />
Butterfly Conservatory also has a little frog habitat with some of the native Costa Rican frogs. Our guide was kind enough to bring the non-poisonous ones to the front of their enclosures so we could see them more closely. Otherwise, it would have been a bit hard to see them at all.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+frogs+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Naturally, Alex and I visited the hot springs whenever we could &#8212; what else would be the point of staying at Tabacon if we didn&#8217;t? Alex also took advantage of the five-star spa there, and hasn&#8217;t stopped talking about it yet. (I have to admit, it does sound wonderful.)<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+waterfall+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Even MPN got a chance to try the hot waters, while Alex was at her massage. Yes, I took my daughter into 39 degree Celsius water. And she loved it. I tried her in the cooler pools first, just to make sure, but when I slowly put her into the hot pool, it must&#8217;ve felt like heaven for her &#8212; she splashed around like a seal. The bridge overlooking the pool was soon filled with spectators. We might as well have been the featured attraction at Sea World.<br />
This is normal, by the way &#8212; it&#8217;s rather absurd the amount of attention MPN attracts down here.<br />
Monday being a holiday in Costa Rica (Independence Day), we took a leisurely return Monday afternoon, going through San Francisco and San RamÃ³n instead of San Carlos and Naranjo. This is the route that we had travelled (in the other direction) 3.5 years ago with Interbus on our way to Arenal. But Alex and I didn&#8217;t remember a thing, something we feel pretty guilty about. Alex claims that it was culture shock at the time. I think I can live with that.<br />
We stopped only twice &#8212; once to feed MPN (and have a Coke), and another at a gift shop we&#8217;d stopped at with Interbus 3.5 years ago. The only other place in the area that we knew of. It was weird because we didn&#8217;t really recognise it, but we did remember it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2862455883(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Sadly, this weekend cost a lot more than I&#8217;d budgeted for, so we&#8217;re not likely to do anymore long-distance trips for a while. (Besides which, we&#8217;re out of long weekends until Christmas). Of course, there&#8217;s still stuff around us for day trips, so stay tuned for more adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise weekend at Bow Lake</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/07/10/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go. We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise weekend at Bow Lake"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surprise weekends are a good thing. Especially if you have a good place to go.<br />
We have no standing rule that says we have to go anywhere, though. Although the &#8220;rules&#8221; (such as they are) suggest that staying at home is an option, we have yet to actually do that. This weekend was no different.<br />
<span id="more-440"></span>This weekend was grossly delayed, though. This year has been quite busy with a multitude of things to do and see. As such, we&#8217;re several months behind schedule on surprises. To make sure I don&#8217;t follow too far behind, I felt something particularly nice was important. That&#8217;s how we came to Bow Lake in Banff National Park and Simpson&#8217;s Num-Ti-Jah Lodge.<br />
We went up on Saturday, the first weekend of the Calgary Stampede. In fact, because it&#8217;s Stampede time again, it gave us the opportunity to have a hearty Stampede breakfast in our neighbourhood. I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s a homeowner&#8217;s group specifically, but someone definitely has their act together. We came across the same breakfast a year or two ago (admittedly I can&#8217;t remember which) and thought that it would be neat to attend. Little did we know that we&#8217;d be living there. The group puts on a mean breakfast.<br />
We then started the long drive out to Bow Lake. Only I knew where we were going, so it did raise the constant question: &#8220;Where are we going?&#8221; That was usually tied with: &#8220;When will we get there?&#8221; The gaps in between were punctuated with &#8220;How far are we going?&#8221;, &#8220;Are we going to [insert place name here]?&#8221;, and &#8220;Would Asia like going to [insert place name here]?&#8221; (That last one is a nod to a previous spoiled Surprise Weekend where I was caught off-guard with the [[Surprise weekend in Edmonton|mention of my oft-misbehaved cat]].)<br />
Thankfully, I&#8217;m very good at not answering questions like this. In order, the answers might sound like this: &#8220;Somewhere&#8221;, &#8220;Before we go to bed&#8221;, &#8220;As far as we need to&#8221;, &#8220;We might be going there&#8221;, and &#8220;Possibly, but I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;d enjoy being caged in the car for more than five minutes&#8221;. (Asia hates going to the vet, which only takes 10 minutes.)<br />
Our first stop was Banff. Not for any real reason other than we had to eat lunch. Our favourite place, the Old Spaghetti Factory, has finally lost its charm. A couple of years ago, they changed their recipe for the bread. It&#8217;s not bread anymore, it&#8217;s some conglomeration of bread-like powder. And the Italian salad dressing is &#8230; I don&#8217;t know how to describe it, but it ain&#8217;t the same. The quality has slumped overall, which is probably to recoup some of the costs on their otherwise reasonably-priced meals. It will likely be the last time I eat there. Considering we&#8217;ve already written off Starbucks, who knows how many more places will end up on the banned list&#8230;<br />
We did a little shopping (I can&#8217;t say for what, though) and I searched for sandals. As of yet, I&#8217;ve found nothing. But then I&#8217;m a picky sandal person, so it&#8217;ll probably take a while. Hopefully not too long, though &#8212; I need a second pair, and soon.<br />
Returning to the car, we headed back to the Trans Canada and continued west. This brought a return of questions regarding our destination, and a wad of non-commital responses. About 40 minutes later, we turned up Highway 93 (the Icefields Parkway part of it, of course). This brought about a specific direction of questions. It&#8217;s about three hours to Jasper, and there isn&#8217;t much in between. Alex wasn&#8217;t too keen on being in the car that long. While not giving away anything truly important, I swore that we wouldn&#8217;t be long until we got there. Well, except for one thing:<br />
I&#8217;d totally forgotten the name of the place we were going.<br />
Thankfully, when the sign came into view, it wasn&#8217;t too hard to realize that we&#8217;d arrived. The cat, as it were, was finally out of the bag.<br />
Room 24 overlooks Bow Lake, facing roughly south. The view is spectacular. They key is big and old, tied to a horseshoe so you don&#8217;t lose it. No fancy electronics here. When we entered the room, we had our Romantic Package waiting for us. In all honesty, I&#8217;d totally forgotten about it. A bottle of champagne and chocolate-covered strawberries all served on a flat rock. Decadent, most certainly.<br />
Being late in the afternoon, we wandered around looking at the natural splendour of the area before going to dinner. One downside were all the bugs. Not mosquitoes, but flies of somekind. Mildly annoying. That and the American tourists who wanted to know about Calgary, yet seemed to &#8220;know&#8221; all the answers. Can&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn &#8217;em&#8230;<br />
Num-Ti-Jah is known for an amazing kitchen. The reputation is well-deserved. The food there is outstanding, if a tad over-priced. (I will freely admit that the Lodge as a whole is expensive. This is not your average stay at a Holiday Inn &#8212; this is on the order of a Fairmont, but at a log-cabin appearance. In all honesty, it&#8217;s worth it. Especially if you&#8217;re there for the nature. If you just want a room, you can go many places that are a lot cheaper. But if you want to hit the trails right after an excellent sleep and a killer breakfast, there isn&#8217;t much better.<br />
Which is pretty much what we did the following morning. Following breakfast, we checked out and packed the car. Tying my car keys to a loop in my pants, we headed off on the 4.5 km trail to Bow Glacier Falls. (As a point of note, bear bells or jingling keys do very little. Bears apparently have no better sense of hearing than humans. So if you think you can hear a bear bell past a couple of hundred metres on a flat plain &#8212; let alone in the forest &#8212; you can imagine how easily you&#8217;d run into a bear. The recommendation is to make a lot of noise. Apparently, that&#8217;s what helps most.<br />
The hike took us about an hour, depositing us at a glacial valley. It&#8217;s bleak, cold, wet, and utterly gorgeous. There&#8217;s just something inspiring about the sheer rawness of an area that has barely any vegetation, where snow probably fills the area metres deep during the winter. Where few humans tread (indeed, we saw only two couples in the area) there is much to be seen.<br />
Returning to the car, we found that a storm was brewing at the south end of the Bow Valley. It seemed that there was a massive storm going over the mountains, probably heading right for Calgary. Indeed, a fair amount of rain and golf ball-sized hail wreaked havoc in the north of Calgary (the south seemed to be spared) later that day.<br />
We ate a bag lunch (courtesy of Num-Ti-Jah) before taking a leisurely drive back to Calgary, managing to avoid getting the Mini hailed on a second time.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603434328282[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/07/surprise-weekend-at-bow-lake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">440</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surprise Visit to Drumheller</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=surprise-weekend-drumheller</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2004 03:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drumheller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/06/28/surprise-weekend-drumheller/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come. The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Surprise Visit to Drumheller"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was a bit of a surprise. Not that it suddenly appeared from out of nowhere, but that until something happened, I had no idea what was yet to come.<br />
The weekend started with the one thing I did have control over: a barbecue. Specifically, the first Jerks BBQ of the summer. What is a &#8220;Jerks BBQ&#8221;, you might ask? The group of people that I work with most around the office are The Jerks. Effectively, we&#8217;re mostly web developers. Why &#8220;Jerks&#8221;? Well, we have a rather odd term of endearment around here: &#8220;JERK!&#8221;. Hence, we&#8217;re Jerks.<br />
<span id="more-363"></span>This was only the second barbecue I&#8217;ve had since I bought the house (see [[My Housewarming Party]]), and was a far cry from the housewarming audience. Suddenly, I remember why I only have these barbecues once in a while &#8212; they&#8217;re a lot of work.<br />
For example, I was up late putting together the fixin&#8217;s for the barbecue, specifically hamburgers and potato salad. I didn&#8217;t want to buy pre-made burgers (they taste like crap, and you really don&#8217;t know what goes into those things). I decided to make everything. Wanna know what went into them? I can&#8217;t give you quantities (I made it up as I went), but it went like this:<br />
Hamburgers<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
&#8211; medium ground beef (you need the fat for flavour)<br />
&#8211; beer (specifically Big Rock Traditional)<br />
&#8211; caramelized onions<br />
&#8211; garlic (lots of it)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; cumin<br />
&#8211; rosemary<br />
&#8211; thyme<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; seasoning salt<br />
&#8211; oregano<br />
&#8211; chipotle powder (adds a great kick)<br />
Potato Salad<br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;<br />
&#8211; roasted potatoes (with coarse salt, olive oil, and rosemary)<br />
&#8211; whole grain mustard<br />
&#8211; olive oil<br />
&#8211; salt and pepper<br />
&#8211; balsamic vinegar<br />
&#8211; scallions<br />
&#8211; red, orange, and yellow peppers<br />
Everything was ready for when my guests arrived Friday after work &#8230; about 20 minutes before it began to rain. At first, it only rained a little. Soon, it was raining a lot. Apparently someone had decided to ignore my purchase order for a nice, sunny evening. We ended up cramming into the kitchen and living room. Still, a good time seemed to be had by all, which is all I really wanted.<br />
Pat and Scott were the last two to roll out the door, shortly before 22:30. That gave me time to go over to Alex&#8217;s. Which was important for activities the next day&#8230;<br />
&#8230;starting with the Inglewood Festival, and the pancake breakfast. We were originally going to walk from Alex&#8217;s, but when she found out that her sister had a layover in Calgary on her way back to Vancouver, the plan changed to driving. Though we walked from the south side of the Zoo to Inglewood.<br />
The breakfast was put on as part of the festival, but I think also for the footrace runners so they could eat after their event. The food was quite good (there&#8217;s nothing like greasy spoon flapjacks and Spolumbo&#8217;s sausage), and we were serenaded by local group, The Wake Ups.<br />
We did a quick circuit of the various stalls (many still setting up) before running back for the car, and heading up to the airport. Sadly, we would not see Nicky that day, as she had only 40 minutes between flights, and I gather the staff felt she wouldn&#8217;t have enough time to see anyone. We headed back down to downtown.<br />
Originally, the intent had been to go back to Inglewood. To go easy on parking, we stopped at the Calgary Zoo, planning to walk from there. But we soon found ourselves at the entrance to the Zoo. We had the option of going around, or going in. Suddenly, the Zoo seemed so much more appealing.<br />
It was a perfect day to see the Zoo. I&#8217;d only been there two times before, and both times were cold and nasty, and not all the animals were really active. This time, we were tripping over them &#8212; especially the flock of peacocks that seemed to be running around the grounds (including peahens with their peachicks). And then there were all the kids. Hundreds of &#8217;em. They were almost as interesting as watching the monkeys.<br />
We started off in the dinosaur section. This is little more than a static display and a garden, with some dinosaur sculptures thrown in for accent. They&#8217;re not the best models, perhaps, but for a portion of the zoo, it&#8217;s not too bad. Then we were off in search of elephants, bears, monkeys, horses, and tigers before we had to stop for lunch. After eating a fresh Spolumbo&#8217;s sandwich (albeit a little pricey), we were off to Africa (to see hippos, giraffes, zebras, ostriches, lions, gorillas, more moneys, bongos, several species of birds), the botanical garden to see various plants and the butterflies (which even after three times, have been very light in numbers), then over to Australia.<br />
The Australian section (which until this weekend I didn&#8217;t even know existed) included kangaroos (which didn&#8217;t move much), one of the roaming peacocks, and a building full of oddities from Down Under. Part of the building is dedicated to &#8220;Creatures of the Night&#8221;, a rebranding for the nocturnal section.<br />
Inside there, it&#8217;s dark. Really dark. You almost feel like squinting, it&#8217;s so dark. In there, you find things like a little fox with REALLY big ears, wallabies, and of course, bats. Lots of bats. But my favourite thing was a little mouse-sized creature, the name of which I currently forget. This little marsupial zipped along at high speed, and could crawl up the surface of a vertical pane of glass. (Apparently, sweat glands in its feet create suction.) It was quite an experience.<br />
Then it was off through the Canadian Wilds. Nothing particular here, just the usual cougars, lynxes, moose, ducks (but they&#8217;re everywhere, so you can&#8217;t avoid them), bison, wolves, caribou, owls, hawks, porcupines, deer, elk, and goats. Y&#8217;know &#8212; the same stuff you see every day on your way to work. (Sorry, that&#8217;s a bit of an in-joke for us Canucks.) That concluded our Zoo visit, and it was time to get on with the day.<br />
A quick stop at London Drugs retrieved photos that Alex has been taking for the last couple of months. One of them was of her bedroom wall, which she painted milk chocolate brown. Prior to painting it over completely, she&#8217;d drawn a large heart, inside of which she wrote: &#8220;AA + GS&#8221;. Although I&#8217;d known that she drew something on that way, she wouldn&#8217;t tell me what was there until I saw the photograph.<br />
Have I mentioned that I love this woman?<br />
Collecting our things, it was time for the surprise (it might take a while, but you knew I was going to get to it eventually). First off was dinner. For that, we tried to find Mother&#8217;s Pizza in Beddington Town Centre. However, it appears that the store front is currently hidden under the mask of renovation. I only hope it makes a return. We ended up at the Boston Pizza, instead.<br />
From there, we headed out towards Deerfoot Trail, and then north. You need to understand that, at this point, I had no idea where we were going. In &#8220;return&#8221; for the surprise I pulled on Alex in Banff (see [[Jazz Up Your Weekend at the Banff Centre]]), Alex wanted to take me somewhere mysterious. Her &#8220;clue&#8221; had been misinformation, to throw me off the scent. I had guessed Kananaskis. As we drove north on Deerfoot, I assumed that she was taking a very circuitous route.<br />
When we turned east onto one of the many regional highways at the north end of Airdrie, I put Kananaskis off to the side. I soon thought it might be Irricana, though I couldn&#8217;t imagine why. When we passed it on Highway 9, I tried to think of something else. When we passed Beiseiker, there weren&#8217;t many options left. Alex was trying to convince me it was Saskatoon. While this was the same route I&#8217;d take when we&#8217;d moved Nana to Calgary (see [[Moving Nana from Prince Albert to Calgary]]), the drive out is a little long. I felt it safe to assume she was trying to distract me from our destination: Drumheller.<br />
Though when we first pulled into the downtown core, I had second thoughts. Alex passed by most of the hotels, and started taking South Dinosaur Trail away from downtown! (It&#8217;s all industrial park out there.) It wasn&#8217;t until she crossed over the railway tracks and pulled into the Newcastle Inn that the surprise was fully exposed.<br />
The Inn is a small place, with about 12 rooms. It looks sort of like your grandmother&#8217;s place, but with an extra fridge in the kitchen, and a bathroom for each bedroom. Family photos adorn the walls. The Inn was mostly empty when we were there, save for the owner, and two other couples (who seemed to be in the basement). It was certainly comfortable enough for us for the night.<br />
We checked in just before 22:00, dumped our bags, and headed out for a short walk. Which ended up being a long walk (about 30 blocks) to the 7-11 and back. The night was cool, but not uncomfortable. Many small homes, and a few with firepits (we smelled a little like smoke by the time we got back). The unmistakeable scent of prairie-bound small town was just the sort of thing I needed to clear the head.<br />
The next morning, woken up by the other guests who had decided to eat their breakfast on the patio outside our window &#8212; the first ones to do so since the Inn opened &#8212; we ate our breakfast on the patio next to the kitchen. Cereal, toast, and a little fruit salad. We showered, dressed, packed up, and headed out for the adventure of the day.<br />
Our first stop was at the Tourist Information Centre. Why? Originally, to find the local TD Canada Trust, of which there is none in Drumheller. Every other bank is there, just not the TD. While we were there, we felt it necessary to do the tacky tourist thing, and climbed the World&#8217;s Largest Dinosaur.<br />
The 26.2 metre (85 ft.) tall structure is a massive version of a tyrannosaurus rex (or something similarly nasty), about 4.5 times the life-sized versions found in a museum not too far away. It&#8217;s not nearly as life-like, but that&#8217;s part of the charm. The internal structure is steel, though aside from the stairs it&#8217;s hard to tell &#8212; the inside is a plastic &#8220;tunnel&#8221; lined with fossil reproductions.<br />
The tunnel ends at the dinosaur&#8217;s jaws, where you peer westward over the town of Drumheller. It&#8217;s a pretty neat view, especially with the teeth in the way. Alex and I got a great view of the city, and the children playing in the water park just beneath the dinosaur.<br />
Then it was off to the real thing &#8212; the Royal Tyrell Museum. It&#8217;s been a while since the last times that I&#8217;ve been there (see [[Kathryn comes for a visit]], [[Touring Alberta, Calgary Stampede, Columbia Icefields, Lake Louise, Banff (Bamf!), Drumheller]], and [[A Boys Night out in Calgary, Drumheller, Banff (Bamf!), and Star Wars]]), and it was good to be back and see it again. Especially with someone who really wanted to see it because of personal interest.<br />
If you might remember, Alex is an x-ray technician, which means she spends a lot of time with bones. That, and her degree in science, leads to a lot of questions. For example, there&#8217;s a skeleton of a lambeosaurus (duck-billed), that showed a lot of spines from the tail bones. This puzzled Alex, as did the series of long bony-looking lines running the length of the spine between the shoulders and the hips. Before, I&#8217;d not have thought twice about this. Alex, however, is very good with anatomy, and knew this wasn&#8217;t right. A passing staff member told us the long bony structures were fossilized tendons (who knew?) and the tail spines were to create the thickness of the tail.<br />
We tried to take our time, but we ended up only taking a couple of hours. One thing about visiting museums off and on &#8212; you see different things upon subsequent returns. That&#8217;s what made it so interesting. I suspect the air conditioning also hasted our movement, since even for me, it was a little chilly.<br />
We ran out to the hoodoos east of downtown for a quick photo stop. Since I was there last, the Royal Tyrell has taken over management of the area, and created paths for people to walk on, trying to keep people from prematurely destroying the hoodoos. A bold and very noble initiative, since you don&#8217;t have to pay for the privilege of seeing them. So kudos to the Tyrell!<br />
With that, we headed back towards Calgary. We stopped at Horseshoe Canyon for a look-see. This meant a lot of climbing. Once we hit the valley floor, Alex was off like a shot, feeling a need to run up and down the slopes. For a while, I thought I was the dog that no-one wants, and was trying to ditch me out in the middle of nowhere. Fortunately, I managed to not fall too far behind.<br />
The trip back was into the setting sun. The excitement of the two days hit me, and for a short period of time, I slept. Soon, we were back in Calgary. We finished our weekend with a simple Greek meal at Santorini. Along the way to the restaurant, we were confronted by a friendly cat who stirred a few old memories in Alex, of a cat she&#8217;d had as a little girl. I had to take a picture for her.<br />
Now it&#8217;s my turn for planning the next surprise. I&#8217;m not sure what to do just yet, but I&#8217;ve got &#8220;It&#8217;s a Small, Small World&#8221; playing in my head&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:drumheller+june+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/06/surprise-weekend-drumheller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">363</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
