<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>earthquake &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/earthquake/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 20:24:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Hell of a good scare</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hell-of-a-good-scare</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 20:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, we just had a doozy of a startle. Costa Rica just had an official 6.1 magnitude earthquake (originally estimated by the USGS as a 6.2), with an epicentre about 10km east of the Poas volcano. That&#8217;s less than 10 km from where I work, and about 15 km from where I live. It didn&#8217;t &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Hell of a good scare"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we just had a doozy of a startle. Costa Rica just had an official 6.1 magnitude earthquake (originally estimated by the USGS as a 6.2), with an epicentre about 10km east of the Poas volcano. That&#8217;s less than 10 km from where I work, and about 15 km from where I live.<br />
It didn&#8217;t just shake a few things, it rattled the windows, shook a computer to the floor (Leo&#8217;s trying to fix it right now), cracked our ceiling (totally caved in the ceiling of the office next door), broke one of our great big front windows (thankfully, we have the roll doors behind them), and scared the bejeesus out of all of us.<br />
<span id="more-1217"></span>The aftershocks are still coming, but they&#8217;re far from other, I think. The last one (only a couple of minutes ago) was quite a lot stronger than the previous few. Hopefully this is nearly over, &#8216;cuz the last time my heart beat this much or this fast, I was running for 30 minutes&#8230;<br />
[flickr]photo:3179703551(small)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3180542892(small)[/flickr]<br />
Some neat links for info:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.ovsicori.una.ac.cr/index.html">http://www.ovsicori.una.ac.cr/index.html</a><a href="http://www.ovsicori.una.ac.cr/sismologia/sentidos/reporte_sismo_sentido.htm"></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ovsicori.una.ac.cr/sismologia/sentidos/reporte_sismo_sentido.htm">http://www.ovsicori.una.ac.cr/sismologia/sentidos/reporte_sismo_sentido.htm</a></li>
<li><a href="http://earthquake.usgs.gov/eqcenter/recenteqsww/Quakes/quakes_all.php">http://earthquake.usgs.gov/eqcenter/recenteqsww/Quakes/quakes_all.php</a></li>
<li><a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23temblor">http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23temblor</a></li>
<li><a href="http://163.178.140.24/gifs/welcome.html">http://163.178.140.24/gifs/welcome.html</a><a href="http://163.178.140.24/gifs/VACR_SHZ_OV_--.2009010818.gif"></a></li>
<li><a href="http://163.178.140.24/gifs/VACR_SHZ_OV_--.2009010818.gif">http://163.178.140.24/gifs/VACR_SHZ_OV_&#8211;.2009010818.gif</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1217</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We had another earthquake last night</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/we-had-another-earthquake-last-night/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=we-had-another-earthquake-last-night</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/we-had-another-earthquake-last-night/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I was falling alseep, the windows rattled. The bed shook. A few other things skittered.   &#8216;T weren&#8217;t no wind &#8212; we had another earthquake. I have no idea where this one came from, but it definitely woke me up. I think Alex slept through it &#8212; she didn&#8217;t bolt up like the last &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/we-had-another-earthquake-last-night/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "We had another earthquake last night"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was falling alseep, the windows rattled. The bed shook. A few other things skittered.  <br />
&#8216;T weren&#8217;t no wind &#8212; we had another earthquake. I have no idea where this one came from, but it definitely woke me up. I think Alex slept through it &#8212; she didn&#8217;t bolt up like the last time.  <br />
And yes, we&#8217;re fine. Nothing broken. Except my sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/we-had-another-earthquake-last-night/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#039;re fine</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/were-fine/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=were-fine</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/were-fine/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 14:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yep, there was an earthquake here last night. Apparently 6.2 on the Richter scale. We slept through it, if that&#8217;s any indication. We were more worried about the strong winds this morning&#8230; [Update!] Okay, so after chatting with Alex, we actually got our stories straight. Apparently, just after I got home last night, I was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/were-fine/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "We&#039;re fine"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yep, <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2008/WORLD/americas/11/19/panama.quake/index.html">there was an earthquake here last night</a>. Apparently 6.2 on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richter_magnitude_scale">Richter scale</a>.<br />
We slept through it, if that&#8217;s any indication. We were more worried about the strong winds this morning&#8230;<br />
[Update!]<br />
Okay, so after chatting with Alex, we actually got our stories straight. Apparently, just after I got home last night, I was heading towards the bedroom when all the windows rattled strongly for maybe a second. I assumed it was the wind (see above). Apparently, it was something a tad stronger.<br />
Not far away, in the Intercontinental Hotel&#8217;s lounge, some of the CMers from last night&#8217;s grand opening party for The Hangar Interactive were all hanging out when the realised they&#8217;d just felt an earthquake. In true CM fashion, they were high-fiving each other while everyone else in the hotel was running out the front door for their lives&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/were-fine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-chiba-party</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2004 23:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chiba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We woke up several times this morning. Once when the phone rang (Mike and Brenda checking in on us), when Kaz and Chris&#8217; new refrigerator showed up, when the phone rang a second time, and when the earthquake hit. And this time, I&#8217;m not joking. It was a light one, maybe only a 3 on &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We woke up several times this morning. Once when the phone rang (Mike and Brenda checking in on us), when Kaz and Chris&#8217; new refrigerator showed up, when the phone rang a second time, and when the earthquake hit.<br />
And this time, I&#8217;m not joking.<br />
<span id="more-342"></span>It was a light one, maybe only a 3 on the Richter scale, but enough that the building swayed (I&#8217;ll assume for the moment that they&#8217;re designed to do that). For a moment, I wasn&#8217;t sure what was happening. Then I rolled over and went back to bed.<br />
Small earthquakes here are common. Chris doesn&#8217;t even bother to tell us about them anymore. This was the first earthquake I was actually awake for that I could feel. When I lived in Vancouver, we supposedly had one or two, but I never felt one. When I worked at Black&#8217;s Camera back in high school, one hit Oakville. It was very deep and nothing really shook. Instead, it just sounded like there was a garbage truck parked right next to the store (which was impossible, since there was a store next to ours &#8212; I found out later that it had been an earthquake).<br />
Pretty much everyone slept in. This was going to be a long day, so sleep was on the order. Chris and Kaz were up early for the arrival of the fridge, but Tony would remain comatose until well after 10:30. That would be about when the household started to rise and move forward with the day.<br />
Chris shaved (mostly his head) while Kaz and I took turns showering.(The bathroom space allows for a shower and a shave independently, but only if the showerer and the shaver can handle being that close to each other). Jen had to wait until Chris and Kaz were ready to head out the door to Chiba.<br />
They had to leave early for preparations of some sort. Jen and I would head over later, around 17:30. Until that time, Jen played video games, and I read.<br />
The day was cold and miserable, and waiting for the bus to take us to the station was not a particularly enjoyable experience. Luckily, we both had umbrellas, and I had brought a pair of gloves for just such an emergency. We wouldn&#8217;t go directly to the train, however, since we needed to do a bit of laundry at Chris&#8217; old apartment first (the new apartment doesn&#8217;t have a washing machine yet).<br />
On the walk over, the phone rang. It was Chris. They had forgotten a guest book at the apartment for people to sign their names in. It was something that had been used at one of the previous parties, which I had never seen or used before. They wanted it for the party there, and asked that I go back for it.<br />
Dropping the laundry off, we returned to the station. Jen waited (and ate cake) while I hopped in a taxi and handed the keitai to the driver so Chris could give him instructions. Despite my near non-existant Japanese and his near non-existant English, we seemed to have a fairly interesting conversation, though I have no idea about what specifically. Returning to the station, Jen and I headed to Chiba.<br />
Despite not having been there for almost a year, I knew where the bar was. For a while, I almost doubted my memory and thought I might have to call Chris for directions. But before I knew it, the glowing breasts of the bar&#8217;s namesake (and no, I&#8217;m not kidding) appeared. It was then I suddenly remembered some of decor. Fortunately, someone had the smarts to remove all the decorations that wouldn&#8217;t be particularly appropriate for some.<br />
Unlike the party in Toyohashi, most of the people spoke English, which made our mingling a lot easier. The fact that I also knew more people here also helped. Scott was at the door the moment we walked in, as was his girlfriend, Miyuki. The last time I&#8217;d seen them was when we&#8217;d left Club Mix after a full night of bar-hopping last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Tokyo and Shibuya]]). I don&#8217;t know if Miyuki remembered me, but Scott did.<br />
Shinichiro was taking pictures of everyone as they arrived. People would later sign the photos and give them to Chris and Kaz (although some didn&#8217;t make it into their hands, one of which was Tony in his monkey suit). Shinichiro and Scott planned the party, though I got the impression from Scott that Shinichiro did most of the work (Shinichiro lives in Chiba, but Scott lives in Narita &#8212; the distance does have a bit of a factor).<br />
Kaz and Chris were hiding in the &#8220;Love Room&#8221;, a secluded room in the back, until Scott and Shinichiro announced that it was time for them to be introduced to the awaiting audience. When the time finally came, the cue was &#8220;Mr. and Mrs. May&#8221;.<br />
I don&#8217;t think Kaz is changing her family name, but the announcement did hit home. Chris and Kaz were engaged almost two years ago &#8212; they met almost exactly two years ago. For that length of time, they were together (even if they were living apart) such that I just saw them as more than just a couple. But they&#8217;re married now. My best friends are almost all married now. Gerry, Stuart, Therese, and Chris. Of my closest friends, only Kathryn and I remain. And Kathryn is in no rush (as she put it).<br />
Chris and Kaz tried to do the circuit of people, but had significant difficulty,mostly because everyone wanted to talk to them. Eventually, Scott called for the toast, and the party officially got underway.<br />
The food was excellent (there was a breaded shrimp in some sauce that might as well have been liquified crack for how good it tasted), the beverages flowed freely, and the conversations as I travelled around the room lively.<br />
I was initially afraid that Jen might feel more out of place than usual. She might be taller than me, and look older than she is (the &#8220;Guess Jen&#8217;s Age&#8221; game continued; the nearest guess was 18), but the simple fact was that she didn&#8217;t know a lot of people here. That said, however, she dove into a couple of conversations and did quite well for herself. Of course, it didn&#8217;t hurt that many of the conversations were with guys, who for all I know were hitting on her.<br />
Jen discovered that sake isn&#8217;t the only drink she likes. Someone introduced her to a &#8220;China Blue&#8221;, a drink with blue curacau, some other liquor, and grapefruit juice. Before the end of the night, Jen would have had several of those, a couple beers, and a smattering of other things. My aunt and uncle are gonna kill me if they hear about this any time soon. At least Jen&#8217;s with people she knows and there&#8217;s far less risk involved than if she were out doing the same things with other people.<br />
Scott had planned a game of bingo &#8212; similar to a team-building game I had one once with the Mercedes Benz USA team back in January. You&#8217;re given a sheet with the bingo grid, but no numbers &#8212; the fields are blank. You go around the room, meeting new people, and get their name. You add it randomly to the fields, and then a draw of names might get you a bingo.<br />
I didn&#8217;t play. Instead, Brian (one of the guests) and I sat, talked, drank, and gave our names to everyone who came by. We figured: &#8220;Why go to the effort if people will come to us?&#8221; It was immense fun, and we had a good laugh as a result.<br />
There were many bingos, and many prizes. Jen won a &#8220;personal massager&#8221;. I think I almost died laughing.<br />
Naome and I had several conversations, and at least one kung-fu tickle fight. Unfortunately, Naome isn&#8217;t as ticklish as I am, so there wasn&#8217;t much I could do to her. I had to try, though.<br />
Slowly, but surely, the crowd emptied out into the cold, wet night until it was Chris, Kaz, Jen, Scott, Miyuki, Shinichiro, Riku, Naome, and Cory (another teacher). We were all looking to head home. This had Jen supremely disappointed because there had been much talk, from well over a month and a half ago, about going to karaoke.<br />
I&#8217;m not a singer. Never have been. Yes, I was in the Concert Choir back in high school (see [[Music Trip to Orlando, Introduction|Music Trip to Orlando]]), but that was as an ulterior motive to go down to Florida. So going to karaoke was never really high on my list of priorities.That said, though, get enough drink in me, and you&#8217;ll have a far easier time convincing me of some things. Like singing.<br />
In the eventuality of karaoke coming around, I&#8217;d even planned some of the songs I&#8217;d wanted to do, mostly Elvis and Tom Jones tunes (they suit my voice far better than, say, Avril Lavigne). Such as it was, that was something I didn&#8217;t have to worry about.<br />
Those of us heading back to Yotsukaido climbed into two cabs, the rest headed off in different directions. It had been a long night, and a long sleep was in order&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:japan+chiba+erotikava+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-chiba-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">342</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
