<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>coffee &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/coffee/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 18:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A week without coffee</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/a-week-without-coffee/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-week-without-coffee</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/a-week-without-coffee/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 18:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A week ago, I sat in one of our meeting rooms at the office, discussing the current state of one of our projects, when I felt the all-too-familiar and sickening sensation of a rush of fluid in my nose. The generous drop of blood hit my finger a moment later. It took nearly 20 minutes &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/a-week-without-coffee/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A week without coffee"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A week ago, I sat in one of our meeting rooms at the office, discussing the current state of one of our projects, when I felt the all-too-familiar and sickening sensation of a rush of fluid in my nose. The generous drop of blood hit my finger a moment later.<br />
It took nearly 20 minutes for the bleeding to stop. It freaked me out a bit because I had no real reason as to <em>why</em> it had bled. By the time I got home, there was no indication whatsoever of any issue, either. But it was Alex who got me thinking. Her thought?<br />
I&#8217;d been drinking way too much caffeine.<br />
<span id="more-3148"></span>You may recall my first cup of coffee. It was yummy. And I knew, immediately, that I was screwed. I love the taste of coffee. Given the choice between just about anything (except beer) and coffee, I&#8217;ll choose coffee. (In the case of coffee-infused beer, I&#8217;m extra screwed.)<br />
And I did. Since that fateful day, I&#8217;ve drank a lot of coffee. Most people start when they&#8217;re in university. In the three-odd years since I started, I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;ve come close to making up the difference. At one point, about two months ago, I think I was downing nearly 12 cups a day.<br />
Twelve.<br />
I don&#8217;t care what the papers say, that ain&#8217;t natural. It would explain some of my more recent blepharospams, and lack of sleep (well, DUH).<br />
So I stopped. Cold. And since then, I&#8217;ve not had a single cup. Not one. Not even a sip, or a whiff.<br />
The headaches were bad. Brutal, even. Withdrawal sucks.<br />
Water takes up most of my intake now, supplemented by (so far, non-caffeinated) tea. Effects, after a week? I feel significantly less irritable and getting to sleep isn&#8217;t as difficult as it has been for the last few months. However, I still feel drawn to the coffee settings on the office coffee maker (it takes packs that make tea, coffee, and other assorted beverages), and rough mornings (still have &#8217;em, of course) are that much harder without the kick in the butt.<br />
Am I going to drink coffee again? Probably, but likely only on certain occasions, notably vacations (where I&#8217;m not tempted to drink coffee all day). During my regular 9ish-to-5ish? I may be permanently moving back to yerba matte, which I found to be less &#8230; dramatic.<br />
So, this is kind of it, coffee. You were a good friend, a reliable companion. It&#8217;s definitely me, not you, at fault here, and it&#8217;s time we moved on. Not that I&#8217;m special to you, of course &#8212; there are many other addicts out there for you to have fun with. For now, I&#8217;ll just be happy to be &#8230; well, happy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/a-week-without-coffee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 things I miss about Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 15:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s just shy of three months since we left Costa Rica. Many people still ask us what it&#8217;s like to be back, if we&#8217;re happy to be back, and if we&#8217;ve acclimatised yet. There&#8217;s no quick or easy answer to all of that, as we&#8217;re not dealing with something as simple as changing from one &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "12 things I miss about Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s just shy of three months since we left Costa Rica. Many people still ask us what it&#8217;s like to be back, if we&#8217;re happy to be back, and if we&#8217;ve acclimatised yet. There&#8217;s no quick or easy answer to all of that, as we&#8217;re not dealing with something as simple as changing from one temperature to another. As anyone will tell you, moving to an entirely different country (outside of North America) involves more than a physical location. Costa Rica was more than just a place, it was a way of life, and an experience that has changed the way I live now.<br />
Almost right away, we missed some things, though most of that was due to the roughly 40 degree Celsius shift in temperature. Other things soon made themselves known, each time with the all-too-familiar pang of loss and regret.<br />
But like when we moved down to Costa Rica, this is just something we&#8217;ll have to get used to.<br />
<span id="more-2629"></span>Now just to be clear, there are two parts to this: things I miss, and things that I should miss but don&#8217;t (at least, not yet). I&#8217;m splitting it up this way just to avoid some of the obvious questions that are bound to appear. C&#8217;mon, I know you guys a little bit, y&#8217;know&#8230;</p>
<h3><strong>Things I Miss</strong></h3>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Fresh fruit</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">As I&#8217;d mentioned a few times before, Costa Rica has fresh fruit. I know that sounds like an utterly silly statement, but unless you&#8217;ve been to a tropical country, you have no concept what fresh fruit is really like. None. Even the best organic produce you get at your local hippie market doesn&#8217;t hold a sniff to the stuff I got at the farmer&#8217;s markets in Costa Rica. The &#8220;reject&#8221; bananas (the &#8220;good&#8221; ones are all exported) were sweeter and lusher than any banana I&#8217;ve ever had here, the strawberries were worth killing over, and the papayas so good that I might never be able to eat them again (seriously).</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Unbelievable greenery</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I live in Calgary, where it barely rains. We get a nice green spring, but usually by mid-July everything&#8217;s starting to dry out. When fall hits, the primary colour is brown. We get white in the winter, at least when the snow is covering the aforementioned brownness.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">In Costa Rica, it&#8217;s green. Always. Everywhere. Even on the tops of volcanoes, it&#8217;s green. There&#8217;s no effort for it to be green &#8212; that&#8217;s just the way it is. It happens naturally. No additives, no preservatives. It&#8217;s <em>overwhelmingly green</em>. There&#8217;s no comparison for the green. And now that brown has fully set in up here, I find myself missing it more than ever.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Volcanoes (but not earthquakes)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Speaking of volcanoes, I&#8217;ve had a thing for geology since I was a kid, and love seeing volcanoes. Especially at a distance (the active ones, any way). I&#8217;ve been fortunate to see a few volcanoes, notably in Hawaii, but also in Costa Rica (and went up Poas just a couple of days before a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/">6.2 earthquake levelled a nearby town</a>). There aren&#8217;t any decent volcanoes in Canada, all of them are either dormant or entirely extinct.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Speaking of earthquakes, I rather like Calgary. It&#8217;s extremely stable. Not necessary free of tremors, but far enough to avoid anything nasty. I like that.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Price includes taxes</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">One pet peeve I always had with the North American pricing system was that the price you see is rarely the price you pay. Taxes are thrown on top, and usually service fees on that, too.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">In Costa Rica, IVI (the tax) is rolled into everything, including your restaurant menu prices (divided into two columns). There&#8217;s no question what something costs, even if the price is in $USD (which it sometimes is, depending on how deep you&#8217;ve dived into tourist areas). I miss that kind of transparency.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Sun in the morning</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Although it bugged me at the time, I now officially miss sun in the morning. The sun is still rising here, and when my alarm goes off it&#8217;s still dark. It&#8217;s something I came to appreciate a lot, as it really made things much nicer. That said, I&#8217;m going to be very happy for the late evening sun come June&#8230;</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Not wearing pants</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Costa Rica, duh, is warm. So I rarely ever wore pants &#8212; shorts were my mainstay for a year and a half. I hate wearing pants. I hate wearing shoes (instead of sandals). And I really, really, <em>really</em> hate wearing socks.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Monkeys (and wildlife in general)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">No, I&#8217;m not saying I don&#8217;t like seeing deer, or moose, or anything else common in our northern tracts. But I do miss seeing wild parakeets, vibrantly colourful birds, and especially the monkeys roaming the treetops. There&#8217;s nothing like monkeys up here, save for zoos.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Driving with the window down &#8230; all year</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I only realised this last weekend, but man I miss driving with the window down! You can&#8217;t do that up here when it&#8217;s 20 below! (Well, I suppose you could, but then you&#8217;re just asking for trouble.) There&#8217;s nothing like being able to go down a street at any time of the day or night, with the window down. That kind of fresh air is just amazing.<br />
<strong></strong></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Dos Piños (and ice cream)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong></strong>Dos Piños is the major dairy producer in Costa Rica, and makes pretty much everything that you can make from milk. Of particular note were their ice cream products. I don&#8217;t know what it is, but Costa Rican ice cream (Dos Piños and Pops, at least that I found) is fantastic. It&#8217;s wonderfully creamy, and not filled with a lot of crap (which seems common in North American ice creams). It got to the point where I was having one a day, on walks with Jason and Ed.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Batidos</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">A &#8220;batido&#8221; is (more or less) a blended fruit drink. Not with ice &#8212; just fruit, mixed with either water or milk. (Milk was my favourite version.) I know I can make them here with whatever fruit I get my hands on, but as you already know (from my first item), it&#8217;s just not the same without fresh Costa Rican fruit. I liked batidos for the fact that it was fruit, it was tasty, and often filling. It was a great alternative to syrupy drinks, or even a coffee if I wasn&#8217;t in the mood.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">You&#8217;re from Canada? So am I!!</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">This one sounds silly, but it&#8217;s true &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing like finding a fellow Canuck (or insert your own nationality, I&#8217;m sure the same is true of other countries) when you&#8217;re abroad. I&#8217;ve been fortunate to have this happen in a few places, and even made some friends that way. It&#8217;s not to say that I can&#8217;t make friends with my fellow Canucks up here, but meeting someone abroad and sharing your experiences is very different than striking up a conversation while on a bus.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">My friends</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Last, but probably most importantly, I miss my friends. The people I knew well, who I worked with, the ones who lived near me, the ones who shared in the experience, the people who asked how I was and were a significant part of my life, and especially the ones so kind as to drive me to and from work every day. I feel exceedingly distant from them now, not just in distance, but because I might never see some of them ever again.<br />
<strong></strong></p>
<h3><strong>Things I Don&#8217;t Miss (Yet)</strong></h3>
<p>Now you&#8217;re probably wondering why some things didn&#8217;t appear in that list. Well, there are a few things that I don&#8217;t miss, at least not yet.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The heat</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I have never liked the heat, at least not for long periods of time. Once in a while, for a couple of hours, I can hack. Even full days are a bit much for me, and dragging that out into weeks? HA! Not a chance. Strange as it sounds, I&#8217;ll take the cold over the heat any day.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Just so long as I can visit the heat once in a while&#8230;</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The constant temperatures in the valley</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">The Central Valley in Costa Rica is consistent in the way you can&#8217;t even imagine. 27 degrees Celsius is the daily high, and 15 degrees is the daily low. Every day. <em>Every</em>. <em>Single</em>. <em>Day</em>. (It does vary a little bit from time to time, but the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mode_(statistics)">mode</a> is pretty much 27/15.)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Now, I know what you&#8217;re thinking: that sounds heavenly! You never have to stare at weather forecasts! But you also never get to see seasons like we do up here. I missed fall and spring (and especially winter). You can handle only so much perfection before you start to go a little wonky, lemme tell ya.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The beaches</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I know, I know, again you&#8217;re thinking I&#8217;m totally batty (and maybe I am). But I don&#8217;t really miss the beaches. That&#8217;s not to say I don&#8217;t like beaches &#8212; I love &#8217;em! But going to the beach was never trivial, and involved far more effort than I care to think about. So much so that, well, now I look back and I think that while I&#8217;m glad to have gone, I don&#8217;t really have any burning desire to visit another one anytime soon.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The beer</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Okay, first off, I loved <a href="http://www.imperialcerveza.com/">Imperial</a>. Truly. But Costa Rica has a limited selection of beer, and about half of them are pretty darn close to the same thing with a different label. Up here, I can lose <em>hours</em> staring at a beer menu (yes, there is such a thing as a beer menu), or standing in the refrigerated room at any of the billion-or-so liquor stores in Calgary, trying to decide what to try next. That&#8217;s a level of selection I missed dearly while I was in Costa Rica, and am very happy to have it back.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The coffee</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Before you freak out, there&#8217;s a really simple reason why I don&#8217;t miss Costa Rica coffee: we brought a lot of it back home with us. When we run out? Well, that&#8217;s another blog post&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2629</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our last weekend away</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/our-last-weekend-away/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=our-last-weekend-away</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/our-last-weekend-away/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 03:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2224</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, we&#8217;re down to less than a month before we&#8217;re back home again. In fact, a month today you&#8217;ll (hopefully) be sound asleep in a bed in our home in Calgary. It&#8217;s hard to believe that this is actually ending. It seems to odd to think that after all that we&#8217;ve been through, that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/our-last-weekend-away/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Our last weekend away"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, we&#8217;re down to less than a month before we&#8217;re back home again. In fact, a month today you&#8217;ll (hopefully) be sound asleep in a bed in our home in Calgary. It&#8217;s hard to believe that this is actually ending. It seems to odd to think that after all that we&#8217;ve been through, that this isn&#8217;t more permanent. Such are the joys of life&#8230;<br />
Thankfully, one of the other joys of life are grandparents. You&#8217;re lucky &#8212; you&#8217;ve got four of them. And you were very excited when Grandpa and Granny came down on Wednesday. It&#8217;s Grandpa&#8217;s third visit since we came to Costa Rica, and Granny&#8217;s second. You might see them nearly every day on Skype, but there&#8217;s just nothing like seeing them in person.<br />
<span id="more-2224"></span>Despite the previous visits, neither of them had seen much beyond the Central Valley, although on their first trip, they flew into Liberia and took a bus to Santa Ana. That&#8217;s not much, sadly, and Mommy and I felt it was important that we take them elsewhere &#8212; some place to rest and relax. Besides, it&#8217;s Grandpa and Granny&#8217;s 20th wedding anniversary in a couple of weeks, and we wanted to give them something special.<br />
So on Friday afternoon, the four of you picked me up from my office, and we went off for a weekend excursion. Though our first stop was for lunch at a nearby Peruvian restaurant called Chancay, in Plaza Rubi. You were quite energetic and ran circles around the tiled floors, squealing everywhich way you went. The woman tending the hot dog shop was particularly entertained.<br />
We hit the highway afterwards, heading west towards San RamÃ³n. You&#8217;ve been this way before several times, and I think you spent more time playing Grandpa than looking out the window. Well, at least until we hit that traffic near Animas &#8212; an accident had brought the Inter-American to a near-dead halt.<br />
Mommy and I opted to leave the highway and take the secondary roads to get around the traffic (we had no particular desire to sit still when we could just as easily entertain a more scenic detour). It might not have been the wisest of choices &#8212; the drive from the intersection with #3 to Naranjo (where we rejoined the Inter-American) is normally about 20 minutes without traffic. It took us nearly two hours. But we did get to see Sarchi, which we hadn&#8217;t seen before, and a lot more of the countryside that Grandpa and Granny hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
Once we got to San RamÃ³n, we headed north to Los Angeles, and then out to Mommy and mine&#8217;s favourite place in Costa Rica (and currently my favourite place in the world), <a href="http://www.villablanca-costarica.com/">Villa Blanca</a>. There are few places I know of that are more beautiful or peaceful.<br />
Normally, Villa Blanca (<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/01/visiting-villa-blanca/">at least by our experience</a>) sits very much in the Los Angeles Cloud Forest. That means the area is usually shrouded in clouds, giving the area a very ethereal look.<br />
[flickr]photo:3238992623[/flickr]<br />
This time, for some odd reason, there were no clouds. At all. I don&#8217;t know if it was a result of the Tropical Storm/Hurricane Ida that went up the coast a couple of days ago monkeying around with weather patterns, or if this is the normal state at this time of the year. At any rate, when we arrived, we could see clearly to Arenal, and even saw the top of that rather elusive volcano.<br />
Mommy, you, and I had our own cabina, with Grandpa and Granny at the next cabin to ours. You were able to walk between them, and were often sent over to say &#8220;hi&#8221;, and get people ready to go for meals. You had your own bed, too, a nice cot that Villa Blanca set up for us. Sadly, you fell out of it on the first nice &#8212; twice &#8212; so the next day Mommy and I put the mattress on the floor so you could sleep more safely.<br />
What did we do at Villa Blanca? That&#8217;s what Mommy and I like most about Villa Blanca &#8212; you don&#8217;t need to do anything but enjoy the area. You went for walks with Mommy and Granny, played with Grandpa, read, and tried to chase the coatis. You looked at all the wonderful flowers, stared at the intensely black skies at night and saw stars you&#8217;ll be hard-pressed to ever see in Calgary (unless there&#8217;s a total blackout), and ran about whenever you possibly could (which was pretty much always).<br />
You even tried to have a bath with Mommy. But Mommy takes inhumanly hot baths, which you found out the hard way when you nearly did a head-first plunge into the tub.<br />
On the Saturday morning, I took Grandpa ziplining. Mommy had gone ziplining at Villa Blanca back in May when Erin came down to visit, and it was time for me to try. I would have been upset if I&#8217;d left Costa Rica without ziplining at least once. And taking Grandpa with me sounded not only like a lot of fun, but perhaps also a little sadistic.<br />
It turned out that Grandpa and I were the first customers in a few days who wanted to go on the canopy tour, and were the only ones going out that morning. We were picked up by our guides, Luis and Oliver, at the hotel and whisked about a kilometre away to the tour&#8217;s hut.<br />
This wasn&#8217;t my first time ziplining. I&#8217;d done the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2007/06/flying-the-zip-line-at-canada-olympic-park/">zipline in Calgary at Canada Olympic Park</a>. But that one is quite a bit different &#8212; it&#8217;s all about the massive drop from the ski jump, not travelling through the trees. This one is decidedly more calm, and probably a lot safer (despite travelling through tree tops).<br />
I made Grandpa go first, though he didn&#8217;t seem to mind one bit. And as near as I could tell, he enjoyed himself quite a lot, too. Even when we dropped vertically from one platform to another, hanging free. I can only hope that I have as much fun as Grandpa when I get into my later years.<br />
[flickr]tag:villablanca+november+2009@Geoff S.[/flickr]<br />
We stayed for two nights, and left mid-morning on the Sunday. My idea was fairly simple: in addition to Villa Blanca, we&#8217;d also go on a coffee tour in Naranjo. My friend Mark (of Mark and Denise fame) had recommended a tour in Naranjo, and we&#8217;d seen the signs during out detour on Friday. We arrived at the <a href="http://espiritusantocoffeetour.com/">Espiritu Santo coffee plantation</a> just before noon, just avoiding a rather large tour that was just departing.<br />
Espiritu Santo is one of an increasing number of coffee-growing collectives in Costa Rica. The colonial past of massive plantation owners gave way to smaller farms, which were then exploited by coffee buyers. The smaller farms have now grown into collectives, using their position to bypass the middlemen and go direct to the customers. In Espiritu Santo&#8217;s case, 90% of their coffee is sold direct to <a href="http://starbucks.com">Starbucks</a>.<br />
The tour was small &#8212; the five of us, plus another ex-pat and his friend from the United States. We started in a covered patio where we sample four types of their coffee: dark, light, house, and peaberry. I drank far too much of the coffee, myself (I had a splitting headache today, and felt quite ill as a result). You drank almost as much as I did, but seemed to have very little affect on you &#8212; well, except for not sleeping at all until your bedtime tonight, that is.<br />
After the coffee sampling (which is usually at the end), we went into the outer edges of the coffee fields. Our guide, whose name I can&#8217;t remember now, explained that the area is geologically a &#8220;failed volcano&#8221;, which explains its hilliness, volcanic-type soils, but lack of a defined peak or caldera. The hills were something to see with the neat rows of coffee plants. I wished I had the ability to take more detailed pictures of it, but someone had to keep and eye on you.<br />
I learned a little more from Espiritu Santo&#8217;s tour than I had with the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/08/snot-and-coffee/">Doka coffee tour</a>. Namely that while harvest season is November to February, it&#8217;s not a constant harvest. In fact, it only happens four times &#8212; once a month for four months. And all of the harvest needs to be processed in one day to prevent any fermentation of the seeds that will eventually become the coffee bean.<br />
[flickr]tag:naranjo+coffee+public@Geoff S.[/flickr]<br />
The afternoon storms were starting to roll in as we started, and Mommy quickly ran back to the car for her jacket and an umbrella. But the tour guides produced umbrellas for us, too. You held onto the one you and I shared (you were on my shoulders most of the tour), and later held it totally on your own.<br />
We visited the processing machinery, which &#8212; at least to me &#8212; seemed so much simpler (and less interesting) than Doka&#8217;s water-powered, turn-of-the-previous-century machines. The guide explained that afterwards, the beans are taken up to an old runway (the former plantation owners were quite wealthy) where they are dried before shipping. Only some is kept for local consumption, which is roasted in-house.<br />
The tour also featured an historic reconstruction of a typical farmhouse, where the guide explained farm life, and how Costa Rican coffee is traditionally made (which you already know &#8212; the chorreador). After that, it was up to the gift shop (of course). You played with a marimba that I know both Mommy and I considered getting for you.<br />
Thus ends what will likely be our last trip here in Costa Rica. The next time we head out from our apartment, it will likely be to head to the airport. It&#8217;ll be hard, for all of us, as it&#8217;ll be a major change in our life.<br />
But that&#8217;s what life is, Monkey &#8212; change. Change isn&#8217;t something to be avoided, it&#8217;s something to be embraced. It&#8217;s something to enjoy as much as you can. Because the alternative &#8212; stagnation &#8212; is really, really, really boring.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/our-last-weekend-away/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2224</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snot and coffee</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/snot-and-coffee/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=snot-and-coffee</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/snot-and-coffee/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 03:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, the last week&#8217;s been quite the slog. Last Saturday, you started showing signs of being sick, having caught something from one of your schoolmates. It basically turned you into a bonafide snot factory. (One upside: you&#8217;ve learned how to wipe your own nose. Now if we can just figure out how to make &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/snot-and-coffee/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Snot and coffee"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, the last week&#8217;s been quite the slog. Last Saturday, you started showing signs of being sick, having caught something from one of your schoolmates. It basically turned you into a bonafide snot factory. (One upside: you&#8217;ve learned how to wipe your own nose. Now if we can just figure out how to make you blow it, too.)<br />
The bug hit me next, kicking in on Tuesday, and then taking me down on Thursday and half of Friday (I didn&#8217;t sleep at all Monday, Tuesday, or Wednesday nights, partly due to your coughing and partly due to feeling so crappy.) Mommy caught it next, and her illness really kicked in on Friday, and is just coming out of her illness today.<br />
The group of us effectively played &#8220;Sick Family Robinson&#8221;, holing up and trying to keep our wits, all the while trying not to spread the sickness to Grandma.<br />
<span id="more-1485"></span>It&#8217;s not been an easy week. Even just the last four days have felt twice as long as they should. Part of being sick, but also from helping keep things moving here. Grandma has helped considerably, and I suppose in an odd way it&#8217;s been extremely helpful that she&#8217;s come down at what would normally be considered an inopportune time.<br />
Mommy needed some time to herself today, so I offered to take you and Grandma out for an excursion. Despite having lived in Costa Rica for over a year now, we&#8217;d yet to do any form of a coffee tour. Although the Café Britt tour is quite close to us, just over in Heredia, we&#8217;d been warned against it by Mark, Jason, and Jen, who declared it &#8220;horrible&#8221;.<br />
Thankfully, nearly a year ago Mommy and I had seen a sign that said &#8220;The Real Coffee Tour&#8221; while on our way up to Arenal. Presumably, the &#8220;Real Coffee Tour&#8221; moniker is used to combat Café Britt&#8217;s much more well-known tour.  It kind of stuck in my head, and today (with the help of a guide book) we hunted it down a few kilometres north of Cuidad de Alajuela.<br />
The tour takes place at the <a href="http://dokaestate.com/">Doka Estate Farm</a> in San Isidro, a not-particularly well-marked location on maps. In fact, if it were not for the very well-placed signs on the right, chances are we&#8217;d have had a tough time finding the place. As this is the off-season for tourists, the parking lot at 9:40 this morning was nigh-empty, and we were met by the friendly guard who ushered us to the shop and restaurant to buy tickets for the tour.<br />
We still had a number of minutes before we started, so the highly bilingual shopkeeper led us to the butterfly enclosure they have on-site. You&#8217;ve been to a few butterfly farms, kiddo, but you seemed to have the most fun in this one. (Well, at least that I&#8217;ve seen.) You were running around the circular enclosure, constantly chattering to have Grandma and I keep up.<br />
[flickr]photo:3830271414(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830274018(square)[/flickr]<br />
When it came time for the tour to start, we were joined by a family of four from Seattle. Our guide, whose name I&#8217;m just realising we never got, was either a worker who moonlighted as a guide during the rest of the year, or possibly one of the family who own the coffee farm. At any rate, he spoke very good English, and was very good at explaining a few things about coffee making I had not been previously aware of.<br />
For example, the only coffee that grows in Costa Rica is arabica. This is, apparently, a law. Mind you, the specific version of arabica in Costa Rica is known by another name. The plants are seeded, which takes nearly three months just to see sprouting. This leads to a properly leaf structure after nearly eight months, at which time the plant is moved to a potting bag for another two years. It&#8217;s nearly three years before a single plant might turn a single coffee cherry.<br />
(Yes, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coffea">coffee is actually a cherry</a>.)<br />
[flickr]photo:3830274782(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830274458(square)[/flickr]<br />
While the coffee plants grow year-round, they only offer beans during a three-month period, lasting from roughly November to January (at least here in Costa Rica). During that time, a huge migrant population (which these days seems to be largely Nicaraguan) moves in for the picking. A single picker can earn as much as $3,000 for the season, which is enough to last an entire family a whole year.<br />
Coffee is picked in a special basket that is a defined size (similar in concept to a &#8220;bushel&#8221;), which denotes how much coffee is put in a sack. It&#8217;s a counting thing. It sounds like overkill, but when you realise that there are 500,000 acres (over 2,000 square kilometres)  of coffee, it&#8217;s probably not a bad idea of have some sense of control. It didn&#8217;t look particular comfortable &#8212; it&#8217;s about 25 kilos completely full &#8212; but I imagine it&#8217;s efficient.<br />
The guide also explained that the coffee fields are often dotted with other plants, such as bananas, mangoes, avocados, and so forth. These plants help control the minerals in the soil, as well as provide some shade for the coffee (which apparently is needed at higher altitudes). They also help offset some of the non-coffee season with (albeit substantially lesser) income.<br />
He also explained that the rains are a significant part of coffee-growing. Coffee, like rice or cotton, is a very water-intensive plant. In lieu of irrigation (which is very expensive), coffee tends to only grow in places that have even (and warm) temperatures year-round, and a lot of rain. So when people talk about &#8220;bad growing seasons&#8221;, they&#8217;re not saying it got cold &#8212; they&#8217;re saying it didn&#8217;t rain enough.<br />
This is what I picked up when I wasn&#8217;t having to keep you from disappearing down the rows of coffee shrubs. I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;d have marched right into the middle of their 50-odd acre farm (just that location; they apparently have several) and likely covered yourself in dirt doing so.<br />
I do need to add that you weren&#8217;t a lot of trouble today, Monkey, but you were a handful.<br />
From the fields, we went into the sorting and separating house. This is a building that&#8217;s now on Costa Rica&#8217;s historic register. Even though the farm itself isn&#8217;t 100 years old, there aren&#8217;t a lot of buildings in Costa Rica older than 100 years &#8212; earthquakes tend to batter them around a lot. This one seemed old, but unlike the defunct grain elevators across Canada&#8217;s prairies, this building is still in use. Well, for three months of the year, anyway.<br />
Coffee is brought in and sorted, using water. (Good cherries sink, bad ones float.) The good cherries are then put through a series of pitting machines that force out all the coffee beans. These are then washed, dried, and stored in sacks. All of the water, and the power needed to drive all the machines, comes from a high-pressure well found on-site. It&#8217;s a pretty slick system that involves no fossil fuels whatsoever. (And this before everyone went green!)<br />
[flickr]photo:3829477009(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830275368(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830275662(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3829477909(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3829478223(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830276838(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830277040(square)[/flickr]<br />
The sacks are kept for no more than three days before being put out in the sun (conveniently, picking season is also when it doesn&#8217;t rain in Costa Rica) to finish completely drying. Only then can they be packed and shipped to their purchasers. Only about 10% of the farm&#8217;s take is actually roasted and sold in the country.<br />
[flickr]photo:3829479377(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3830277846(square)[/flickr]<br />
About 50% of their coffee goes to one company.  Care to guess? Starbucks.<br />
After a quick trip through the gift shop (we were running low on coffee at home, and you really felt the need for a quick sip-or-three of espresso), we headed home.<br />
Sadly, you slept in the car, which seemed to utterly negate your ability to nap in the afternoon. So you slept a grand total of about 20 minutes today. Which made you quite a handful this afternoon. But not as difficult as you were last night, though I&#8217;m told it&#8217;s because I got too fancy with dinner. Oops.<br />
Anyway, we&#8217;re all almost back to normal. And your second birthday comes in just a few days! Hopefully, kiddo, this will be a much better week for all of us!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/snot-and-coffee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1485</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>25 Coffees</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/25-coffees/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=25-coffees</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/25-coffees/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 15:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For those of you keeping track &#8212; and I know there are those of you who do (you freaks!) &#8212; I&#8217;ve officially reached coffee #25. I&#8217;m drinking it as I write this, in order to combat a serious lack of sleep brought on by windstorms we&#8217;re having here at the moment. This is a milestone &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/25-coffees/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "25 Coffees"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those of you keeping track &#8212; and I know there are those of you who do (you freaks!) &#8212; I&#8217;ve officially reached coffee #25. I&#8217;m drinking it as I write this, in order to combat a serious lack of sleep brought on by windstorms we&#8217;re having here at the moment.<br />
This is a milestone in a variety of ways. First, it&#8217;s proven that I am, in fact, a coffee drinker and likely on my way to coffee addiction. I&#8217;m comfortable with that, provided it&#8217;s good coffee. I dread having my first bad coffee. It&#8217;ll happen, I&#8217;m sure, and I&#8217;m not going to enjoy it. But I have to brace myself.<br />
The second part is that I am no longer counting how many coffees I drink. Not for any real reason other than I&#8217;m just too damn lazy to keep it up.<br />
<span id="more-1244"></span>Am I a coffee  connoisseur  after all of this? Heck, no. I&#8217;ve only had 25 coffees, people! And all of it Costa Rican coffee. I&#8217;ve yet to even have a (complete) Starbucks coffee, let alone one from Tim Horton&#8217;s. So I&#8217;ve got a long way to go before I can say definitively what good coffee is.<br />
But I do know what I like. I&#8217;ve had coffee a variety of ways since first trying it. Allow me to elaborate:</p>
<ul>
<li>7 <a href="http://www.zurqui.com/crinfocus/cr/coffee.html">chorreadors</a> (the Costa Rican &#8220;coffee sock&#8221;), including <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/11/my-first-coffee/">my first</a></li>
<li>11 espressos from our home machine</li>
<li>1/2 candy cane mocha latte (or something like that) from Starbucks in the Newark airport &#8212; I&#8217;m counting this as a whole coffee (no partials)</li>
<li>Mocha Freeze from Port City Java (technically not a coffee, but contains coffee, so I&#8217;m counting it)</li>
<li>4 restaurant coffees</li>
<li>1 drip coffee that I just had at The Hangar (<a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/1183150359">my first work coffee</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>Now after all that coffee, I&#8217;m also starting to get set in my ways for the way I&#8217;ll drink it. And yes, I&#8217;m going to annoy a few people with this.<br />
I&#8217;ve had it black, black with sugar, with cream, and with sugar and cream. I&#8217;ve had it from the sock, from a machine, from a drip maker, and have avoided instant altogether (and will continue to do so). In the end, I&#8217;ve found my favourite is with at least 2% milk (no skim, please!) and some sugar.<br />
Yes, the traditional Canuck double-double.<br />
And not because I don&#8217;t like the taste of coffee, but remember that all my history relating to the taste of coffee has been from consuming it usually in the form of a flavour, often sweet and usually creamy (e.g. ice cream, cake, desserts of some kind). So it shouldn&#8217;t come as a big surprise, really.<br />
So there we are. 25 coffees in about 2.5 months. Not too bad, eh?<br />
Now if you&#8217;ll excuse me, I need coffee #26&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/25-coffees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1244</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My first coffee</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/my-first-coffee/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-first-coffee</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/my-first-coffee/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 20:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, you read that right. I drank coffee. Not a coffee-flavoured beverage, not something with Kahlua. Coffee. Real. Honest. Caffeinated. Those of you who know me are probably all thinking the same thing: Uh oh. I offer you the following piece of encouragement: Don&#8217;t panic. I&#8217;m not an addict. Yet. So why now? Well, it &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/my-first-coffee/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My first coffee"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, you read that right. I drank coffee. Not a coffee-flavoured beverage, not something with Kahlua. Coffee. Real. Honest. Caffeinated.<br />
Those of you who know me are probably all thinking the same thing: Uh oh.<br />
I offer you the following piece of encouragement: Don&#8217;t panic. I&#8217;m not an addict. Yet.<br />
<span id="more-1158"></span>So why now? Well, it was partly a snap decision, though there was a wee bit of premeditation to it. Mark had suggested that we take a trip out to the <a href="http://www.orosivalley.com/">Orosi Valley</a>, a region about 30 kilometres east of San Jose. The valley is one of the major coffee-producing areas of Costa Rica, which is evident mere moments after entering the area &#8212; you can&#8217;t miss the rows of coffee plants.<br />
I opted to make this a &#8220;surprise&#8221; journey, and didn&#8217;t really tell Alex where we were going. As usual, this led to an endless string of placenames as Alex tried (unsuccessfully) to guess. This time, I figured I had her, since the route was convoluted enough that should wouldn&#8217;t be able to easily stumble across it. (On <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/17/weekend-at-tabacon/">our previous journey</a>, she knew we were going to Arenal within minutes of us leaving National Route 1.)<br />
Thanks to Hermes, we now had a faster way of getting around San Jose (the route we had known goes through San Jose, and takes well over an hour), which deposited us on the other site quite quickly. From there, the trip out was fairly uneventful, taking us past Tres RÃƒ ­os (the furthest east we had been to that point), over a fairly steep rise in the valley, then down into Cartago.<br />
Cartago is a place of pilgrimage for many Costa Ricans, notably for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuestra_Señora_de_los_Angeles_Basilica">Nuestra Señora de los Angeles Basilica</a>. It&#8217;s the home of the Virgin of the Angels, the patron (saint?) of Costa Rica. But that&#8217;s not what we were going out to see (at least, not this time). Although we did drive past the basilica, we only had the time to glance. We were still bound for our destination.<br />
(I should point out that &#8220;time&#8221; was a consideration. The Premier of China is in Costa Rica, and his arrival was wreaking havoc with traffic as they shut down highways to ease his travels. This meant we had to plan our travels carefully so we wouldn&#8217;t be caught in anything.)<br />
We continued to Paraiso, where I instructed Alex to look for a road sign to &#8220;Orosi&#8221;. Another diversion, since we weren&#8217;t actually going to the town of Orosi. Instead, towards the edge of the south side of Paraiso, we hung a left and started a weavy, windy, and steep drive down into the Orosi Valley.<br />
There are few places in the world I&#8217;ve been that stand out as being truly gorgeous. This is the sort of place I&#8217;d kill to be on a bike for a (sunny) day, just me &#8230; and my camera equipment, of course. High walls seem to surround the valley floor, which is largely taken up with a lake formed by the damming of the El RÃ­o Grande (used for hydroelectric power). The end of the lake near the dam is filled with floating vegetation, which offers a very picturesque view of the area.<br />
Shortly after 11:30, we arrived at <a href="http://www.lacasonadelcafetal.com/">La Casona del Cafetal</a>, a restaurant hidden 500 metres from the road in the middle of a coffee plantation. We&#8217;d come for the buffet (this was the root of the surprise), which is filled with traditional Costa Rican foods. Although some of the staff do speak English (far better than I can speak Spanish), that&#8217;s about where the catering to gringos stops. After that, it&#8217;s all Tico. I think Alex, Mi Pequeña Niña, and I were the only gringos there.<br />
Which, really, is fine with me.<br />
La Casona is perched on a small rise overlooking the lake. Although the day was cloudy, the view was still fantastic. I&#8217;m sure on a sunny day, the view can&#8217;t be beat. It was definitely a great place to go for brunch.<br />
[flickr]photo:3039247800(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3038399813(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3038405537(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
All morning, Alex and I had thought MPN was sick. She was sneezing a lot, her nose was running, and she had teary eyes. (We would later check with Nana &#8212; my mom &#8212; to get confirmation that it was just teething. Oddly enough, my little girl has yet to have a cold.) None of the ooziness seemed to diminish her appetite as she tore into almost everything put in front of her. (She avoided the carrots.)<br />
Being in the middle of a coffee plantation, I figured this place had to have good coffee. I kept asking Alex if she wanted one. At first she didn&#8217;t, but after getting some food, she changed her mind. And when she said &#8220;sÃ­ ­&#8221;, I added &#8220;dos&#8221;.  You could have knocked Alex over with a feather.<br />
It reminded me of when I first started to drink alcohol. Yep, time for a flashback&#8230;<br />
New Year&#8217;s Eve, 1995. It would be my last New Year&#8217;s in Ottawa &#8212; I got the flu the following year, and the year after that I was preparing to move from Toronto to Vancouver. But in 1995, a small platoon of us had traveled up to Ottawa, and were arranged around a massive circular table at the <a href="http://www.yangtze.ca/">Yangtze chinese restaurant</a> along Somerset, about four blocks from Chris&#8217; apartment.<br />
There were around 20 of us (a bit of a guess, my memory is a little fuzzy for obvious reasons), all of whom knew each other quite well. And one thing they all knew about me: I didn&#8217;t drink. It wasn&#8217;t for any reason, that&#8217;s just the way it was. Everyone accepted it &#8212; razzed me about it, I should add &#8212; but never forced anything.<br />
The waitress was taking orders, going around the table one person at a time, getting the list of people. When she got to Therese, Stuart, and Liz, the three of them decided to order a bottle of wine between them and asked if anyone else wanted some. For some reason &#8212; and likely no more reason than &#8220;just &#8216;cuz&#8221; &#8212; I decided that it might be nice to have some, too. Somehow, between all the commotion in the restaurant, the confusion of orders, and my not-quite-seen (or heard) motions, everyone missed that I&#8217;d put myself in with the order. Including the waitress, although she&#8217;d heard the &#8220;me, too&#8221;.<br />
When the waitress returned with the wine and four glasses, she could only figure out where the first three were supposed to go. She asked:</p>
<blockquote><p>Who had the fourth glass of wine?</p></blockquote>
<p>I replied:</p>
<blockquote><p>That would be me.</p></blockquote>
<p>You could have heard a pin drop. The entire table was silent &#8212; the only time for the next many hours that these people would be silent &#8212; and stayed that way for couple of heartbeats. The moment was broken by Stuart, who chipped in:</p>
<blockquote><p>Geoff&#8217;s gettin&#8217; liquored tonight!</p></blockquote>
<p>Such was the experience when Alex heard me order a coffee. For a moment she thought that I was correcting her order, and almost got our waitress to change it. She caught herself about to speak, and then looked at me in sheer shock. Me, her husband of 3 1/4 years, whom had shunned all coffee for the entirety of his life, was about to have a first cup.<br />
Drama, of course, ensued. The moment, for you doubters, was even captured on video.<br />
Now there are a significant number of people whom I&#8217;ve met over the years who were (and in many cases, still are) abjectly terrified of the idea of me drinking coffee. Certainly, a third of my life ago, that would definitely be true. Drinking that much caffeine as a younger man might have well turned me into a Jekyll and Hyde sort of personality (if you doubt me, ask the people who knew me in university), and that prospect scared the bejeezus out of them.<br />
One advantage of age: calm. Well, as calm as a guy like me can get. And frankly, calm enough that I wanted to try coffee. Living in Costa Rica, I feel like I&#8217;m being left out whenever I pass the coffee aisle (I jest not!) and savour the aroma. I love the smell of coffee, and the taste of coffee in things that I&#8217;ve eaten and drank. But coffee itself? I&#8217;d seen too many addicts of coffee to want to go that far&#8230;<br />
Still, I had to know.<br />
The coffee came not as a simple cup, but as a <a href="http://www.zurqui.com/crinfocus/cr/coffee.html">chorreador</a>. This is the way you drink coffee Costa Rican-style. The waitress poured in the hot water, and we waited for the coffee to fill the brown mug underneath. When it was ready, I sniffed at the steam that wafted from the top, not unlike sampling the nose of a fine wine (Alex probably thinks it was a wasted effort &#8212; the coffee was actually too strong).<br />
[flickr]photo:3039229692(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3039229726(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The first sip brought forth the taste of &#8230; well, coffee beans. I know, I know, that sounds like a really stupid thing to say, but the reality is that this was not exactly what I&#8217;d expected. Having only ever tasted coffee blended with other things, the taste of the other things masked some of the coffee flavour. So it wasn&#8217;t quite what I was expecting.<br />
[flickr]photo:3039232914(small)[/flickr]<br />
But it was far from bad.<br />
And yes, I liked it.<br />
In fact, as I continued to drink the cup, I couldn&#8217;t help but notice that things seem to look almost a little different. Colours seemed to be more saturated. Details became a little sharper. Everyone seemed to move just a little bit more slowly.<br />
Alex just continued to make fun of this, mockingly worried that we were going to have to set up a full import business to keep up to my coffee habit. (I hadn&#8217;t even finished my first cup.) I drank it straight, black, no sugar. I figured I had to know what true coffee tastes like before I start adding other things to it.<br />
Oddly enough, the drive home seemed to go a little more quickly than the drive in, even though I took a couple wrong turns (as I&#8217;ve mentioned before, not all the roads here are well-marked).  And I had serious trouble sleeping.<br />
Not that I think it&#8217;s at all related.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/my-first-coffee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>14 things I love about Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 18:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainforests]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I&#8217;ve been in Costa for nearly two straight months now &#8212; this is the longest continuous time I&#8217;ve ever spent outside of Canada &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s high time to answer the two most often-asked questions that I get: What do I like about Costa Rica, and what do I hate? I&#8217;ll answer &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "14 things I love about Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&#8217;ve been in Costa for nearly two straight months now &#8212; this is the longest continuous time I&#8217;ve ever spent outside of Canada &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s high time to answer the two most often-asked questions that I get: What do I like about Costa Rica, and what do I hate?<br />
I&#8217;ll answer the latter in <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/17-things-i-hate-about-costa-rica/">a separate post</a>, but like all reviews, there&#8217;s reason to start with the positive stuff. Of course, these are not in any order whatsoever &#8212; they&#8217;re just as they come to mind.</p>
<h3><span id="more-1103"></span>The Food</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to go to any country and not enjoy eating differently than you do where you came from. Much of the food here is Spanish-influenced (kind of obvious), but draws heavily on Peruvian, Mexican, American (you wouldn&#8217;t believe the number of KFC outlets here), Italian, and then a hodge-podge of other cuisines. There&#8217;s a lot more seafood, especially when you&#8217;re on the coasts, and healthy portions of chicken and beef. And fresh fruit.<br />
It&#8217;s not spicy, but there is a fair bit of fat as a result of oils, which is sometimes a bit hard to get by. But it&#8217;s fairly easy to avoid the deep-fried stuff.</p>
<h3>Fresh Fruit</h3>
<p>The biggest problem in Calgary when it comes to fruit is getting it fresh. And I mean <em>fresh</em>, as in the originating farm is less than 100 kms away. And here, it&#8217;s probably less than 10 kms. I&#8217;ve never had pineapple this fresh, papaya that is outstanding, and absolutely wonderful strawberries. And unlike back in Canada, there is no &#8220;season&#8221; &#8212; you get this fruit year-round.</p>
<h3>The Beer&#8230;</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s no Big Rock, no Sleemans, and certainly no Guinness. But in this heat, lighter beers are much more appreciated, anyway. Especially when they&#8217;re cheap. Your average bottle of Imperial (the most popular beer in Costa Rica) is 4.8% alcohol (by volume) and costs less than a dollar at the store. How can you go wrong with that?!</p>
<h3>&#8230; And Getting It Anywhere</h3>
<p>And wine, and liquor. No stupid rules like back in Canada &#8212; the grocery stores sell beer right next to the legs of lamb. Like it should be. The only place in Canada you can do that is in Quebec, which is a real shame as the heavy restructions on alcohol are likely part of the reason why people drink &#8212; it&#8217;s a taboo, rather than a normal part of life.<br />
The only place you can&#8217;t get any alcohol is at the football games. It&#8217;s an absolute no-no, and searches for booze are pretty strict on entrance. But then, we North Americans aren&#8217;t used to seeing riot police in regular attendance, either.</p>
<h3>Year-Round Green</h3>
<p>A note on the weather: to a Canuck, the seasons don&#8217;t change much in Costa Rica. It goes from warm and dry to warm and wet. (Or hot and wet to hot and dry, or just plain hot and wet, depending on where you are in the country.) People here start to haul out jackets when the sun goes down, but I wear shorts as much as I can (only the air conditioning at the office makes me think otherwise) and I almost always wear sandals.<br />
The heat, combined with the plentiful rain, means the leaves never fall from the trees, so the trees stay green year-round. (There is one tree I&#8217;ve seen that is losing its leaves, but there seem to be new green ones sprouting already.)</p>
<h3>Costa Rican Coffee</h3>
<p>Okay, I don&#8217;t drink coffee &#8212; yet (I&#8217;m determined to try, soon), but all I have to do is smell it to know the coffee here is outstanding. But this is also a coffee-growing country, so you have to expect it. All I do know is that Alex, Mark, and Jason have all raved about the coffee.<br />
And yes, when I do get around to having my first cup of joe, I&#8217;ll be documenting it. You folks don&#8217;t wanna miss that&#8230;</p>
<h3>The Beaches and the Ocean</h3>
<p>We are about 90-100 kms from a the beach. Not just any beach &#8212; a <em>good </em>beach. Given, that 100 kms takes about 2.5 hours to drive, thanks to the rather poor road situation here (see <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/17-things-i-hate-about-costa-rica/">the  Hate list</a> for more info). The ocean is also warm, like a nice warm bath. Not like the oceans on either side of Canada, which will deliver a pretty decent chill up your spine, no matter what time of year it is.</p>
<h3>Rainforests</h3>
<p>There is nothing like walking under the thick canopies, listening to countless birds, monkeys, insects, and who-knows-what-else while rain trickles down from above. That is, if you can get past the creepy-crawly things that live there. Not everyone can hack the spiders, snakes, huge beetles, millipedes, and mosquitoes. Personally, I love it. The closest I&#8217;ve come are the coastal forests in British Columbia. But these are, well, foreign to me, and offer such a different experience.</p>
<h3>The Birds</h3>
<p>I&#8217;m used to magpies (which I hate), robins, sparrows, crows, hawks, and if I&#8217;m really lucky, we might get some finches. All fairly typical of western Canada.<br />
Down here? Buzzards, toucans, birds of nearly every colour, and songs that we&#8217;ve never heard and that seem to change nearly every day. This is something I never tire of.</p>
<h3>Crickets</h3>
<p>I grew up with crickets chirping out my window at night. Alberta is devoid of crickets. Or at least where I am, there aren&#8217;t any to be heard. Once again, when the screen door is open (which is most nights), I can hear not only the chirping, but also the croaking of frogs out in the lago.</p>
<h3>Monkeys!!!</h3>
<p>I love monkeys. (Yeah, probably because I&#8217;m related to them. I&#8217;ve heard the joke. Next&#8230;) It is very easy to find wild monkeys in Costa Rica. Howlers are easy to hear at a distance, and if you&#8217;re lucky <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2774164871/">you&#8217;ll be chased by capuchins looking for a banana</a>.</p>
<h3>Relaxed Environment</h3>
<p>No-one really rushes here. The insane drive that most North Americans are attuned to doesn&#8217;t exist down here. There is no urgency (which is also not a good thing), no heavy pressure, and a much more laid-back attitude. While you might hate it at first, you slowly get sucked into it. It&#8217;s actually nice, once you get used to it.</p>
<h3>Storms</h3>
<p>It rains here nearly every day (we&#8217;re in the rainy season at the moment), sometimes for a few minutes, sometimes for hours. But at least once a week, we get a good thunderstorm. A rip-snorting one that rattles windows and knocks out power. I grew up to those kinds of storms, too, and Calgary just doesn&#8217;t get good thunderstorms.</p>
<h3>Extreme Friendliness</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to find someone who&#8217;s a real jerk. (And you know it when you do!) Most people here smile on mere gaze, and if you&#8217;re carrying a cute baby (like we regularly do), you&#8217;ll have people walk right up to you and chat you right up as if you&#8217;re a local. They&#8217;ll even ask to pick your child up and show it off to whomever&#8217;s around. It&#8217;s a little odd, but it&#8217;s still a wonderful thing.</p>
<h3>Things You Won&#8217;t See On The Hate List</h3>
<p>These are things I don&#8217;t hate, but perhaps not necessarily love. Still, they&#8217;re worth calling out because &#8212; believe it or not &#8212; I&#8217;ve been asked about all of them.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rain. Believe it or not, I actually don&#8217;t mind it here. It&#8217;s not cold, and even in the heaviest part of the year (which we&#8217;re in), it&#8217;s not really terrible as one might think.</li>
<li>Heat. I don&#8217;t dig heat, I admit that. But I&#8217;m acclimatising. I don&#8217;t sweat (as much) and I don&#8217;t complain about the heat (as much).</li>
<li>Lack of skilled help. This should drive me crazy, given that I need to find skilled help, but in the end I&#8217;m actually looking forward to the training aspect</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First weekend in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=first-weekend-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 19:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "First weekend in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, bought the things we need to make life reasonable (note: not &#8220;comfortable&#8221; &#8212; we&#8217;re still working on that), moved into a temporary office, got connected (still need cell phones), started working on new work, and had a surprising number of meetings given that there&#8217;s only four of us.<br />
So when we got to the end of the week, we had pretty much declared ourselves &#8220;beat&#8221;. Had we been a lot more set up than we are now, we&#8217;d probably have just gone home to our respective places, kicked back, and relaxed. But it&#8217;s hard to do that when you have to flag down a cab. Which you can&#8217;t here, for some reason.<br />
We rented a car instead.<br />
<span id="more-1010"></span>Sooner or later, you have to decide when enough is enough. Spending hours (I&#8217;m not joking, by the way) waiting for a taxi is not fun. While they&#8217;re fairly inexpensive (rarely more than a couple of dollars), it&#8217;s a colossal waste of time. As we&#8217;re all Type A people, it&#8217;s beyond frustrating.<br />
For the record, Jason wants to be a rally driver. I&#8217;m certain of this. We&#8217;ve got some dinky white Nissan that I swear could be foot-powered for all the oomph it has. But in Jason&#8217;s hands, that think could handle the Paris-Dakar race. On Sunday, we were exploring old Escazu, and Jason was whipping up and down roads like it was a marked course. No problems at all. This guy has adapted to Costa Rican driving.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603884205(small)[/flickr]<br />
Our first task with the car? Shopping.<br />
Yes, this was our wild Friday night. We went to the nearby Mas Por Menos (&#8220;More for Less&#8221;) store for various odds-and-ends that we&#8217;re all missing. I didn&#8217;t get much (I don&#8217;t want to get much; Alex and I are aiming for a more minimalist existence), but Mark filled a shopping cart.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603881365(small)[/flickr]<br />
After that, we went out in search of dinner. We searched for a Tican restaurant (we&#8217;ve done <em>gringo</em> to death) and found a place called Yakky&#8217;s. Kind of a dive, but by 21:00 the place was packed. The food was great, the beer was cheap (Imperial is the Costa Rican favourite, and it&#8217;s about $1 a bottle &#8212; markups are really small here). For the three of us, it was only $60 with a lot of food, several beers, and Mark and Jason endulged in a little JD. I drove us home.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603882479(small)[/flickr]<br />
Saturday was a trip into Escazu for some shopping. We were aiming for a place we thought was called &#8220;Se Marco&#8221; (turned out it was &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, which is a name of a department store ala The Bay). We found a box store called EPA, which is mostly a home improvement place. Mark loaded another shopping cart. Jason got keys cut for our office space, and we all got slop buckets and mops so we can actually clean our places. The cat hair in mine (Asia&#8217;s shedding like crazy) is getting out of hand.<br />
We found our way to Grau, a local chain of coffee shops. I still don&#8217;t drink coffee (I imagine it won&#8217;t be long before I do), but Jason and Mark were dying for one. I settled for a pineapple smoothie. It&#8217;s called a &#8220;batido&#8221;, which directly translates to &#8220;beaten&#8221;. Mixed with milk. Mmmmmm.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603885915(small)[/flickr]<br />
A trip to the mall found the real &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, and also the times for the English showing of <em>The Hulk</em> that we saw that night. (I have to say, a surprisingly good movie.) Not far from there was Aliss, another store that has a massive baby section that Alex will love.<br />
All the while, I should point out, Mark was searching for a french press so he could make coffee. This was almost an exercise in futility. French presses aren&#8217;t common here (yet). Unlike in North America, where you can about trip over all the Bodums, they&#8217;re a rarity even in the gringo centres. I kept telling Mark that he needed <a href="http://www.zurqui.com/crinfocus/cr/coffee.html">the Costa Rican method of making coffee</a>, but couldn&#8217;t remember the damn name of it (Chorreador de café), nor easily find it.<br />
Something I noticed as we went from store to store to store. The Euro Cup was playing on virtually every set. Everywhere we went, eyes were glued to sets. Football (&#8220;soccer&#8221; to us heathen North Americans) is second in importance only to the church. I think it even eclipses family when it comes to certain games. You really need to pull a sales guy away from the game to get his (or her, but they&#8217;re usually male) attention.<br />
We ate lunch in likely the last Chichi&#8217;s restaurant on Planet Earth. Might have been the prototype, too. Despite the disappointment in realising it was a restaurant chain, it was actually pretty good. Possibly the best fajitas I&#8217;ve had, actually.<br />
Sunday was notably quieter, with really only our excursion into old Escazu being a notable point. In fact, Ihad to work on a priority item for the Toronto office. It is nice to be wanted, though. Tricky part is the lack of connectivity at home, still. Weak internet means no phone or means of communication with the outside world. It&#8217;s a bit of a nuisance, admittedly. But slowly, adjusting.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603887367(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1010</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
