<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>birthday &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/birthday/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 14:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; not of woman borne! &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. Well, mostly. That &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Healthy 10th Birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A decade ago right now, Mommy and I were preparing to go to Foothills Medical Centre. There, Mommy would have a caesarian section and you would be pulled forth into this world &#8212; <em>not of woman borne!</em> &#8212; with your arm draped around your neck like a feather boa, safe and sound. </p>



<p>Well, mostly. That whole anti-K thing and all, as we remind you of every now and then. Which is almost a bizarre parallel to today: almost immediately after you were born, the doctors wanted to whisk you away to the NICU to ensure that the anti-K situation wasn&#8217;t affecting your health. You were isolated. </p>



<p>Ten years later, you&#8217;re isolated again. This time, none of our doing (biological or otherwise), but because of COVID-19. You&#8217;re spending your birthday apart from nearly everyone but your family. </p>



<span id="more-3685"></span>



<p>You had wanted a grand party for today, and had selected a pretty cool venue: Petland. With lots of animals and friends and cake and food and fun and &#8230; it was all cancelled. Everything non-essential is closing, or has already closed. School was cancelled, all classes for the rest of the school year. I hope you might remember this year for the longest summer ever, but who knows what is yet to come with restrictions. I&#8217;m not sure which you lament more, that you won&#8217;t have any friends for your birthday, or that you won&#8217;t have the party. You love your animals.</p>



<p>It seems today will be just the four of us. Mostly the three of you, I suppose, since I&#8217;m trapped in the basement, working from home. I hadn&#8217;t planned it this way, of course, and this is the World&#8217;s Lamest Excuse on a day like this while we&#8217;re all in this situation (I <em>am</em> in the house, after all), but this is the last card in my hand after playing all the others&#8230;</p>



<p>My vacation time this year was planned for next week, March break, as we were going to go Saltspring Island. And with today being a school day, you were <em>originally</em> going to go to school. (Admittedly, that changed, too, but by then my vacation time was all gone.) I was going to see you as much as possible today as I could. That was the plan. </p>



<p>Only three days ago, Sunday the 16th, the Government cancelled all classes. School out for summer. International travel was effectively banned. Albertans were <em>strongly </em>encouraged to not partake of any non-essential travel, effectively forcing a cancellation of vacation. The day after, my office went into full &#8220;work from home&#8221; mode, and I became one of the most needed people in the office to ensure that this was going to work. </p>



<p>Two days later, I&#8217;m in the basement, wishing I could have avoided this. I am sorry, Choo Choo. I wish this situation were different, very different. I wish I was with you the entire day, not just a part of it. I wish we could have your party, I wish we could go to the coast and see seals and whales and fairy doors. I hope that, somehow, we still manage to make today a good day for you, given the limitations on what we can &#8212; what we should responsibly &#8212; do. </p>



<p>One day, I hope, we will make this up for you. Maybe you&#8217;re 11th will be more memorable for the things we couldn&#8217;t do this year. Or, maybe, many years from now, you&#8217;ll reminisce on today: &#8220;Lemme tell you about my 10th birthday, when the whole world was on quarantine&#8230;&#8221;</p>



<p>Now that&#8217;ll be a story.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2020/03/healthy-10th-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Years a Monkey</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/10-years-a-monkey/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=10-years-a-monkey</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/10-years-a-monkey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 03:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Monkey, Ten years. A decade. Where do I start? Not the beginning. I&#8217;ve done that nearly every year for the last nine. Truth is, and as much as it&#8217;s hard for me to accept, you&#8217;re not my little baby anymore. You&#8217;re nearly to my chin. You&#8217;ve made us meals. You don&#8217;t need my assistance &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/10-years-a-monkey/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "10 Years a Monkey"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Monkey,<br />
Ten years. A decade.<br />
Where do I start?<br />
<span id="more-3638"></span>Not the beginning. I&#8217;ve done that nearly every year for the last nine. Truth is, and as much as it&#8217;s hard for me to accept, you&#8217;re not my little baby anymore. You&#8217;re nearly to my chin. You&#8217;ve made us meals. You don&#8217;t need my assistance for &#8230; well, pretty much anything anymore. We&#8217;re well past most of your significant firsts: steps, walks, baths, swims, jumps, foods, big-girl beds, school, friends, plane rides, train rides, horse rides, Christmases, Santa&#8217;s laps, Easter egg hunts.<br />
&#8220;Alone&#8221;. We have to come to terms with that. You&#8217;re starting to leave us, even if by those same first baby steps. You&#8217;re starting your escape from Mommy&#8217;s and my gravitational pull, flinging yourself out into the universe beyond, to explore the worlds beyond, to find your place, to find your own home. It&#8217;s the way of all life. It&#8217;ll be exciting, and while I&#8217;ll hold all the hope and pride for your success, I cannot deny that I&#8217;ll be drowning in your absence.<br />
We&#8217;ve got a lot of firsts yet to come, before then. Some of them will be wondrous, like your first date. Others will be heart-wrenching, like your first breakup. You&#8217;ll take busses on your own. You&#8217;ll drive a car. Going to the mall with your friends will be a sense of freedom that you can&#8217;t comprehend right now. And then, one day, you&#8217;ll leave with your things. The place and feeling you call &#8220;home&#8221; you knew will forever change.<br />
You&#8217;ve travelled more in your first ten years than I did in my first thirty. You&#8217;ve been to Europe, Central America, and several parts of North America. You&#8217;ve played on tropical beaches, shivvered in North Sea winds, seen the lights of New York City at Christmas, you&#8217;ve met an astronaut, climbed to the top of a mountain, looked across a city from one of the tallest structures in the world, seen Tinkerbell fly by as fireworks lit up the skies over Cinderella&#8217;s castle, jumped from a dock, held a chick in your hand, hugged a lamb, reached the top of the tree in our backyard. You&#8217;ve boarded a plane all on your own, and flew away.<br />
Ten years. A decade. Is this where <em>you</em> start? Is this where Monkey starts to become herself, instead of just my daughter?<br />
I suppose only time will tell.<br />
Happy birthday, Monkey!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/10-years-a-monkey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3638</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 5th Birthday, Choo Choo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 04:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m having some serious trouble, Choo Choo. You&#8217;re five. FIVE. You&#8217;ve hit that penultimate step from wee babe to being a grade-schooler (the last, obviously, is going to Kindergarten; at least we have a few months before that). But still, five. You&#8217;re a funny one, Choo Choo. You may be the oldest in your preschool class, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 5th Birthday, Choo Choo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m having some serious trouble, Choo Choo. You&#8217;re five. FIVE. You&#8217;ve hit that penultimate step from wee babe to being a grade-schooler (the last, obviously, is going to Kindergarten; at least we have a few months before that).<br />
But still, <em>five</em>.<br />
<span id="more-3425"></span><br />
You&#8217;re a funny one, Choo Choo. You may be the oldest in your preschool class, but you sure don&#8217;t act your age. And I&#8217;ll be honest, that is what I love about you. You&#8217;re playful, loving, accepting, and stupidly adorable (something you seem to instinctively know, and use to your advantage, I might add). You skip more than you walk or run (I call you &#8220;Skippy&#8221; for a reason). You love doing flips by holding my hands, walking up my legs and flipping over backwards. You&#8217;ll curl up on Mommy&#8217;s or my lap as readily as Asia. You&#8217;re trying to not grow up.<br />
And yet, you are. You&#8217;re taller than your sister was when she turned five. You&#8217;ve outgrown and/or destroyed several pairs of pants. You&#8217;re bigger than the bike you learned to ride last summer. You don&#8217;t fit in pretty much anything meant for a pre-schooler. Your car seat no longer uses its five-point harness. You can power back a pretty big chicken dinner.<br />
But my <em>lord</em> do you have the sweetest face, the most wonderful (and ear-piercing) shriek when you&#8217;re having fun, you tell the greatest stories, and your imagination runs rampant in ways I can&#8217;t even begin to describe. I know that the day you actually decide to let us teach you how to read, you&#8217;ll discover great new things.<br />
But I&#8217;m getting ahead of myself. You&#8217;re not there just yet.<br />
For now, you&#8217;re still my wee one. Even if you&#8217;re not so wee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/happy-5th-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3425</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A birthday hike</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/08/a-birthday-hike/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-birthday-hike</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/08/a-birthday-hike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 22:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, you&#8217;re seven. Like, seven. I&#8217;m having trouble really saying that. It&#8217;s just weird that you&#8217;re so much older than I always feel like you should be. You&#8217;re growing up a little more every day, and flit between my little girl and &#8230; well, kind of an evil genius, really. And truly, both are awesome. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/08/a-birthday-hike/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A birthday hike"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, you&#8217;re seven.<br />
Like, <em>seven.</em> I&#8217;m having trouble really saying that. It&#8217;s just weird that you&#8217;re so much older than I always feel like you should be. You&#8217;re growing up a little more every day, and flit between my little girl and &#8230; well, kind of an evil genius, really.<br />
And truly, both are awesome.<br />
<span id="more-3424"></span><br />
Okay, so let&#8217;s start with the obvious: Your birthday was two days ago, not today. We were all in Banff, enjoying ourselves. And by &#8220;we&#8221;, I am, of course, referring to the entire troupe: Mommy, you, Choo Choo, and myself, plus Auntie Cathy and Uncle Craig and your cousins, plus Nana and Auntie B. That was Auntie Cathy&#8217;s idea. Going up a mountain? That was Uncle Craig&#8217;s&#8230;<br />
So let me throw you my little perspective on this one.<br />
First off, neither you nor Choo Choo nor your cousins objected. Only Mommy did, and that was largely because Mommy wasn&#8217;t feeling terribly well. That left the rest of us (save for Nana and Auntie B, of course) to tackle the mountain. Sulphur Mountain, to be exact.<br />
That hike, by the way, is 5.5 km straight-line distance, running about 700 m straight-up. It&#8217;s not a tough climb, per se, but let&#8217;s remember that you young&#8217;uns are topping out at eight years old, and Choo Choo&#8217;s barely four and a half. (Never mind Uncle Craig, Auntie Cathy, and I, who are far from being spring chickens, with the latter two of us having office jobs and not being in very good shape.)<br />
Following a hearty (and filling) breakfast at Melissa&#8217;s across from our hotel, we drove up to the main parking lot, unloaded, and proceeded to start our climb. (Well, after Choo Choo <em>had </em>to stop to pick up a rock. She loves rocks. I don&#8217;t know why. But she wanted to carry a rock.)<br />
I will give you all massive amounts of credit for the fact that none of you said a thing for the first few switchbacks. (If anything, it was the grown-ups telling you to slow down and pace yourselves.) You were having fun, even enjoying it. I was worried we&#8217;d hear &#8220;can we go back now?&#8221; after only a few bends.<br />
In fact, I don&#8217;t recall any of you suggesting we head back. Of course, it could be that you were all pre-empted by us saying where we were on the trail, looking at how far you&#8217;ve come, keeping you moving, and so forth. But you did have your moments &#8212; you especially, Monkey &#8212; where you were pretty much done, and didn&#8217;t want to go another step. But, of course, we gave you no real option, either: you were almost at the top, and going back down was rather pointless.<br />
Still, at just over 90 minutes from starting, we all arrived at the top of a mountain. Which hugely impresses me. That&#8217;s not a quick hike for adults, let alone kids, and yet you did it pretty darned fast! And on your birthday!<br />
So, no, I&#8217;m not going to make you climb a mountain on your birthdays, though cool this was. With luck, however, this will end up being the start of a better trail habit for all of us. And maybe &#8212; just <em>maybe</em> &#8212; you&#8217;ll like hiking a bit better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/08/a-birthday-hike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 3rd birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 04:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s one of those funny things you sometimes run into as a parent. In one moment, you&#8217;re nearly panicking at the seemingly rapid passage of time, that your tiny infant is suddenly racing around the house, reading books far too advanced for her age, and threatening to debate logical positivism. Then you look down and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 3rd birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s one of those funny things you sometimes run into as a parent. In one moment, you&#8217;re nearly panicking at the seemingly rapid passage of time, that your tiny infant is suddenly racing around the house, reading books far too advanced for her age, and threatening to debate logical positivism. Then you look down and see that one child is adorably cute and had been so for, also seemingly long, forever.<br />
Today, dear Choo Choo, you turned 3. And while the world seems to be spinning around me beyond my control, you sit there at the centre of the storm, giggling and playing and singing songs and making faces and smiling, smiling, smiling. Oh, how I cannot believe how much happier my life is when I get a big hug from you.<br />
Like this morning, when you got up&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3242"></span>It wasn&#8217;t the greatest of mornings, sadly &#8212; your sister, Monkey, was having trouble getting moving. It was a struggle to get her to school on time, and even that didn&#8217;t go particularly well (her water bottle leaked, soaking her snow pants, which then froze). Things were better when I got home, and got a big hug from you.<br />
Then you, Mommy, and I hopped in the car to go get your birthday presents. We decided to try something a little different this year, and let you choose what you got. So we headed over to Market Mall, where you played for a bit in the play area, and then marvelled at all the toys at the Toys &#8216;R Us.<br />
And I have to say, kiddo, you were pretty conservative with your choices. When I was a boy, I would have gone bananas in a store like that, and would have tried to clean the place out. You hung onto a teddy bear dressed a Woody from <em>Toy Story</em> for most of the time, passed up on the lightsabres (which was good, we&#8217;d have to buy two and they ain&#8217;t cheap!), fell in love with a <em>My Little Pony</em> set and a Duplo set with Ariel, and a pair of sunglasses (which you needed, anyway). Mommy added in a Richard Scarry boardgame with airplanes (you&#8217;ve been wanting an airplane since before Christmas). And, finally, you gave up the teddy bear (why, I&#8217;m still not sure) for a Bubble Guppies stuffie.<br />
As Mommy handled the transaction, you hugged your new stuffie tightly, looked at Mommy and I with big wide, eyes, and then gave us each a big hug.<br />
After finding a coffee for mommy (and a hot chocolate for you), I got Monkey from school and Mommy wrapped all of your presents so you could open them later. Then Mommy made a fresh carrot cake and I made dinner while you and Megan played. Then all of us went to go watch Monkey&#8217;s last dance class. You sat on my lap for most of the class. I got lots of big hugs.<br />
After a stop at the library to acquire a few new books, we returned home to find Grandma waiting for us. At first you were terrified of seeing Grandma (I have no idea why), though that quickly subsided and you were ecstatic to be around her again. You played with her until dinner time, and shovelled in your butter chicken, followed by your birthday carrot cake. (A note for next year &#8212; wait until we stop singing before you blow out your candles, okay?)<br />
Present opening and playing came next, which was rapidly ending the day &#8212; both you and Monkey were tired, and tensions began to run very thin. Monkey, sadly, was feeling left out because it wasn&#8217;t her birthday, and no-one was paying her as much attention as we were paying to you. It&#8217;s understandable, and I guess I&#8217;m thankful I don&#8217;t remember doing the same to Auntie Cathy.<br />
Finally, we packed you off to bed, where you settled into your warm sheets, your smile just as big as it was when you woke up. You talked about your new toys, and your new books, and were very happy about your new pyjamas. Then, with your turtle on, you lay down for sweet birthday dreams.<br />
Right after you gave me a great, big, awesome hug.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/happy-3rd-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3242</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 5th Birthday, Monkey</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/happy-5th-birthday-monkey/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-5th-birthday-monkey</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/happy-5th-birthday-monkey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 04:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today was a big day, Monkey. A milestone &#8212; yet another of many to come. Another year has passed, but it&#8217;s an important one. You&#8217;re past infant, toddler, and now preschooler. You&#8217;re a real kid, now. You&#8217;re going to school &#8212; real school. You&#8217;re not my &#8220;little&#8221; girl anymore. You&#8217;re a big girl now, really. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/happy-5th-birthday-monkey/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 5th Birthday, Monkey"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was a big day, Monkey. A milestone &#8212; yet another of many to come. Another year has passed, but it&#8217;s an important one. You&#8217;re past infant, toddler, and now preschooler. You&#8217;re a real kid, now. You&#8217;re going to school &#8212; real school.<br />
You&#8217;re not my &#8220;little&#8221; girl anymore. You&#8217;re a big girl now, really. (You&#8217;ll always be little, by the way. Just accept it and let&#8217;s move on, shall we?) I still find it hard to see you growing up, almost like you&#8217;re slowly getting away from me with every day.<br />
I can&#8217;t believe you&#8217;re 5 already, Monkey.<br />
<span id="more-3144"></span>It&#8217;s hard to think of all things you&#8217;ve been able to start doing on your own since the start of the year. You could already dress yourself, and you&#8217;re sort of okay with brushing your teeth, but now you&#8217;re starting to read on your own, and you no longer need training wheels on your bike. You&#8217;re big, Monkey!<br />
It&#8217;s with that rather wistful thought that we review your birthday, which was today. (We had your party a couple of weeks ago, mostly because that was when we could actually get your friends to come over. Summers are hard to schedule.) We&#8217;d agreed on the event when Grandpa was here last &#8212; we were going (back) to Calaway Park.<br />
We arrived just as the gates were opening, and zipped inside for a (half) day of fun. You and Mommy were on the bumper boats almost immediately, while Choo Choo and I tried to figure out how to stay occupied until the ride was over. (Sorry, Choo Choo, but you&#8217;re just not quite big enough for some of the more fun rides just yet.)<br />
Then it was off to the &#8220;antique cars&#8221;. You drove, Choo Choo ran shotgun while Mommy and rode in the back. You drove very well &#8230; not that you had much of a choice &#8212; the track is pretty hard to get away from.<br />
Mommy and you went on the spinny ride that Choo Choo didn&#8217;t much like &#8212; she went on the plane ride (which you followed on later). We went to the (laser) shooting range. You actually hit things (with a bit of help). Mommy won at the skeeball game; you and Choo Choo got a pair of unicorns from the deal. We did the train ride again, after you both went on the kiddie roller coaster. We had lunch.<br />
The afternoon ended with a trip on the hot air balloon ferris wheel and a ride around on the Baja buggies before we headed back home. Grandma met us there for dinner. We had a ladybug-shaped cake (you wouldn&#8217;t believe how the black spots of the icing did a number on your lips, tongue, and teeth). You got some wonderful presents.<br />
And you passed out, hard, Monkey. But you had a really, really big, wonderful day.<br />
I still can&#8217;t believe you&#8217;re 5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/08/happy-5th-birthday-monkey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3144</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 2nd birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 04:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy 2nd birthday, my dear Choo Choo! It&#8217;s almost impossible to believe you been with us only two years, you shining little light. Two short &#8212; and somehow, impossibly long &#8212; years ago, you found yourself suddenly freezing, weighed, and then set upon by a dozen doctors and nurses who were all convinced you were &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 2nd birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy 2nd birthday, my dear Choo Choo!<br />
It&#8217;s almost impossible to believe you been with us only two years, you shining little light. Two short &#8212; and somehow, impossibly long &#8212; years ago, you found yourself suddenly freezing, weighed, and then set upon by a dozen doctors and nurses who were all convinced you were not exactly in the best of health. To see you running around today, inhaling chocolate cupcakes like they were air &#8230; well, if anything, I&#8217;d suspect those doctors would feel proud you&#8217;ve turned out so well.<br />
Goodness knows I am, kiddo.<br />
<span id="more-3000"></span>Today&#8217;s events started almost as normally as any Sunday could. We got up, we had pancakes. Of course, Grandpa being around was definitely a different thing &#8212; he&#8217;s here a lot, but not that often. And then we had no blueberries for our pancakes (we ran out, and I forgot to get more). And then we tore out the kitchen.<br />
Oh, did I forget to mention that, on your second birthday, we gutted the kitchen and Mommy&#8217;s and my bathroom and moved to another house?<br />
My dear, you will not remember our old kitchen. Monkey will, but likely only a little. You likely won&#8217;t remember it at all. We&#8217;ll show you pictures of it, and you might think it reminds you of something, but &#8230; well, Choo Choo, you&#8217;re not old enough. You&#8217;re only two.<br />
Funny thing is, you&#8217;ve been acting a lot older than two for a long time. I credit your sister with this &#8212; she has taught you a lot. And sadly, a lot of it is BAD HABITS (*ahem*, Monkey, thank you for that!). I&#8217;m not saying you act badly, Choo Choo, but you tend to put your foot down (literally) a lot more easily than perhaps you should. Your attitude has formed very early.<br />
As has your vocabulary. You still can&#8217;t say your sister&#8217;s name right, and you can&#8217;t say &#8220;milk&#8221;, either. You have, however, a wonderful little &#8220;click&#8221; in place of the &#8220;k&#8221;. You can say &#8220;cat&#8221;, &#8220;coat&#8221;, &#8220;cars&#8221;, and &#8220;cup&#8221; fairly well, though they do tend to sound more like &#8220;tat&#8221;, &#8220;toat&#8221;, &#8220;tars&#8221;, and &#8220;tup&#8221; a little more than anything. It&#8217;s developmental, though, and we&#8217;re hearing signs that you&#8217;ll be getting that nice hard-&#8220;k&#8221; sound soon. The question will then be how long it takes you to say &#8220;yellow&#8221; instead of &#8220;lellow&#8221; (Monkey went about a year before she got it right, much to Grandpa&#8217;s delight).<br />
After Daddy and the people who bought our kitchen cabinets were done, we went to the Cabin Cafe for lunch. You squealed though most of your baby bagel egger sandwich, and then we went back to the house for you to have a nap. When you woke up, we went over to our temporary house for dinner (roast chicken, potatoes, and brocolli &#8212; one of your favourites), and Mommy made you chocolate birthday cupcakes. You got some wonderful presents, including a new baby doll (&#8216;cuz this family needs a sixth baby doll&#8230;)<br />
Tonight, you&#8217;re trying to sleep in a bed. Well, on a mattress on the floor, anyway. You&#8217;re not in your crib, which is proving to be a bit of a problem. Mommy&#8217;s been in with you now for about 45 minutes, and you&#8217;re really just not interested with going to sleep. I foresee many nights coming up of you needing to be held before you go to bed. But don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s a problem, Choo Choo &#8212; your daddy is always willing to cuddle up with you.<br />
I hope you had a wonderful second birthday, even if you won&#8217;t really remember it. Next year&#8217;s birthday, if Mommy has her way, should not only be memorable, but should hopefully be one you do remember.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/03/happy-2nd-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3000</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 4th Birthday, Monkey!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/08/happy-4th-birthday-monkey/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-4th-birthday-monkey</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/08/happy-4th-birthday-monkey/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 05:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My big girl just got a little bigger. You turned 4 today, Monkey. You&#8217;re now so old that I&#8217;m having trouble remembering when you weren&#8217;t in my life. I&#8217;m also having trouble remembering when you were a wee babe, which kind of breaks my heart a little. Unlike your other birthdays, I didn&#8217;t get to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/08/happy-4th-birthday-monkey/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 4th Birthday, Monkey!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My big girl just got a little bigger. You turned 4 today, Monkey. You&#8217;re now so old that I&#8217;m having trouble remembering when you weren&#8217;t in my life. I&#8217;m also having trouble remembering when you were a wee babe, which kind of breaks my heart a little.<br />
Unlike your other birthdays, I didn&#8217;t get to spend all of today with you. I had to go to work, so you spent most of the day with Mommy, and then with Grandma just before I got home. But in case you don&#8217;t remember today, Monkey, I hope you remembered yesterday.<br />
That&#8217;s when we partied.<br />
<span id="more-2964"></span>Okay, maybe not &#8220;partied&#8221; in the ways that you will in the years to come. (C&#8217;mon, you&#8217;re only four, for cryin&#8217; out loud!) But you did have a party, with friends you met at school (and not kids that were invited because their parents are friends of Mommy and me), and some of the kids from the neighbourhood. It wasn&#8217;t huge &#8212; we topped out at maybe 5 kids running around all at once? (Well, 6 if you count me&#8230;)<br />
We all got up early, as we had a lot of things to do before your friends arrived. Chocolate blueberry pancakes with real maple syrup. (Does it get any better?) Then you and I had to race out to run a couple of errands: take the rented hedge trimmer back, and then go get your Rapunzel-themed birthday cake from Safeway in Westhills (along with a few other commodities). Then it was a race back home.<br />
Not 10 minutes after we got back, the castle arrived. You&#8217;ve been missing your bouncy castles, Monkey. Ever since the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market moved, you&#8217;ve not been getting your bouncy castle fix. Mommy agonized over it, but found one for you that fit rather nicely on the front lawn. You couldn&#8217;t wait to get inside.<br />
Choo Choo, you had a little bounce, too, and despite a current inability to jump, I can already tell that you&#8217;re going to love these things.<br />
The first guest to arrive was a special guest, Princess Kim, a woman from Mommy&#8217;s high school who does girls&#8217; parties dressed as a princess. It really fit with the princess theme that we were drilling into everyone.<br />
(A note to future dads who find that they are having girls: Yes, you will have to deal with dolls, and hair, and princesses, and painted nails, and all the things that will make you cringe in abject fear. Remember one detail: if it makes them happy, then it&#8217;s good. Because when the princesses are happy, you&#8217;re the King, baby.)<br />
Next up was Camilla, followed soon by Nicole, both from your Spanish preschool. I&#8217;m still rather amazed that you don&#8217;t seem to have trouble at preschool, but you also seem to have no ability to speak it (yet for a while in Costa Rica, you spoke far more Spanish than English). The final guest was Sophia, the little girl from across the street whom you adore. I hope the two of you are friends for a long time to come.<br />
You bounced, you ate cake at 11:00, you danced with Princess Kim (who also painted your nails, and attempted to do crafts with you), you bounced some more, you opened presents (our home has finally seen its first Barbie), and you bounced.<br />
By noon, Camilla and Nicole were gone, and the bouncy castle saw the arrivals of Coen (the little boy from next door) and Zane (the boy from a few doors down), along with brief appearances from a couple of the other kids in the area. There was bouncing, and there was giggling and laughing, and there was me chasing people with the garden hose (hey, seemed like a good idea at the time).<br />
After a small lunch of berries (fresh, of course), you and Choo Choo both passed out like lead weights. For a brief time, the echoing  cacophony  that had erupted throughout the yard vanished, and it was silent. It was glorious. And Mommy and I realised that, yes, we aren&#8217;t the only people in the neighbourhood who have to yell at their kids to get their attention&#8230;<br />
You went for your final bounces just after 15:00, and waited right up until the last second before the man pulled the plug on the bouncy castle so he could pack it up and take it away. I felt sorry that it had to go, Monkey, I really did. I almost wish there were a way to get one in your room all the time.<br />
Tonight, Grandma stayed for dinner, and we finished off your Rapunzel cake. We opened your presents (ah, who am I kidding? &#8212; you opened your presents &#8230; there was no &#8220;we&#8221; involved, here), and you stayed up late watching <em>Kiki&#8217;s Delivery Service</em>.<br />
I hope you had a good birthday, honey. And I hope this is one you remember. Because I hope you remember it for a long, long time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/08/happy-4th-birthday-monkey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2964</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Birthday Weekend</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-birthday-weekend</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 05:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy birthday to me, etc., bla bla bla and yadda yadda yadda. Yes, it was yesterday, but I was a little too preoccupied with my birthday to actually write about it. So it comes, here at the end of the weekend, as we wind down the festivities and prepare for another week of near-abject mayhem. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Birthday Weekend"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy birthday to me, etc., bla bla bla and yadda yadda yadda. Yes, it was yesterday, but I was a little too preoccupied with my <em>birthday</em> to actually write about it. So it comes, here at the end of the weekend, as we wind down the festivities and prepare for another week of near-abject mayhem.<br />
I will freely admit that it wasn&#8217;t my &#8220;best&#8221; birthday, but it was definitely memorable (and positively so), which in the end is pretty much all you can ask for, right? Besides, it&#8217;s the last birthday before I get tagged with all those &#8220;other the hill&#8221; monikers. (Cathy, if you even <em>think</em> about pulling a lawn full of fake gravestones next year, you have no idea the wrath I shall drop on you for your 40th&#8230;)<br />
It all started at 4:00am on Saturday morning&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2953"></span>That&#8217;s when Choo Choo woke up. Choo Choo has a nasty habit of waking up long before a &#8220;reasonable&#8221; hour, notably 8:00am, which after many late night for many weeks/months, is a significant improvement over, oh, anything before it. I managed to get her back down in her crib and back to sleep, and it looked like that might work. Which it did, for about 30 minutes or so. Up again.<br />
I was up for good before 6:00am, although exactly what time it was, I couldn&#8217;t tell you. Nor can I tell you the exact details from when I got up until about 7:15 or so, which is when the Daily Battle of the Wills started again (in other words, when I tell Monkey that she needs to get dressed for the day), and I effectively ended up going back to bed to lie down from physical and mental exhaustion.<br />
And this, dear reader, is where things at Casa del Sowrey went decidedly sideways. I (moronically) decreed that unless Monkey got changed, we were leaving her behind for breakfast (the plan was to go up to the Sunterra). It was a hollow threat, and I (wrongly) assumed it would motivate her to get dressed. Monkey slammed her door (yes, she&#8217;s only three &#8212; I&#8217;m installing bumpers before too long), and after being (rightly) admonished for my overbearing behaviour, I (idiotically) sulked off to my room and inadvertently slammed my door, too (swung the door too hard, got caught in the draft, I dunno, nor does it matter). I laid down, closed my eyes to stop the throbbing, and must have passed out, if only for a few minutes.<br />
Alex, for her part, remained the calm centre of chaos, and (wisely) wrote the both of us off. She took Choo Choo and proceeded to breakfast, as neither Monkey nor I were really being cooperative, and it was wholly unfair to have Alex and Choo Choo go hungry because of our bad behaviour. I didn&#8217;t know that they&#8217;d left (having apparently passed out) until Monkey came in and woke me up because she was hungry (and actually dressed). I (still wrongly) assumed we were all going to Sunterra. I was then informed that Mommy had left. I was &#8230; well, still exhausted, and also a little stunned.<br />
I went into a heavy funk. Be it due to my aforementioned exhaustion, or ego, or what-have-you, I felt a little put out. It didn&#8217;t help that I&#8217;d woken with a wicked sense of abandonment to begin with, but now I&#8217;d had an actual instance to back it up, too. I fed Monkey, and then started to wallow in self-pity (along with a couple of strong cups of coffee).<br />
Okay, let me explain a little&#8230;<br />
Some 10 years ago, I used to hang out with friends frequently (it didn&#8217;t help that I lived with one of my best friends, Chris, so we had guests almost constantly). Even after I moved into my own home, I still lived with a good friend, and did pretty much what I wanted when I wanted. I saw people, I went out, I had &#8220;fun&#8221;. (I use the quotes only to indicate the general term of &#8220;fun&#8221;, rather than imply some form of negative or sarcasm.)  Even when Alex and I got married, there was still the sense of seeing friends and other people &#8212; Alex and I went out fairly frequently, so we never felt house-bound.<br />
And then we had kids. And my friends got married. And moved away. Had kids of their own. And suddenly &#8230; I realised that despite all the people I knew, I felt very much alone.<br />
That&#8217;s what hit me Saturday morning. Even though I had a loving family (we&#8217;ll ignore the whole 4:00am-10:00am window due to sheer irregular chaos), I felt like I was at the end of my line. I was the afterthought, the forgotten bottom rung on the ladder that no-one pays attention to until it breaks, the unimportant character who merely provides some iota of accessory plot development in a story. Pick your version of &#8220;insignificant&#8221;, I thought about it and threw myself a little Pity Party for One.<br />
Why? I&#8217;ve had a bad sense of abandonment since I was a kid. I <em>hated</em> being left out of things. I&#8217;d hear about a great party that lots of people were invited to &#8230; but not me. Or was the last to be chosen for a baseball team. Or found out about a movie that friends went to without me, and wasn&#8217;t asked. And so on. I still have that problem, and I probably always will. I haven&#8217;t come to terms with it; I&#8217;ve become jaded, and even perhaps a bit bitter, too. But, it is what it is.<br />
Now, maybe you can picture me being all bitter (stupidly so) and wanting to crawl back into bed and writing off my birthday entirely &#8212; I could and it was everything in my will to not actually do that. Leave it to the Monkey to improve the situation by changing the day&#8217;s schedule.<br />
Alex and Monkey had spent the better part of a day making me a cake. (Alex had found a train-shape cake mould a couple of years ago, and <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/07/happy-birthzap-to-me/">I bore witness to it for the first time last year</a>.) They&#8217;d baked it almost in secret (the mould was found in the sink, which tipped me off), and had taken it to the basement to decorate away from my prying eyes. To say that Monkey was excited about this cake is as much an understatement as saying that standing under Niagara Falls will get you a little damp.  Alex referred to it as a &#8220;cake made with love&#8221;. And Monkey hauled it out at 10:30am because she simply couldn&#8217;t wait any longer for her Daddy to see it.<br />
You couldn&#8217;t really recognise the train shape underneath the mashed, lumped, and smeared icing, or the zillions of candies and Bits &#8216;N Bites that encrusted the semi-circle of cake cars. The locomotive was green, and was proudly declared to be a manifestation of my favourite locomotive, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/sets/72157624305549435/">CN 6060</a>. Any critic would have regarded it at &#8220;hideous&#8221;. I looked at it, and immediately felt like an ass for feeling like ass. Sometimes, you need a kid to remind you that life is wonderful from nearly any angle.<br />
The cake, for the record, was delicious. (Alex makes amazing baked goods. If I haven&#8217;t stated it before &#8212; though I&#8217;m sure I have &#8212; she makes my favourite cookies.) The fact that my family had gone to that extent for me really hit home the fact that no matter how bad I feel, they&#8217;re there for me. Always. It was definitely what I needed.<br />
And my friends did come out for me &#8212; via the internet. (I think I might die without the awesomeness of social media, if for no other reason than for the plethora of birthday wishes.) From around the world, no less, which really makes it that much more awesome.<br />
Although an original plan had us going out to Banff for a picnic (Parks Canada&#8217;s official 100th birthday party was also on Saturday), we opted for a nearer picnic at the park next to the primary school Monkey and Choo Choo will attend in the years to come. I made chicken sandwiches, cut some grapes, and grabbed some of the leftovers from the night before. Monkey wheeled her doll in her stroller, and we sat down to a wonderful little lunch.<br />
One of the reasons we didn&#8217;t go to Banff was that we &#8220;had dinner plans&#8221;. This was another surprise Alex had lined up (have I mentioned that <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2004/04/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/">I like surprises</a>?), and I couldn&#8217;t wait to see what was going to happen. When Janice (aka Grandma) arrived, we ducked out and (mostly) walked up to LeVilla, a nicely upscale restaurant in the West Market Square not far from the house.<br />
I hadn&#8217;t ever actually planned on going to <a href="http://www.levilla.ca/">LeVilla</a>, although Alex had assumed I did. Why? Well, last weekend &#8212; the only time we managed to do the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/monkeys-first-stampede/">Stampede pancake breakfast</a> this year &#8212; LeVilla (wisely) distributed cards to everyone waiting in line. I pocketed it, not having any particular plan at the time, except possibly to follow up on it. Alex took it as &#8220;boy, would I ever like to eat there!&#8221; and looked into it. By happy circumstance, it was the best possible thing to happen.<br />
Neither Alex or I can remember exactly the last time we had an adult meal at a nice restaurant without having to cut spaghetti for one of the kids. We suspect it was at Bacchus, which was a fairly nice restaurant in Santa Ana, a few kilometre from our condo in Costa Rica. I think it was either for Mother&#8217;s Day, or for Alex&#8217;s birthday. But it was one of the only times in recent memory. This meal was not only outstanding (seriously &#8212; Calgarians, check it out, you won&#8217;t be disappointed), it was worth every penny of the much-higher-than-we-normally-pay price.<br />
My meal was prime rib. Although a little more done than I would have preferred (I like mine rare), I cannot remember the last time I had such an excellent piece of roasted beef, and Dad, I can finally say after many, many years that I&#8217;ve found a yorkshire pudding to rival yours. My slab was huge, I definitely ate too much, and it was worth every little twinge of mild discomfort.<br />
Alex told me that she had hoped to pull off a three-event evening, starting with dinner, and ending with a trip out to the nightly fireworks at the Stampede (or more importantly, to see the fireworks near the Stampede). Mini-golf had been her goal for the middle event, but a fairly central mini-golf doesn&#8217;t seem to exist in Calgary, and going a long distance wasn&#8217;t really  desirable. Bowling was a consideration, but eventually we just decided to take our time getting to the fireworks.<br />
We got to Inglewood around 8:30 &#8212; easily two and a half hours before the fireworks would begin. So we drove through and around Inglewood, mostly just to see what was there (neither of us had really looked much beyond 9th Ave). Then we drove up into Ramsay to find a place to park.<br />
The city had (wisely) cordoned off the streets on Scotsman&#8217;s Hill/Bluff (not sure what the correct name is) to residents only, so the streets wouldn&#8217;t be completely jammed with Stampeding crowds (there&#8217;s a handy set of stairs that go right into the grounds). We had to walk from a few blocks away, and up a fairly steep hill to get to the park. We were early enough that benches were still vacant, and the sun was setting behind the downtown core.<br />
I always forget how nice a view it is from there, and really need to remind myself to go up there more often. We strolled over to a bench, sat down, and laid on the bug spray as thickly as we could. (We knew from a similar sojourn many years earlier that the mosquitos up there are near-epic in concentrations.) Then we sat down to wait.<br />
Alex and I haven&#8217;t had such long sustained conversations in ages, without having been interrupted by our kids, anyway. There were, however, kids aplenty to offer distractions. Such as a pair of girls (I estimate at 5 and 8, respectively) who were operating a truly wonderful lemonade stand across the street from the park. They loudly and proudly announced their business and offered it readily to whomever was in need of refreshment. I simply couldn&#8217;t resist.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/yay-lemonade/' title='Yay! Lemonade!'><img width="300" height="200" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Yay-Lemonade--300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3281" alt="Yay! Lemonade!" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5948980431/">Geoff S.</a><br />
It&#8217;s the little things like that &#8212; the lemonade stand, and the great chat I&#8217;d had with the kids mother &#8212; which remind me why parts of Calgary are truly great. Give me the &#8220;inner city&#8221; any day &#8212; the vibrance of the communities remind me that it&#8217;s not just about having a roof over your head to sleep, it&#8217;s about being around your neighbours.<br />
I snapped picture after picture as the sun set behind the downtown core. I don&#8217;t remember the last sunset Alex and I watched, although I&#8217;m willing to bet it was when we were living in Costa Rica (the fantastic sunsets were nearly daily). The clouds overhead created fantastic orange ripples, and a bright yellow glow seemed to burst from behind the Calgary Tower.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/downtown-silhouette-1/' title='Downtown silhouette #1'><img width="300" height="104" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Downtown-silhouette-1-300x104.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3282" alt="Downtown silhouette #1" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5948526495/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/downtown-sunset-sky/' title='Downtown sunset sky'><img width="300" height="181" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Downtown-sunset-sky-300x181.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3283" alt="Downtown sunset sky" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5949087086/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/downtown-silhouette-4/' title='Downtown silhouette #4'><img width="300" height="156" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Downtown-silhouette-4-300x156.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3284" alt="Downtown silhouette #4" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5948534799/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The Grandstand Show started, and we listened to the music in the distance, watching the tease of sporadic fireworks that accentuated the show. As the hour crept closer and closer to 23:00, more and more people began to arrive at the park. Kids in the pyjamas, couples with blankets, people with their pets, and even a guy with his bike who had clearly been fishing out cans and bottles from the garbage bins sat down to wait for the show.<br />
Finally, the show hit its finale, and the lights went out to witness the pyrotechnic spectacle.<br />
I love fireworks. I love the artistry that goes into them &#8212; not just the construction of a big shell, but the arrangement of a variety of them into a single segment of flashes and streams and bangs and thuds. I remember when we were kids, Dad would take us out on the lake to watch the Benson and Hedges Symphony of Fire at Ontario Place. We&#8217;d listen to the choreographed show over the radio, which played the music to which the fireworks danced. Although there was no music at the Stampede (really, I can&#8217;t figure why not), the show was nevertheless stupendous.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/stampede-fireworks/' title='Stampede Fireworks'><img width="300" height="200" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Stampede-Fireworks-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3285" alt="Stampede Fireworks" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5949095136/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/stampede-fireworks-2/' title='Stampede fireworks'><img width="300" height="149" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Stampede-fireworks-300x149.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3286" alt="Stampede fireworks" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5948541935/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/multi-coloured/' title='Multi Coloured'><img width="300" height="295" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Multi-Coloured-300x295.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3287" alt="Multi Coloured" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5948549475/">Geoff S.</a><br />
  <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/nearing-the-end/' title='Nearing the end'><img width="300" height="162" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Nearing-the-end-300x162.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3288" alt="Nearing the end" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5949114148/">Geoff S.</a><br />
The fireworks were divided into three sequences (or so I heard), but we left shortly after the first one ended. The mosquitoes were bad, and it was late (we were tired). As it turned out, it was a good plan, since the sky was filling with its own flashes, which turned to heavy rain, hail, severe claps of thunder, which led to (we think) a short blackout in Mission. Not bad for one day&#8230;<br />
Today, the Sunday, was pretty good, too. Choo Choo finally slept in a bit, and although Monkey and her were a bit loud in the morning, both Alex and I got some much-needed rest. Pancakes, then a bit of play time. We visited with our newest neighbours next door, who are reaching the end of a major renovation (they bought the house in March) and we&#8217;re still getting to know them. Monkey plays with their kids, ages 7 and 3, and I had gone over to retrieve her for lunch &#8230; and stayed for nearly 90 minutes chatting.<br />
I love this neighbourhood. I wasn&#8217;t originally thrilled about moving here &#8212; I wanted to be closer to downtown, admittedly &#8212; but having such awesome people around really makes it hard to not want to know everyone.<br />
Their kids came over after dinner, and we all played in the basement. I found out their daughter &#8212; the 7 year old &#8212; has a devious streak in her. (She tried, almost successfully, to cram an icepack down my shirt.)<br />
So now I sit at my kitchen table, looking at the events of two days. Alex says I&#8217;ve been sighing a lot as I write this. I think it&#8217;s a good thing &#8212; they&#8217;re the moments that remind me that, yes, life may be periodically difficult, but it is those little moments that make it matter.<br />
Thank you, my family, for making this a great weekend. Thank you for caring, for making me feel special, and being there for me every day. I love you all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/07/a-birthday-weekend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2953</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy first birthday, Choo Choo!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-first-birthday-choo-choo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 05:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, my little girl, you&#8217;re a year old today. A year ago, you came into our world early, confused, cold, and separated from Mommy. It wasn&#8217;t exactly how any of us had hoped you&#8217;d arrive, but we were happy to have you no matter how it all went. Mommy and I had been looking forward &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy first birthday, Choo Choo!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, my little girl, you&#8217;re a year old today. A year ago, <a title="Arrived: Choo Choo" href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/03/arrived-choo-choo/">you came into our world early, confused, cold, and separated from Mommy</a>. It wasn&#8217;t exactly how any of us had hoped you&#8217;d arrive, but we were happy to have you no matter how it all went.<br />
Mommy and I had been looking forward to today for a long time. We wanted your first birthday to be small, surrounded with just a few of us, making as much fuss as we could without completely overwhelming you. Today wasn&#8217;t really about you, so much as it was about us. You see, we&#8217;re actually kind of sad, today.<br />
Why? Well, you&#8217;re no longer our baby girl. You&#8217;re grown up.<br />
<span id="more-2879"></span>In the year that&#8217;s passed, an awful lot has happened. While I can&#8217;t say you&#8217;ve travelled as far as your sister (who&#8217;d seen four countries before she was a year old), or have as many teeth (she had more than six; your third tooth has yet to pop through), you&#8217;re easily as tall as her, and you&#8217;ve been walking around on your own &#8212; Monkey was still a week from that. You&#8217;ve come a long way, kid.<br />
This is a bit of a hard day for Mommy and I. By most definitions, you&#8217;re no longer an infant &#8212; no longer our <em>baby</em> &#8212; you&#8217;re a toddler. You&#8217;re toddling. You&#8217;re growing, despite all of our wishes that you remain forever small, forever ours.<br />
It started early, just after 6:00, when you woke up, cooing in your crib. I brought you to Mommy, softly singing &#8220;Happy Birthday&#8221; to you. I didn&#8217;t see you again until just before I left for work, giving you a kiss on the head.<br />
When I came home, you were awake and playing, and make that &#8220;GAH!&#8221; sound you frequently do, and panted quickly for a moment, which appears to be your current way of saying &#8220;Daddy&#8221; (or at least &#8220;someone I recognise&#8221;). We played while Mommy worked on your birthday cake.<br />
Mommy made you snowmen cupcakes. (I really want to take credit for the idea, but Mommy really make it all her own &#8212; she did a fantastic job!) They were yummy chocolate cupcakes with a sugar icing on them, with chocolate arms, a candied papaya nose, and a gumdrop hat (you didn&#8217;t eat the gumdrop, the arms, or the nose, by the way). Your snowman came with a candle in the shape of a &#8220;1&#8221; &#8212; the very same candle Monkey had on her cake for her first birthday.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/choo-choos-1st-birthday/' title='Choo Choo&#039;s 1st Birthday'><img width="200" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Choo-Choo-s-1st-Birthday-200x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3269" alt="Choo Choo&#039;s 1st Birthday" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5539290052/">Geoff S.</a><br />
 <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/alex-ices-the-snowmen/' title='Alex ices the snowmen'><img width="300" height="200" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Alex-ices-the-snowmen-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3270" alt="Alex ices the snowmen" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5538699917/">Geoff S.</a><br />
 <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/choo-choos-1-year-cake/' title='Choo Choo&#039;s 1 year cake'><img width="200" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Choo-Choo-s-1-year-cake-200x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3271" alt="Choo Choo&#039;s 1 year cake" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5538700673/">Geoff S.</a><br />
 <a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/a-fistful-of-cake/' title='A Fistful of Cake'><img width="300" height="200" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/A-Fistful-of-Cake-300x200.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3272" alt="A Fistful of Cake" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5538705755/">Geoff S.</a><br />
Grandpa and Granny came out from Ruskin for the party (Grandpa having taken the bus, in an effort to reduce his carbon footprint), and Grandma came over later in the afternoon. You didn&#8217;t have a nap in the afternoon, so it was a bit of a question to see how&#8217;d you do with exhaustion.<br />
We did presents first. You got a Fisher Price Little People barn with a variety of animals, a walker/ride-on cart, some bath toys, crayons, some clothes, and Mommy knit you a little stuffed pig. You wanted to play with the torn pieces of wrapping paper &#8230; of course.<br />
You were the first to get your snowman, brought to you with candle alit. You poked it tentatively at first, but them pretty much dived right in. It wasn&#8217;t quite the level of cake carnage your sister had unleashed nearly over three years ago, and we didn&#8217;t give you ice cream to amp up the messiness, but you still required a bath afterwards. You decimated the cake, filling your hands with chocolate cake and icing.<br />
Although your sister took to the sugary dessert like a flame to gasoline, your lack of a second nap seemed to take you down fairly quickly. (Although I should point out that &#8212; as of this writing &#8212; you&#8217;ve woken up twice since going to bed, likely due to teething.) And thus ended your first birthday.<br />
So happy birthday, my little one. May all those yet to come be far more memorable, and filled with all the best memories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/03/happy-first-birthday-choo-choo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2879</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
