<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>times square &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/times-square/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 5</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-5</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 03:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.   Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?   So, where to start?   &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 5"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for missing Day 4, folks, but we were having a bit too much fun to go anywhere near a computer to blog about it. Nyah, nyah, nyah.  <br />
Yes, we&#8217;ve been busy. And been having fun. I mean, what else are you gonna do in New York City?  <br />
So, where to start?  <br />
<span id="more-1199"></span>We didn&#8217;t want to stick around the hotel any longer &#8212; the breakfasts here are so darned expensive considering the quality you get. So we opted to head off to a place Alex wanted to see: Alice&#8217;s Teacup, a teahouse up on 64th. Sadly, despite the published opening time at 8:00, the place wasn&#8217;t opening until 10:00. So we adjourned to the French restaurant we spotted along the way.  <br />
By the time we got back to the hotel, Mom was trying to check in. (Such began the longest check-in process I have ever experienced at a hotel.) We gathered together, chatted, and almost immediately put Mi Pequeña Niña to bed. It was nap time, and she was getting a little cranky. She didn&#8217;t wake up again until we stirred her until just after noon, at which point we all headed out for lunch.  <br />
My bright idea? Finding an eatery at Grand Central Terminal.  <br />
Yes, it&#8217;s the train thing. Suck it up. I haven&#8217;t seen a real train in months.  <br />
We found Michael Jordan&#8217;s (I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s related to the basketball player) where we endulged in some seriously tasty edibles. (I think MPN got the best of all of us &#8212; her macaroni and cheese was fantastic). While we were there, we were entertained by a lightshow that was going on in the main concourse, which kept MPN completely fascinated.  <br />
We strolled a bit, but ended up back at the hotel before long, about in time for MPN to crash again. Which was about the time Alex and I started planning our night out. It&#8217;s part of the reason Mom came down &#8212; to keep an eye on MPN while Alex and I tried to paint the town &#8230; well, maybe not red so much as pink.  <br />
We walked to Times Square (again) and started our task at finding a place to see a movie, which was a lot harder than it seems. There are two movie theatres in the area (Regal and AMC), and you have to figure out which movie that you want to see is at which theatre. Which was about when Alex made it clear to me that she needed to eat dinner. That led us to some diner just south of Times Square with the driest chicken I ever ate. (But, admittedly, I&#8217;ve had worse.)<br />
The movie, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was Bedtime Stories. Overall, a well done movie. And I&#8217;m still giggling at Russell Brand&#8217;s rendition of Sleep Panic Disorder. Then we hit the Virgin Megastore for more movies. I had a serious need for a movie fix.  <br />
This morning started a little different, and much more slowly than the previous mornings. We headed off to the Waldorf Astoria (the next block south) for breakfast, and then returned for MPN to have another nap. By the time she awoke, it was time for luch, which was at Au Bon Pain a couple of blocks away. We hopped a cab and about 25 minutes later we were at the Cloisters Museum, a branch of the Met up at the north end of Manhattan island.  <br />
Barely 2 minutes after arriving, Alex realised in a panic that the little backpack that she uses to carry MPN&#8217;s stuff (and her wallet) were in the bag, and the bag was still in the taxi, now departed from the Cloisters. That sent me to a phone to cancel the credit card, and list a missing bag with the Taxi and Limosine Commission. That said, I was also told that it&#8217;ll be a cold day in hell before we get this stuff back, due to the way that the taxis run in this city. Which, I have to admit, is a little odd.  <br />
The Cloisters, for the record, is one of New York City&#8217;s unspoken gems. It&#8217;s out of the way, admittedly, which is why, but it is gorgeous. It was like the churches I saw in England, Scotland, and Ireland (although most of it came from France). Absolutely wonderful! I can see why Mark has said that he wants to hold his wedding there. (Well, when he gets around to getting married, that is.)  <br />
The driver of the hired car we took on the way back really didn&#8217;t listen to me and ended up taking us through Times Square. The hard way. (Believe me, there are easier ways.) He apologised for the mistake, and didn&#8217;t charge us what he should have charged us if he&#8217;d had a meter running.  <br />
Dinner was at a place called Bobby Van&#8217;s, a steakhouse on 54th between Lexington and Park Ave. We were perhaps a bit underdressed, but the meal was fantastic. I&#8217;m going to have such a steak hangover in the morning. And I&#8217;m going to revel in it as much as possible.  <br />
But until then, I&#8217;m exhausted, and looking forward to going home. (That&#8217;s Costa Rica, in case you&#8217;re not sure.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 02:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merry Ho Ho, everyone!   Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 3 (aka Christmas Day)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Merry Ho Ho, everyone!  <br />
Today, of course, is Christmas Day. We started our morning with a waltz down to breakfast in the hotel&#8217;s restaurants in our PJs. (Well, I wore clothes. I wouldn&#8217;t be allowed into most places with what I wear to bed.) Breakfast for all, with coffee for Mom and Dad. (For those of you keeping track, I&#8217;m at 12 coffees since I started.)  <br />
Then it was back for present opening. &#8216;Cuz it just ain&#8217;t Christmas without presents.  <br />
<span id="more-1196"></span>Due to our travel plans, Alex and I opted not to actually get each other presents. Instead, we went for the &#8220;Aw, Honey, You Shouldn&#8217;t Have!&#8221; move where we buy what we want for ourselves, and then thank the other for being so thoughtful. (Yes, it borders heavily on the extremely lame, but we neither need or want much, and it&#8217;s just easier to do it this way rather than try to bring it all, or remember what the other wants and try to purchase it when you&#8217;re rarely alone). Alex already did her book run earlier in the week. I might never get a chance to do mine, and I&#8217;m okay with that. Lately, I&#8217;ve been realising that I haven&#8217;t cared as much about me as I have about Alex and Mi Pequeña Niña.  <br />
The scavenger hunt wasn&#8217;t long &#8212; the presents were easy to find for Megan (that&#8217;s the point) and we didn&#8217;t have a chance to wrap anything. There will be wrapped presents back in Costa Rica, but for now she&#8217;ll do without. She found her new books in her stocking, her new shirts, and Yorkie (the name we gave to the stuffed dog). Then came much playing with all of them while we tried to find some sort of Christmas movie on TV. The best we could do was <em>Bad Santa</em>. Not exactly a kid-friendly movie.  <br />
We chatted with Cathy, Craig, and their kids (well, Tori &#8212; Natalee the newborn babe seems to be asleep every time we see her) &#8212; and my mom &#8212; while they were having breakfast, awaiting the time we could call Allen. Sadly, we had problems lining up our time with Allen, so we eventually had to give up and start working on our day. Bundling up, it was time for our Christmas Day excursion to the Central Park Zoo.  <br />
New York City never slows down, never stops. Even Christmas Day, traffic is bustling, people are everywhere, stops (some) are open, and it&#8217;s almost business as usual. It&#8217;s truly my kind of town! (No, I doubt I&#8217;ll ever get a chance to live here.) We walked from our hotel at 51st and Lexington to Central Park, watching all the people and wondering if we bundled up Megan well enough for the brisker-than-it-first-felt weather. In the end she seemed fine, and didn&#8217;t complain about the cold. (She would later complain about missing a nap.)  <br />
The Central Park Zoo isn&#8217;t what I thought it would be. Again, damn you Hollywood!, my vision wasn&#8217;t what it was. No attention-hogging lions, no wise-cracking zebras, no hypochondriatic giraffes, and no pushy hippos. Mind you, I could swear one of the penguins looked like he was up to something. (Mind you, it could have been a &#8220;her&#8221; &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to tell.)  <br />
Don&#8217;t get me wrong, the Central Park Zoo is really a wonderful place on Christmas Day. Not only does the clock chime Christmas Carols, but it&#8217;s not really busy, and easy to get around. It doesn&#8217;t hurt that the place is miniscule &#8212; literally the smallest zoo I&#8217;ve ever been to. (I&#8217;ve been to petting zoos that were larger.) Good use of the space, I should add.  <br />
By the time we were leaving, MPN was rapidly approaching meltdown due to lack of sleep. It was a near-race to get back to the hotel and get her down. Along the way, I ended up having to carry her (it calms her down), and before long I had a little bobble head baby &#8212; she was literally falling asleep and trying to sit in my arms. I leaned her forward into my chest and that was that &#8212; she went deadweight. Alex and I took the opportunity to go into the Oxford Cafe for lunch, putting her back into her stroller to sleep.  <br />
I had turkey. My only turkey of the day, as it would turn out. Alex indulged in perhaps the largest tuna salad bagel I&#8217;ve ever seen. It was far from gourmet, but given the circumstances, I was hardly one to argue.  <br />
Although MPN woke up briefly on the way back to the room, it was a tenuous consciousness, and it wasn&#8217;t long before she was back down and passed out. We tried to figure out where to go for dinner. While New York City truly is a wondrous place for food, Christmas Day is a little more limited. While (almost) every hotel restaurant is open, not all of them are easy to get into, have availability, or even turkey for that matter. We ended up going with San Martin, a nearby Italian restaurant.  <br />
Seafood risotto and fusilli primavera. Not exactly traditional, but then this trip has been anything but &#8212; so why stop with dinner? I wouldn&#8217;t go so far as to recommend the place, however. It&#8217;s okay, but I wouldn&#8217;t call it &#8220;great&#8221;.  <br />
MPN and I tried to check out Rockefeller Center while Alex endulged in a long-overdue bath. I think about half of New York came out for it, and I had the briefest glimpse what Times Square on New Year&#8217;s Eve must be like. It was a roundabout trip before we headed back and got the wee one to bed.  <br />
Speaking of which, it&#8217;s our turn to do the same. Mom arrives tomorrow, and we&#8217;re both in need of some serious ZZZs. I hope you all had a Merry Christmas. (And for those of you back in Canada, enjoy the Boxing Week sales!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-3-aka-christmas-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1196</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xmas in NYC, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=xmas-in-nyc-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 21:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our first family Christmas away from Canada has ended up being colder than we expected it to be a mere couple of months ago. Back then, we were expecting to be in Costa Rica. But due to certain unforeseen circumstances, we&#8217;ve had to fly up north for Christmas. Well, actually, the fact that we flew &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Xmas in NYC, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our first family Christmas away from Canada has ended up being colder than we expected it to be a mere couple of months ago. Back then, we were expecting to be in Costa Rica. But due to certain unforeseen circumstances, we&#8217;ve had to fly up north for Christmas.<br />
Well, actually, the fact that we flew to New York City is itself a bit of a twist &#8212; we hadn&#8217;t planned to come here for Christmas until about a month ago. Until then, we were working on someplace a lot warmer. In the act of researching flights, I happened to throw out New York City mostly as a joke. I mean, we&#8217;ve been living in a tropical country for six months. Why on Earth would we fly five hours north to free our asses off?  <br />
Funny, how humour sometimes becomes reality&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-1190"></span>New York City at Christmastime is one of those Hollywood-created myths. Everyone has heard of it (sort of like Paris in the Spring), but few (compared to the population of the planet, keep in mind) have actually done. Knowing full well that it would be a lot colder than the weather we&#8217;d been experiencing for months, we decided that this year, we&#8217;d do something fun. (And because next year, our darling baby daughter will officially have to occupy a seat of her own at full price.)  <br />
The taxi rojo met us just outside out building, and the driver helped me load all our things into the trunk: my backpack full of our clothes, our two carry-ons, and the Bugaboo (the stroller). Yes, folks, we travel light. Even when it&#8217;s cold on the other end. The driver spoke about as much English as I speak Spanish, but we managed to converse enough for the ride to the airport. Apparently, we were the driver&#8217;s fourth fare to the airport that morning.<br />
Our Continental Airlines flight left Juan Santamaria Airport yesterday at about 13:20. Or rather, it was supposed to leave at 13:20. Due (most likely) to the weather of the last couple of days, the flight was delayed 30 minutes when we checked in. This was not a good sign, as Mi Pequeña Niña did not have her morning nap so she would be nice and tired for the five hours of flight. She&#8217;s become a very active 16-month old kid, and keeping her confined in a small airplane seat for a long period of time is not fun.  <br />
By the time we finally boarded, we were 40 minutes behind schedule. By the time we were taxied and ready to take off, over an hour. But we were finally airborne and on our way. Twenty minutes after that, our daughter was sprawled across our two laps, sound asleep. It was a little chilly on the plane, and we opted to ask for a blanket from a passing flight attendant. Somehow, someone managed to get a holstein to look human, &#8216;cuz this cow was certainly a piece of work. It was, without question, the most unhelpful flight attendant I&#8217;d experienced in years and went out of her way to make it sound like this was a serious problem rather than part of the reason we paid out a ridiculous sum of money to fly.  <br />
Maybe 90 minutes. That&#8217;s all she slept, and was soon awake and full of energy. Keeping a child calm and unwound for over three hours in a confined space? Not easy. The flight itself was otherwise uneventful, though for reasons I don&#8217;t understand there was a non-stop line for the toilets almost the entire flight. People were pushing and shoving to get their way out (connections, I can only assume), and I was just plain tired.  <br />
Immigration was relatively easy (the poor woman ahead of us was trying to get home to Toronto and the 1 hour delay in her flight might pretty much have prevented her from making it &#8212; I hope she did), and customs was almost a joke &#8212; they didn&#8217;t even look at us, really. Just passed right through&#8230;<br />
After that, we found the desk to ask for our Super Shuttle connection, and then ventured out into the -10 degree weather. It had been in the mid-20s when we boarded our flight. A thirty degree temperature swing might affect most people badly, but I actually enjoyed it. Everyone back in Calgary and Toronto has been complaining about bitter cold (okay, even -37 is a bit much for me) and blizzards. I miss that. I&#8217;m Canadian, man, and December means snow and ice to me. Looking out my windows and see palm trees just weirds me out.  <br />
My breath was clearly visible. Alex started sniffling, and poor Mi Pequeña Niña was shivering within minutes. We were quickly donning extra layers. Our very indignant driver showed up about 15 minutes later, and tried to brush us off (the prick) before we were finally let on. Then off for our 30-minute drive into Manhattan. We were the second group to be let off.  <br />
This morning, we woke up a bit chilly. Our room isn&#8217;t particularly warm, sadly, and while we had a thick blanket, MPN didn&#8217;t and her hands were ice cubes. (Things we&#8217;re changing tonight.) Showered and dressed, we all headed down for breakfast. The first thing I said to the hostess (who looked strikingly like Emmanuelle Beart) was &#8220;hola&#8221;. Habits are hard to break.  <br />
Bacon. Real bacon. Ye gods, I had forgotten what real bacon tastes like. The eggs were fake (I already miss Costa Rican eggs), but the juice was real. The fruit nowhere as fresh as I&#8217;m used to. None of us paused, and inhaled heavily.  <br />
Our excursion today was down to Times Square, the chief need being to hit the Toys &#8216;R Us. Our trip took us to a little set of stalls set up in front of St. Bart&#8217;s a block from our hotel, where we happily splurged on new hats and mittens for Alex and I (as we didn&#8217;t have any), before continuing westward to St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral. There we turned south on 5th Avenue, passing by Rockefeller Center, winding our way down to 47th St, where we crossed westward again. We did this a couple of more times before entering Times Square along 43rd St. (we should have some in at 44th, but my memory was a little vague &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t that far off!). We turned the block north to the Toys &#8216;R Us.  <br />
If MPN were a little bit older, she&#8217;d probably have freaked out when we entered. As it stands, we entered into an area that was replete with Hello Kitty NYC paraphenalia, and she couldn&#8217;t stop her little half-waddle between all the various things she could get her hands on. It was horribly cute, and I felt kind of bad that she didn&#8217;t have more stuff to play with.  <br />
We were at Toys &#8216;R Us for well over hour two hours. We left just after 12:00, which was about the time I&#8217;d finally had it with all the pushy morons, people fully devoid of Christmas cheer, and just plain assholes. I have a whole new level of respect for people who work retail during the Christmas season, because there are a lot of real winners out there this time of year. This is also where I make a comparison to Costa Ricans &#8212; they are among the nicest people in the world. Even in confined places, Ticos are just plain awesome people.  <br />
Back out into the not-quite-as-cold cold, we started our slow journey back towards the hotel. We hit a small gift store barely two blocks away. MPN was already sound asleep. (She&#8217;s sleeping again now, which is why I&#8217;m able to type this out during the day.) A little further away, we found a street artist who hand-paints name signs. Alex chose a pattern made of dragons. The poor woman&#8217;s fingers were beyond numbed. I was about to offer her my gloves (hey, they only cost $5) when I realised that she wore the gloves she had for a reason &#8212; they have the ends cut off so she can paint. Barely 10 minutes later, we had a new name painting for MPN, and we continued our way back.  <br />
We had lunch at the Metro Café, a small (modern) deli next to the hotel. The single biggest thing for me? Chicken noodel soup. I can&#8217;t tell you the last time I tasted anything this good. Seriously! I think it&#8217;s because I&#8217;ve eaten Tico for the last six months, and seriously forgotten many of the things I grew up on. Not that I&#8217;m complaining! I just find these things interesting.  <br />
Well, as I said, MPN is napping, and I&#8217;m on guard duty. Alex is off drooling over books in her first all-English bookstore in six months. I imagine I won&#8217;t see her for at least another hour. I hope she finds what she wants.  <br />
Me? I want a drink. I&#8217;m thirsty as hell. I hope the bar&#8217;s open now&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/12/xmas-in-nyc-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1190</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New York Meetings: Touring New York</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-york-meetings-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-touring/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 22:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/14/new-york-meetings-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My first Valentines day with Alex, and I have to be 3,500 kilometres from her. It could be worse. I could be in Kanata. First thing: Room change. Last night&#8217;s room was one Mark and I had booked. Tonight&#8217;s is on the company&#8217;s bill, and we get our own. Mine wasn&#8217;t an improvement, and ended &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New York Meetings: Touring New York"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My first Valentines day with Alex, and I have to be 3,500 kilometres from her.<br />
It could be worse. I could be in Kanata.<br />
<span id="more-457"></span>First thing: Room change. Last night&#8217;s room was one Mark and I had booked. Tonight&#8217;s is on the company&#8217;s bill, and we get our own. Mine wasn&#8217;t an improvement, and ended up over the HVAC again. I changed rooms later once I got back. For one night, I could hack it. Two nights, forget it.<br />
I ate McDonald&#8217;s for the first time in a couple of years, as it was the only near thing we could find for breakfast. It&#8217;s a last resort. But it&#8217;s the only thing at McDonald&#8217;s that I&#8217;ll eat. And it&#8217;s cheaper than the hotel&#8217;s breakfast.<br />
We walked a <em>lot</em>. I&#8217;m sure Mark has never walked that much before. We did a lot on our feet that resembled last night, heading to Times Square, New York Public Library, Rockefeller Center, St. Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, Grand Central Terminal, and the Empire State Building. (If you don&#8217;t know what Manhattan is like, that&#8217;s a lot of walking.) Given that the rain was beginning to start and we needed to get off our feet, we headed into the subway to go down to Rector St. station and the WTC site.<br />
It was raining when we got out. Somehow, that seemed appropriate.<br />
Ground Zero still shows signs of damage, even over four years later. Though some has been rebuilt, one building is still shrouded in black awaiting demolition (there&#8217;s a massive hole in one side). The actual WTC site is still under construction, as they have yet to finalize the plans for the Freedom Tower (the name that keeps being thrown around). I suspect it&#8217;ll be quite a while before something finally rises there. Only the NJ Path train is already in place.<br />
We walked around the site. Three sides are blocked by high fences that pretty much prevent photography of any kind (why, I don&#8217;t know). The fourth is so far away from the site that it&#8217;s almost impossible to see anything. The south, east, and north sides are parts of buildings or walkways to get you around. It was strange seeing the hole in the ground, and made me think about what I&#8217;d seen on TV that fateful date (see [[Reaction to September 11, 2001 (9/11)]]). It&#8217;s been a long time.<br />
Avoiding the protests at City Hall (they were against same sex unions &#8230; oh, the ignorance), we passed by the city building and out onto the Brooklyn Bridge, walking out as far as the first pier. I know a fair bit about the construction of the bridge (relax, I&#8217;m not going to recap it&#8217;s history &#8212; the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brooklyn_Bridge">Wikipedia does a much better job of that</a>), and it was neat to actually be on top of it. Even if it was raining.<br />
Returning to Manhattan, we headed over to Pier 17 to get something to eat. Another pub, and another unsatisfying meal. You&#8217;d think I&#8217;d be able to get a decent corned beef in New York!<br />
Back out in the rain, we headed down the river passing all the ferry and ship docks, eventually arriving at Battery Park. This would be as close as I&#8217;d get to the Statue of Liberty. In fact, I think it&#8217;s the only time I&#8217;ve actually seen it with my own eyes. The rain, now blowing, was really beginning to piss us off, and it was time to move on.<br />
Heading over to the Battery Tunnel vent tower (the one that doubles as the Men In Black headquarters), we found the globe that previously stood outside of the World Trade Center. It&#8217;s now there until it can be replaced back on the site after reconstruction. Considering the utter devastation, it&#8217;s in surprisingly good shape. Just a little battered.<br />
Past the Wall Street Bull, we found the NYSE. Six years ago, you could walk right past the doors without being noticed. Now half the road is blocked with security fences and police give you the evil eye the moment you walk in view. (I should note that there seem to be cops on almost every corner these days. You feel secure, but you do feel like you&#8217;re always being watched.)<br />
Onto the J train, then to the A train, and finally a C train took us to 81st Ave. Finding the museum of natural history, we  ducked through Central Park, seeing the Gates, an outdoor &#8220;sculpture&#8221; done by avante-garde artist Christo. (The same guy who surrounded islands with fabric.) I knew about these before going, and I have to admit that I felt somewhat privileged to see it for the short period that it was open. But I got to say, I honestly don&#8217;t see the big deal.<br />
The best thing we saw about it was one of the keepers who stand around ready to answer questions. Each of them carries a long pole with a tennis ball on one end. We had to ask. It&#8217;s to unfurl the flags when the wind wraps them around the supports. As the keeper answered the question, a New Yorker passed, commenting: &#8220;It&#8217;s an ugly waste of money!&#8221;<br />
The Met was closed, so walked over to the Guggenheim for a look. By this time, we resembled more sponges than people. It took a bit of wandering on Lexington to find a subway station (it&#8217;s harder than you think if you don&#8217;t have a map). A 6 and a 7 got us to the hotel to dry off.<br />
Allard had arrived by then, and we headed next door for dinner and debriefing for tomorrow. After a decent dinner, I made a note to call Alex before going over my presentations again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">457</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New York Meetings: Outbound</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-outbound/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-york-meetings-outbound</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-outbound/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2005 16:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[times square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/13/new-york-meetings-outbound/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leaving Alex this morning wasn&#8217;t easy. Given the events of the last couple of days, I would have preferred to stay in bed with her. But business calls, and I&#8217;m off to New York (though Newark) for business meetings with the IT department of our Mercedes client. It&#8217;s mostly an educational exchange, as we try &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-outbound/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New York Meetings: Outbound"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leaving Alex this morning wasn&#8217;t easy. Given the events of the last couple of days, I would have preferred to stay in bed with her.<br />
But business calls, and I&#8217;m off to New York (though Newark) for business meetings with the IT department of our Mercedes client. It&#8217;s mostly an educational exchange, as we try pass on a lot of the knowledge we have to the IT group. Exactly <em>why</em> we&#8217;re doing this I&#8217;m admittedly a little unclear on, but I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s all for a good reason.<br />
<span id="more-455"></span>Skipping the agony of trying to get back from the airport sans automobile (see [[Mercedes-Benz meetings, going home]]), I drove to the airport and parked in the Park &#8216;N Fly. It&#8217;ll actually be cheaper than taking a taxi, and way more convenient. Taxis in this city are really beginning to bother me, and I suspect it&#8217;s only going to get worse.<br />
Thankfully, Mark was already in line &#8212; I was running late and didn&#8217;t want to have to wait all the way through. Mark and I are flying out early to get a day of tourism in New York City. Mark&#8217;s never been there before, and I&#8217;m dying to see the city again. I was there last in September, 1999. Yes, I stood under the Twin Towers, probably two years to the day that they fell down. Creepy.<br />
Crossing customs was worse than usual. Maybe there&#8217;s a need to crack down on things, but I seemed to be getting fourth degree from the officer about my genetic makeup. Passing that, we dropped bags at the belt and passed through security for my second flight to Minneapolis in a week. (There&#8217;s something seriously wrong with that, I&#8217;m sure.)<br />
The first leg went quickly. Pizza at Minneapolis while we waited for the second leg. Although denied my Chantico, I was sure that I would be able to get one in New York. Mark V&#8217;s suggestion that I picked up flying to and from Chicago paid off and I got an exit row to New York. Yay, foot room!<br />
Arriving took forever (New York is a tough place to fly into), and USD$63 later we were at our Best Western near Times Square. Mark had done his research well. The place was barely two-star (not updated in a few decades, I&#8217;d say), but it sufficed for the need. Kind of what happens when the creme de la creme sits out too long without refrigeration.<br />
Our room, a junior suite, had a queen and a pull-out. I took the pull-out, not realizing it was next to the rather loud HVAC system out the window. We stayed only long enough to dump our things before heading out.<br />
Times Square hadn&#8217;t really changed much since I last saw it. Mark was in a daze (I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;d ever been to a large city before!). Having been to Tokyo twice now, this seems almost trivial for me. I feel like such a snob! The Toys &#8216;R Us is new, and the ferris wheel inside is &#8230; almost insane. As if the ADD isn&#8217;t bad enough in that place. But it&#8217;s part of making Times Square more impressive. So far, I think it&#8217;s working. Soon, it should be like it was &#8212; the ultimate place to go in New York.<br />
We wandered all the way down to a few blocks from the Empire State Building (lit up in the red, white, and blue) before walking up 5th Ave towards Rockefeller Center. We passed the main branch of the New York Public Library before cutting over to Grand Central Terminal (a wonderful view at night). We found the mysterious black rectangle Stephanie had told us to look for &#8212; proof of what the ceiling had once looked like before it was revitalized in the 1980s.<br />
Heading back to Times Square, we tried to get a hold of Andrew to find a good restaurant in the area. Sadly, he was out of town, so we ducked into the first pub we could find &#8212; the Pig and Whistle. Not the best, but it was food and drink, which we needed in spades.<br />
Chantico in hand (I told you I&#8217;d find one), we headed back to the room to catch up on work while watching <em>Ronin</em>. Tomorrow &#8212; Manhattan in one day!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/new-york-meetings-outbound/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">455</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
