<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>castles &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/castles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Obligatory Vacation Recap</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-obligatory-vacation-recap</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british airways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[churches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glasgow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[st. alban's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the few minutes I have before I dive back into another conference session, figured I&#8217;d cover some of the items of our last vacation. This was a 2.5 week excursion mostly to Scotland, with a few days in England. Alex planned most of the trip, with me handling things like the transportation and hotels &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Obligatory Vacation Recap"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the few minutes I have before I dive back into another conference session, figured I&#8217;d cover some of the items of our last vacation. This was a 2.5 week excursion mostly to Scotland, with a few days in England. Alex planned most of the trip, with me handling things like the transportation and hotels to stay along the way. Overall, about a 50/50 split on the events et al.<br />
Sadly, at the end, it wasn&#8217;t a usual vacation. Until now, it&#8217;s always been either just me, or myself and Alex. Now there&#8217;s three of us, and the Wee One doesn&#8217;t have our stamina for travel and has a pseudo-schedule that needs to be followed from time-to-time.<br />
<span id="more-928"></span></p>
<h4>British Airways</h4>
<p>We flew BA from Calgary to London (via Heathrow). Air Canada &#8212; are you listening? These are the guys you should be looking to for level of service. Wow. Allow me to describe: We arrive at the plane along the jetway, with stroller (and babe) in hand. They tell us that they might not be able to bring the stroller on-board, but they&#8217;d let us know. They didn&#8217;t ask for seat or name &#8212; they figured it out on their own, checked the stroller, and gave us the claim ticket. They presented us with a small toy bag for the Wee One with a small stuffed plane for playtime. Free wine. Good (read: real) food. A feeling like people actually cared about the passengers&#8217; well-being. Excellent in-flight entertainment for that 8-9 flight. Sure, it costs a bit extra. But not so much that I wouldn&#8217;t even think twice about flying with them again &#8212; that&#8217;s a definite.</p>
<h4>Travelling with the Wee One</h4>
<p>Most people thought we were nuts for hauling our offspring to Europe. A seven hour time difference, air travel, trains, ferries, lots of packing and moving, and add an infant to all of that?<br />
<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/24/we-have-a-travel-safe-baby/">I said it before</a>, but our kid rocks. Sleep on the flight out (sadly, not so much on the way back), adjustment to the timezone in two nights (by the third day, all was well), played a lot on the trains (although she did have trouble sleeping due to lack of space), and she didn&#8217;t keep us up at night even though we were all in the same room. It didn&#8217;t matter how many places we went or how many people wanted to hold her (the Wee One apparently is the cutest thing many Brits have ever seen, judging by the near-endless stream of comments we got).<br />
And hey, I got to spend 2.5 of constant time with my child! What on Earth could be wrong with that?<br />
About the only bad thing (if you could call it that) was one bad habit picked up by a three-week older infant, and now the raspberry has entered the vocabulary.</p>
<h4>Iona and the Iona Community</h4>
<p>This was our first stop. Iona is a small island off the coast of the Isle of Mull, which is in turn off the western coast of Scotland. (The nearest major port is Oban, in case you&#8217;re looking for a geographical reference.) The day we arrived, there was a viciously strong and cold north wind. We immediately regretted having arrived, but pressed on. The Community itself runs mostly out of the Iona Abbey, which is owned and operated by Historical Scotland. For a week, we were guests, and basically had free run of the place.<br />
That said, a week at a Christian commune (even an ecumenical one) takes a bit of a toll on the less- (or non-)devout. Although the people were wonderful &#8212; and I have to say that while I lamented the absence of meat in our meals, the things they can do with vegetables are stunning &#8212; I was happy to be on the road again for the mainland.<br />
It&#8217;s a very small island, so it&#8217;s (relatively) easy to get around on it. Though parts of it are very boggy, you can cross the island in about 30 minutes, and go the length in about three times that. Even the highest point on the island &#8212; Dun I &#8212; takes about 15 minutes to climb, if you take your time.<br />
It&#8217;s quiet, and it&#8217;s very dark at night &#8212; there are almost no street lights. It&#8217;s so quiet that doors mostly don&#8217;t have locks. The Abbey (technically-speaking) is open all the time.</p>
<h4>Oban</h4>
<p>I heard a few people trash Oban before I went there. But I have to say it&#8217;s a nice little town. It&#8217;s a good base for day trips, and there&#8217;s a lot to see in the area. You could easily stay there a week and not be bored. Given, the hotel we stayed at (Oban Caledonian) had some trouble &#8212; when you have to name the springs in your mattress due to the intimacy you&#8217;re getting with them, it&#8217;s time to replace the mattress. But I&#8217;ve stayed in far, far worse for much more money.</p>
<h4>Train Travel</h4>
<p>I love trains. Duh. You know that. So travelling all over the place on trains is generally not a problem. But I gotta say, someone has to change the rules that puts an end to the drunken football hooligans from spreading out all over the car, singing their songs and disturbing the crap out of everyone else, stinking the place up with their booze, and generally being belligerent. No, asshole, I&#8217;m not student. Unlike you, I have the good sense to travel responsibly, but there&#8217;s not enough luggage racks in the car for my backpack. That doesn&#8217;t give you the right to use it as a pillow or a reason to tell me off. (I also have the good sense to not say anything, since I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re looking for a reason to get into a fight.)</p>
<h4>Inverness</h4>
<p>I also had people tell me not to go to Inverness. Why, I have no idea. It&#8217;s a beautiful little city. The trip there north of Perth is gorgeous, with all the rolling hills. It&#8217;s the highlands there, and it&#8217;s the best way to see it all. Anyway, the city of Inverness is amazing. The River Ness seems almost Disney-esque in the way it cleanly cuts through town, with banks of green grass and the sprouting daffodils. Add to that the lovely old buildings, winding little roads, and the general hospitality of people (drunken football hooligans notwithstanding), you just can&#8217;t go wrong.</p>
<h4>Ramada Inverness</h4>
<p>Except for the Ramada Inverness. For the record, the location is excellent. But overall, I found their staff to be bordering on incompetent. There were a couple of shining stars, no question, but I kept running into people who couldn&#8217;t answer the most basic questions, such as telling me why I can&#8217;t make a long distance phone call. It drove me CRAZY. So sorry, Mom, I couldn&#8217;t call you on your birthday. I tried, really.</p>
<h4>High Tea at the Edinburgh Hilton Caledonian</h4>
<p>Just as good as we had the last time we were there. Outstanding service. Great food. Great tea. Just wish we could have been there longer. Such is life.</p>
<h4>York</h4>
<p>I finally got to spend some actual time in York. The last time we were there barely 5 hours, so didn&#8217;t see much of it. That said, I didn&#8217;t really understand the road map until well into the second day (I kept getting turned around) and even then still took wrong turns. Confusing, but I still love the place. I could easily do month-long stints there to do some photo essays: York at Night, York Minster&#8217;s Hidden Places, Up Close with the National Rail Museum, etc. Love it.</p>
<h4>York to St. Albans without going to London</h4>
<p>Big mistake. Too many switches, we missed a connection, and it&#8217;s too much movement. Going through London is out of the way, but it&#8217;s a lot easier.</p>
<h4>St. Albans</h4>
<p>I still love this little place. The last time, we swore we&#8217;d spend more time there the next time. But we ended up with not even 1 day again, sadly. One day, we will spend more time there. It&#8217;s a very nice place.</p>
<h4>Pictures</h4>
<p>Some are already <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/tags/scotland2008/">posted on Flickr</a>, and others will come once I get them all done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/the-obligatory-vacation-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">928</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2004 23:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[osaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/02/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;. The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Osaka"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We attempted to move a bit quicker this morning. The key word being &#8220;attempted&#8221;.<br />
The idea was to go to Osaka and do the touring thing. That meant we had to leave at a reasonable time so we could catch the various trains (subway, shinkansen, local, loop, and subway, in that order) to get from our hotel to the Osaka Aquarium, our first destination of the day.<br />
<span id="more-340"></span>The problem was that Jen&#8217;s stomach was beginning to rebel. It doesn&#8217;t appreciate the Japanese diet the same way mine does. Mind you, mine&#8217;s been tempered with age, and isn&#8217;t wholly dependant on low-fat, unsweetened milk (which Jen&#8217;s seems to be). So the lack of milk and high fish content (which Jen&#8217;s not a particular fan of) really didn&#8217;t create an ideal situation.<br />
So we were a little later leaving than I had planned.<br />
We arrived at the aquarium about five minutes ahead of my prediction (noon), despite all the trains and transfers we&#8217;d had to take. Overall, not such a bad thing. Why were we going to an aquarium on the opposite side of the planet? Simply put: because Osaka Aquarium is one of the largest in the world, and features a whale shark, which I&#8217;ve never seen.<br />
Jen got screwed on the entrance fee. According to their fee schedule, she is still a child, which meant a mere 900 yen fee (rather than the 2000 yen adult fee). However, even armed with her passport (as proof of age), the clerks simply didn&#8217;t believe that she was 15. If only we had those guys from the izakaya (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]]) for assistance.<br />
We headed into the aquarium, going up a long escalator into the main building&#8217;s 7th floor, where we were introduced to the Japan Forest, at the heart of the building. This started us on a slow spiral all the way down to the 4th floor, taking us through the Aleutian Islands, Monterey Bay, Gulf of Panama, Ecuadorian Rain Forest, Antarctica, Tasman Sea, Great Barrier Reef, Pacific Ocean, Seto Inland Sea, Kelp Forest, Coast of Chile, Cook Strait, and the Japan Deeps.<br />
Each portion of the trip represented one part of the Ring of Fire, of which Japan is part. (The Ring of Fire is a geological name for the ring around the Pacific Ocean, characterized by tectonic and volcanic activity.) It also is arranged in a way that is supposed to representative of the Gaia theory, which states the world is in fact a living organism from which the life we see sprouts, and returns to upon death.<br />
At the top, the aquarium is interesting, but not particularly thrilling. Monterey Bay was a bit of a laugh, having been to Monterey myself (see 18 July 1998) and having seen the Monterey Bay Aquarium (which I would quite willingly put on the same scale as the Osaka Aquarium for size and quality). As you spiral down, you&#8217;re given a deeper look into some parts, and completely exposed to others for the first time.<br />
At the core of the aquarium is the Pacific Ocean exhibit. This massive tank, sealed in by 30cm-thick acrylic walls, contains 5,400 tons of water and a huge number of aquatic species, including tuna, sun fish, manta rays, oscars, a couple kinds of sharks, especially the whale shark (a species that grows to 12m in length; this one was only about 6m).<br />
We were treated to many different views from several different levels of all the environments, before finally reaching the Japan Deeps, a small, dark tank with the largest, most creepy-looking crabs you&#8217;ve ever seen. It was like something out of &#8220;Alien&#8221;. Down an escalator, and we were at the jellyfish. We heard a lot of &#8220;kawaii&#8221; (Japanese for &#8220;how cute!&#8221;).<br />
Leaving the aquarium, we headed over to the Tempozan Marketplace for food and shopping. The latter was scarce, but the former wasn&#8217;t hard to find in good quantity. Jen inhaled not only her lunch, but half of mine (I wasn&#8217;t keen on eating all the rice) and was still hungry. Apparently, the sauce is the key.<br />
After calling a draw on a seriously insane air hockey game, featuring two paddles per player and three pucks at any given time, we decided to give the Tempozan Giant Ferris Wheel a whirl. This is apparently the world&#8217;s largest giant ferris where (as opposed to the world&#8217;s largest miniature ferris wheel, I can only suppose), and runs to a height of about 100m. The view from up there is quite something.<br />
We headed back to the JR Loop line (via subway) and hopped over to the other side of the city to check out Osaka Castle. This structure dates back to the 16th century, when it was built by Toyotomi Hideyoshi (a warlord who unified Japan) as his stronghold showpiece. After he died, his forces lost to the Tokugawa Shogunate, and it became a Shogun&#8217;s residence until the capital was moved to Edo (now Tokyo). The main building was destroyed by fire in the 17th century and left abandoned until the 20th century, when Osaka chose to rebuild the tower and reopen the castle for all to see. The existing structure is now concrete (hence not original), but the appearance is believed to be correct.<br />
The JR Loop line stops right at the castle grounds. However, it is not a short walk. It&#8217;s well over a kilometre to reach the tower itself. But it&#8217;s a walk work taking, since the view from there is quite good, and the tower itself is very beautiful (not as nice, perhaps, as Himeji Castle supposedly is, but I won&#8217;t be seeing that on this trip).<br />
We returned to the train to try some shopping. I had hoped to go to Dotombori, one of the major shopping and food districts in Osaka, but Jen&#8217;s energy level was so low (and we&#8217;d spent a lot of money over the last couple of days in various bits of non-JR transportation) that even considering going there was not really much of a consideration. Something else that will have to wait for the next time I come this way, I suppose.<br />
We ended up hitting part of Kita, a shopping area next to Osaka Station. There wasn&#8217;t much there. We thought of doing dinner, but due to a miscommunication, it wasn&#8217;t dinner that was of interest, but was just a thought. So it was back to Kyoto.<br />
We ate at Kyoto Station, partaking of gyoza (for Jen) and ramen (for myself) at one of the ramen shops on the 10th floor. (The station is big.) Following dinner, we headed back to the hotel. Jen really wanted to rest and draw. Being so early, I went back out.<br />
I walked down Kurasame St. to the Kyoto Tower, a rather unassuming edifice just north of Kyoto Station. It&#8217;s not particularly tall, but offered a decent view of downtown at night (although unlike the World Trade Center at Hamamatsucho in Tokyo, the interior lights are far too bright), and of the lights out at Kiyomizudera Shrine (which look very nice at night).<br />
I walked around the station again afterwards, taking some more pictures (but at night) before heading back to the hotel.<br />
On my way back, I popped into the Family Mart (a convenience store) to grab a snack. That&#8217;s when it hit me &#8212; I should find some milk for Jen. She&#8217;s desperately needed milk for a couple of days now, and most of the stuff we find just doesn&#8217;t cut the mustard. But at the Family Mart, I found something that apparently will do for now.<br />
The whole milk thing is just one of a few things that have not been ideal. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not complaining. Just that travelling with Jen has, at times, been a bit more of a challenge than I would have hoped for. We&#8217;ve had to cut short some things because, somehow, this 31 year-old can out pace his 15 year-old cousin. Osaka was a good example of this. I just hope that the milk we&#8217;ve found helps restore her energy so we can handle things like Nikko, Kamakura, and the various Tokyo excursions.<br />
[flickr]tag:osaka+japan+april+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kyoto+japan+april+2004+&#8221;2&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-osaka-touring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">340</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
