<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>palaces &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/palaces/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 14:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Forbidden Starbucks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/forbidden-starbucks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=forbidden-starbucks</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/forbidden-starbucks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 14:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/01/18/forbidden-starbucks/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I came across an article in Yahoo!&#8217;s Oddly Enough section this morning about how an internet protest movement is might drive out Starbucks from their location in the Forbidden City. Frankly, I&#8217;m trying to understand how the Chinese government let it in there in the first place. The kicker is that I don&#8217;t remember seeing &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/forbidden-starbucks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Forbidden Starbucks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came across an article in Yahoo!&#8217;s <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/i/757">Oddly Enough</a> section this morning about how an internet protest movement is <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/nm/20070118/od_nm/china_starbucks_forbidden_city_dc">might drive out Starbucks from their location in the Forbidden City</a>.<br />
Frankly, I&#8217;m trying to understand how the Chinese government let it in there in the first place.<br />
<span id="more-610"></span>The kicker is that I don&#8217;t remember seeing Starbucks <a href="http://www.howtogetlost.com/2005/05/31/enter-the-forbidden-city/">when I was there almost two years ago</a> (has it already been nearly two years??) &#8212; I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;d have ranted about that on the blog if that were the case.<br />
Starbucks is a strangely evil thing, first and foremost. There&#8217;s far too many of them to start with. Why are there so many of them? It&#8217;s not that people are dying for a coffee. But for the love of GOD people, do they need to be so close to one another? (There&#8217;s two places in Vancouver, BC alone where two locations are<a href="http://flickr.com/photos/ceciliacotton/170150864/"> less than 20 metres apart</a> and even <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/danfmoore/203041632/">kiddie-corner</a>! <a href="http://www.lewisblack.net/">Lewis Black</a> has a similar vein of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ddG_BTWee4Q">end of the universe</a>.)<br />
They constantly rename their products, so that even locations in the same country don&#8217;t sell the same product by the same name. (This is what drove us to boycott Starbucks.) Then they [[Starbucks discontinues Chantico?|removed Chantico from their list]]. And if that&#8217;s not reason enough, consider the <a href="http://www.schillmania.com/content/opinion/2004/11/27/the-$5-coffee/">$5 coffee</a>!<br />
The internet protest (sparked by a television host) claims that &#8220;a U.S. coffee shop in the former imperial palace is an insult to Chinese culture&#8221;.<br />
It&#8217;s not an insult to Chinese culture &#8212; it&#8217;s an affront to all humanity, really. Everywhere Starbucks goes, it brings it&#8217;s own culture with it. I know &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen Starbucks in many countries now, and they&#8217;re all the same. <strong>Every one.</strong> Given, the ingredients are slightly different, but the look and feel is identical.<br />
Even McDonald&#8217;s has enough sense to change the menu when it goes to another country.<br />
But even that said, I&#8217;d prefer that American chains stay in America (and I&#8217;ll even toss out North America as a compromise). When I go to China (or any other country, for that matter), I want to see, eat, and drink China. I have to actively <em>avoid</em> all the familiarities of home. That&#8217;s why I travel &#8212; to experience something <em>different</em>.<br />
If you don&#8217;t want anything different when you travel, just rent the bloody DVD and stay home!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/01/forbidden-starbucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">610</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Summer Palace in Beijing, and a duck</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2005 14:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/01/the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[About the only thing Amy and I had on tap today was the Summer Palace. For this, we took three subways and a (decent) taxi to the location. Total cost: about 30 yuan, and about 30 minutes. The palace entrance was crowed with about half the population of Beijing, it seemed. High for a weekday, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Summer Palace in Beijing, and a duck"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About the only thing Amy and I had on tap today was the Summer Palace. For this, we took three subways and a (decent) taxi to the location. Total cost: about 30 yuan, and about 30 minutes. The palace entrance was crowed with about half the population of Beijing, it seemed. High for a weekday, but we soon realized why&#8230;<br />
There&#8217;ve been storms here the last few days. Big ones. I haven&#8217;t heard a good thunderstorm in a long time. The rains, it seems, have washed away the all the haze and pollution that&#8217;s been hovering around the area for the last few days. (We should have gone to the Wall today, but c&#8217;est la vie.) This made The Summer Palace near perfect for visiting today. It wasn&#8217;t too hot, there was a great breeze (almost to the point of calling it &#8220;windy&#8221;) and the sky was actually blue (instead of the usual white with a blue tinge).<br />
<span id="more-559"></span>The Summer Palace was meant as a place for the royal family to escape the heat of the Forbidden City. It&#8217;s not hard to imagine why &#8212; all the walls there must prevent a good airflow. Out at the Summer Palace &#8212; easily three or four times the overall size &#8212; wind blows very easily. I&#8217;m almost surprised that the Forbidden City wasn&#8217;t just abandoned in favour of the Summer Palace. But that&#8217;s royalty for you&#8230;<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03641.JPG" alt="Protect the railings!" width="300" /></a><br />
We wandered all the way around the main lake, a distance of about five kilometres or so. The willow trees drifted in the wind, the clouds scattered the shadows about. Children played at the water&#8217;s edge while countless tourists and locals tried to escape the inevitable heat of the day. It&#8217;s a park now, with a bit of museum thrown in for flavour. It&#8217;s 35 yuan (about CDN$6) and worth every penny of admission.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03642.JPG" alt="The Summer Palace in Beijing" width="300" /></a><br />
After our ripoff cab ride, we went in search of dinner. The goal: Peking (Beijing) Duck. I&#8217;d had it before at Silver Dragon in Calgary, but Amy had never tried it before. We ended up at the same restaurant where we&#8217;d ate lunch about eight hours before, having ordered two places of potstickers that were easily three times the size of any I&#8217;d ever seen before (and boy, oh boy, were they good!). The place is down a back alley, on the second floor of an area that sells pretty much any food you can think of. The restaurant looks like an old community hall from Small Town Canada, and is sparsely decorated. That&#8217;s because the attention is put into the food.<br />
The kung pow chicken was spicy, but tasty. The boiling wok of whatnot (mostly chicken, chilies, and celery) was yummy. The duck, which arrived 45 minutes after ordering, was great. You know you&#8217;re in a good place to order Peking Duck when it meets the following criteria:</p>
<ol>
<li>It&#8217;s not advertised outside the restaurant.</li>
<li>The restaurant doesn&#8217;t have the word &#8220;duck&#8221; written anywhere in it&#8217;s name, especially in English.</li>
<li>You see the locals ordering it.</li>
</ol>
<p><a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03643.JPG" alt="Peking Duck ... mmmmmm" width="300" /></a><br />
I currently bear the battle scars of grease on my shorts. It&#8217;s a sign that the meal was good. My stomach might forgive me tomorrow. I doubt I&#8217;ll eat for a day or so, though&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/the-summer-palace-in-beijing-and-a-duck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">559</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enter the Forbidden City</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/enter-the-forbidden-city/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=enter-the-forbidden-city</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/enter-the-forbidden-city/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2005 14:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beijing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/31/enter-the-forbidden-city/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My calf muscles are killing me. I don&#8217;t know how many stairs Noah, Justin, and I climbed yesterday, but I swear my calves have never received such a workout in their existences. And now they&#8217;re taking their revenge on me. Even small stairs hurt &#8230; a lot. They&#8217;re rocks attached to the backs of my &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/enter-the-forbidden-city/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Enter the Forbidden City"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My calf muscles are killing me. I don&#8217;t know how many stairs Noah, Justin, and I climbed yesterday, but I swear my calves have never received such a workout in their existences. And now they&#8217;re taking their revenge on me. Even small stairs hurt &#8230; a lot. They&#8217;re rocks attached to the backs of my legs. They don&#8217;t flex, they pulse. Forget the Stairmaster, folks! If you want a great workout, spend the money on a trip to China, then visit three different sections and walk as much of it as you can. Your legs will be cut out of stone in days.<br />
<span id="more-557"></span>The first thing we had to do this morning was change hotels. Due to a change in plans (namely, deciding we needed more time in Beijing, and no availability in the New World Beijing Courtyard), we had to madly scramble for a new hotel that wouldn&#8217;t put us out by the airport. The best we could end up with &#8212; and I do mean this figuratively &#8212; was <a href="http://beijing.peninsula.com/index.shtml">The Peninsula Palace</a>. For the record, I would like to state that I originally thought this to be a fancy name for a half-ways decent hotel in Beijing. I didn&#8217;t realize that this is also one of the top hotels in the country. I&#8217;m very thankful that the dollar goes <em>much</em> further here than it does at home. This hotel is not much more expensive than a decent place in Calgary. I still feel uncomfortable staying here.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03639.JPG" alt="The Peninsula Palace Hotel in Beijing" width="300" /></a><br />
Checked in, we headed out in search of a quick bite for lunch (we were actually hungry for a change). Pork dumplings packed away, we headed towards the Forbidden City.<br />
For the record, this place is big. Really big. Insanely big. It&#8217;s hard to imagine how big it is until you&#8217;re inside and walking up the middle of it. I&#8217;ve never seen anything so big. It&#8217;s a seemingly endless stream of courtyards, halls of Harmony (most of them were &#8220;bla bla of Harmony&#8221;), and scaffolding. Yes, scaffolding. We knew about this back in St. Petersburg. Beijing, in preparations for 2008, is dusting off the old China and polishing up the silverwear. Where there were probably at least 103 items on the audio tour menu, there are now a mere 17. Only the middle sections of the City are open &#8212; the wings and sides are all closed, undergoing a massive overhaul in preparation for a flood of tourists.<br />
Oh, as a side note, there are a number of people who warned us about the bathrooms here. And the chaotic lines, and the spitting &#8230; the list was quite lengthy, I assure you. While I can&#8217;t speak for Amy, I&#8217;m sure she&#8217;ll agree that so far, we can&#8217;t understand what all the problems are. Bathrooms are mostly clean (the squat ones, anyway &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been in the western side to know for sure), the crowds are more than manageable, and spitting has been minimal. We still have a few cities to go, mind you, so that might yet change.<br />
We picked up the audio tour. The English version is voiced by none other than Roger Moore. Assumedly, the recording is a few years old, now, but 007 still sounds as cool now as he did in <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071807/combined">The Man With the Golden Gun</a></em> &#8212; my favourite Bond film with Moore. Even if you&#8217;re here before the palace completely reopens, I highly recommend the audio tour. Although there are nice signs put up by American Express and some audio explanations piped over speakers, there&#8217;s nothing quite like velvet pouring into your ear as you walk around (although bring your own headphones &#8212; the ear piece they supply is a tad painful).<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03637.JPG" alt="Inside the Forbidden City in Beijing" width="300" /></a><br />
Barely halfway into the tour, thunder rumbled. We&#8217;d had a thunderstorm last night, and it looked like we hadn&#8217;t seen the end of it. Sure enough, just as we reached the end of the tour, the smattering of rain we had been receiving turned into a deluge. When it finally let up a bit, Amy and I darted out from our shelter under one of the many covered patios and made a break for the exit and a taxi. Not wanting to get stuck with some schmuck trying to rip us off, we decided to walk down the block a bit. We had vendor after vendor offer us umbrellas and carts and bicycle-rickshaws try to pick us up and get us out of the rain. We pressed on. It started to hail, but we pressed on.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03638.JPG" alt="Some strange signs" width="300" /></a><br />
Finally taking shelter under an eaves down a road on the east side of the City, we contemplated the fact that we were soaked. Our bags, thankfully, are built well enough to prevent leakage. Our clothes, not so much. When the rain finally let up, we headed back to the hotel to rest up a bit. A dip in the pool, a shower, and we went in search of the nearby mall for dinner. We found a bakery and the illusive BBQ pork buns. It took us until today to find these tasty little morsels. But when we tried to leave to go home &#8212; more rain. Torrents of us. We holed up in the Grand Hyatt&#8217;s lobby lounge (the hotel is attached to the mall) until it passed.<br />
Tomorrow, we&#8217;re going to check out Dead Mao, and possibly the Summer Palace. One more full day, and then we&#8217;re off to Shanghai!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/enter-the-forbidden-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">557</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Mongolia</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=adventures-in-mongolia</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2005 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mongolia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ulaan baatar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/05/25/adventures-in-mongolia/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.) Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Adventures in Mongolia"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re back in Ulaan Baatar after a few days out in the Mongolian wilderness. It&#8217;s a brief return &#8212; we hit the #24 train to Beijing at 8:00 tomorrow morning. (It&#8217;s about 21:30 right now, as I&#8217;m writing this.)<br />
Without question, Mongolia has been the highlight of this adventure. Unless something really spectacular comes up that somehow manages to sway us (which I doubt will happen), then Mongolia will be <em>the</em> thing on the trip. Also without question, we would heartily recommend coming to Mongolia (and soon, before the rest of the world discovers how cool this country is) and signing up with Nomadic Journeys. They take far too good care of you.<br />
<span id="more-550"></span>Our campsite was about 300 km west of Ulaan Baatar &#8212; a trip that takes six hours. Most of the roads in Mongolia were built back in the 1950s by the Russians and Chinese &#8230; and haven&#8217;t really received any major attention since then. Needless to say, if you&#8217;re not driving something well-built, you don&#8217;t be driving it too long &#8212; the roads will turn them to pulp. We drove in a small Russian-built jeep without seatbelts. Our driver, Lasaa (assuming I&#8217;m spelling his name correctly) is an expert driver, and avoided the majority of the disasters of the road. That meant driving all over the road, including the shoulders.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03595.JPG" alt="The scenery as you drive in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
It&#8217;s an interesting commentary when the dirt roads that sometimes parallel the highway are better than the highway.<br />
When we arrived at our camp (which appeared rather suddenly), we found three gers, tents used by the Mongolian nomadic people. They&#8217;re wood-framed, built in a circle with a sloped conical roof. The entire frame is covered with felt and canvas. They&#8217;re ridiculously comfy, even in the heat we experienced. Amy and I were the only tourists there &#8212; we&#8217;re the first of the season at that location. There were two nomadic families across the valley.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03596.JPG" alt="Our ger camp" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03597.JPG" alt="Just to prove I was there" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03598.JPG" alt="The all-important toilet; which, thankfully, did not stink" width="300" /></a><br />
The first day there was a laid-back one: hiking up the adjacent mountain (Amy to half-way; I couldn&#8217;t resist the surge to the top). Meals were in the middle ger. The second day took us on a hike north through the valley, passing a family of domesticated camels, and through a mountain pass to a small Buddhist temple on the other side (Lasa met us there to drive us back). The temple has but a single nun (not even a monk, so far as we could tell) and a museum curator, who showed us around. There&#8217;s ruins there from a previous building destroyed when the Soviets ran amok through Mongolia in an attempt to stamp out all religion.<br />
To give you an idea of how unspoiled this place is, when we wandered around the ruins, we found fragments of Buddha statues and artwork still in the dirt. That&#8217;s how few tourists have been here. (Even though there is a &#8220;card shop&#8221;.)<br />
After lunch, we visited a small lake featuring kites, ducks (that sounded like frogs), and horses. Beautiful scenery, too. Then it was a visit over to one of the nomadic families to see how they live. Truth be known, they live pretty well. The gers are so comfortable, most nomadic families choose to live in them instead of permanent shelters. It&#8217;s also necessary as many families have to move (up to four times a year) to keep their herds of animals fed and watered. We petted baby sheep and goats. One tried to milk me by banging it head repeatedly into my groin. I mean, honestly, do I look like a goat?? After dinner, Amy and I dragged Ganaa (our guide/translator) up the side of a sand dune to watch a sunset. We were treated to a rather strange spectacle when we returned as the nomadic family tried to get their herd into a small corral for milking time.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03599.JPG" alt="Down by the bay (but no watermelons grow)" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03601.JPG" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03602.JPG" alt="Inside a nomadic ger" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03603.JPG" alt="Sunset on top of a sand dune" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03606.JPG" alt="Our driver, Lasa, with a baby goat" width="300" /></a><br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03607.JPG" alt="Not nearly as noisy as you think it should have been" width="300" /></a><br />
Our third day marked a trip to Kharakorum and Erdene Zuu, the former being the ancient capital of Mongolia, and the latter being the monastery that still operates there. Three hours on bumpy roads. Beatiful buildings, though. Amazing part of it was that we were among the first tourists there that day &#8212; most of those in attendance were there for the ceremony marking the first 15 days of summer, which was the monks chanting the entire day. The fact we could walk around the museum temples unimpeded by a single tourist was &#8230; very zen.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03608.JPG" alt="The temples of Erdene Zuu" width="300" /></a><br />
The weather on the morning of our fourth day was unbelievable. The wind that had started the night before had given rise to rain, blowing sand (you couldn&#8217;t see the dunes &#8212; a mere kilometre away &#8212; for the clouds erupting from them), and eventually snow as we rolled to Hustai National Park, 95 km from Ulaan Baatar.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03610.JPG" alt="Crappy weather on the road" width="300" /></a><br />
Hustai is a preserve that hosts the only wild population of tahki &#8212; the Mongolian wild horse. It was reintroduced here in the early 1990s, and has grown to over 200 horses in 14 small herds. (That, and an insane number of marmots.) It was freezing as we got our glances at a distance, but they were neat to see. We stayed in Ger #7 at the Hustai Tourist &#8220;Resort&#8221;. (About 20 gers, a couple of permanent buildings, and a &#8220;restaurant&#8221; serving food so lacking in flavour, I&#8217;d describe it as a gastronomic vacuum.)<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03611.JPG" alt="The ger camp at Hustai National Park in Mongolia" width="300" /></a><br />
I woke up about 3:00 this morning in a big shivering ball. Our fire had gone out and the temperatures had plunged. Needless to say, I&#8217;m a little tired as a result. Even once I was more bundled up (and I was beginning to think that long underwear wasn&#8217;t a good idea to bring!), my brain ran crazy with ways of trying to rekindle our dead fire. Note to self: always bring matches in the future when going to places that need fires.<br />
We returned to UB today and made a beeline for the Gobi Factory Store. Gobi is the major manufacturer of cashmere goods, at least in Mongolia. I knew of them before coming, but hadn&#8217;t really thought that this was the place. It really was a factory store, too &#8212; the store was attached to the Gobi factory. Prices were decent, although the place was mobbed by some very unruly and rude French tourists.<br />
The real prize, however, was not the completed fabrics. It was cashmere yarn, which Gobi does <strong>not</strong> sell in their stores. And Amy could not leave Mongolia without it. To get it, Ganaa went through the most amazing display of digging that I&#8217;ve ever seen. It took 90 minutes, including walking deep into the Gobi factory to find the yarn storage room to select the spools, but we walked away with 2.3 kilos of it. Amy&#8217;s happy, to say the least. But I&#8217;ll leave that portion of the story to her. It&#8217;s a doozy.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03614.JPG" alt="Cashmere yarn at the Gobi Factory in Ulaan Baatar" width="300" /></a><br />
After that, we visited the Bogd Khaan&#8217;s Summer Palace in the south part of the city. It&#8217;s nice, but poorly maintained. Some of the treasures inside are wonderful, but it wasn&#8217;t worth the 5500T it cost for me to take pictures (even though that&#8217;s only about US$5). After Erdene Zuu, it was hard to look at the Summer Palace and think it was wonderful.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03615.JPG" alt="The gates of the Bogd Khan's Summer Palace" width="300" /></a><br />
And so we leave Mongolia for China. Our plans have changed a bit, there. We&#8217;re hitting only Beijing, Xi&#8217;an, and Guangzhou (only because it&#8217;s right next to Hong Kong, and after the train from Xi&#8217;an, we won&#8217;t be up to crossing the border right away). Then it&#8217;s into the Hong Kong area, first with Macau, then HK proper. Why the cutting back? Too much running in and out of places has made us weary, and after hearing a few too many horror stories, we&#8217;re not sure that we&#8217;re even going to like China that much. But we shall see&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/05/adventures-in-mongolia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">550</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (still)</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2004 23:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/06/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The alarm went off early. Earlier than usual, anyway. Jen was still sleeping, so I thought I&#8217;d let her sleep a bit longer. But at 9:00, I got her going. Unforunately, Jen started off with a killer headache, so she didn&#8217;t move very quickly. Compound to that a very irregular bus schedule and not being &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Touring Tokyo (still)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The alarm went off early. Earlier than usual, anyway. Jen was still sleeping, so I thought I&#8217;d let her sleep a bit longer. But at 9:00, I got her going.<br />
Unforunately, Jen started off with a killer headache, so she didn&#8217;t move very quickly. Compound to that a very irregular bus schedule and not being able to catch a limited express to Tokyo wound up pretty much killing the point of today&#8217;s journey &#8212; going to Nikko.<br />
<span id="more-344"></span>Nikko is about 50 minutes north of Tokyo by shinkansen. We neeed to get to Nikko in enough time to look around, and still get back at a reasonable hour. Problem: the first shinkansen was at 13:16, which would get us to Nikko (including the time on the local train) at almost 15:00, far too late to be useful for us.<br />
Instead, I thought a different plan might be in order: a tour of Tokyo. So off on the Yamanote line to Hammamatsucho to catch one of the Hato Bus tours. This is the same thing Chris and I did last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Tsukiji Fish Market]]), and I thought that the commentary might be better for Jen than me trying to explain things as we either walked too much or whizzed by on the train (on which Jen loves to sleep).<br />
Initially, Jen wasn&#8217;t too keen on doing it, but with a little encouragement (and me paying the fare), things were arranged. I am slowly starting to have issues with motivation. Jen really wanted to come to Japan, but in the last few days, I&#8217;m having trouble getting her to want to go out and do things. Sometimes, I think all she wants to do is sit back and play video games at Chris and Kaz&#8217;s. And I really hate having to say things like: &#8220;you didn&#8217;t come to Japan to play video games&#8221;. I&#8217;m hoping this is just because of Jen&#8217;s headache today.<br />
The bus tour was the same as the one we&#8217;d taken last year, starting off at the World Trade Center, then out to the Imperial Palace (via the Ginza district), out through Akehabara to Asakusa Kannon Temple, and then a boat cruise down the Sumida River. I think the order is different than last year, and the stop at the Imperial Palace was different.<br />
Also different were the guides. The guide for our bus was missing at the time the tour started, so one of the guides had to take our group in addition to his. The way this guy talked reminded me of Mr. Chen from &#8220;Big Trouble in Little China&#8221; with his odd humour and speaking manner.<br />
Tokyo was hazy again, so we couldn&#8217;t see too far. No chance of seeing Mt. Fuji from the top. Soon, we were back down at the bottom and on our way to the bus. There we met our tour guide, Rika.<br />
Rika knew English quite well, but had an odd speaking manner. Unlike most people speaking English, Rika&#8217;s annunciation sounded like the earlier generations of computer synthesized speech: choppy construction, inflection in the wrong parts of the speech, and the odd bit of mispronounciation. Otherwise, her English was inpeccable. (Except when she tried to tell us that people hang out their clothes to &#8220;disinfect&#8221; rather than &#8220;dry&#8221;.)<br />
The tour was busy. There were at least five groups running through at the time, including ours. One particular group appeared to be school kids from the United States. We weren&#8217;t sure if they were there on some kind of field trip or on an exchange. They were a bit annoying. Like how gnats are annoying. Luckily, they weren&#8217;t with us.<br />
Our bus was thankfully light on the load, and all adults. We had a multicultural group, with people from the United States (both coasts), Switzerland, Sweden, Argentina, Mexico, and Peru.<br />
We stopped at a different part of the Imperial Palace Plaza than last year, which was the uninteresting part. The double bridge entrance has more to see, the side next to the East Gardens is kinda dull.<br />
Off to Asakusa and the Nakamise shopping arcade. Last year, this wasn&#8217;t a huge issue. This year, I think every tour bus in Tokyo had delivered people there, in addition to the countless regular tourists. &#8220;Crowded&#8221; is an understatement.<br />
Trying to follow Rika proved to be a problem, not just because she was shorter than the average crowd height, but trying to get through the throngs of people proved to be a challenge. Even having to elbow our way through everyone, we finally arrived at the temple mostly intact as a group. Everyone else who didn&#8217;t join the group were out in the shopping arcade.<br />
Rika gave us the quick tour of the temple, how it was built and how it worked. Then we were cast to the winds for 25 minutes, at which time we needed to be at the boat dock. Jen and I started down towards the arcade, but just barely outside of the actual temple grounds, we were sidetracked by the smell of fried noodles and chicken yakatori. Both of us were hungry enough that we sat down for a quick meal.<br />
Then it was a quick walk down the arcade, bypassing all the stores, almost running the last little bit to the boat dock. The boat trip down the Sumida River was the same one we did last year, so there really wasn&#8217;t much new for me. The fact that the cruise was also full of people certainly didn&#8217;t make the cruise particularly exciting. We just enjoyed a lazy trip down the river, periodically taking a bit of chop as a result of the incoming tide.<br />
We arrived at the Himeda Pier, hopped the bus, and headed back to Hammamatsucho. Once there, Jen and I headed back to Tokyo and then onto Chiba. Along the way, Kaz and I exchanged messages, discussing possibilities for dinner. Chris was still at work, we wouldn&#8217;t see him again for a while, so it was just us for a while.<br />
We tried to get on an NEX at Tokyo, but without success. Although our passes supposedly work on the NEX, we couldn&#8217;t get on the train because there didn&#8217;t seem to be any cars with unreserved seats. We got on a regular rapid train instead.<br />
We met up with Kaz at Chiba station, and headed off in search of the 100 Yen store, just above Yodobashi Camera. Jen had thought of finding some things there to take back for friends and family. But Jen disappeared almost as soon as I rounded a corner. I found her in the toy store next to the 100 yen plaza.<br />
She&#8217;d found a hoodie (sweatshirt with a hood) for Full Metal Alchemist. To say she was excited was putting it mildly. So excited that I actually couldn&#8217;t resist buying it for her. Mostly because she couldn&#8217;t afford to buy it for herself.<br />
Purchases in hand, we headed off in search of dinner, specifically sushi. It didn&#8217;t take much to direct them to the sushi restaurant under the railway tracks. Yep &#8212; the same one I went to the first night I was in Japan a year ago. The three of us picked off what we wanted as it came around on the conveyor, supplementing with a couple of ordered items, such as shrimp tempura, singed salmon, and Jen had a huge bowl of miso soup.<br />
Completely full, we rolled out and headed back to Yotsukaido. It turns out Chris was unable to join us tonight &#8212; he&#8217;s back at his old place packing up the remainder of his things. Hopefully, we&#8217;ll see him tomorrow night.<br />
[flickr]tag:japan+tokyo+april+2004+&#8221;6&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:japan+chiba+april+2004+&#8221;6&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-tokyo-touring-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 23:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much. Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much.<br />
Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up the Karasuma line to the Kyoto Imperial Palace. I really wanted to see what it&#8217;s like in there.<br />
But first, we had to pack up and check out. Which wasn&#8217;t easy &#8212; we&#8217;d spread ourselves all over the room. Although it didn&#8217;t take me long to pack, Jen had to take a bit longer out of necessity. It&#8217;s safe to say that, either way, both of us officially have too much stuff.<br />
<span id="more-341"></span>I had some troubles at the front desk trying to pay for the bill. It came to about 85,000 yen for the four days (about CDN$1,000).<br />
Yes, this is what people refer to when they say that Japan is expensive. Last time, I hadn&#8217;t noticed this because I&#8217;d stayed with Chris. Now I know better.<br />
For whatever reason, my Mastercard wasn&#8217;t accepted. Neither was my VISA. Not by the hotel &#8212; by their system. Quite odd, and highly annoying. So it had to be cash, and I needed a post office for that. First, though, Jen and I brought our bags down to put into storage.<br />
Luckily, there&#8217;s a post office about a block and a half from the hotel, and unlike Canada&#8217;s post offices, was open on a weekend. But my financial woes didn&#8217;t end &#8212; for whatever reason, I couldn&#8217;t withdraw more than 60,000 yen, barely covering our hotel cost with the money I already had. I think I have only about 10,000 yen to get me through the weekend. I hope I make it.<br />
This prompted a long series of emails to and from North America (over the keitai), specifically to my sister, to try and figure out what happened to my bank account. My paycheque should have gone through two days ago (even with the time change). Thankfully, my money is still there, I just can&#8217;t get to it for some reason.<br />
We got to the Imperial Palace and walked over to the Household Agency, which governs the operation of the Palaces and grants the tours.<br />
On weekdays. We&#8217;d forgotten that it&#8217;s Saturday. I knew there was a reason I&#8217;d wanted to go to Osaka today and not yesterday.<br />
After taking a bit of a leisurely tour through the palace grounds, we returned to the hotel to collect our things and head off to the shinkansen. The 12:37 Hikaru would put us in Tokyo a little after 15:00, and have us at Chris&#8217; door by 16:30 or so. (As it stands, we arrived at 17:00.)<br />
Nearing Kyoto Station, the unmisstakable sound of women running in high heels echoed through the tiled hallways. (In the hotel room, women running down the road in high heels always seemed to sound like horses clip-clopping.) Women always seem to be running in heels here. If there was an Olympic event for running in high heels, Japan would capture the gold every time.<br />
The train ride out was mostly uneventful, Jen and I snoozing most of the trip from Kyoto to Tokyo. Arriving at Tokyo, we found our way down to Sobu underground track #4, where we waited for the 15:50 to Chiba. For the first time since I started taking trains in Japan, one was actually late.<br />
By five whole minutes.<br />
Chris and Kaz were kept appraised of our location at all times. Chris was off to work again, so Kaz would pick us up at the train station. How did I know all this? The rented cell phone, of course. Today, if anything, has proven why renting a cell phone in Japan is a good thing &#8212; being able to confirm a bank account balance or make sure you meet up with friends is not only extremely handy, but really cuts some of the guess work out of things. So if you&#8217;re planning to come to Japan and know people here, really consider renting a phone. It&#8217;s almost too convenient not to have one.<br />
Arriving at Yotsukaido, Kaz directed us to the taxi. I didn&#8217;t think Chris&#8217; apartment was so far away that we needed a taxi, but after a long trip, taking a ride seemed far more pleasant. As we would find out, however, we were not going to Chris&#8217; apartment. Suddenly, the slightly garbled phone conversation I&#8217;d had with Chris made sense. We were going to Kaz&#8217;s (and now also Chris&#8217;) new apartment.<br />
It you get off on the taxi/bus side of the station, and go down the road that runs perpendicular to the station for about three kilometres, hang a left at the Eneos station, and go up about a block, you&#8217;ve found their place. It&#8217;s not as convenient as Chris&#8217; old apartment, but it is really nice. Brand-new (it was finished only days before we left Canada) and full of gadgets (the hot water for the bath/shower is turned on from the kitchen/living space, all electronic, and actually says something &#8212; in Japanese, of course). It&#8217;s pretty sweet.<br />
It&#8217;s a bus ride from the station, or taxi, or a long walk. So we won&#8217;t be hoofing it all that often, especially after a long day. No big deal, especially for such a nice place &#8230; even if it is going to be a bit cramped for the next couple of days. (Tony&#8217;s here tonight, and probably tomorrow night, too.)<br />
Kaz and I took the bus back to the station after dumping our things out (Jen stayed behind to read and draw), and then walked to the local Home Depot-like store. They&#8217;d purchased a gas range so they could cook, but had to pick it up. Although a fairly light piece of equipment, it&#8217;s just awkward enough that you needed to borrow a truck to take it home. We took the opportunity to pick up a few things from the apartment.<br />
Like the heater&#8230;<br />
&#8230; the TV &#8230;<br />
&#8230; the VCR, DVD player, Playstation, movies, books, CDs, CD burner, a small cabinet, boxes of who-knows-what, and anything else we could pack in the back of the truck.<br />
I should point out that this is a *Japanese* truck. One that could fit in the bed of most large American pick-up trucks. So there wasn&#8217;t that much room for us to store stuff. Not that it was a big deal of any kind. It was weird to sit in because it was so small. You literally felt like the steel of the cab wrapped right around you to conserve space.<br />
Chris arrived just as we were finishing up, and we quickly packed the remainder. Kaz and I drove over in the truck while Chris biked. Due to rush hour traffic, Chris arrived before we did. A quick unpacking, and Chris and Kaz whipped off to take the truck back before they&#8217;d run out of time.<br />
Jen and I waited around, either drawing (in Jen&#8217;s case) or writing (in mine). It took a while, but they eventually returned to the apartment. They ran into Jen on her way back from coffee run (now that we&#8217;re in the Tokyo area, we&#8217;re actually able to find Georgia Max coffee again &#8212; the southern part of Japan seems to be devoid of it).<br />
With that, we were off to dinner at a nearby restaurant. We went for something called okonomiyaki, which is basically food that comes in a bowl, is mixed together, then cooked on a grill that&#8217;s built into the table. It&#8217;s sort of like a Japanese omelette or fritatta. It&#8217;s very tasty. We also had some grilled beef and pork, along with noodle and gyoza.<br />
Tony (yep, the Monkey Man) finally appeared around 22:00, after repeated attempts to try and get a hold of him. The five of us sat around, ate a little, before heading back to Kaz and Chris&#8217; apartment. We stopped first into a 24-hour drug/grocery store to pick up snacks and various things for around the house (they&#8217;re still moving in, so don&#8217;t have a lot of things). Jen bought three more Georgia Max coffees, and had downed two of them before we&#8217;d walked the block and a half to the apartment. She was still wired when we went to bed three hours later.<br />
Upon returning was the Great Soul Calibur II Matchup. Chris and Jen had been talking about this for a long time. Chris is very good at this game, as is Jen. Chris has a sort of &#8220;home field&#8221; advantage because this is a Playstation 2, whereas Jen plays on a GameCube. Doesn&#8217;t sound like it should matter, but it does. Jen won only a single game. Chris thoroughly trashed her in all the others. I just looked over at Jen, smiled, and said:<br />
&#8220;Now you know how I feel when I play you.&#8221;<br />
We called an end to Jen&#8217;s repeated &#8220;just one more!&#8221; requests, turning to the movie &#8220;Zatoichi&#8221;, a Japanese film about a blind master samurai and how he changes the lives of others. It&#8217;s a fairly violent film, but intermixed with comedy and some rather good rhythm (Stomp-like performances appear at various points in the movie). The ending&#8217;s a little disjointed, in my opinion, but it&#8217;s still a good film.<br />
And with that, we went to bed. Tomorrow is light: sleeping in, laundry, and the Fourth Party for Chris and Kaz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2003 18:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/05/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today was my last full day in Japan. There was so much I still wanted to see and do. I couldn&#8217;t do everything &#8230; but I darn well tried! Chris had to work, so would stay behind in Yotsukaido. Kaz, her friend, Ellesen, and myself went into brave the city of Tokyo and what wonders &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Trip to Japan, Imperial Palace and Ueno Park"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was my last full day in Japan. There was so much I still wanted to see and do. I couldn&#8217;t do everything &#8230; but I darn well tried!<br />
Chris had to work, so would stay behind in Yotsukaido. Kaz, her friend, Ellesen, and myself went into brave the city of Tokyo and what wonders there were yet to find.<br />
<span id="more-279"></span>I bade Ellesen and Kaz&#8217;s friend farewell at Tokyo station. I had a very rigorous trip planned for myself, and I didn&#8217;t want to drag people to somewhere they didn&#8217;t want to go. Kaz and I agreed to meet back at 16:30 (we parted ways at 13:30). It didn&#8217;t give me a lot of time, but then, that&#8217;s part of the challenge.<br />
My first stop was at the Imperial Palace. There were a couple of things I wanted a picture of that I didn&#8217;t get on the bus tour. That, and it was actually somewhat sunny for a change. I hurried through the complex. It took almost 30 minutes, counting traffic lights, photographs, and the fact that the palace grounds are very large.<br />
Then it was back towards the Yamanote line, which I would follow to the stop before Hamamatsucho, where I had previously spied a steam locomotive on static display. The day was becoming quite warm, and I was sweating quite a lot. Another reason why I was glad not to have anyone else with me.<br />
Along my route, I saw a few things I hadn&#8217;t seen before. Most of it was architectural, but there were a few interesting things and views. One of the strangest was when I was held up at a crossing by a traffic cop. At first I couldn&#8217;t tell why, since there was no traffic. But then I saw it. Or rather, heard it.<br />
It was a parade, of sorts. All marching bands, and all Japanese, so far as I could tell. I assumed it was for some sort of competition. I didn&#8217;t have time to find out, though, and blasted past to find my steam locomotive.<br />
A few blocks away, I found my quarry. Although I couldn&#8217;t read the sign, I could only gather that this was a switcher, or short-distance locomotive. Tank engines usually didn&#8217;t go too far. As near as I could tell, it was based on a British design, but Japanese-built. It had served its last a long time ago, and now served as decoration next to the JR lines supporting both the ring railway and the shinkansen lines. The only passengers the locomotive handles now are eager children and birds.<br />
Turning away from the locomotive, I navigated my way through the maze of streets at the edge of the Ginza district to find my way to the Hama-rikyu Garden. Formerly the private hunting grounds of the Edo shogun, it&#8217;s now a public park (with a 300 yen admission). It&#8217;s a beautiful place to spend an afternoon.<br />
I didn&#8217;t have an afternoon. I had about 20 minutes. I figured I&#8217;d blast through the park, come out the other side and hit the JR train at Hamamatsucho, going up to Ueno. Little did I know, however, that I was going to be blocked by one little crucial detail: The park has only one entrance and exit. Of course, I didn&#8217;t realize this until I was on the other side of the park. But this gave me a chance to see the large tidal pond, the bridges, the pathways, and the 300 Year Pine (actually only 295 years &#8212; it was planted in 1708).<br />
By the time I got to the JR Hamamatsucho station, my feet, legs, and back were discussing mutiny from the rest of me. Couldn&#8217;t blame &#8217;em, though &#8212; I&#8217;d been through a very long walk in a very short period of time. I still had about 45 minutes.<br />
Ten minutes later, I was in Ueno Park. I made a beeline for the first drink machine I could find. I was dying of thirst, and quickly guzzled half of a 3/4 litre bottle of Coke. I still had a lot of walking to do, so got started.<br />
Ueno was once a forest on the outskirts of the shogun&#8217;s city. Now firmly wedged in the Yamanote area of Tokyo, Ueno is the location of a large park, the zoo, Art Museum and National Museum. It&#8217;s very much like Central Park in New York, except that you&#8217;ll also find shrines scattered throughout the park. It&#8217;s very picturesque and calming. I only wish I had more time to see it.<br />
My ultimate goal was to visit the Shogun Tokugawa Graveyard at the north end of the park before boarding the train back to Tokyo station. Not being able to read Japanese, I accidentally took a wrong turn when I exited the main part of the park, taking myself away from the park and the JR station. Luckily, my spidey senses told me I was going the wrong way, and got myself going the right way again.<br />
The cemetery is quite large, and very old. (It holds the mausoleum for the 7th shogun.) It&#8217;s very Zen. Japanese graves are elaborate, yet very simple. Clean lines, but are often shrines onto themselves. I would have loved to wander a bit more, but had to hurry. I was already late for getting to Tokyo station.<br />
I was about 15 minutes late meeting Kaz. We still had some time to kill &#8212; Chris didn&#8217;t get off work until 20:30. This meant I could do two things that I hadn&#8217;t got the chance to do: buy me a small digital camera in Akehabara, and raid Shibuya for the infamous 100 Yen shop and music stores. Luckily, Kaz was more than willing to indulge my whims.<br />
Our first stop was Akehabara, where I made a beeline for the Laox store. (Supposedly one of the best places to purchase electronics.) They also deal in duty-free sales. I have no idea how one would apply for duty-free status, but suffice to say, I&#8217;m glad they do. Twenty minutes and one new digital camera later, we were back out on the street and heading for the train. It was off to Shibuya.<br />
Shibuya&#8217;s darn near on the opposite side of the Yamanote circle, so it was almost a half hour before we got to Shibuya station. Once outside, there were two destinations: HMV, and the 100 Yen store. I had promised a friend of mine to pick up some Japanese albums for him while here, and I knew HMV would have what I wanted.<br />
As it turns out, the first store we hit crossing the intersection sold CDs. Since CDs are the same price (or pretty darn near) at every store, we skipped the HMV in favour of a closer quarry. (After we had a quick drink at the Starbucks, of course.) Having Kaz with me proved very helpful again, since she&#8217;s able to read Japanese, allowing us to find the albums we were searching for.<br />
Then it was off to find the 100 Yen store. A little more of a challenge, but a few questions to others walking around soon led us to spendthrift heaven. Four floors of all sorts of things for 100 yen. The 100 Yen stores are very similar to the Canadian dollar stores, with one major difference: unlike the dollar stores where things can cost several dollars, every last item in the 100 Yen stores is 100 yen. No exceptions. (100 yen is worth roughly CDN$1.25.)<br />
I walked out with 2,300 yen worth of stuff, most of it dinnerware.<br />
We returned to the station, and started back towards Tokyo station. There was one more stop I wanted to make before I left Tokyo for the last time (at least on this trip): see Tokyo at night. Tokyo gets dark by about 19:00. Luckily for me, the World Trade Centre is open until 20:00. Arriving with 30 minutes to spare, Kaz and I took a look at nighttime Tokyo from 40 floors up.<br />
Arriving back in Yotsukaido around 21:30, we immediately went to Chris&#8217; apartment to dump our things, and so I could change into a less smelly set of clothes. Because it was already so late, going to Chiba wasn&#8217;t a great idea &#8212; we&#8217;d end up taking a taxi back again. Instead, we would hunt down a local restaurant. We ran into Jan (doing a midnight garbage run), who recommended a restaurant that was open until 05:00. Jan is a connoisseur of these restaurants.<br />
What&#8217;s with the midnight garbage run? It&#8217;s so he can dispose of his garbage, of course. In Japan, space is at an absolute premium &#8212; landfills are extremely few. So recycling is vigorously practiced, as is the separation of combustible and non-combustible refuse. Garbage collection, as a result, is fairly complicated. Jan ends up having to distribute his stuff over a fairly wide area, lest he put it all in one place. Or that&#8217;s so I gather&#8230;<br />
The restaurant was nothing particular special, but the food was good &#8230; just like the company I had. We ate and talked until well after midnight, when the table next to us finally got too loud, and it was time for us to leave.<br />
[flickr]tag:tokyo+may+&#8221;5&#8243;+2003@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/trip-to-japan-imperial-palace-ueno-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">279</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
