<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>vancouver &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/vancouver/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 22:27:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>20 years from Ontario</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=20-years-from-ontario</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two decades ago today, I did something immensely stupid: I left home. Literally and figuratively. Twenty years ago, I was still sleeping in my room on Gatestone Avenue in Oakville. While I had lived on my own at university, and while I was on my co-op work terms in Ottawa, staying at home was &#8230; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "20 years from Ontario"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two decades ago today, I did something immensely stupid: I left home. Literally and figuratively. Twenty years ago, I was still sleeping in my room on Gatestone Avenue in Oakville. While I had lived on my own at university, and while I was on my co-op work terms in Ottawa, staying at home was &#8230; comfortable. And as my parents didn&#8217;t object, it seemed like a good idea. Literally leaving home wasn&#8217;t the problem &#8212; I&#8217;d already done it a dozen times.<br />
Figuratively leaving home &#8212; notably the familiarity of the Greater Toronto area, but Ontario in general &#8212; was another matter. I&#8217;d not really lived abroad, where going to my parents&#8217; house was something I did in an afternoon. I decided to throw myself into the world without any plan whatsoever.<br />
Twenty years on, it was the smartest move I ever made.<br />
<span id="more-3621"></span><br />
Toronto is often derided as the &#8220;centre of Canada&#8221;. It&#8217;s the largest city, and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_Toronto_Area" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greater Toronto area</a> has around six million people, roughly one sixth the entire population of Canada. It&#8217;s a massive economic base &#8212; most of the banks are headquartered there &#8212; so there&#8217;s a significant amount of perceived power &#8230; and utter disregard for the Rest of Canada.<br />
This is the mentality I grew up with, and the one I carried with me when I moved to Vancouver. Until that point, I&#8217;d only visited Vancouver twice: both times in the prior five months to moving away. I&#8217;d experienced only a brief glimpse of Vancouver and what it would do to me.<br />
So why did I move? In a way: complacency, though I didn&#8217;t really recognize that at the time. I had a job in Toronto, I had my family, I had my friends. What I didn&#8217;t have was &#8230; <em>something</em>. To this day, I genuinely don&#8217;t know what it was that I was missing, nor do I think I&#8217;ve found it in the 20 years since. But I knew that I wasn&#8217;t going to find it in Toronto.<br />
In the span of only a few weeks, I packed up what little I considered as &#8220;my life&#8221;, threw it in a bag and a couple of boxes, packed myself into a cramped Canada 3000 plane, and soon found myself wandering Granville Street asking myself: &#8220;Now what?&#8221;<br />
No plan, no expectations, no worries. And at a mere 25 years old, I had enough education and experience under my belt to know I&#8217;d find a job (though I didn&#8217;t know where), I&#8217;d find a place to live (something I can definitely say would be a problem if I were doing that today), and things would somehow figure themselves out. Oh, the wonderful naiveness of my youth!<br />
Twenty years on, I have a family of my own. I&#8217;ve been many places, I done many things, and yet &#8212; to quote U2 &#8212; I still haven&#8217;t found what I&#8217;m looking for. I&#8217;ve had to create a plan (several, really), and I have to set expectations (both with myself, and with others), and my worries &#8230; well, I think I&#8217;d terrify poor 25 year-old me. Relatedly, to answer the question of &#8220;what would I tell a younger me, if I could&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>You are coming to a lot of mountains. Some you will have to cross over, some you can travel under. But you will always get to the other side, and there will always be loved ones there for you.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yeah, I know, it&#8217;s  wishy-washy. Why not tell myself the truth? Because I love my life. For all the hell I periodically go through, I can&#8217;t imagine it any other way. It&#8217;s a classic science-fiction trope: one little change in the past could dramatically alter your future. Could be for the better, could be for the worse. I like what I have, and I&#8217;d like of like to keep it that way.<br />
Actually, slight correction: I like what I have, but there are many days when I long for things of the last. People I miss, places I&#8217;ve been, or in the case of earlier today, when I didn&#8217;t have to cook or clean the dishes in the carefree days of my youth. Right now, Monkey and Choo Choo are playing in the room next to me with their LEGOs, and I miss those days. Responsibility weighs heavily.<br />
And while we&#8217;re at it, exactly <em>who</em> left me have my own kids, anyway? I mean, my wife is a fairly significant part, but anyone who truly knows me will wonder what reasonable agency allowed me to reproduce. It&#8217;s been a decade of that, and I still have this strange feeling that some strange agent will appear at my door, saying I broke some kind of law.<br />
Until that day, I&#8217;ll just take the things I could have told my younger self &#8230; and tell them to my kids. They haven&#8217;t had their futures yet (barring the presence of time loops that haven&#8217;t made themselves present), so hopefully I can impart some of that wisdom so their mountains aren&#8217;t so tall, the snow drifts aren&#8217;t so deep, and that they know what&#8217;s waiting for them on the other side before they even start climbing.<br />
If they listen, that is. They&#8217;re definitely my kids: know-it-alls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/20-years-from-ontario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3621</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Believe</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-believe</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 08:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Canada, I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I Believe"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Canada,<br />
I must, in true Canadian form, say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221;. I doubted. All I could see was fault, all I could see was mediocrity, all I could see was the world laughing at our attempts to be more than our humble selves.  I thought that Vancouver was the wrong place to hold the Winter Olympics (having lived there a couple of years, I know how finicky the weather can be).<br />
And I wasn&#8217;t alone. Thanks to media mainstays, such as The Guardian and the Denver Post, and CTV&#8217;s frequently slipshod and amateurish approach, there was little reason for me to think otherwise.<br />
I find myself, now at the end, relieved to be wrong, and fiercely proud to be a repatriated Canadian.<br />
<span id="more-2626"></span>The <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/">Own The Podium</a> program had me enraged. It was meant to increase the chances of medal wins &#8212; to the point where we had the most medals. Not only was it arrogance beyond our Canadian norm, I found that the program sponsored only those who were in medal contention &#8212; and abandoned the rest. Considering we&#8217;re a socialist country, it seems a very un-Canadian setup. (And can someone tell me, please, why on earth the <a href="http://www.ownthepodium2010.com/Funding/detailsw.aspx?id=8">Men&#8217;s Hockey team received Own The Podium funding</a>? It just seems odd to support millionaires who already have significant amounts of training and coaching resources.)<br />
Then came the the death of Georgian luger Nodar Kumaritashvili mere hours before the cauldron was lit.  (And no, Tom Clark, CTV <em>did not need</em> to show footage of the fatal run to &#8220;tell the full story&#8221;. That was utter <em>pandering</em> to sensationalist news coverage. You want to be better than CBC? You&#8217;d better <em>act</em> like you are, first.) The pall cast over the opening felt almost suffocating.<br />
The opening ceremonies themselves were filled with a host of flubs: lip syncing (seriously, we are unable to trust our biggest performers to perform in public?), slight delays (starting even with the snowboarder not coming down on cue), and mechanical failures (erectile dysfunction, anyone?). Problems seemed to continue past the hutzpah, with broken ice resurfacing machines, and an ill-timed rampage by ill-tempted and extremely short-sighted rioters. The press ate us alive.<br />
Our lauded best, held on pedestals for months, were put to the test. But the gold we were promised didn&#8217;t come. Our speedskaters failed to place, and our former moguls world champion could only garner a silver. And admit it, Canada, for a little while, you doubted, too. Had we put too much pressure on our athletes? Did we expect too much? Maybe where I failed was not to recognise it as a beginning of something bigger.<br />
The next day &#8212; less than 24 hours after our first disappointment &#8212; things started to change. Someone I&#8217;d never heard of, suddenly appeared on top. After almost 34 years of waiting, Alexandre Bilodeau had won Canada&#8217;s first gold medal at home. For a moment, the country stood and cheered! We would walk away with something, at least. We would feel like we&#8217;ve achieved. Maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; it was enough to take away our collective dread. Or at least mine.<br />
But the medals were still slow to come. It was two days before another gold from Maelle Ricker. Five days into the games, we had a mere five medals. Our hubris was an embarrassment. Our medals, though appreciated, would stand more as an example of an effort not carried to fruition.<br />
And then something happened that we didn&#8217;t expect. It caught me by surprise, as I know it caught many others. A word that is rarely used in Canada, because of the imagery of our neighbours to the south that it usually invokes: Patriotism. Not a fevered adherence to dogma, but a feeling of national pride the likes of which have not been since I was barely two months old. We all suddenly noticed that you can&#8217;t spell &#8220;Canada&#8221; without &#8220;can&#8221;. And we did.<br />
For me, it was the evening of the men&#8217;s skeleton finals, 19 February. Canada had already won another gold in speed skating, but it was Jon Montgomery&#8217;s victory that seemed to spark something in me. He is not your typical Canadian &#8212; he is brasher, bolder, more outspoken, and not afraid to do things in public that the rest of us would feel the urge to poo-poo as &#8220;not proper&#8221;. His primal scream of victory was the first cry, followed shortly after by a tremendous leap to the top of the podium at the sliding centre; he carried the entire nation with him in that moment. This time, I didn&#8217;t look back down. I &#8212; like you, Canada &#8212; looked forward.<br />
I started to believe.<br />
(And yes, I even started to like that &#8220;<em>I Believe</em>&#8221; song. Probably because after watching enough coverage, you don&#8217;t really have much choice.)<br />
We started the second week with seven medals. Forecasts still placed us well into the 20s. Even with all of our victories in preliminary curling and hockey, it just didn&#8217;t seem possible. But funny thing about believing &#8212; you worry less about failing, and you don&#8217;t want to get left behind.<br />
Our games started with difficult stories:  the disappointment of silver, the struggle in speed skating, and seemingly random disqualifications. The stories had changed. The commentators seemed to take on the energy not just of the crowds, but of the athletes themselves. The stories covered the brotherly dedication, the triumphant (and periodically beer-fuelled) victory marches, impromptu parades, double medals, first wins in new sports, and the sweetheart skaters who not only stole the gold but also the hearts of millions.<br />
But no story could exceed that of Joannie Rochette.<br />
I&#8217;m no figure skater &#8212; I can&#8217;t even skate, really. Growing up, though, I watched a lot of figure skating as a result of watching TV with my mom, a former skater herself, and still an adamant lover of the sport. So, in some small way, I am periodically attracted to it. It was with great fortune that I caught her performance, only days after learning her mother had suddenly died.<br />
I couldn&#8217;t tell you how well she actually skated &#8212; I&#8217;m no judge &#8212; but I can tell you that on that night, Joannie embodied the strength and courage of an Olympian, producing her best possible performance, allowing herself tears only after she was done, to the sound of a thunderous standing ovation. Her medal may have only been a bronze, but as a local paper emblazoned on its headline: it was as good as gold to us.<br />
Most of us Canadians never made it to the games, though I know more than a few who were there, who witnessed gold first-hand. The closest I ever got was my home in southwest Calgary, where I subjected my family to my growing obsession, cheering on my country in its quest for gold, to the point where Alex and I taught the Monkey to chant: &#8220;CA-NA-DA!&#8221; as loudly as she could. We all watched, we all cheered, we all hoped, and we all cried.<br />
And we achieved. We achieved records the likes of which exceeded our expectations. Even with Own The Podium&#8217;s lofty goals, most of us never expected to set a record for the most number of gold medals won in a Winter Olympics. We might not have owned the entire podium, but we took the step that mattered the most to us: the top.<br />
The top was capped with our national games: curling and hockey. Men&#8217;s curling gold, a three-time victory for the women&#8217;s hockey team, and a rematch against our oldest nemesis, the United States. It was joked many times by many people that the men&#8217;s hockey final would effectively close the entire country for the three hours the game would be played. I suspect the joke was not far off. The game would prove to be something special, especially to those born after the early 1970s &#8212; it would become my generation&#8217;s Summit Series, the game that we watched with extreme anticipation, desperately wanting that gold back in our hands.<br />
Vancouver did something to Canada that few would have predicted, even with our previous experience with Calgary and Montreal. For a few weeks,  Vancouver brought together our country &#8212; six timezones and a hugely diverse culture (yes, Canada, we are not just one group; we thrive in our multiculturalism, even if we can&#8217;t always recognise it). Not just in representation, but in anticipation and celebration.  We broke out of our Canadian mould &#8212; we stopped thinking we&#8217;d stop short, that we&#8217;d choke right at the key moments &#8212; and we started to live the dream.<br />
The media has suggested that maybe we&#8217;ll break out from our mould permanently, and be more like our cousins to the south. But we won&#8217;t. That&#8217;s not us. That&#8217;s not <em>Canadian</em>. These games are over, and we&#8217;ll return to our Canadian ways. But we won&#8217;t shrink away, we won&#8217;t forget what happened. We&#8217;ve gotten stronger; we&#8217;ve learned. We&#8217;ve learned how to perform, that success isn&#8217;t just a dream &#8212; it&#8217;s a reality. That we can compete head-to-head with the best the world has to show us, and not be just &#8220;that nice country&#8221;. We&#8217;re now <em>that</em> country: a tough competitor, a fierce opponent. The ones everyone else has to beat.<br />
And it would be nice if we could get our legends back. Mr. Orser, are there not Canadians you can train? Can our curling coaches consider teaching our up-and-comers, rather than guide our competitors? And can we please treat all our athletes with some form of equality? If nothing else, these games proved that underdogs can achieve what no-one expects.<br />
We&#8217;ll freely admit we had things that didn&#8217;t go perfectly. Massive events aren&#8217;t perfect &#8212; the best you can hope for is to mitigate the troubles. So, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14414668">yes Mr. Kiszla, we had a few problems</a> &#8212; I assure you that your lauded Denver games will have their own headaches that will made you cringe. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2010/feb/15/vancouver-winter-olympics-2010">And Mr. Donegan? I&#8217;ve heard better whining</a> from my two-year old when her cereal ends up a bit soggy. Rather than suggesting you return to the golf courses you seem to understand so much better, I suggest you join London&#8217;s Olympic Committee and become personally responsible for London&#8217;s success. Because we&#8217;ll be watching. Closely.<br />
Oh, and one more thing, <a href="http://www.denverpost.com/kiszla/ci_14398658">Mr. Kiszla, about the trash talk</a>? After listening to American bragging for so long, you have no idea how wonderful it is to say: <a href="http://media3.hockeycanada.ca/digital_asset/7/1/6/6/3/image_17ee18aea2c8fd14b8ba92026a8b7525.jpg?cache=305395">It&#8217;s still our game</a>. I believe it will remain that way for a long time to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/i-believe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2626</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary Transit Sucks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-transit-sucks</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 01:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ottawa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was having a discussion with Doug down in the Bistro this morning, and I came to a rather interesting realization: Calgary Transit sucks. Let&#8217;s have a realistic view, here. Calgary is the third or fourth largest city in Canada. We&#8217;re over a million people (we recently had our one millionth baby, but I suspect &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary Transit Sucks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was having a discussion with Doug down in the Bistro this morning, and I came to a rather interesting realization: Calgary Transit sucks.<br />
Let&#8217;s have a realistic view, here. Calgary is the third or fourth largest city in Canada. We&#8217;re over a million people (we recently had our one millionth baby, but I suspect we&#8217;re actually well over that number in population). We have a massive city by area because Calgary hasn&#8217;t quite figured out that we should be building up, not out.<br />
<span id="more-3535"></span>Calgary is attempting to address this fact by improving roads. Roads. As in expecting people to drive. Wow. There&#8217;s incentive to take public transit. Okay, in their defense, the C-Train will be up in the Northwest at Crowfoot Crossing in the next year or two. But not in the Northeast or in the effective places in the south, where the city is growing the fastest.<br />
The bus system is a joke. Some parts of the city are well-served. But overall, it&#8217;s far from what this city needs. Ottawa at least had the smarts to put in bus routes that use their own roads, where cars cannot go. Calgary can&#8217;t do that because the roads are already filled with cars carrying a single person. I know &#8212; I used to be one of them.<br />
A few months ago, I used to drive to work. Seven-odd kilometres one way. Fifteen minutes if I hit every light and got stuck behind slow people. I had a prime parking spot. It was everything I shouldn&#8217;t be doing. I live <strong>SEVEN</strong> kilometres from work. Why on earth would I drive? I decided in the spring to bike and bus. So far, the biking is going very well &#8212; I can get to work almost as fast as it took me to drive. Getting home takes a bit longer, but it&#8217;s mostly uphill.<br />
The bus is a different story. Although the #7 is actually pretty convenient in the morning, the afternoon is another issue. I&#8217;ve been passed by at the stop near my office several times because the bus was full. (There were a couple of cases where the bus simply didn&#8217;t show up.) The telephone schedule is wildly inaccurate because the bus never actually follows that schedule.<br />
The bus where I am is good compared to those poor folks who end up living on the outskirts of town. Bus service exists out there too, but the timing sucks. Somewhere, the person at Calgary Transit who sets the schedules needs to spend some time with the people who ride the bus and ask how it works for them. Based on all the people I&#8217;ve talked to, it&#8217;s not working.<br />
There are a series of express buses designed to help funnel people in from the outer ring. For these people, it can cut as much as 50% off their commute time. But it doesn&#8217;t come without a price. People have to start earlier and have to leave early or face a long ride to and from work. One of my co-workers, Colin, has to run out at 16:55 sharp every day or face the prospect of a long ride home because he&#8217;ll miss the last express. The last one. Not the last for an hour &#8230; the last of the day.<br />
<em>What Einstein doesn&#8217;t know that most offices actually close at 17:00?</em><br />
This baffles me beyond belief. Yes, some places in Calgary close earlier in the day, but not all of them. Many places are open until 17:00 or later. But too bad if you&#8217;re not one of the lucky few who actually close when Calgary Transit says you should. This insular ignorance of reality amazes me to no end. (The same problem exists with the West Coast Express in Vancouver. Vancouver runs more on the 9-5 workday than Calgary does!)<br />
And lest you think that I&#8217;m just some rambling idiot (which I very well may be), my friend Tom has piped in with his own thoughts:</p>
<blockquote><p>I figured moving to a company right downtown where the C-Train is close would be great. Not so. In order for me to catch the C-Train at the Dalhousie station, I have to be there before 06:40 just to get a parking spot. The Citadel bus (199) goes right past the Dalhousie station and feeds the Brentwood station. Where&#8217;s the logic in that? When the weather is nice, I get to ride my Hog-2-be to work (I double park in the bosses spot). Riding the bike takes 25 minutes from Citadel to downtown. Driving to Dalhousie and taking the train usually takes about 40 to 50 minutes. It costs in fuel for the bike $1.00 each way, transit &#8211; $2.25. Just to recap, when I can ride my bike, it takes half the time for less than half the price and I don&#8217;t need to squeeze myself on the homebound train, which of course is the last stop out of downtown going North West. Why in the world would I ever want to take Calgary Transit??? I am so looking forward to our company moving out of downtown and up on Centre street and 11th ave North in October where I will have my own parking spot and never have to rely on Calgary Transit again!</p></blockquote>
<p>Calgary has a 15 year plan to expand all the C-Train stations to add a fourth car to the trains. And eventually they&#8217;ll get enough cars to handle the load. Already the trains are packed tight. We&#8217;ll need to hire some Japanese pushers to get everyone in before too long. We don&#8217;t need longer trains in 15 years &#8212; we need more trains <strong>now</strong>. We need to double the number of trains, and then use those cars to expand the three-car trains to four-car trains in the future. We need to expand the C-Train route to the southwest to Westhills, the southeast to Mackenzie Town, the north west to Tuscany, the northeast (admittedly, I don&#8217;t know the area up there that well), and for God&#8217;s sake, can we please run the C-Train to the airport? Would it really kill someone to think that Calgary should have a <strong>single</strong> route from the airport to downtown? Or am I being grossly naive here?<br />
The bus routes, as Chris recently pointed out, are all undocumented. If you don&#8217;t live here, you have no idea where the bus is going or when it should come. It doesn&#8217;t take a lot of effort to put up schedules on the bus stops and put maps so people know where they&#8217;re going. Really smart bus companies show major routes so people know where to change to other routes. London has this figured out. Tokyo has it down to a science. Paris has it made. Honk Kong is a breeze. Calgary&#8217;s a frickin&#8217; disaster.<br />
And it costs a lot for the privilege, too. $2.25 by current prices. That doesn&#8217;t get you much. And Calgary Transit wonders why they&#8217;re losing money.<br />
Someone please wake up and check out the reality of the city&#8217;s transportation needs? We&#8217;re grossly behind compared to other cities, and if we have any hope at all of stemming the tide of cars driving in and out of downtown, we need some common sense helping set the direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>256</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3535</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2004 23:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/10/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day. And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind. Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Returning to Canada"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t even call this a &#8220;last day&#8221;. Yesterday, really, was our last day. Today is the packing/travelling day.<br />
And the day to say goodbye to dear friends. I hate leaving friends behind.<br />
<span id="more-348"></span>Chris is one of my dearest, closest friends. (Of course, you already know that.) When he moved to Japan almost two years ago, it hurt to have him leave. When Therese and Stuart moved to Montreal, it was hard to handle. But as I stood in the doorway of the train today, I looked back at my friend &#8212; my brother &#8212; and wondered when I will see him again.<br />
There is never enough time. Too many things happening, and too much distance separating us. I miss living with Chris. I miss the knowing glances and mouthed expressions we could give each other that conveyed meaning on a level only we knew.<br />
But such is life. Life is change, life is motion. It has to continue, lest life stop.<br />
Chris didn&#8217;t come to the airport with us, but Kaz was kind enough to guide us. When we arrived, we&#8217;d found that our flight time had changed. We had originally been booked for an 18:35 departure, but had been rescheduled for a 15:30 departure &#8230; or so I&#8217;d thought. The boards read a 17:15 departure, so I began to wonder if Air Canada had changed the times on us again, and not informed us. In retrospect, I think we&#8217;re okay, but I&#8217;m not 100% on that yet.<br />
Normally, a chance in flight times wouldn&#8217;t worry me. But I have to catch a flight in Calgary to take me to Kelowna, and I can&#8217;t afford to miss that flight. At the time, I started to worry. I had based my flight from Calgary on the changed (and perceived) time of 15:30. If we were now leaving Japan later, I might not make my Kelowna flight.<br />
Either way, we were at the airport far too early to determine what was going on, so it was just a matter of waiting. Putting the bags into storage (we had almost two hours to wait until we could check in), we went in search of lunch.<br />
One of the restaurants offered beef don, or a relative facsimile thereof. Jen was dying for beef, so this is where we went. Kaz and I had more traditional Japanese meals. It was a way of using up the remaining 2,000 yen I still had. (As it turns out, not such a wise move, since we had to pay to get the bags back, which was 1,500 yen.)<br />
We did a bit of shopping. Well, looking around, anyway. The only thing we really needed to buy still was a bottle of sake for Uncle Mike. But Terminal 2 really didn&#8217;t offer anything particularly interesting. And as we had time to kill, anyway, we went over to Terminal 1.<br />
I finally figured out why I&#8217;d been so disoriented when we arrived two weeks ago. Last year, I came in at Terminal 1 (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]), which I think is a lot nicer than Terminal 2. It was quite clear when we got close enough to see inside.<br />
We returned to Terminal 2 to check in. This is when we got another nasty bit of news: Jen and I were not sharing the same flight coming from Vancouver to Calgary. We had set it up that way so we didn&#8217;t have to worry about the flight. In fact, there supposedly weren&#8217;t any available seats at all on the flights and we didn&#8217;t really have reservations. I urged them to correct that sitation, but the best we could get was two flights over three hours apart. This is something I&#8217;ll have to sort out in Vancouver.<br />
Once checked in, we had to start heading to the flight. Kaz walked us to the security gate, where we had to say goodbye to her. Kaz and Jen had grown close (mostly as a result of yesterday&#8217;s rather interesting shopping spree). Kaz is my best friend&#8217;s wife. I don&#8217;t know her nearly as well as perhaps I should, but if she&#8217;s able to capture his heart, I know I will miss her as much as I miss him.<br />
The flight boarded only a few minutes later than scheduled, but far in advance of us departing the gate. The flight isn&#8217;t completely full, so is rather comfortable. Hopefully, the flight will be a short one, so we don&#8217;t have to sit down for too long.<br />
Jen and I chuckled a bit at the first movie. Not just because it is a funny movie, but because it was very appropriate for all the Japanese/English mishaps we&#8217;ve had throughout our trip.<br />
&#8220;Lost in Translation.&#8221;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
The plane arrived more or less on time. We hustled from the plane, bypassing many of the passengers (they were taking the escalators, we took the adjoining stairs) and getting into the immigration line. We had to go through Canadian Immigration in Vancouver before heading to Calgary.<br />
This was the only time &#8212; *only* time &#8212; throughout the entire trip that someone asked my relation to Jen in an official capacity. I had legal documents on me that stated that I was Jen&#8217;s legal guardian, but never had to show them to anyone. Even the clerk at Immigration didn&#8217;t ask to see them, but said that I might have to show them.<br />
I never had to.<br />
We had to collect our bags and go through Customs (which amounted to them taking our form of Declaration, not even saying &#8220;thank you&#8221;) and check them in again for our connecting flight.<br />
It was the connecting flight that was a bit of an issue. As you might recall, we found out at Narita airport that Jen and I were not on the same flight. This had me mildy irked, because we were supposed to be on the same flight. It&#8217;s not that I didn&#8217;t trust Jen to get back to Calgary on her own, but I was supposed to be her legal guardian, and wanted to make sure she got back to her parents.<br />
Fortunately, the flight I was on was not completely full, and the Air Canada clerk was reasonably certain that Jen would be able to get on the flight. She set Jen up as stand-by, and even checked her bag to Calgary (so even if Jen didn&#8217;t make it, her bag would). With that, we went off to our gate.<br />
I got pulled over at security again. I always seem to get pulled over in North America. It&#8217;s all my freaking electronics. Japan didn&#8217;t care. Maybe they&#8217;ve got better technology. I mean, they&#8217;ve got vending machines that will take bills upside down, backwards, and probably crumpled beyond recognition. They&#8217;ve gotta have better scanning machines than we do.<br />
At the gate, after giving the clerk a few minutes, we asked if Jen could get on the flight, and if it was possible if we could sit together. The clerk, originally seeming a little harsh, turned out to be quite congenial, and settled our last hurdle quite easily.<br />
At that point, I called Aunt Brenda. (I had my cell phone with me for in-Canada communications upon my return.) I let her know we were on the 12:00 (PST) flight from Vancouver, getting into Calgary around 14:30. She was quite happy to hear we&#8217;d be home soon, and said she&#8217;d meet us there.<br />
The flight was quite hot. Unlike our A340 plane, our little A320 was quite warm, even with the air vents cranked all the way open. But it didn&#8217;t really matter. Soon, we&#8217;d be at home. Thankfully, the flight went quickly (that happens when you sleep for half of it &#8230; or all of it, in Jen&#8217;s case), and soon we were exiting Gate A to the awaiting arms of Uncle Mike, Aunt Brenda, and Nana.<br />
Now, you&#8217;d think at this point that I&#8217;d be somewhat relieved to unload the responsibility for handling Jen back to her parents, right? Not really. It was at that point that I realized that Jen hadn&#8217;t really been that hard to handle. Aside from having to curb her manga-buying sprees, and encouraging her to see more things (which was more trouble than I would have thought), she was very easy to get along with. But then, we already had a good relationship.<br />
Jen immediately became a chatterbox, telling Brenda and Nana about the trip &#8212; almost entirely randomly-selected portions &#8212; while Mike and I exchanged a few thoughts about my perspective. All this while waiting for the bags to come out. Then it was back to their place to unload.<br />
Now, dear reader, this is where this tale should end. But it doesn&#8217;t. While Jen&#8217;s journey was over, mine still had a bit left to it. I had another flight to catch. I&#8217;m now in Kelowna. Why would I be coming to Kelowna? Two words:<br />
David Bowie.<br />
Remember when I said that if David Bowie was returning to Canada anytime soon that I&#8217;d go to see him? (See [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]].) I wasn&#8217;t kidding. A couple of months ago, during my only sick day of the year (so far, anyway), Tamara had burst into my room in a near state of ecstacy because David Bowie was playing in Kelowna. In an auditorium that holds only 5,000 people.<br />
Naturally, we were going.<br />
This was after I&#8217;d booked my flights to Japan and back, and had Jen booked in. This meant I had to catch another flight from Calgary to Kelowna. With WestJet, not a particularly huge deal. (The flight cost about as much as the ticket to David Bowie, at least before adding on all those ridiculous taxes.)<br />
I passed out in my chair on the plane (an aisle seat) mere moments after doing up my seat belt. I vaguely remember the word &#8220;juice&#8221;, and awoke only when the plane slapped the tarmac at Kelowna. I dozed until the plane finally stopped. I was soon met by my roommate Tamara, her boyfriend Dan, and her friend Andrea. (They&#8217;d driven out earlier in the day.)<br />
Our first stop was the White Spot, a BC-favourite for restaurants. Not one of mine (don&#8217;t really care for the place), but it was food and it was cheap. That was enough for me. Then it was to the hotel (the Royal Anne Hotel, situated in beautiful downtown Kelowna, a mere block from the lake, and four blocks from Prospera Place, the site for tomorrow&#8217;s David Bowie concert) to dump the bags.<br />
We went bar-hopping, in search of something fairly decent. The sad part is that most of Kelowna&#8217;s downtown has either really seedy biker bars (read: strip clubs, and we all know how much I like those places) or yuppie pubs. We weren&#8217;t thrilled by any of them. We finally gave up around 21:00 and went back to the hotel.<br />
I shaved off two weeks&#8217; worth of beard (much to my delight &#8212; the damn thing was driving me crazy) while Tamara and Andrea watched &#8220;Princess Bride&#8221; on the TV. Dan had already passed out. The four of us were asleep before the movie was over (and we only came in halfway-through).<br />
God knows I needed the rest.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-yotsukaido-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">348</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2004 22:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/26/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept like crap. And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh? It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Flying to Japan"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept like crap.<br />
And it wasn&#8217;t because I slept on the couch at Aunt Brenda and Uncle Mike&#8217;s last night. I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s because of stress. Kind of ironic to have this crop up the night before I leave on vacation, eh?<br />
<span id="more-333"></span>It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not traveling alone. But I&#8217;m not just Jen&#8217;s travel companion, I&#8217;m Jen&#8217;s legal guardian for the next two weeks (I&#8217;ve got the documents to prove it). I&#8217;m responsible for her safety, her well-being, and certainly to some extent, her life. I have to make sure that all is taken care of so there&#8217;s little concern about what will happen or where we will go.<br />
The Kyoto guest house worries me a bit. The map I have isn&#8217;t horribly clear. I&#8217;ll have the chance to review the map when we get to Chris&#8217; place later &#8220;today&#8221;. But there&#8217;s also the cell phone that I supposedly reserved, but never received confirmation on. I hope we can get that, because it will be very handy for communication. That, and I&#8217;d hate to get charged for something I never got to use.<br />
Getting to Chris&#8217; is actually the least of my worries. Even though Chris was generous in sending me a &#8220;refresher&#8221; map to guide me around Yotsukaido (Chris won&#8217;t be meeting us when we get there &#8212; he&#8217;ll already be off to Toyohashi), I&#8217;m pretty sure of my memory of the area. Then it&#8217;s just a matter of catching the correct trains on Saturday to get us to Tokyo, then to Toyohashi, on time so we can catch a shuttle bus.<br />
I think once I&#8217;m in Toyohashi, I can relax a bit.<br />
Although I was awake before 6:00 this morning, I didn&#8217;t rise until 6:30. I proceeded to shower and dress, while Brenda made us all breakfast. Maggie (the dalmatian) was going insane &#8212; she knew something was up because of the activity and the bags being packed. Fried eggs, sausages, hashbrowns, and cheese bread toast.<br />
Then it was off to the airport. Brenda drove, Mike ran shotgun, while Jen and I sat in the back. It was a quiet ride up. There seemed to be a lot of anxiety in the car. Not that I noticed &#8212; I was telling myself over and over that this wasn&#8217;t a big deal, and being responsible for more than just myself was not a problem.<br />
Sooner or later, I hope to start believing it.<br />
Security was an issue. Normally, I breeze through it. Every so often, they ask to turn on my camera or start my Minidisc player. But this time, I&#8217;m carrying wedding presents for Chris and Kaz from friends back home. I had packed a few of them in my carry-on. And that&#8217;s what they wanted to look at.<br />
Specifically, it was the juicer that Karen and Mark were sending. It had never dawned on me that it could be a problem. It was extremely light, so I figured it was plastic. But what about blades, or some moving part? I hadn&#8217;t actually <em>seen</em> the juicer &#8212; Karen and Mark had already wrapped it. But security wanted to. I had to open it.<br />
My hands were shaking. I couldn&#8217;t let them confiscate it. I <em>needed</em> to take this, and had no-one else who could get it from me. For a moment, I forgot about Jen.<br />
I realized quickly why security wanted to see this thing. Although it had no moving parts or &#8220;sharp&#8221; edges, the outline on the x-ray machine really must&#8217;ve set off some alarms. It&#8217;s shaped like a tripod: three legs that rise not quite vertically, in a slight curve, towards a central node. The node rises from the union of the three legs to a roughly egg-shaped and -sized pod. The pod has the grooves common with hand-operated juicers. The whole thing is one-piece aluminium. And thankfully, not a threat.<br />
With that, we headed to the gate to wait for our plane to arrive, deboard, restock, and for us to get on. While we left a little late, our arrival in Vancouver should be roughly on time.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
We&#8217;ve about five hours to go before we land at Narita. So far, we&#8217;ve had lunch (ravioli), watched one movie (&#8220;Master and Commander&#8221;) and are most of the way through a second (the classic &#8220;Roman Holiday&#8221;, with Gregory Peck and Audrey Hepburn). I fell asleep not far into the second movie, owning to what I can only describe as sudden, inescapable exhaustion.<br />
But it&#8217;s what I needed. Earlier, I was stressed out. I wasn&#8217;t rested, I wasn&#8217;t ready. I wasn&#8217;t looking forward to arriving in Japan. You could almost say I was scared.<br />
Not now. I&#8217;m looking forward to it. I think the nap was all I needed. I&#8217;m awake, alert, and eager. This is going to be fun. Best part is, the usual headwind going in this direction isn&#8217;t as strong, so we&#8217;re moving at a faster clip than usual, arriving about a half hour earlier. This is a good thing.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if Jen is excited or terrified. Apparently, she was talking her head off yesterday, repeatedly saying she wasn&#8217;t excited. (Riiiiight.) Jen&#8217;s been pretty quiet, though. Her usual half-giddiness is almost non-existent, and hasn&#8217;t said much since we left the house earlier this morning. She claims she&#8217;ll be excited once we get there. We&#8217;ll see.<br />
A little under five hours to go&#8230;<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Our flight arrived even earlier than predicted, which was fine with me. It was good to get off the plane &#8212; my back was beginning to give me some trouble, and my feet were dying to be used. Sitting down for nine and a half hours really isn&#8217;t my cup of tea.<br />
We came in at a different point in the airport than I had come into last year (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]) &#8212; a completely separate building for Terminal 2. (This is a really flipping huge airport.) We even had to take a short shuttle ride from one building to the next.<br />
Immigration was about the same as last year, but a little quicker. This time, I didn&#8217;t have to explain myself to the clerk. I had the immigration form filled out correctly, so there was no questions about what I was doing. Jen passed through with equally as little trouble.<br />
Customs was a little more trouble than I would have liked (the clerk wanted to look at a few too many things in my duffle bag), but we passed through again without much affair.<br />
And before we knew it, we were in Japan. There were three things I needed to do before we left for Yotsukaido: Get more money from the Post Office ATM, pick up the rented cell phone, and pick up our rail passes.<br />
The Post Office was easy &#8212; I vaguely knew were it was. The desk for G-Call (the company we were renting the cell phone from) was a little harder to find. The information desk didn&#8217;t quite understand, so we ended up on the third floor before being directed to the first floor. But we found the place. The clerk spoke just enough English to understand most of what I was asking, but not enough for me to understand him.<br />
It&#8217;s amazing what you can communicate with hand gestures.<br />
Cell phone in hand, we then went to the JR Office to get our passes. Took a little while (the people in front of us were very good at monopolizing time), which was fine, as we&#8217;d missed the 16:04 train to Yotsukaido, anyway. As soon as we&#8217;d done that, Jen promptly proceeded to lose her mind.<br />
Jen had spotted a couple of the infamous Japanese vending machines while we were running the quick errands. Now she was in full vending machine glory. She had to personally inspect each and every machine in sight. She kept apologizing for the exuberant (if perhaps a bit odd) behaviour. No big deal as far as I was concerned &#8212; it was all a good laugh for me.<br />
I went through the same thing last year.<br />
Jen immediately bought a can of hot tea, which she found to her surprise (and partial dismay) to be actually hot. (It was very warm, but not discomforting.) Can in hand, we headed off in search of a train.<br />
The JR platform was, in stereotypical Japanese fashion, spotless. Jen was thoroughly fascinated by this. But no more so with the continued abdunance of vending machines. By the time we got on the train at 17:04, she had four cans, one of which was mine.<br />
The trip to Yotsukaido was fairly easy. Upon arrival, we headed over to the Yotsukaido ALS school (where Chris works) to grab a key for his apartment. After a quick conversation with his coworkers, Jen and I were off to the apartment.<br />
Chris called while Jen was showering. He suggested I call Tony and make arrangements to get together with him the following day for our trip down to Toyohashi. Made sense to me. So while Jen dried and dressed, Tony and I worked out a couple of details for tomorrow.<br />
The next order of business? Food. We needed food. Luckily, I know where the Mos Burger is around here, thanks to Kaz showing me the first night I came to Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]). Jen had a hamburger.<br />
Hey, at least it wasn&#8217;t McDonald&#8217;s!<br />
Home again (following a quick run to 7-11 for green tea ice cream), we settled down for a well-deserved rest. Not counting a couple of cat naps on the plane, we haven&#8217;t slept in almost 24 hours. Hopefully, jet lag won&#8217;t be a big deal this time around.<br />
It&#8217;s good to be back.<br />
[flickr]tag:narita+march+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-calgary-yotsukaido/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
