<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>television &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/television/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>TV is dead. Long live the internet!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 03:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyrights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TV is dead. Long live the internet!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like an old man. I can now look at my kids, and say with far too much vigour: &#8220;When I was your age&#8230;&#8221; I refer to, of course, having to get off my ass, walking over to the cathode ray tube-based television set, change the dial to UHF, and move the oversized dial that changed the direction of the UHF antenna&#8230;<br />
I&#8217;ve lost you, haven&#8217;t I? I shudder to think how few of you have an <em>inkling</em> of what I&#8217;m talking about. Yeah, that&#8217;s how old I am. I remember when there were only a handful of channels, when almost all of the content was on ABC, NBC, CBS, CBC, CTV, Global, and a few independent stations (such as the awesome CityTV and the the extremely nacent Fox). I remember the introduction of cable. I remember having to wait for the summer reruns because I missed that crucial episode of <em>The A Team</em> that everyone was talking about in class the next morning. I remember when the season debuts were a big thing. I remember when missing a live televised event was significant, because it was gone forever.<br />
It seems somehow just as bizarre a concept as the Spanish Inquisition.<br />
<span id="more-3076"></span>Up until a few years ago, this model was still fairly static. Despite the massive influx of cable, the ridiculous proliferation of specialty channels (seriously, I cannot fathom how some of them make any money), Youtube, Torrents, and the like, the concept of &#8220;television&#8221; hadn&#8217;t really changed. You still relied on the networks. Waiting for the most recent <em>Survivor</em> was still a big thing. And people watched the evening news.<br />
In the last 24-30 months, however, I&#8217;ve seen a massive shift in service. The <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/research/2010/01/the-itunes-effect-and-the-futu.html">iTunes Effect</a> completely altered the way that we consume music (despite the music industry continually trying to roll the clock back as if nothing ever happened), and it&#8217;s echoed into the way we consume video. And I choose that word very carefully: <em>video.</em> Not &#8220;television&#8221;, not &#8220;movies&#8221;. The length of a given item, or its relevance to a related group of videos (say, a television series of yore, or a trilogy of films) is largely irrelevant. Thanks to devices such as DVRs, tablets, Boxees, Apple TVs, and so forth, we can consume video on our own terms, and not at those of the telecommunications companies to whom we enslaved ourselves for over five decades.<br />
A month and a half ago, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2012/03/upstairs-reno-the-fun-begins/">my family moved out of our home</a> so the kitchen renovation could begin in earnest. When we did that, we took our living room video display (I now loathe to call it a &#8220;TV set&#8221;) and the Apple TV so we could watch, well, <em>something</em>. For three weeks, all we had were whatever videos were on the Apple TV &#8212; we had no network connection to speak of, so no new videos during that time.<br />
When we got back into our home, the living room was far from any suitable state to be able to hook our video displays back up to the television display boxes. No TV. (In fact, hardly any video at all.) At the end of a month and a half, it&#8217;s hard for us to really &#8220;miss&#8221; television at all.<br />
We had Telus Optik. It was a decent service, and the only real complaint I had with it was that we had about 180 channels more than we watched. There were four on any form of rotation: Discovery (for my <em>MythBusters</em> fix), Treehouse (for the kids&#8217; shows), whatever channel showed <em>Greys Anatomy</em>, and one or two other channels were in the mix for a few things. But that was it. No kidding. No joke. We paid $80 to watch less than a half dozen things.<br />
Yesterday, I pulled the plug (not <em>completely</em>, mind you &#8212; I rather stupidly signed up for a three year contract, thinking this blog post was still quite a ways away; the account is in &#8220;suspension&#8221; for $5/month, though it counts towards the contract term), and we started onto a new path: internet-only content.<br />
We are far from the first to do this. I have several friends who cut their cable a while ago, and have sufficed quite well off of whatever they could glean from the internet. iTunes has been a major source of material, as has the ubiquitous YouTube. Many have turned to the less-legal Torrents to acquire television shows and movies, while others have looked to online services such as Netflix.<br />
My problem with the internet aspect until recently was twofold: fragmentation, and accessibility. There&#8217;s a lot of different venues in which to find the content one might want to watch &#8212; think of it as having two constantly criss-cross a typical urban mega-strip mall on an erratic shopping spree, rather than being able to go to a single store and finding all that you need. And then it&#8217;s an issue where you go to a given store expecting to find the very shirt your American friend told you about, but despite it being an American clothier, that specific shirt isn&#8217;t available in Canada. (Canada remains, frustratingly, a digital backwater when it comes to internet content.)<br />
So what&#8217;s changed? Aside from the realization that we just don&#8217;t watch regular television anymore, it was the introduction of a &#8220;content aggregator&#8221; (not sure what else to call it), some handy (but legally grey-area) tools, and the ability to be a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing. Allow me to introduce our new media setup&#8230;</p>
<h2>The Device</h2>
<p>Ultimately, you need a unit to actually serve content (the stuff &#8212; literally &#8212; doesn&#8217;t fly through the air, anymore). The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_TV#Apple_TV_First_Generation">Apple TV (version 1)</a> had been a decent first attempt, but it failed in a number of ways, not the least of which was a strong tie to iTunes and not a lot of expandability (even the <a href="http://firecore.com/atvflash">aTV Flash</a> hack offered little more). It meant that it was hard for us to use different media sources, or even watch DVDs through a single device.<br />
Enter the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mac_Mini">mid-2010 Apple Mac Mini, model A1347 (non-server)</a>. Slightly taller than the Apple TV, this is a complete computer, and can run any software we need. Furthermore, it has full support for 1080p video, complete audio support, and because it&#8217;s a full computer, it can be used by Monkey and Choo Choo as they grow up and need to use computers in their school (while Mommy and I get to help/watch). Even more key for this specific release of the Mac Mini, however, is that this is the last one that came with a SuperDrive built-in &#8212; the next release was without an optical drive, making it hard to watch those reams of physical media we&#8217;ve been accumulating.<br />
The Mac Mini is limited to 320 GB, which seems like a lot, but it&#8217;ll fill up quickly with the media we hope to deliver through it. So instead, I&#8217;m going to be attaching it to a terabyte drive (ideally a RAIDed one, with a secondary backup for real redundancy) that will store all the music, movies, photos, and various videos that our family will use. Our network is gigabit (thanks to Telus), so network speed shouldn&#8217;t be a problem.</p>
<h2>The Software</h2>
<p>Operating system aside, the complete list is still pending, but I&#8217;m looking at:</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Duh. We have a significant amount of content in iTunes, and there is zero reason not to use iTunes to access it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plexapp.com/">Plex Server</a><br />
This is the aggregation tool. It offers a significant amount of functionality for linking disparate pieces of content (including iTunes) into a single interface, and offers a variety of &#8220;channels&#8221; for watching online content. Because it works full-screen, it&#8217;s a suitable replacement for the venerable Front Row. It also includes a player that can play software copies of DVDs&#8230;</li>
<li><a href="http://thelittleappfactory.com/ripit/">RipIt</a><br />
Boy, it didn&#8217;t take long to get back into that legal black hole, didn&#8217;t it? Yes, I am using a piece of software to extract the content from media I have purchased and am placing it in a non-public system for my own personal entertainment, digital lock provisions be damned. Big Media pushing bullshit like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">SOPA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_Canada">C-11</a> can <a href="http://www.freshnewsound.org/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/johnny_cash.jpg">suck my balls</a>. I don&#8217;t like physical media, it&#8217;s too prone to damage by jam-covered fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, we will install what&#8217;s needed, when it&#8217;s needed. Right now, I&#8217;m not sure what that is, but I&#8217;m sure we can adapt when the time comes.</p>
<h2>The Services</h2>
<p>The hardware and software alone will not solve our problems. It&#8217;s not really any different than buying a &#8220;regular&#8221; television set. The problem is that you still need to have content provided from <em>somewhere</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>iTunes<br />
Again, duh. Our existing library is one thing, but iTunes still has an extensive (and lovely) collection of media from which to select. We&#8217;ve used iTunes for quite some time, and plan to keep using it.</li>
<li><a href="http://goo.gl/EY0O4">The Service I Can&#8217;t Really Talk About</a><br />
Okay, this is another one of those &#8220;grey area&#8221; items. Technically, Canadians can&#8217;t see American content (think Hulu, American versions of Netflix and iTunes, and Comedy Network) because some dumbass decided that we&#8217;re not allowed to see it. So our IP blocks are scanned and summarily blocked. This service makes you look like an American &#8212; a sheep in wolf&#8217;s clothing &#8212; and away you go. It&#8217;s not illegal, but I&#8217;m sure that some moron lawyer will cry foul (because he&#8217;s paid to do so) and it&#8217;ll get yanked. Hence, I refuse to name it. Like Plex, it also provides a number of channels, so we should be able to watch &#8230; well, pretty much anything we want, really.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.netflix.ca">Netflix</a> (the American verison!)<br />
My biggest gripe with Netflix is that the Canadian content is so wildly different than the American content &#8230; despite it running off the same system. So thanks to the aforementioned service, we get the added benefit of a larger library.</li>
</ul>
<div>Okay, what about live television? Say I want to watch the hockey game, or even the Olympics? Well, this is where the Mac Mini comes to the rescue again. Because it&#8217;s a full computer, it has a full browser (and various necessary plugins) so that we can visit a website and watch live feeds. Perfect? Probably not, but at least it&#8217;s better than channel surfing.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>The Result</h2>
<p>To be honest, I don&#8217;t know yet. From everything I&#8217;ve read and from everything everyone who&#8217;s already gone down this road has told me, this seems like a solid path. But I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that it won&#8217;t be a bed of roses (and, really, when you think about it, is a &#8220;bed of roses&#8221; all that appealing? Think of the thorns!) and this could fail. I doubt it will fail entirely, since we get content no matter what, it&#8217;s just the depth at which we get it.<br />
So what of actual &#8220;television&#8221;? We&#8217;re in the shift now, and already it&#8217;s showing. Advertisers are trying to find new ways to market to people who are willingly skipping commercials. Big Media is slow to adapt (surprise, surprise!), but is at least starting to recognise the revenue potential, so it&#8217;s doubtful they&#8217;ll fight against it. But the transition from network model (which provides funding and marketing for television shows) is at risk, given a more fragmented market.<br />
For us, this can only be a win-win. People want to make video, and we want to consume it. The question of <em>how</em> remains, and its only a matter of time before these bits of technology-in-infancy are replaced by more robust and &#8220;complete&#8221; systems that hide the mess of aggregation, bringing about a true &#8220;on demand&#8221; environment that has been promised for the better part of 20 years.<br />
As for our specific experience, we&#8217;ll keep you posted. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve got a Mac Mini to set up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/tv-is-dead-long-live-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3076</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Switching from Shaw to Telus</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=switching-from-shaw-to-telus</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For those of you not already following the story, I&#8217;ve sworn off Shaw. As much as I am tied &#8212; nay, symbiotically attached &#8212; to the internet, I would have been quite willing to end the service at home with the continued lack of service I was receiving from Shaw. It was past &#8220;infuriating&#8221;, past &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Switching from Shaw to Telus"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For those of you not already following the story, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/09/from-the-frying-pan/">I&#8217;ve sworn off Shaw</a>. As much as I am tied &#8212; nay, symbiotically attached &#8212; to the internet, I would have been quite willing to end the service at home with the continued lack of service I was receiving from Shaw. It was past &#8220;infuriating&#8221;, past &#8220;mind-bendingly torturous&#8221;, and I was way passed &#8220;pissed off&#8221;. We had to move, or I could have possibly killed someone. Consider that move a public service, folks.<br />
We moved to Telus. Not solely because they&#8217;re really the only other option in town, but partly because the new Optik service had proved highly appealing (nicer interface, and free PVR with long-term contract), and a very lucrative introductory offer combined with Shaw&#8217;s epic failure really cinched the deal.<br />
Not that it&#8217;s gone completely flawlessly&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2773"></span>If you followed the link above, you&#8217;ve already read that the install didn&#8217;t go according to plan. In fact, thanks to Telus&#8217; internal systems, it didn&#8217;t go at all. Telus was almost painfully apologetic about the incident, and has made strides to make up for the oversight. Nearly a month after calling, they did finally arrive, on the 29th, to set us up with brand-new service.<br />
The installer, Glenn, arrived just after 9:00 and proceeded to make sure he knew where everything was, notably the TVs, and the Telus phone panel. The TVs, easy to find. The panel? Not so much. Over the course of renovating the basement and a year and a half abroad, our phone panel had gone <em>missing</em>. And, equally inexplicable, the Telus line outside the house was completely cut. (We had a second cable, yes, but apparently both were Shaw &#8212; Shaw told us one was Telus.)<br />
Glenn had to run all-new wiring, which I viewed as a good thing. Sadly, for simplicity&#8217;s sake, it also meant running along the wall outside, since there was no easy way for it to enter the house where the Shaw line went in. It&#8217;ll be something we can live with for the time being, and when we do proper renovations upstairs, we&#8217;ll move it.<br />
Once inside, Glenn set to work removing the Shaw hardware (which is headed back to Shaw tomorrow &#8212; I wanted to wait a bit, and you&#8217;ll see why in a moment), and hooked up the DSL router (quite literally, a black box) and the Telus wireless router (a special one that allows TV signals to be routed as well). He then set up the PVR in the living room, and the set-top box in the bedroom. The two are networked via the cable and the wireless router (though I can&#8217;t see them on the network &#8212; the HDPA part of the network is invisible, sadly).<br />
Telus quoted four hours. Glenn was done in under three. Barely before he was out the door, I&#8217;d already set up the PVR to start recording every episode of <em>MythBusters</em> and <em>Dirty Jobs</em>. I also lobbed in a setting to start recording some of Monkey&#8217;s favourites, the ones Alex and I use when we need 30 minutes of peace.<br />
In theory, this should have been the ultimate end of Shaw. But knowing my luck, I opted to hang onto the Shaw stuff, just in case something else went wrong.<br />
Which it did.<br />
Two days after install. Suddenly, the TV and internet signals were gone. (The phone, now a hard-wired landline, continued unabated.) Alex called Telus, and after a short wait, was told to reboot both the DSL box and the wireless router. Boom, TV and internet were back.<br />
Problem solved, right?<br />
Sunday evening, same thing. Rebooted both DSL and router again, without calling Telus, and all was well. One time, I could understand. Two was beginning to look like a pattern. I swore that if it happened once more, I was calling Telus. Which I did, on Monday evening.<br />
I was talking to a human within five minutes. The problem was already flagged in their system as &#8220;reoccurring&#8221;, which apparently immediately afforded me a lot of attention. The first tech (yes, <em>first</em>) and I went over the scenario, and reset the system before he transferred me (and did the introductions) to the next guy, who worked with the hardware group. We proceeded to check the router settings and make sure that it wasn&#8217;t the problem.<br />
Which, he felt, it might be. Here&#8217;s where the Telus setup has a flaw: unlike Shaw, where you provide your own internal router, Telus has to provide one in order to deliver the TV service. The router, made by D-Link, has custom firmware to allow all the fancy stuff (namely the TV signals embedded in the DSL channels, and the PVR network). Part of that requires a bridging of wireless and wired networks. In theory, this is transparent to the user, and you&#8217;d never know. <em>In theory.</em> In reality, there&#8217;s a weird behaviour where wireless devices (notably Apple devices) are unable to see wired devices. Sort of like, say, an Apple TV trying to wirelessly sync with a wired computer.<br />
I discovered this through the wonders of the internet a few nights earlier, after I became unable to sync the Apple TV. This drove me to re-enable my Linksys router to serve the Apple TV, and routed the desktop computer appropriately. Boom, problem solved. But the second tech thought this could actually be a problem, where the two wireless routers were now fighting, and the Telus router might hiccup and hang. Odd, yes, but D-Link stuff (at least in my experience) has always been a bit &#8220;odd&#8221;, so I wasn&#8217;t surprised.<br />
Telus wireless disabled, and we moved on in life. Which meant tech #3, who worked in the networking group. He wanted to send out a tech to verify that the lines were okay. He felt it might be an issue. Seemed perfectly fine to me, so we set up an appointment. Total call time? Nearly 90 minutes. Very little of it on hold. I&#8217;ve been on short calls that had me really, really angry. After 90 minutes, you&#8217;d think someone had just given me a million dollars, I was so happy.<br />
Now I should point out that Glenn actually left us his card, with instructions to call if there were issues. In my (crappy) defence, I saw that only as a nice token, and that real work wouldn&#8217;t get done unless I called Telus. This was, after all, how Shaw has treated me for the last nine months &#8212; why should Telus be any different, right?<br />
J.P., the next service tech, came out and looked the place over. He did a couple of trivial things, checked the lines (and spent an hour doing so), and all seemed to be well. Emphasis on &#8220;seemed&#8221;. Sure enough, boom, the TV and internet dropped again. We tried calling J.P., but for some reason, we could never connect. Fortunately, Telus was very nice to set up a call for Saturday. Lo and behold, Glenn came to the door.<br />
Glenn was fairly well-briefed with the situation, and having already been to the house, was familiar with the setup. His thought? The card at the other end &#8212; the part that our line eventually plugs into to access the Telus network. He swapped it, and that was pretty much it. In my view, this makes sense &#8212; it was the DSL modem locking up, and if it was losing sync with the network because the card was faulty, it would explain why we were having trouble.  That was almost five days ago, and we haven&#8217;t had a single issue since.<br />
And because so many people have asked, here&#8217;s how I net out Telus&#8217;s offering thus far:<br />
<strong>TV</strong>: Mildly irritated that I have to get the next package up to get my <em>MythBusters</em>, but the extra channels are kinda nice. The ability to search for a TV show is the killer app, here, and the only real improvement would be to allow recording for a given show across any channel, not just one.<br />
<strong>Internet</strong>: Po-tay-toe, pah-tah-toe &#8212; roughly the same as Shaw, and I&#8217;m in no screaming need for insanely fast internet. I just don&#8217;t (ab)use it enough at home to need it. 15 down, 1 up is plenty for my needs.<br />
<strong>Phone</strong>: Landline. Enough said.<br />
<strong>Service</strong>: Here&#8217;s the real deal-breaker, kids. So far, Telus is <em>lightyears</em> beyond what Shaw had offered me. They&#8217;ve actually reestablished my faith in the telecommunications industry, and make me feel like they&#8217;re listening to my concerns and have a <em>genuine</em> interest in repairing my problems. The issues cropped up two days after install, and were resolved just over a week later (I hope). Telus&#8217;s staff have treated me with dignity, kindness, and respect (even talking techie with me once they realise that I do know what I&#8217;m talking about), and have been very good with promptness and callbacks. And the two-hour window (opposed to Shaw&#8217;s five-hour window) makes planning life a lot easier.<br />
So far, I&#8217;m glad we switched. I hope it stays that way&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/10/switching-from-shaw-to-telus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2773</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
