<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>concerts &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/concerts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 05:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>My Hip Stories</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-hip-stories</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 05:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3529</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In two days, I&#8217;m going to see The Tragically Hip play at the Saddledome. I will freely admit that, somewhat stereotypically Canadian of me, The Hip is my favourite band. So I will also state that I&#8217;m excited to see them play. However, I&#8217;m also somewhat dreading it, too. It&#8217;ll be the last time I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "My Hip Stories"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In two days, I&#8217;m going to see The Tragically Hip play at the Saddledome. I will freely admit that, somewhat stereotypically Canadian of me, The Hip is my favourite band. So I will also state that I&#8217;m excited to see them play. However, I&#8217;m also somewhat dreading it, too. It&#8217;ll be the last time I see them live, in person. It&#8217;s their final tour.<br />
Not all Canadians care. I don&#8217;t know how many do (I&#8217;ll optimistically suggest 40%), but a few of us are more passionate. But it&#8217;s not because we&#8217;re that passionate about the band per se, it&#8217;s more about how The Tragically Hip have affected our lives (past and/or present), to the point where we have defined stories that involve or revolve around them.<br />
Here&#8217;s mine&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3529"></span></p>
<h2>My First Hip</h2>
<p>I can&#8217;t tell you the date, but I can definitely tell you the year: 1991. And I can tell you the place: Dave Begg&#8217;s parents&#8217; house, where he was hosting a classic &#8220;high school house party&#8221;. I believe it was later in the year, as I do recall university being a factor, and all of us had graduated high school in spring of that year. We were energetic, naive, enjoying our first years beyond the households we&#8217;d been nurtured within, defining ourselves as individuals &#8230; well, when you&#8217;re fresh to university, you think freely, right?<br />
Anyway, this particular party, I was admiring Dave&#8217;s capacity to down copious amounts of beer with the only apparent effect being the colour of his cheeks. (Though nearly all of us were 19 and legally allowed to drink, I would not start drinking for another four years.) We were all chatting, laughing, not really reminiscing high school yet (we wouldn&#8217;t yet learn how sublime high school was compared to the pressures and stress of the Real World<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> beyond), and vaguely listening to the CD playing loudly in the stereo.<br />
I&#8217;m attracted to music. Today, in the present, I will freely admit that music can distract me so much that I find it difficult to have conversations with people right in front of me when there&#8217;s music I wish to listen to. But even then, in my youthful ability to do a thousand things at once, I found myself paying close attention to the song I heard: <em>Cordelia</em>.<br />
By that point, like anyone who listened to rock on the radio, we knew of The Hip. <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em>,<em> Blow At High Dough</em>, and <em>38 Years Old</em> were already well-known from The Hip&#8217;s second album. By the time of the party, <em>Little Bones</em>, <em>Twist My Arm</em>, and <em>Three Pistols</em> had all received sufficient CanCon airtime to enter into our &#8220;oh yeah, I&#8217;ve heard that before&#8221; catalogues. <em>Cordelia </em>hit me rather suddenly:</p>
<blockquote><p>Angst on the planks, spitting from a bridge<br />
Just to see how far down it really is</p></blockquote>
<p>Those are the opening lines. They don&#8217;t seem like much, but having read Margaret Atwood&#8217;s <em>Cat&#8217;s Eye</em> earlier in the year (for one of my high school English classes), the scene of the novel&#8217;s protagonist standing on a bridge with her friend Cordelia, acting out that very motion, suddenly rang with me. (For the record, I&#8217;ve always believed that <em>Cordelia</em> references <em>Cat&#8217;s Eye</em>; I also suspect I&#8217;m the only person who believes that.)<br />
I paid much closer attention to the album after that, since no-one bothered to replace it with anything else, so it just kept playing. Though it was nascent, it was that night I became a fan of The Tragically Hip.</p>
<h2>Midnight Release</h2>
<p>By the time <em>Fully Completely</em> came to existence barely a year later, The Hip had gone from being merely known to more of a household name. So much so that, for the first time that I&#8217;d ever heard of it, their album would be released for sale at midnight on 6 October 1992.<br />
I was attending the University of Waterloo. Just a block to the east of the campus, at 150 University Drive (where it meets Phillip Street), was an HMV (I think it&#8217;s now a Burger King). It was a store I knew well, but generally didn&#8217;t frequent (CDs started at $20 back in those days, and university students generally were on tight budgets). But that night, easily a hundred like-minded people joined the line to be among the first in Canada to get their hands on the new Hip album.<br />
Twenty-four years on, it&#8217;s hard to remember details, but I do remember the store being smart enough to have stacks of the discs ready to roll, and the cashiers ready to roll them out as quickly as possible. The album was playing over the speakers, which gave us the sample of what we were about to listen to as soon as we could get back to our respective holes in the wall.<br />
At the time, I was living at the University&#8217;s Columbia Lake Townhouses, a student &#8220;community&#8221; on the northwest corner of the University&#8217;s land, a series of buildings that generally felt like they&#8217;d been assembled <em>by </em>students, with all the attention to detail one would expect. Though my memory is a bit faded, I&#8217;m fairly certain I walked (I don&#8217;t recall having a car at the time, but I&#8217;ve been known to be wrong before.) It was 2.5 km straight-line distance to my stereo.<br />
It was a $500 special my dad had helped me buy some years earlier, when I worked for his company as a general labourer (I supplied the hard-earned cash, he supplied the bargaining experience). He&#8217;d taken me to a discount stereo place on Dundas St. at the edge of Toronto. It was a Fisher. Nothing fancy, but it had more than enough oomph to overpower most of the stereos in Village 1 the year before.<br />
My roommates were asleep when I got back. Roger, Brian, and Ed were great guys, but were studious. They weren&#8217;t partiers, something I was thankful for. But it also meant that I had to listen to my new purchase on headphones, rather than disturb them with <em>Fully Completely</em>. From beginning to end, it was an album that helped me rethink of how I viewed Canadian music. Like <em>Road Apples</em> before it, there were a few hits, but there were many songs that went well beyond a mere guitar hook or melody. These were things I wouldn&#8217;t yet appreciate for years to come, but it was here I learned more about the strength of a lyric.<br />
Skip ahead 22 years. I&#8217;m married, with kids, living a few thousand kilometres away in the foothills of the Rockies. And The Tragically Hip were touring again, playing <em>Fully Completely</em> in its entirety, front to back (despite the album being pressed in one order, and the liner notes suggesting a different one), and for a few moments I felt that moment back in my sparse university room, listening on headphones, to something new.</p>
<h2>Another Roadside Attraction</h2>
<p>It was 1997. I&#8217;d left university (I&#8217;d not actually <em>graduated</em> yet, though my mother would usher me though that stage), and was working in downtown Toronto at a small software company. My friend Gerry Dessureau had gotten me the interview, and I was willing to subject myself to some rather poor startup habits in an effort to make a mark in my career-to-be.<br />
I&#8217;m not sure if was Gerry, or our co-worker and friend Mike Klinowski who had first mentioned it, but <em>Another Roadside Attraction</em> was coming. And the lineup sounded pretty darned good.<br />
The 1990s had seen the rise of the music festival: Lollapalooza, Lilith Fair, Ozzfest, Warped Tour, Edgefest (a Toronto-area event), and the Woodstock revival. (Interesting fact: The Tragically Hip were lauded for their appearance at Woodstock &#8217;99.) Whether these tours became a factor in their decision to run their tour that year (<em>Trouble at the Henhouse</em> came out the previous year, followed by their live album, <em>Live Between Us</em>, earlier in &#8217;97), or that they just wanted to have fun with a bunch of friends, I don&#8217;t know. But tour they did, and they brought some really big names with them, starting with supporting and promoting Canadian indie band Wilco and indie sensation Ron Sexsmith, and Canadian Ashley MacIssac (who was still riding high on his <em>Hi<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> How Are You Today?</em> album). Along for the ride were also Sheryl Crow (her self-titled second album also released in 1996), and Los Lobos (who, really, needed no introduction). But the headliners were still The Tragically Hip.<br />
The date was set for Sunday, 3 August 1997. The location was Molson Park in Barrie, a large festival space next to the Molson brewery. I picked up Mike at the Kipling Station in far-west Toronto, then swung north to pick up Gerry in Brampton. We drove up the 400 that morning in anticipation of a great day in the sun, to experience &#8230; whatever there was to experience. I&#8217;d never been to an event such as this, and though there had been many like it by this point, it was unknown to me.<br />
Even in 1997, the approach to Barrie was slow on the 400, and we were diverted to Veterans Drive to the west to sneak in through the north end of the facility. (It&#8217;s worth noting that Molson&#8217;s closed in Barrie, and sold all the land. Where we saw the Hip is now a shopping mall.) We parked, and braced ourselves for whatever was to come.<br />
The more unknown acts, notably Van Allen Belt, Change of Heart, and the Mutton Birds were on early. So we diverted to the beer garden and the merchandise stalls. It would be Ron Sexsmith that drew us out to the massive greenspace where some 35,000 of new-found friends would gather together over the course of the next few hours. I don&#8217;t quite remember the order of performers, though I know that Ashley MacIssac, Los Lobos, Sheryl Crow, and the Hip were the last four. I remember being front-and-nearly-centre for MacIssac, who elicited a mosh pit for playing a (fiddle!) cover of the Bee Gee&#8217;s <em>Stayin&#8217; Alive</em>.<br />
And I remember someone landing on my head.<br />
Remember, it was the 90s. People crowd-surfed. And as was always the case, you had to keep an eye out for people headed towards the front of the crowd. Sadly, I didn&#8217;t see this guy coming, and I ended up creating the dreaded &#8220;hole&#8221;. My head cranked to the right. Before I could blink, Gerry had grabbed me and hauled me out of the pack to make sure nothing was broken. Lucky, owing largely to my youth (and possible intoxication), I was fine (I wouldn&#8217;t even have the sore neck later). But the events kept me away from the front. Mike, however, was at the front fence; we wouldn&#8217;t see him again until nearly midnight.<br />
I still remember the moment The Hip took the stage. It was the first time I&#8217;d seen them live, a moment I&#8217;d been (unknowingly) waiting to happen for years. If you <a href="http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-tragically-hip/1997/molson-park-barrie-on-canada-6bdc560e.html" target="_blank">believe the internet</a>, the first Hip song I heard live was <em>Springtime in Vienna</em>. Though, to be fair, I don&#8217;t remember. I do remember hearing the audience overpower them, singing <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em>, and I remember Ashley MacIssac joining them for a song (history records this as <em>Wheat Kings</em>). I remember witnessing Gord Downie&#8217;s presence on the stage, how he both fed and drew energy from the audience. I remember thinking that he must&#8217;ve been high on something, because I couldn&#8217;t understand how someone could be so acutely strange on stage without being deliberate; I would learn later that to witness Canada&#8217;s Poet Musician in the act is an experience in and of itself. And I remember the thunderous applause for the Sons of Kingston, Ontario.<br />
And I remember looking for nearly an hour to find Mike, who&#8217;d been pressed so hard into the fence that he&#8217;d not been able to escape, the lucky bastard. We waited another hour before the traffic died down enough that we could leave. It was a long, quiet trip back into town. Downtown Toronto was silent at 3am Monday morning, save for the woman in a taxi next to us who flashed her breasts at a rather stunned Mike, who neglected to alert Gerry or I to the spectacle. Gerry stayed at Mike&#8217;s that night, whereas I would return to Oakville; all of us still had work in a few hours.</p>
<h2>Road Trip to Red Deer</h2>
<p>In 2013, the tour supporting <em>Now For Plan A</em> would not come to Calgary until July; their route would only come as close as Red Deer, about 90 minutes north of Calgary. And in the prairies, 90 minutes is just a long commute, not remotely a barrier for my friend Scott and I.<br />
But a mere concert this was not, if just because of the date: 22 January 2013, just three days before Alex&#8217;s birthday. So when Alex decided that she wanted to go to Edmonton, there was a problem to resolve. One does not tell one&#8217;s wife that you will not be present for their desires.<br />
Options included both Scott and I driving (not ideal, as then both Alex and I would be driving to Edmonton and back), Alex dropping us off for the concert and waiting (also not ideal, since Scott wouldn&#8217;t have a way back, and it meant an overnight in Red Deer), or (in the final version), Scott would drive me to Red Deer, and then I would bus to Edmonton after the concert.<br />
Scott and I left early from work. Alex and the kids would leave roughly the same time, but would go directly to Edmonton (they would meet with one of Alex&#8217;s friends that evening). Scott and I went to the Toad n&#8217; Turtle, a pub at the south end of Red Deer, a short hop from Westerner Park, where the concert would unfold that night. We ate, we drank, we whiled away the hours until it was time.<br />
The last time I&#8217;d been in a &#8220;small town&#8221; venue was when I&#8217;d been fortunate enough to see David Bowie in Kelowna. (The two cities are fairly similar in size.) It was a large hockey arena, appropriate for its two Canadian guests that evening: The Hip, and their opening act, The Arkells.<br />
Until a few days earlier, I hadn&#8217;t really known of The Arkells. I might have heard a song or two of theirs on the radio, but it would have likely been by chance and I wouldn&#8217;t have known it. But since we knew they were the opening act, both Scott and I listened to them in advance to see if they were worth seeing. In roughly the same amount of time since we&#8217;d started listening, both of us had each bought both of The Arkells&#8217; albums, and were anxious to see them perform.<br />
Well-placed on the floor towards the front, we were left in awe of The Hip&#8217;s choice to prime the audience. The Arkells came out punching, and didn&#8217;t let up for the entire hour of their set. They engaged directly with the audience. They played the songs that Scott and I had come to know only days earlier (such as already-mainstays <em>Whistleblower</em> and <em>The Boss Is Coming</em>), and dropped epic covers from not only Motown, but also The Clash&#8217;s <em>Rock The Casbah</em>.<br />
I might not remember all that was said that night, but I do remember commenting to Scott during the lull between acts that The Hip had a hell of an act to have to follow.<br />
The Tragically Hip did not disappoint. Not even remotely.<br />
They played more from their recent albums than from their back catalogue, including the rather curious <em>Man Machine Poem</em>, a literal poem set to music. To watch Gord Downie perform it on stage was like a grand operatic drama woven amongst the guitars and drums of modern rock.<br />
Selfishly, my favourite moment was hearing <em>My Music At Work</em>, which had been a personal theme of mine for years, stemming from my career in digital marketing. I found the words echoed very much in mind:</p>
<blockquote><p>Everything is bleak<br />
It&#8217;s the middle of the night<br />
You&#8217;re all alone and<br />
The dummies might be right<br />
You feel like a jerk<br />
My music at work</p></blockquote>
<p>Following the final song of the encore, <em>Blow At High Dough</em>, Scott dropped me off at the Denny&#8217;s on 50th Ave so I could wait in relative comfort until my bus. Despite all my grand foresight, one thing I had not picked up on until much too late was that the buses didn&#8217;t run as frequently as I&#8217;d liked. The earliest bus was 3am. Like so many years before, I would find myself up to a very early hour, catch glimpses of sleep, before needing to be awake in a distant city.<br />
Others would come into the Denny&#8217;s as I sat and read. I overheard their conversations. More than a few were commenting on the concert. It was strongly believed that The Hip were staying at the Sheraton just down the road, and wouldn&#8217;t it be cool to see them there? <em>It would</em>, I nodded to myself, <em>but I wouldn&#8217;t want to be a pest.</em> So I sat and drank my coffee, ate my snack, and packed up for the cold walk to the bus station.</p>
<h2>Canada Day</h2>
<p>In June of that same year, I caught wind of plans for a Canada Day concert in London, England, which would feature The Tragically Hip. At the time, I could only smile to myself and think of how fun that would be &#8230; and how much I wanted to go back to London. But without even having to question, I knew that getting time away from my family (which included three- and five-year olds) was only a pipe dream. The wistfulness only got worse as The Arkells were added, followed by The Sheepdogs.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Then they added Jann Arden to the line-up.<br />
I have to admit, I&#8217;m not a ardent Arden fan. I feel kind of bad for having to say that, especially given that I live in her hometown. I&#8217;ve been to one of her concerts, and she is a brilliant performer. Her ability to deliver cracking stand-up comedy amidst heart-wrenching songs is an admirable talent. But her music doesn&#8217;t resonate with me as much as it does my wife. Mind you, that might not be a fair comparison; I&#8217;m not sure that I love The Hip as much as Alex loves Jann Arden. It&#8217;s almost stalker-ish.<br />
So when Alex joked that we should go to London for Canada Day, the laughter was short and nervous, filled with a thick dose of &#8220;why not?&#8221;.<br />
The kids were &#8220;why not&#8221;, of course. We weren&#8217;t comfortable with the idea of taking them to England. Then we turned uncharacteristically selfish (at least insofar as our offspring are concerned) and started wondering how we might be able to steal away for a few days and leave them in the hands of family who live in town. And, rather suddenly, we had booked airfare to England and found as cheap a hotel as we could while remaining inside Zone 1 of the Underground.<br />
It was a wonderfully refreshing experience to fly with only Alex at my side, and not having to worry about children on a plane. (We would worry about them in other ways, of course, but entertaining children on an eight-hour flight was something were just weren&#8217;t ready for.) We weren&#8217;t in First Class, but for our first parents-only getaway, it might as well have been a private berth on a luxury steamship.<br />
In the days leading up to Canada Day, we took advantage of being childless in London: we toured. We walked the streets in the rain, went to the Tower of London, and Tower Bridge. We saw <em>Spamalot</em> on a whim. I finally got to visit St. Paul&#8217;s Cathedral, something I&#8217;d longed to do since my first visit to London many years earlier.<br />
As a boy, my father participated in a choir. He was known as &#8220;The Deacon&#8221; to his friends; he loved to belt out Christmas carols. One year, he had travelled to London, and performed at St. Paul&#8217;s. This was a source of personal pride for him. I wanted to know what it was like.<br />
St. Paul&#8217;s is an impressive building, both for architecture and for art. And it that had been all that I had seen, then perhaps the moment would have passed as little more than a tick on my London To Do list. But as I rounded a pillar (cursing again the limitation that prevented me from taking pictures inside), a choir started to sing. I looked over, to see a small group of kids, boys and girls, directly under massive dome. I froze. As their voices wafted and echoed across the stone interior, I could almost hear my father&#8217;s voice. It&#8217;s rare for me to cry in public.<br />
On the day before the concert, we were invited to join Alex&#8217;s friend&#8217;s family in Cambridge, where she had obtained her law degree. I nearly had another brush with my father&#8217;s ghost, in the form of King&#8217;s College Chapel, the home of my father&#8217;s favourite choir. Thankfully (I suppose), the Chapel was closed for a private function, so the waterworks were kept at bay. Instead, Alex&#8217;s friend Kirstie took us on a guided tour of the millennia-old university.<br />
Kirstie and her family would meet us the following morning in Trafalgar Square for Canada Day. Though not a Bank Holiday in London, it was a chance to get some Canadiana for them; Kirstie had spent some of her childhood in Calgary (it&#8217;s how she and Alex know each other). We got in line for the pancakes and waffles, walked past the Blackberry booth (Blackberry was a sponsor of the event), and sat down to watch the street hockey tournament. Kirstie wouldn&#8217;t stay the entire day, she had to retrieve her youngest from daycare; her husband Grenville would stay for the concert.<br />
The first band up was one I&#8217;d never heard of before: Northern Cree, a First Nations Pow-Wow and Round Dance singing group. It&#8217;s a bit of a shame that as Canadians, we didn&#8217;t know who they were, or could recognize that we&#8217;d probably heard them perform many times before but didn&#8217;t know. And I wonder how exotic they seemed to the British, who certainly don&#8217;t come across such music.<br />
The Arkells came next, and unloaded their vibe across the Square, and onto the streets beyond. Where Northern Cree might have attracted attention, The Arkells became a full-on beacon for what was to come, and the crowds started to grow. That was when I ran into my friend Terri, who had moved to England some years earlier, and had acquired an accent to boot. It wasn&#8217;t easy to chat up while also trying to listen to music. I think I did it rather poorly, to be honest.<br />
I lost Alex (and Terri) for the duration of Jann Arden&#8217;s set, even though Jann had stripped her performance down considerably, coming only with two other musicians and playing acoustically. As The Sheepdogs started to play, we opted to take our leave for a bit and get a break from the crowds. Though I did want to see The Sheepdogs play, even I felt like a break might be good.<br />
We got only as far as Parliament Square Garden, across from the Palace of Westminster. Alex opted to call it an evening and head back to our room, and leave me to wind up the show. I will admit a certain amount of conflict within me: should I stay with my wife, or go see what would likely be a brilliant outdoor concert? (There&#8217;s a Clash song that echoes the sentiment&#8230;)<br />
But Alex encouraged me to go. We had come all this way, and she wasn&#8217;t going to have any part in me missing The Hip in London. So I wound my way back to Trafalgar Square, dove back into the crowds, and as politely as a Canadian can, worked my way within a couple of people of the front fence. No mosh pits would land people on my head this time.<br />
From my position at Stage Left, I could see the band approach on the stairs, following George Stroumboulopoulos. Strombo, as he&#8217;s known in shorthand, is Canada&#8217;s music geek. He hosts a show on CBC Radio 2, playing pretty much what he likes, saying whatever comes to mind. He&#8217;s known for being a terrific interviewer, and does his research. Although he&#8217;s appeared on CNN (a point that still puzzles me), I suspect that non-Canucks in the audience that night hadn&#8217;t a clue who he was. But everyone knew who he was introducing.<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5_1RoiSQHaY" target="_blank">They opened with <em>At Transformation</em></a>, a leading track from <em>Now For Plan A,</em> and followed with <em>Grace, Too</em>. The one-two punch got people excited. And we all waited for Gord Downie to unleash himself, demonstrating to Britain that their former colony had talents they couldn&#8217;t have imagined.<br />
Though the set was fairly close to the one I&#8217;d seen in Red Deer only a few months earlier, the crowd was decidedly more energetic, likely further enthused by the day and the location. Canadian flags were everywhere, either in the traditional form, or emblazoned on hats or shirts. Everyone in the audience knew the words. The only thing saving the band from being overpowered during the chorus of <em>New Orleans Is Sinking</em> (which wrapped <em>Nautical Disaster</em>) was the size of the audio system; had I been further back, I suspect the audience might have won.<br />
There was no real encore. Instead, The Hip did a song I&#8217;d never heard them play before: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YNyzFCaDA84" target="_blank"><em>O Canada</em></a>. If there were a moment to give me real chills, despite the hot summer evening, I&#8217;d struggle to think of one.<br />
With the concert over, the Square started to empty. In hopes of finding Terri and apologizing for our rather aborted discussion, I raced back to the steps before The National Gallery where I had last seen her. However, amongst tens of thousands of people, it&#8217;s exceptionally hard to find just one. So I was quite surprised to suddenly find myself talking to Grenville, whom I&#8217;d lost track of several hours earlier.<br />
We moved to The Chandos, a nearby pub, to quaff a pair of pints before having to go our respective ways. We discussed the concert in quite some detail. I was curious to hear Gren&#8217;s thoughts, especially being a Brit, and Brit&#8217;s take their music seriously. I mean, this is the home of more legends of rock and influences to nearly every genre of music I know. It&#8217;s not a place you walk into and expect to be respected; you have to earn that right. And Gren is probably as good a representation of that knowledge as I can think of. Suffice to say, I expected reservation.<br />
What I got was: &#8220;They&#8217;re really good!&#8221; he exclaimed between sips of a bitter, &#8220;I&#8217;ll need to listen to more of them!&#8221;</p>
<h2>The stories to come&#8230;</h2>
<p>Like any good book, there&#8217;s always room for more. The question that dogs us is: how much more? Since Gord Downie announced his cancer diagnosis, we&#8217;ve all breathed softly, already expecting the worst. Though he has endured treatment, the inevitability of the disease hangs over everything like a looming storm.<br />
I have at least two more stories to add. The first one will be on Monday, when The Hip play here in Calgary, the first of two shows. I&#8217;ll be in the 8th row with Alex &#8212; her first Hip concert. I&#8217;m simultaneously excited to see them again, and I&#8217;m dreading the finality of it. I hate to see them leave.<br />
The second, and possibly last, will be on 20 August, when The Hip play what might be their final concert. Ever. They&#8217;re playing at home in Kingston, which CBC is livecasting to those of us unable to be there.<br />
We don&#8217;t know what to expect. We don&#8217;t know what to think. In the end, though, we&#8217;ll always have our stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/07/my-hip-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3529</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A musical evening in Red Deer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-musical-evening-in-red-deer</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3226</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A musical evening in Red Deer"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Red Deer? Music? Honestly, what on Earth are you thinking, Geoff? You haven&#8217;t exactly had the most &#8230; inspiring of times in Red Deer. Okay, I admit, I&#8217;ve not got the best stories of this, our third largest city in Alberta, but it&#8217;s far from the armpit of Alberta. And I had good reason, y&#8217;know!<br />
Back in July, during the Calgary Stampede, the Tragically Hip played the Calgary Roundup, <em>the</em> outdoor concert of the year. I had wanted to go, but I totally messed up where the tickets were sold (stupid me, I thought it was Ticketmaster), and by the time I&#8217;d realised it &#8230; it was too late. Sold out, and I was out of luck.<br />
This is what brought me to Red Deer.<br />
<span id="more-3226"></span>I&#8217;ve been listening to the Tragically Hip since their <em>Road Apples</em> album, back in my last year(s) of high school. I was immediately hooked, and remained that way ever since. The only thing I hadn&#8217;t done is gone to a lot of their concerts. There was usually a reason, I assure you. My own idiocy aside, it was either bad timing (I wasn&#8217;t around/available), or was without someone to go with (while I may see a movie solo, a concert is an entirely different matter).<br />
So when the Hip announced Red Deer, I was quick to jump on getting tickets, this being the closest the Hip would come to Calgary this go around. Even with a presale code, the best I could do was 10th row on the floor (which, as it turns out, was still pretty darned good). My accomplice was a fellow former-Ontarioan, Scott &#8212; one of a few hundred Scotts that I seem to know.<br />
We left Calgary shortly before 15:00 for our just-over-an-hour jaunt north. (Alex and the kids had left nearly 90 minutes earlier for their trip to Alberta Beach &#8212; we meet up tomorrow in Edmonton. More on that in a moment&#8230;) The worst problem we had beyond some less-than-savoury other drivers was some fog that reduced visibility to about 200 metres or so. Once we were past Olds, it seemed to clear up.<br />
We arrived in Red Deer just after 16:00, and ran a couple of errands before holing up at the Toad and Turtle for a couple of hours of beer, nachos, and random conversation about &#8230; well, pretty much what you&#8217;d expect from a pair of geek programmer fathers who don&#8217;t get out enough. (If you are one, you&#8217;re nodding in agreement. If you&#8217;re not one, you probably don&#8217;t really want to know.)<br />
Westerner Park (an oddly named place, IMO) lay a mere click away, and we quickly found a place to park the car. We were soon accosted by another concert-goer &#8212; originally from Hamilton &#8212; who swore he was going to start a chant so the Hip would play <em>Wheat Kings</em>. He was rather pleased to hear that both Scott and I originally hail from Ontario.<br />
The concert venue is the two-tiered arena, primarily for the Red Deer Rebels, the local CHL team. So, as you can imagine, it&#8217;s not a big place. Which was completely fine with me. And so we waited for the opening act, to start at 20:00.<br />
Opening was a band called The Arkells, out of Hamilton. Until the concert had been announced, I hadn&#8217;t heard of the Arkells. The announcement, of course, drove both Scott and I to check out their music. Within 10 minutes, I&#8217;d bought both of their albums and put them onto heavy rotation. This was not for any form of preparation, this was solely because the albums were that good. I cannot think, in my musical history, of any band that has turned out albums so strong that I&#8217;m compelled to buy and listen constantly for nearly two weeks. Several of their songs are still on my frequently-listened playlists. (Side note: I swear some of their songs must be written for people who work in marketing&#8230;)<br />
Live? I was pretty much floored. Not only did the Arkells come out with a bang, they <em>refused</em> to let up. They got everyone on their feet, and they got the entire audience going. In terms of what an opening act should do, they did it far better than any opening act I&#8217;ve ever seen. It&#8217;s just a shame that their set was so short. I pray that they come to Calgary in the near future as a solo act, or with an opening act of their own.<br />
The intermission was short, filled with roadies racing across the stage to clean off the Arkell&#8217;s equipment, and make sure the Hip&#8217;s equipment was good to go. Shortly before 21:00, some fifteen and a half years since the last time I&#8217;d seen them, the Tragically Hip took stage to a roar. And they kept roaring for two-odd hours.<br />
It was sort of like listening to my own Tragically Hip playlist, which is a kind of &#8220;best of&#8221;. But live and loud, complete with Gord Downie&#8217;s interjections and rants, for which he is famous (though none as legendary as the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gjSyZslQp0w">Killer Whale Tank</a>, or of July&#8217;s Roundup concert, which should approach <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1N4AQGON5_o">the same level of epicness</a>, if you ask me).<br />
The encore was five songs, including <em>Wheat Kings</em>. I could hear the audience over the band. We were in the 10th row.<br />
Following the concert, Scott dropped me off where I now am, at the Denny&#8217;s on Gaetz, before he headed back to Calgary. Why am I still here? Well, remember how I said I&#8217;m meeting Alex and the kids in Edmonton? Well, I have to get there. Right now, they&#8217;re in Alberta Beach (google it, folks) visiting a friend. In a little over two hours, with luck, I&#8217;ll be boarding a Greyhound bus for Edmonton, arriving at 6:00.<br />
Yes, that&#8217;s 6:00 in the morning. Look at the datestamp folks, it&#8217;s after midnight.<br />
This is what&#8217;s led me to sitting in a back booth at the Denny&#8217;s, using their wifi, to &#8230; um &#8230; well, kill time. Then I can walk (yes, walk) to the Greyhound station, and try get a couple of hours sleep before arriving in Edmonton, for a short vacation and some fun.<br />
But for now, I&#8217;ve got the Hip and the Arkells on repeat in my head. &#8216;Cuz they&#8217;re a lot better than listening to some of the shmucks in this place&#8230;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/01/a-musical-evening-in-red-deer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day of the Ya Ya</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/day-of-the-ya-ya/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=day-of-the-ya-ya</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/day-of-the-ya-ya/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 03:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heredia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2163</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, today was your Ya Ya day. In case you don&#8217;t remember what &#8220;Ya Yas&#8221; are when you get around to reading this, this is your name for The Backyardigans. And a couple of weeks ago, Mommy noticed there were commercials on TV for a live show, about a half second after you screamed &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/day-of-the-ya-ya/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Day of the Ya Ya"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, today was your Ya Ya day. In case you don&#8217;t remember what &#8220;Ya Yas&#8221; are when you get around to reading this, this is your name for <a href="http://www.nickjr.com/shows/backyardigans/">The Backyardigans</a>. And a couple of weeks ago, Mommy noticed there were commercials on TV for a live show, about a half second after you screamed &#8220;YA YAS!!&#8221;.<br />
Naturally, that evolved quickly to us getting tickets for the show, which was today. I think both Mommy and I had an idea of what we were going to get into, but having never been to an &#8220;infantil&#8221; show before, there was a considerable amount of guessing.<br />
<span id="more-2163"></span>We were up early, no thanks to someone&#8217;s alarm clock and you waking up before 6:00 because Costa Rica has its time set too far back for the sunrise (seriously, we should be EASTERN time, not MOUNTAIN). Mommy and I tried to drag it out until 6:00, and I think we were at best only marginally successful.<br />
The plan, a fairly simple one, was to have our Saturday breakfast outing at the Marriott, which is more-or-less along the way from our home to El Palacio de los Deportes in Heredia. It has a lot of things that are very yummy, and in particular, I get to have bacon. You&#8217;ve had bacon, and you like it, but we don&#8217;t give it to you often.<br />
As we were eating, I came to a horrible realisation &#8212; that in our haste to get out of the house, we&#8217;d forgotten the tickets. Only one go at the buffet for me, sadly, and I was off back home to get the tickets. As usual, I got stuck behind slow drivers. Whee.<br />
I was back by 9:45, which left me just enough time to suck back a second coffee before we left. Finding the Palacio was fairly easy, and we lucked into parking very nearby. It was perhaps not the best parking, as we had others park behind us and block the way, but the attendants told us that it was just for the show.<br />
Less than a block away from the Palacio, we could hear the Backyardigans theme. It was being blared out front by Kern&#8217;s, one of the local juice producers (and a major sponsor of the show). We got in line, and slowly worked our way in. I was a little worried that we had only 30 minutes, and the line seemed to be very long. After a little while, it started zipping along and we were soon inside.<br />
The Palacio de los Deportes is a sports hall, pure and simple. It looks like a really, really large community gymnasium. The floors were covered in plywood and covered with folding chairs in blocks. The upper decks weren&#8217;t fully open, but the areas that were open were packed.<br />
To no surprise, the show didn&#8217;t start on time. It was about 15 minutes late, I think. Maybe 20. The lights went out, and the Backyardigan&#8217;s logo &#8212; featuring the Backyardigans themselves &#8212; started to move slightly. Then the characters blinked. A moment later, a &#8220;hole&#8221; appeared in the projection and spotlights behind the projection screen showed Pablo. You immediately took interest. This continued a few times until Uniqua walked out. You pointed at her.<br />
Yet no-one got the same reaction as Tasha. You went fairly ga-ga over her, Monkey. Tyrone came out moments later, and four of the five were on stage. They then realised that they were missing Austin, and had the entire audience call out to find him. Then the projection screen went up, and we found the Backyardigans in their backyard. They sang their theme song, and the show officially began.<br />
The stage play was an extended version of one of their episodes, I think it&#8217;s called &#8220;Brave Knights&#8221; in English. Of course, the entire show was in Spanish, but you&#8217;ve seen it so much in Spanish that you don&#8217;t seem to mind. They added a couple of songs and changed a couple of things, too.<br />
I had thought you would scream and yell and jump up and down for this show. But you were pretty quiet, actually. For a good part of the show, you just sat there and sucked your fingers. Even when all the other kids were screaming and yelling (because they were asked to by the Backyardigans), you just sat there. I had to entice you to wave &#8220;bye bye&#8221; when the show was finally over.<br />
At that point, Mommy&#8217;s friend Larissa and her husband Roberto asked us to join them for lunch at a special restaurant up north. It took a while to find it, and thankfully we have directions now should we want to find it again, but it was certainly worth it.<br />
<a href="http://lallunadevalencia.com/">La Lluna de Valencia</a> is one of those restaurants you&#8217;d be lucky to find on your own, which is to say, &#8220;not easily&#8221;. It really helps to have a local who knows the place (and it seems, the owner, too). According to Roberto, it&#8217;s the most authentic Spanish restaurant he knows in Costa Rica. He claimed that he compared it extremely favourably to the restaurants he visited in Barcelona.<br />
Their  specialty  is paella, a Spanish rice dish that I hadn&#8217;t had since &#8230; well, since before I met Mommy, I think. Either way, it had been far too long. You and Luba (Larissa and Roberto&#8217;s daughter) ran around playing while we tried to figure out what we were ordering. We settled for two versions: a seafood paella and a paella with chicken and rabbit.<br />
Paellas take a bit of time to make, so we also ordered a simple appetizer of cheese, sausage, a tomato garlic sauce, and bread. You&#8217;d try everything, and drank a few glasses of mora (blackberry) juice all on your own.<br />
The restaurant is &#8230; well, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;eclectic&#8221; only because it&#8217;s definitely not your run-of-the-mill kind of place. The tables are all made from thick slices of what was probably one great, massive jungle tree, so there were huge folds creating a really neat effect. Massive paella pans hung on the walls, and there was a large stage at one end.<br />
You and Luba loved the stage. You climbed up the stairs and ran back and forth, doing this cute little hop/jump you&#8217;ve started to do. You ran back and forth, stomping around. Then you spied a Spanish flag hanging from the ceiling. You tried to catch it with your hands. You walked further and further into it &#8230; which was when we noticed that the stage didn&#8217;t sit flush against the far wall.<br />
Considering that you tumbled face-forward over the edge into a space that was quite small without any preparation for it, you got out without so much as a scratch. (Mommy and I, however, had near heart-attacks. I&#8217;ve never seen Mommy move so fast before.) After only a minute of crying, you were back to prancing around happily.<br />
The paella was worth the wait. It was fantastic. I ate far more than I should have. (I didn&#8217;t eat dinner tonight because of that.) You ate quite a bit, too.<br />
The drive home was uneventful, and you slept part of the way. When we got home, we tried to put you back down for a nap, but you&#8217;d have none of it. You wanted to be with us, and I think the thunderstorm that was rolling past kept waking you up. We ended up watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0910970/"><em>WALL-E</em></a>. Again. For the 20th time. (Not that I&#8217;m complaining. But after a while, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/">you start to notice smaller details</a>.)<br />
After dinner, you watched The Backyardigans again, while wearing your new Backyardigans shirt. It was a Backyardigans day.<br />
I just hope tomorrow isn&#8217;t quite so &#8230; Ya Ya.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/day-of-the-ya-ya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Bowie plays Kelowna Prospera Place</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2004 23:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concerts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kelowna]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/11/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all woke at about the same time. I was awake, though eyes closed, when I heard Tamara and Andrea whispering. I joined into the conversation, joined shortly thereafter by Dan. At that point, there wasn&#8217;t much reason to stay in bed, so I called first shower (I hadn&#8217;t had one since getting up &#8220;yesterday&#8221; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "David Bowie plays Kelowna Prospera Place"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all woke at about the same time. I was awake, though eyes closed, when I heard Tamara and Andrea whispering. I joined into the conversation, joined shortly thereafter by Dan. At that point, there wasn&#8217;t much reason to stay in bed, so I called first shower (I hadn&#8217;t had one since getting up &#8220;yesterday&#8221; in Japan).<br />
The plan had been to go for dim sum for breakfast, at the Chinese restaurant across the road. Not being open until 11:30 proved to be a bit of an issue, however, so we opted for breakfast #2: IHOP. Unlike Calgary, there is an International House of Pancakes in Kelowna. And we weren&#8217;t the only ones who knew that. The lineup was clearly out the door, and not just by a few people. It would be a long wait before we got breakfast if we&#8217;d stayed. We opted for the much shorter lineup at a nearby Perkins.<br />
It felt good to not eat Japanese for a change.<br />
<span id="more-349"></span>Having thoroughly packed ourselves full, we returned to the hotel and went for a walk down by the lake shore. We&#8217;d been trying to figure out what to do, and headed for a boat ride on the Fintry Queen, a stern-wheeler ship that runs out of Kelowna. As we would find out, it runs during the tourist season, which we weren&#8217;t in. The ship was closed down, and not operating. We turned instead to the boardwalk, and slowly walked our way north along the lake, past the condos, rounding the park, turning around only when we got to the estuary marsh. We walked back passing Propera Place (where David Bowie would play later in the day).<br />
We started to look for a patio. We thought that we&#8217;d take advantage of the great weather (it was warming up very quickly) and sit out in the sun with a drink or two. Turned out to be harder than we thought. Unlike Calgary and Vancouver, which open patios at the first hint of a warm day, Kelowna&#8217;s stayed closed. We ended up at the Earl&#8217;s, instead. Not my first choice, but it wasn&#8217;t too bad.<br />
Back at the hotel again, we were desperate for something to do. While Tamara, Andrea, and Dan perused the various pamphlets and brochures in a pair of racks in the hotel&#8217;s entrance, and searched the Internet. I took the opportunity to use a local call to give my relatives a ring.<br />
Uncle David answered the phone, which I thought a bit surprising &#8212; I&#8217;d fully expected him to be on the golf course. Temporarily put down by a cold and a wrist injury, he was reduced to merely watching the Masters game on TV. Not the best way to get a golf fix, but it would have to do. We talked for a bit about the trip to Japan, the things we&#8217;d seen, and how much Jen had apparently liked the experience. We got onto the topic of what we were doing before the concert, and soon, we had our destination for the afternoon.<br />
Knox Mountain is just north of downtown Kelowna. It&#8217;s not too high a rise, but is high enough that you can see quite a distance from the apex lookout. Almost the entire city if Kelowna is visible (some parts are blocked by trees and/or parts of the mountain). It&#8217;s an old mountain, having long since been worn down by the glaciers that were up to 7,000 feet thick in the area that now supports Kelowna. Now the mountain features many coniferous trees and a lot of daisies.<br />
Having done our tour of the mountain, we headed back to the hotel to prepare for the concert. Well, Tamara and Andrea were preparing. Dan and I were pretty much set to go. I ended up falling asleep on my cot. Not sure if it was jet lag, exhaustion from all the wandering around, or both. But it was a rest I needed.<br />
When I woke, it was dinner time. We hoped to eat with enough time to get there before the concert actually started (last time, we were a tad late &#8212; see [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]]). After a quick discussion, it was off to Earl&#8217;s again. No dice &#8212; the stable was full. We looked at a place called Cattle Country, but the prices were a little out of our range. Luckily, we could get into The Keg. However, despite our fortune in finding a restaurant, we had issues with the slow service, and ended up having to eat quickly and set a quick pace to get to the concert.<br />
Once again, the opening act was already on stage. We didn&#8217;t consider this a huge deal, since we weren&#8217;t really there to see them. To be honest, we&#8217;d never even heard of The Polyphonic Spree before. Quite an odd band &#8212; there are 25 members, including a nine-person choir, harpist, flautist, trombone, trumpet, two percussionists, bass and guitar, lead singer, and two keyboardists (one of whom plays the therimin). They call themselves a pop choir. I wouldn&#8217;t use the word &#8220;pop&#8221; to describe the music, though. It&#8217;s very melodic and very different. Out of our group, I think I was the only one who liked it, though.<br />
During the break, I got a chance to know some of our neighbours. The couple sitting next to me were a bit older (the guy, whose name I&#8217;ve already forgotten, commented that he was glad not to be the oldest one there &#8212; he couldn&#8217;t have been older than late-30s), and very excited to see David Bowie. But they didn&#8217;t hold a candle to Tannis. She sad in the row ahead of me. I had thought I was pretty gung-ho for coming off a plane from Japan and coming out to Kelowna for a concert I&#8217;d already seen.<br />
Tonight is Tannis&#8217; sixth David Bowie concert since January. She went to the Calgary concert, and also the ones in Winnipeg, Edmonton, Vancouver, and Seattle. Tonight is her last, though, having run out of both money and vacation time. But she was just as excited to see him this time as the first time. She epitomized the ideal &#8220;fan&#8221;. (Thankfully, not to the extremity of the freak in the bunny suit, a perfect example of someone taking it too far. She was staying at our hotel, too.)<br />
Prospera Place is small &#8212; it&#8217;s a large community ice rink. It seats no more than 5,000 people. It&#8217;s got one level of seating, not counting the floor (where we sat). The place is so small that the stage set had to be slightly reduced. No-one seemed to have any idea what possessed David Bowie to play there.<br />
You wouldn&#8217;t hear any of us complain.<br />
The music changed on the sound system, and Tannis went crazy. Even I knew what it meant &#8212; no-one else around us did &#8212; this was the beginning of Bowie&#8217;s stint onstage. The lights dimmed, and the video showing the animated version of the band appeared on the video wall. It faded to video of the band, as the members walked on. The delay between the band entering onstage and starting the first song was much shorter than before &#8212; &#8220;Rebel Rebel&#8221; was soon starting, and as they&#8217;d probably practiced almost endlessly, David walked up the microphone just as he needed to start singing.<br />
Andrea and I were on the left side of the stage, in the fifth row. (Tamara and Dan were in the eighth row, on the other side of the floor.) While our seats sound wicked, I actually prefered the seats we had at the Calgary concert &#8212; at least I didn&#8217;t have some completely unanimated gorilla standing in front of me.<br />
I have to say that the Kelowna crowd was FAR more laid back than the one in Calgary. On the slower songs, they all sat down (as did Andrea &#8212; I think Tannis and I were one of a handful who stayed standing; Tamara and I would later comment that we should have stayed in the fifth row, with Andrea and Dan in the eighth &#8230; oh well), there wasn&#8217;t nearly as much jumping up and down, and not as much singing as I had expected. There was, however, a lot more pot than in Calgary (hey, we are in British Columbia). I should point out, however, that Andrea and I were among the youngest ones in our area&#8230;<br />
The playlist had changed since Calgary, much to my delight. The second song up was &#8220;Modern Love&#8221;, one of my all-time favourites, and the song that got me hooked on Bowie in the first place. (He never did play &#8220;Space Oddity&#8221;, but I think I can live with that.) At this show, David dug out the oldies, playing a few songs I&#8217;d never heard before. He also changed up the beginning to &#8220;Let&#8217;s Dance&#8221;, to the point where I didn&#8217;t initially recognize it. If nothing else, the song selection just further proved Bowie&#8217;s artistry.<br />
He also continued his habit of joking around, especially with &#8220;China Girl&#8221;. Unlike last time (see [[David Bowie Plays the Calgary Saddledome]]), Bowie didn&#8217;t make us sing. Instead, he tried to sing the whole song in Chinese. (Apparently, he&#8217;s done this &#8212; it appears on a DVD.) He made it two verses before stopping, unable to remember how the rest of it went. He restarted with the original English version.<br />
The concert was much more intimate than Calgary&#8217;s, with David making lots of jokes with the audience (starting off with &#8220;What&#8217;s with &#8216;Kamloops&#8217;, anyway?&#8221;) and ribbing Kelowna about its history. He even brought out a little plush representation of Ogopogo, and started comparing it to the Loch Ness Monster. He claimed it wasn&#8217;t much to talk about, being only four inches long, fuzzy, and wearing a bowtie. He even pointed out the freak in the bunny suit. He nodded to Tannis &#8212; I think he was actually looking for her.<br />
A little shorter than Calgary&#8217;s show, the Kelowna show was notably louder. (Although when it came to the &#8220;Wham, bam, thank you, ma&#8217;am&#8221; part in &#8220;Suffragette City&#8221;, you couldn&#8217;t really hear the audience.) My ears rang well into the night, and long after I went to bed.<br />
I thought it was a great concert, though I have to admit it lacked the energy I felt in Calgary. Might have been partly because of the crowd, or perhaps because I&#8217;d already seen him. I&#8217;m still glad I went, though, because it was great to see him perform again. If he comes around in the not-too-distant future, I might go. But I won&#8217;t feel quite as much need as I have before.<br />
[flickr]tag:davidbowie+kelowna+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/david-bowie-kelowna-prospera-place/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">349</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
