<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>car rental &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/car-rental/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 13:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>In Hazy Burlington</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-hazy-burlington</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 13:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our last day in Calgary &#8212; yesterday &#8212; was filled mostly by me repacking all of our bags so we could fly out, and then the actual travel here to Burlington, Ontario. We&#8217;re here to visit with family (today is Alex&#8217;s family reunion) before we leave for Costa Rica. Or face the long-distance wrath of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "In Hazy Burlington"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our last day in Calgary &#8212; yesterday &#8212; was filled mostly by me repacking all of our bags so we could fly out, and then the actual travel here to Burlington, Ontario. We&#8217;re here to visit with family (today is Alex&#8217;s family reunion) before we leave for Costa Rica.<br />
Or face the long-distance wrath of scorned relations&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-1022"></span>We have four large pieces of luggage, including  Alex&#8217;s large Air Canada bag and my backpack. In principle, I think we were supposed to be charged for taking more than one bag each (Air Canada&#8217;s policy dings you for each additional bag these days). But I was a bit of a dink yesterday. Air  Canada&#8217;s so-called efficient process has you check-in at kiosks first, and then you get into a line to talk to an agent. Why? Seriously? It&#8217;s really silly to have to check-in twice &#8212; which is effectively what that process is. At any rate, I ended up bypassing it because of flying with an infant, and managed to  actually check in at a clerk&#8217;s desk before the line suddenly exploded with about 100 people.  <br />
The flight out wasn&#8217;t too bad. I find they&#8217;re slowly getting better again, but they&#8217;re still only reaching back up to the point where WestJet has always been.  Air Canada will never return to its former glory &#8212; domestically-speaking &#8212; but at least I&#8217;ll be able to  likely  fly them again without  all my bitching about their service level.<br />
The new Toronto Pearson terminal is massive. Huge.  Totally forgot how big it is.  Getting out was surprisingly easy, although Avis had run out of the small car we had reserved, and &#8220;upgraded&#8221; us to a Chrysler 300. This is not an upgrade in my world. This is cruel and  inhuman torture. It&#8217;s a boat.  I feel like I should be looking at a radar display to make sure I&#8217;m not going to run aground. It&#8217;s way more car than we need. And no,  Mr. Desk Clerk,  despite what your fancy chart says, a Nissan Versa actually does have a bigger trunk. Or at least it fit our bags better.<br />
It&#8217;s humid, stick, and hazy here.  But it smells  just like I remember as a kid. I always loved summer in Ontario. Except for the heat and humidity, that is. Forty degrees with the humidex. Ugh.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/in-hazy-burlington/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First weekend in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=first-weekend-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 19:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "First weekend in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week was a rough one. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe we&#8217;ve only been here a week now. (A week ago right now, I was in the lobby of our hotel, chatting with Jason and Javier, waiting for our realtors to come and whisk us away to our condos.) Since then we&#8217;ve gotten our places, bought the things we need to make life reasonable (note: not &#8220;comfortable&#8221; &#8212; we&#8217;re still working on that), moved into a temporary office, got connected (still need cell phones), started working on new work, and had a surprising number of meetings given that there&#8217;s only four of us.<br />
So when we got to the end of the week, we had pretty much declared ourselves &#8220;beat&#8221;. Had we been a lot more set up than we are now, we&#8217;d probably have just gone home to our respective places, kicked back, and relaxed. But it&#8217;s hard to do that when you have to flag down a cab. Which you can&#8217;t here, for some reason.<br />
We rented a car instead.<br />
<span id="more-1010"></span>Sooner or later, you have to decide when enough is enough. Spending hours (I&#8217;m not joking, by the way) waiting for a taxi is not fun. While they&#8217;re fairly inexpensive (rarely more than a couple of dollars), it&#8217;s a colossal waste of time. As we&#8217;re all Type A people, it&#8217;s beyond frustrating.<br />
For the record, Jason wants to be a rally driver. I&#8217;m certain of this. We&#8217;ve got some dinky white Nissan that I swear could be foot-powered for all the oomph it has. But in Jason&#8217;s hands, that think could handle the Paris-Dakar race. On Sunday, we were exploring old Escazu, and Jason was whipping up and down roads like it was a marked course. No problems at all. This guy has adapted to Costa Rican driving.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603884205(small)[/flickr]<br />
Our first task with the car? Shopping.<br />
Yes, this was our wild Friday night. We went to the nearby Mas Por Menos (&#8220;More for Less&#8221;) store for various odds-and-ends that we&#8217;re all missing. I didn&#8217;t get much (I don&#8217;t want to get much; Alex and I are aiming for a more minimalist existence), but Mark filled a shopping cart.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603881365(small)[/flickr]<br />
After that, we went out in search of dinner. We searched for a Tican restaurant (we&#8217;ve done <em>gringo</em> to death) and found a place called Yakky&#8217;s. Kind of a dive, but by 21:00 the place was packed. The food was great, the beer was cheap (Imperial is the Costa Rican favourite, and it&#8217;s about $1 a bottle &#8212; markups are really small here). For the three of us, it was only $60 with a lot of food, several beers, and Mark and Jason endulged in a little JD. I drove us home.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603882479(small)[/flickr]<br />
Saturday was a trip into Escazu for some shopping. We were aiming for a place we thought was called &#8220;Se Marco&#8221; (turned out it was &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, which is a name of a department store ala The Bay). We found a box store called EPA, which is mostly a home improvement place. Mark loaded another shopping cart. Jason got keys cut for our office space, and we all got slop buckets and mops so we can actually clean our places. The cat hair in mine (Asia&#8217;s shedding like crazy) is getting out of hand.<br />
We found our way to Grau, a local chain of coffee shops. I still don&#8217;t drink coffee (I imagine it won&#8217;t be long before I do), but Jason and Mark were dying for one. I settled for a pineapple smoothie. It&#8217;s called a &#8220;batido&#8221;, which directly translates to &#8220;beaten&#8221;. Mixed with milk. Mmmmmm.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603885915(small)[/flickr]<br />
A trip to the mall found the real &#8220;cemaco&#8221;, and also the times for the English showing of <em>The Hulk</em> that we saw that night. (I have to say, a surprisingly good movie.) Not far from there was Aliss, another store that has a massive baby section that Alex will love.<br />
All the while, I should point out, Mark was searching for a french press so he could make coffee. This was almost an exercise in futility. French presses aren&#8217;t common here (yet). Unlike in North America, where you can about trip over all the Bodums, they&#8217;re a rarity even in the gringo centres. I kept telling Mark that he needed <a href="http://www.zurqui.com/crinfocus/cr/coffee.html">the Costa Rican method of making coffee</a>, but couldn&#8217;t remember the damn name of it (Chorreador de café), nor easily find it.<br />
Something I noticed as we went from store to store to store. The Euro Cup was playing on virtually every set. Everywhere we went, eyes were glued to sets. Football (&#8220;soccer&#8221; to us heathen North Americans) is second in importance only to the church. I think it even eclipses family when it comes to certain games. You really need to pull a sales guy away from the game to get his (or her, but they&#8217;re usually male) attention.<br />
We ate lunch in likely the last Chichi&#8217;s restaurant on Planet Earth. Might have been the prototype, too. Despite the disappointment in realising it was a restaurant chain, it was actually pretty good. Possibly the best fajitas I&#8217;ve had, actually.<br />
Sunday was notably quieter, with really only our excursion into old Escazu being a notable point. In fact, Ihad to work on a priority item for the Toronto office. It is nice to be wanted, though. Tricky part is the lack of connectivity at home, still. Weak internet means no phone or means of communication with the outside world. It&#8217;s a bit of a nuisance, admittedly. But slowly, adjusting.<br />
[flickr]photo:2603887367(small)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/first-weekend-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1010</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halifax to Huntsville</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=halifax-huntsville</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2002 06:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halifax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nova scotia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/12/halifax-huntsville/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I hate alarms. Especially when they go off while you&#8217;ve still got an hour of darkness left of the night. I had an early flight to Toronto, though, and wasn&#8217;t keen on missing it. I had packed the night before, so all I had to do was shave, shower, dress, and throw all my bags &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Halifax to Huntsville"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hate alarms. Especially when they go off while you&#8217;ve still got an hour of darkness left of the night. I had an early flight to Toronto, though, and wasn&#8217;t keen on missing it.<br />
I had packed the night before, so all I had to do was shave, shower, dress, and throw all my bags in the trunk of my rented car. Checking out was trivial, just the way I like it. Then it was off to the airport.<br />
Now here&#8217;s where either my unbelievably good sense of direction, or my unbelievable stupidity, shows through. Most normal people would ask where the airport is and how to get there. Not me. I decided I could find it based on the solitary sign I&#8217;d seen on the Highway 102/103 interchange yesterday. Oh, I should mention that it was still dark when I entered the highway, and the radio was calling for dense patches of fog &#8230; about 10 seconds before I ran into one myself.<br />
So I drove north. I wasn&#8217;t sure if I was even going to the correct airport. (I didn&#8217;t know how many airports were in the Halifax area.) For a short time, I considered turning off to get directions. But something kept me going. I found my way to the airport, though. The correct one, at that!<br />
One of these days, this behaviour is going to get me into trouble. Big trouble.<br />
Checking in was fast, as was picking up the seafood feast I was bringing back to Ontario. Five lobster, two pounds of mussels, and a pound of scallops. And so help me, none of it cooked in butter. (Not counting sautéing the onions and garlic for the white wine sauce.) The box the seafood came in, however, needed to be taken on the plane. Along with my two carry-on bags. This was over my limit, and a bit of worry. Luckily, the plane was only about three-quarters full. The staff didn&#8217;t stop me.<br />
Toronto came quickly, and I was soon waiting in the baggage claim with my three carry-ons. My duffle bag was the first bag off. My knapsack was significantly later. As I exited baggage claim, my mother came in the main doors. Five minutes later mom, Cathy, and I were on our way north.<br />
I was goaded into coming back to Ontario for Thanksgiving. I wanted to go home to Calgary. I&#8217;ve been away for a month and a half, and I want adjustment time. But somewhere in the back of my mind, staying for a couple of days in Huntsville seemed like a good idea. I gave into pressure and decided to come in. However, I&#8217;ll probably only see the airport, the highway, and the cottage. I doubt I&#8217;ll see anything else, or anyone else.<br />
The ride north was uneventful, save for the Teeming Thousands who were similarly heading north. The traffic, according to Cathy, wasn&#8217;t too bad though. On long weekends during the summer, you simply just don&#8217;t go up on Saturday&#8217;s. It&#8217;s just shy of declaring insanity. When we hit the Highway 69/Highway 11 split, the traffic lightened. The rest of the trip wasn&#8217;t so bad.<br />
At Orillia, I convinced Cathy that we needed to stop for lunch. I hadn&#8217;t eaten a thing since leaving Halifax, and it was now 3:00pm according to my stomach. This meant, of course, a stop at Weber&#8217;s &#8212; an institution in this part of Ontario. Virtually everyone who&#8217;s driven this stretch of highway more than once has eaten at Weber&#8217;s. And for good reason: it&#8217;s fast, fresh, and good.<br />
We were in Huntsville about an hour later. After a quick stop for beer (I&#8217;m a picky drinker), we made the long trek out to the cottage. It&#8217;s a bit of a hike &#8212; a lot longer than I remembered from my last journey out here (see [[Visit to Ontario, Cottage in Huntsville, Thanksgiving Dinner, Algonquin Park]]). But the cottage was as I remembered it. The outside, anyway. Cathy and Craig (mostly Craig) have put in a huge amount of renovation. It&#8217;s not done yet, but one day it&#8217;s going to be the smartest-looking small cabin on Lake Vernon.<br />
Craig was already there, having been doing yard work for most of the day. Bear and Kylie (both dogs) raced out of the woods to greet us. Within minutes of being inside, I started to feel a little more relaxed. I still wanted to go home to Calgary, though. I guess all this travel has just left me feeling a little tired.<br />
The renovations were awesome. The kitchen was totally different, the floor all tiled, and the bathroom looked almost totally new. (Well,it practically is.) Still, some work was still needed, including the walls of the living room and dining room, and the downstairs. But one thing at a time.<br />
Dave arrived not long after, Chuckie (Dave&#8217;s dog) in tow. Anne and Rebecca arrived not long after. We chatted and made fun of each other until it was time to get cooking. Which was when the lobster pot finally got to a boil &#8212; after being on the burners for about three hours.<br />
Lobsters: about 10 minutes. Mussels: about 7 minutes. Scallops: about two minutes. Time to eat it all: about an hour and a half. But worth it, if for no other reason than it cleared out the memory of the scallops I had in Lunenburg. We had no room for dessert.<br />
The fun continued after dinner as we resumed making fun of each other. I didn&#8217;t participate as much, being quite tired from everything (and the alcohol not helping much). It was a good time, but I didn&#8217;t really feel all that relaxed. I still wanted to go home. Maybe tomorrow, I won&#8217;t feel so uptight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">248</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
