<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>zoo &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/zoo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 03:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Disney World 2016: Animal Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/disney-world-2016-animal-kingdom/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=disney-world-2016-animal-kingdom</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/disney-world-2016-animal-kingdom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 03:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I moved the family as quickly as I had the day before. My biggest need that morning wasn&#8217;t to get to Animal Kingdom, it was to return the car before we got dinged another USD$133. I&#8217;d gotten over the fact that we&#8217;d ended up with an inappropriately large and expensive car, I just didn&#8217;t want to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/disney-world-2016-animal-kingdom/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Disney World 2016: Animal Kingdom"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I moved the family as quickly as I had the day before. My biggest need that morning wasn&#8217;t to get to <em>Animal Kingdom</em>, it was to return the car before we got dinged another USD$133. I&#8217;d gotten over the fact that we&#8217;d ended up with an inappropriately large and expensive car, I just didn&#8217;t want to be reminded of it again.<br />
We charged through breakfast, Alex and I started to really dislike the constant pattern of food without sufficient variation. Finishing first, I double-backed for the car, and brought it closer to Animation Hall for pickup. However, either due to miscommunication or misunderstanding, my family went left instead of right, and took longer to get out than I&#8217;d planned. I ended up literally chasing them around the building, only to find them at the car, wondering where I was.<br />
<span id="more-3575"></span>Getting to the Alamo was a breeze, dropping off the car was a snap, and before I could be reminded too many times that I&#8217;d put on my sunscreen too thickly, we were on a shuttle bus to the <em>Animal Kingdom</em>. We arrived shortly after 9:15, which although earlier than planned, was a convenient arrival time &#8212; the park had only just opened, so wasn&#8217;t too busy.<br />
Almost immediately, I was struck with the lushness of the park. <em>Animal Kingdom</em> is, in effect, a kind of zoo. And it&#8217;s built in the Central Florida swamp. But to look at all the plants Disney put in, you&#8217;d swear it was utterly natural.<br />
Unlike Epcot, the girl&#8217;s MagicBands didn&#8217;t get them in. I have no idea why. However, an alert cast member stepped in tapped something, snapped a picture (which, like the fingerprints, went unexplained), and we were in. From then on, there were no issues with the MagicBands that day.<br />
For the first couple hundred metres, you see plants, a few souvenir stands, the <em>Rainforest Cafe</em>, and then you&#8217;re into tall trees, thick bushes, and large animal pens carrying all kinds of birds, lizards, and even things like wallabies. At the end of that, you come up a rise, the vegetation clears, and suddenly you&#8217;re looking right down the main path into Discovery Island, and the Tree of Life.<br />
Every Disney park has an icon. In Epcot, it&#8217;s <em>Spaceship Earth</em>. In the <em>Magic Kingdom</em>, it&#8217;s Cinderella&#8217;s castle. In <em>Animal Kingdom</em>, it&#8217;s the Tree of Life: a greatly oversized baobab tree, its trunk littered with wonderful sculptures of dozens of different animal species. (It&#8217;s worth noting, of course, that the tree is fake. Not that you could tell&#8230;)<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31793891892"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/353/31793891892_063d83207a_c.jpg" alt="Details from The Tree of Life" width="534" height="800" /></a><br />
Alex was already on the hunt for both pins, and the &#8220;mission&#8221;. We found it even before we reached the end of the bridge: we would become Wilderness Explorers (ala Russell from <em>Up</em>), and be given a detailed set of things that we had to accomplish to get our badges. It made the passport at Epcot look positively trivial. Alex was immediately excited &#8230; though the kids and I had to do the first badge, which was do the Wilderness Explorer pledge, because Alex felt a bit silly doing it.<br />
I mean, come on, we&#8217;re at Disney. It&#8217;s an <em>excuse</em> to be silly!<br />
We headed through Discovery Island, looking for the first badge, which was just left of the Tree: flamingoes. Lesser Flamingoes, to be specific. They were in there with dozens of white ibises, all vying for food. And the Wilderness Explorer Troop Leader who would test us was quite knowledgeable on both animals, even though the white ibises aren&#8217;t actually in the exhibit (they&#8217;re actually pests).<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31904394776"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/718/31904394776_d86d12180e_c.jpg" alt="Lesser Flamingoes" width="533" height="800" /></a><br />
We would quickly discover that the WE Troop Leaders (and many other cast members) who were around the animals knew a <em>lot</em> about those animals.<br />
We headed around, and wrapped around behind the Tree, looking for other animals. Right away, we saw a saddlebeaked stork &#8230; and then Choo Choo dropped her WE handbook (in which we were collecting the badges) into the exhibit. Thankfully, there was a small gap at the bottom, and Alex was able to fish out the book.<br />
But down the past a little way, Monkey did the same thing, except this time into a turtle pen (there were none in there at the time, thankfully), and we had to get cast members to help us get it back out. It was the last time one was lost.<br />
We headed across the bridge into &#8220;Africa&#8221;, one of the four major areas of the park (Africa, Asia, Dinoland USA, and Discovery Island). As we trooped across the bridge, I looked down the manmade river they&#8217;d built, and had to pinch myself: we were entering &#8220;Harambe&#8221;, and already my brain was telling me that we weren&#8217;t in <del>Kansas</del>Florida anymore.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31793882292"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/528/31793882292_97aecb21d5_c.jpg" alt="Port of Harambe" width="800" height="533" /></a><br />
The other side could just have easily been the other side of the world, save for the paved pathways.<br />
Our first FastPass was for the Kilimanjaro Safari, which would take us on a tour of <em>Animal Kingdom</em>&#8216;s animals, many of which sit in large, unfenced areas. But we were so early, I steered us towards the steam train.<br />
There&#8217;s a train that runs from &#8220;Harambe&#8221; station around in a loop to a conservation area called &#8220;Rafiki&#8217;s Planet Watch&#8221;, basically a biological station at the north end of the park that doubles as a surgery for small-to-medium sized animals, including things as large as a gorilla.<br />
The station is lined with unclaimed bags, signs warning about pickpockets and poachers, and the train looks old, abused, and the roof is stacked with all kinds of cargo. The locomotive, sadly, wasn&#8217;t steam; it was either gasoline or diesel, though it had a decent whistle. The seats, instead of facing forward or back, faced out to one side of the train; the other was closed over with shutters. This is to keep people from seeing the backstage roads and facilities that keep the <em>Animal Kingdom </em>running.<br />
The route is fairly short, but it allows you to see some of the larger animals (we saw a white rhino) in the more formal pens. When we arrived at the other station, we headed down the relatively short path to the Planet Watch building. Along the way, we stopped at two places, where we learned about certain kinds of monkeys (including my favourite, the Geoffroy&#8217;s marmoset), and another one where we earned another WE badge.<br />
The Planet Watch building houses some of the veterinary clinics, and they&#8217;re all glassed-walled for viewing. Some even encourage conversation (such as with the nutritional specialist). In the middle, there&#8217;s a larger space where animal &#8220;encounters&#8221; take place. One had just started as we arrived: an opossum.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31132037903"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/487/31132037903_629249827d_c.jpg" alt="Opossum encounter" width="800" height="533" /></a><br />
For we Canucks, an opossum is a bit of an odd thing to see. There aren&#8217;t any in Canada, so it&#8217;s pretty neat to witness. For Southern Americans, it about as common as urban raccoons, and about as welcome. Actually, probably a bit less: opossums have a rather intimidating mouth full of sharp teeth that they love to bear when confronted. And given their terrible eyesight, it&#8217;s something they do quite often.<br />
I also (finally) learned that the &#8220;dead possum&#8221; response has a purpose. While I knew that playing dead was to have potential predators leave, I never understood while a perfectly good-smelling (dead) animal would go to waste like that. But the opossum has a gland that lets out a fairly nasty smell that suggest rotten meat. Now I get it.<br />
The surgery ended up being active that day, working on a tiny bird (the name of which now escapes me) that had liver trouble, and the doctors wanted to know why. So at what can only be summed up as great cost, they brought in a single, tiny bird, to run an expensive procedure.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31904373666"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/775/31904373666_a602ef9dcb_c.jpg" alt="Open surgery" width="533" height="800" /></a><br />
In that moment, I gained a considerable amount of respect for Disney. While I&#8217;m not a fan of zoos in general, the dedication to a single bird (one of many of its kind) was a sign to me of the kind of care the animals must receive. And from what I saw of the other animals in their various habitats, it seemed to be far more humane than other zoos I&#8217;ve seen.<br />
Just outside the building was a petting zoo, featuring goats and sheep. It was quite telling to see that neither Monkey nor Choo Choo were interested in petting animals they&#8217;d seen dozens of times at petting zoos back home, when there were far more exotic animals to find.<br />
We returned on the train. As the train approached Harambe station, we passed by a &#8220;market&#8221; that we would later see. From the train, I had that abruptly familiar feeling: I&#8217;d seen scenes like that before, travelling through Russia and China. This was decidedly African, but the haphazard collection of market-like things were terribly real-feeling.<br />
The Kilimanjaro Safari is a fairly basic concept: put animals in controlled spaces (either by well-hidden walls, large gaps the animals will not cross, grating that hooved animals will not cross, or (presumably) some kind of invisible fencing. Oh, and feed the dangerous ones so they don&#8217;t feel a need to hunt.<br />
To get around the rather large space, they outfitted large offroad cargo trucks with bench seating, and run them constantly around a large, entirely artificial rutted &#8220;dirt&#8221; road, over a &#8220;rickety&#8221; bridge, and through areas that look far too real to believe. Of course, everything is Imagineered to the inch, to ensure both the safety of the passengers, and the animals.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31904359206/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/775/31904359206_2cbab1eedb_c.jpg" alt="Giraffes" width="533" height="800" /></a><br />
I saw more animals in the 30 minutes on the ride (hippos, wild dogs, wildebeest, giraffes, zebras, antelope, elephants, crocodiles, flamingos, cheetahs, rhinos, just to name a few) than I get to see the Calgary Zoo during any particular visit. While there are probably a couple of dozen trucks out on the range at any given time, you rarely see more than one or two due to the spacing and the curves. And you don&#8217;t see the infrastructure, try as you may. Because that would ruin the magic.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31904367806"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/340/31904367806_9b6d7f7645_c.jpg" alt="Kilimanjaro Safari" width="800" height="533" /></a><br />
With the return to the station, we offloaded and headed for lunch. We quickly found ourselves in the &#8220;market&#8221;, on the other side of the fence we had seen from the train. We found ourselves in a line, and started to debate on the meal of the day.<br />
As the kids decided what they would eat, I looked over in a corner between two of the buildings. It was probably hiding an access for the cast members, but there was no way Disney would allow a simple access to be &#8230; well, <em>simple</em>. It had to look like it belonged. It had to look real.<br />
There was a tree. A small one, but it looked like it could be from Africa. There was a blue bike, propped against the wall, as if one of the store owners had brought it that morning and left it there. Signs were attached to the wall, and addition words painted on. They did absolutely nothing in reality, but there was no question that their purpose was to sell you reality.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31904348816"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/696/31904348816_5e78126ce1_c.jpg" alt="A quiet corner" width="800" height="534" /></a><br />
Around us were &#8220;market&#8221; items, like water jugs, tubs, pottery, fabrics, and the like. The poles that rose above the market had (non-functional) wiring that exploded from (equally unused) electrical boxes, The tops of buildings looked like they hadn&#8217;t been plastered in a decade.<br />
Forget the Matrix. You want to question reality? Spend a week at <em>Walt Disney World</em>. It totally messes with your head.<br />
Tikka masala for Alex and I. The girls ate corn dogs (okay, the <em>least </em>region-appropriate food we&#8217;d seen all week, but &#8230; c&#8217;mon, <em>corn dogs</em>). The track record for our Disney lunches continued to impress.<br />
As we ate, we heard the sound of an instrument being played over (very well hidden) speakers. After some careful looking around, we spotted a man wielding a large, 21-stringed &#8220;kora&#8221;. He played the same tune in a long loop as he walked around, even swinging by our table, as I tried to understand how on Earth he&#8217;d managed to master something that looked so complicated.<br />
<a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31793473542/" title="Video: Playing for the crowd by Geoff S., on Flickr"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/565/31793473542_7a9b5dd950_c.jpg" width="800" height="450" alt="Video: Playing for the crowd"></a><script async src="https://embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script><br />
After lunch, we resumed the hunt for WE badges. Though we had another FastPass to attend to, far down in Dinoland USA. We took the opportunity to start from Africa, wind our way through Asia, stopping as needed along the way.<br />
When we reached the building that housed <em>Finding Nemo: The Musical</em>, I was moderately dismayed to see so many people already in the FastPass line. I was worried we wouldn&#8217;t get in. I, apparently, was an idiot. The theatre was massive. We had seats right down in front.<br />
The show is a condensed form of <em>Finding Nemo</em> (the movie), retold with large puppets, carried about on stage by actors who not only provide the voices, but also bring the puppets to life. The actors are very much part of the show, and you almost watch the actors as much as the puppets. And Disney (wisely) went with people who knew how to act with puppets, rather than merely looking the part. The actor running Marlin, for example, was no Brad Pitt. He even wore glasses. But he sang the part for all it was worth, and did a fairly decent Albert Brooks.<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31793815032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/5611/31793815032_01dc19ebee_c.jpg" alt="Finding Nemo, the Musical" width="800" height="600" /></a><br />
Amazingly enough, they even included Mr. Ray (a large puppet mounted to an adult-sized tricycle), the sharks (Bruce is still favourite), Crush (a huge puppet; Squirt was another actor who was suspended on wires), and even Nigel, the pelican (well, only his head, which to scale is massive compared to the fish).<br />
It might not have been Broadway, but I nothing to complain about the show. Considering how many times I&#8217;ve seen <em>Finding Nemo</em> (even before I had kids!), they did more than a fair job, doing the movie justice. Even if they downplayed the seagulls (MINE!) a little too much for my liking.<br />
Being on the edge of Dinoland USA, there was little reason not to go in. Alex was still on her mission, and I was a bit curious. As we entered, we saw a midway-like area that reminded Alex and I too much of the Stampede midway, which we wanted to avoid. Instead, we found a play area that was built to look like a dinosaur dig site. The girls were gone like a shot. It seemed a good time for a bit of a rest while the girls burned out some energy.<br />
Even something as simple as a play area got loads of attention: signs about dinosaurs, replicated artifacts, decent casts of dinosaur bones, places for the kids to discover, and of course, really big slides. I stayed in the shade while they ran around.<br />
Energy not dispersed, and Alex still itchy for WE badges, we suckered them out for ice cream (there was a stall not far away). Alex then continued on her mission, while the girls and I went for our last FastPass: DINOSAUR.<br />
Now I have to confess: I knew that this was likely going to scare the crap out of them. But I knew that a) they loved dinosaurs, and b) they liked a good ride. Monkey was a bit trepidatious, but Choo Choo was game. So we hit the front, held up our wrists, and went in.<br />
The intro video featured both Phylicia &#8220;Mrs. Huxtable&#8221; Rashad,  and Wallace &#8220;David Hodges from <em>C.S.I.</em>&#8221; Langham. We were going on a time travel trip to the ancient past to see dinosaurs. But Langham&#8217;s character had a different plan, sending us to mere moments before the asteroid put the final nail in the dinosaur&#8217;s coffin, to retrieve an Iguanodon. I giggled quietly, knowing what this meant.<br />
The time travel station looked about as legit as one could expect for a technology that doesn&#8217;t exist, and was loud, dark, and filled with things that had no apparent purpose. We climbed into the back row of our over-sized vehicle, buckled in, and off we went.<br />
I knew the kind of ride: it&#8217;s a large, tracked machine that has a three-axis platform that gets raised up and down, tilted left and right, and forward and backward, all of which is designed to give the impression that you&#8217;re moving much more quickly than you are.<br />
Into the tunnel we went, and after a moment, we were looking at dinosaurs, lit by black light, glowing and moving. Langham&#8217;s character was talking to us as we whipped around corners, and zipped this way and that. Of course, after mere moments, things started to go awry, the vehicle started lurching, a large carnivore started chasing us, and then the camera flash went off. (Of course, there&#8217;s a picture in the ride. I don&#8217;t have the copy, by the looks on the kids&#8217; faces are priceless.)<br />
r still hate me for that ride. And I had to promise never to do that to them again.<br />
We headed back to Discovery Island, heading to Africa again, to meet up with Alex. We stopped briefly at the Tree of Life for pictures, then found Alex just over the bridge.<br />
We headed for a last hurrah at getting our WE badges, heading into the Pangani Forest Exploration Trail. There were at least three more badges (there might have been more). The badge system closed down at 4:45pm, so we needed to hurry.<br />
At the gate heading onto the trail was our first badge: radio. This was paying attention to a repeating radio loop, listening for a certain keyword that we had to fill in on a form. That got the badge, and we were off to find the next thing. And that largely meant following the path signs, weaving through pavilions and aviaries, crossing over bridges, and passing through some pretty darn convincing Indian &#8220;ruins&#8221; (that&#8217;s the country, not the First Nations), all the while trying to find the hints we needed for the next badge.<br />
Along the way, we saw some lovely fish, zebras, meerkats, tigers (okay, <em>a</em> tiger), and some lowland gorillas. It was a decently long path that gave us plenty of room to view. And Disney, being the geniuses they are, had build the enclosure in such a way that there were no fences, no glass, nothing but air between us and our quarry. Except the tigers. There was thick glass for them. Because, tigers.<br />
Exiting the Trail, and our badges nearly complete, it became very clear that a) we weren&#8217;t getting the rest (it was too late), b) we were tight on time to meet anymore characters, and c) it was getting close to dinnertime. So having realized a), we figured out b), hoping to complete before our c) reservation at the <em>Rainforest Cafe</em>.<br />
The only character the girls had any interest in was Pocahontas, who conveniently (and somewhat inexplicably) was set up on the edge of Discovery Island. The line was quite short, but the clock was ticking steadily closer to our reservation, and I really didn&#8217;t want to lose out on a table. If the <em>Rainforest Cafe</em> at <em>Animal Kingdom</em> was as busy as the one at <em>Disney Springs</em>, there would have been the strong possibility that they&#8217;d drop our reservation if we were late.<br />
I left the camera with Alex and the girls, and headed to the <em>Cafe</em>. You can enter the <em>Cafe</em> from the park, but you still technically exit <em>Animal Kingdom</em> to do so. It seemed a little odd, but it made sense once I got there. The <em>Rainforest Cafe</em> there is huge, and locking it inside the park would necessarily lock out potential customers.<br />
But despite its size, I couldn&#8217;t get the table until Alex and the girls arrived. Rules are rules, it seems. When we were finally seated, the hostess did indicate that the particular <em>Rainforest Cafe</em> is the largest in the world. Though as I walked through it afterwards, it didn&#8217;t seem dramatically so.<br />
It was Monkey and Choo Choo&#8217;s first visit to a <em>Rainforest Cafe</em>, so there was the requisite looking around, not to mention the mild shock at the thunder and lightning (I was disappointed to find that the location didn&#8217;t have the tropical rain that had been in the ones I&#8217;ve been to), though the fascination did wear off fairly quickly. After all, we were at <em>Walt Disney World</em>, and the <em>Rainforest Cafe</em> animatronics just don&#8217;t stack up.<br />
At dinner, we dropped the bomb. The week had already been surprise after surprise, but we had one left to lower on the girls. The following morning was going to be early, much earlier than any other day we&#8217;d already done, including our flight out! They had to be up early so there was time to eat, get on the bus, and get to the <em>Magic Kingdom</em> in time for their appointment at the <em>Bibbidi Bobbidi Boutique</em>. Their excitement was dialled well past &#8220;11&#8221;.<br />
By the end of a fairly decent dinner, Alex was done, and wanted to head back to the resort. I still wanted to see the Tree of Life at night (I knew there was a light show). The girls were hell-bent to find their elusive stuffies that they were very locked into, so wanted to go with me. Then Choo Choo fortuitously discovered her long-lost (but not forgotten) Bananas stuffie in the <em>Rainforest Cafe</em> shop. This time, I couldn&#8217;t say no.<br />
We raced into the park, fighting against the stream of people heading out of the park, arriving fairly quickly at Discovery Island. I immediately was struck by the loveliness of the light show on the Tree of Life. I mean, it&#8217;s a <em>tree.</em> Artificial or not, how good could it possibly look?<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/31824812921/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/5597/31824812921_4bcc4d1fa3_c.jpg" alt="Animal Kingdom light show" width="800" height="533" /></a><br />
The stores on Discovery Island were missing the stuffie that Monkey was looking for &#8230; a monkey. (Because &#8230; monkeys?) She recalled that it had been out in Africa when she&#8217;d seen it, so we headed off to the left as we had several times that day, and rushed to the stalls that I was almost certain were already closed. Unlike <em>Epcot</em>, <em>Animal Kingdom</em> closes &#8220;early&#8221; due to the actual animals that need their rest. So it was no surprise to find the the stalls already locked up.<br />
That didn&#8217;t stop us from checking every still-open store on the way back to the front gate, and ever stall thereafter. Which, as it turned out, was the right thing. In the very last store before the bus stop, Monkey found her monkey, and all was right with the world again. (And Daddy didn&#8217;t look quite as much the jackass for saying &#8220;no&#8221; earlier.)<br />
We piled onto the bus found for the Art of Animation Resort, and packed into the rear. The girls sat while I stood. A large group was there with us, and even before the bus started away from the gate, they&#8217;d started belting out &#8220;Jingle Bells&#8221;. They knew a few verses of it, too, which was rare to hear (since most people know only the chorus). &#8220;Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer&#8221; came next, and had about half of the bus singing.<br />
Before someone else could start the third song, Choo Choo and Monkey both started singing &#8220;Feliz Navidad&#8221;. I kind of wondered how many people would join in &#8212; we&#8217;re decidedly slanted to Spanish, after all &#8212; but before I knew it, nearly the whole bus was singing along.<br />
Well, except for the &#8220;Prospero año y Felicidad&#8221; bit. Most people don&#8217;t know those words. But pretty much everyone was calling out &#8220;from the bottom of my heart&#8221; as the bus pulled into the stop at the resort.<br />
We went back to our room, and rested. The following day was going to be a long one. And after an episode of &#8220;Great American Bake-Off&#8221;, we all hit the sack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2016/12/disney-world-2016-animal-kingdom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3575</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Blitzkrieg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-blitzkrieg</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas Blitzkrieg"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of sleep than from trying to do too much.<br />
Heck, it even makes me feel a bit young! Ish. Sort of.<br />
Except for the prolonged yawning, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-3199"></span>Tuesday evening, I went on a mission to find &#8220;Santa&#8221; presents for Monkey and Choo Choo, for a party Evans Hunt was holding for all the company&#8217;s children. I failed miserably for them (Alex would later prove to be a much better Santa in this regard), though it wasn&#8217;t a total wash for Christmas as a whole.<br />
Wednesday night was wrapping, notably a batch of presents from my sister that came in sans trimmings and trappings. My folding skills got a dusting off.<br />
Thursday was the Evans Hunt End of the World / Last Pitch party, our annual fest with clients and spouses. I honestly feel like I leave these parties too early, and I miss out on the good stories. I got the backfill the following day, and was moderately relieved to have missed some of the trouble.<br />
Friday was something slightly different, but very exciting (for me). Along with Tamara, Adrian, and Barb, I went to go see <em>The Hobbit: An Expected Journey</em>. It had been 11 years (I&#8217;d thought it only 10 at the time, but I just double-checked) since Tamara, Adrian, myself, and a couple of others had sat and waited for hours in the hallways at the Famous Players Chinook theatre (now Scotiabank Cineplex) to wait for the opening night of <em>The Lord of the Rings: Fellowship of the Ring</em>. A lot has happened in those years since&#8230;<br />
Eleven years later, I still love movies like that: long, and epic.<br />
I passed out nearly as soon as I got home, mostly due to exhaustion. (I&#8217;d also been running around before getting to the theatre, trying to find a Car2Go that I could actually get into &#8212; their system has been having issues for a couple of weeks, now.)<br />
Saturday morning was a blur of surreptitious present wrapping for the afternoon&#8217;s Santa visit, helping/forcing the kids to clean up the basement, making breakfast, and something else that I now forget. Then it was a blur of lunch-making, dressing (notably the kids in their nice dresses), and then loading into the car for the trip down to Evans Hunt for the party.<br />
This was the first office party for kids that I&#8217;ve ever attended, at any company. For reasons I&#8217;m sure someone much smarter than me could explain, Evans Hunt employees have a statistically high number of kids under the age of 10, and I&#8217;m willing to bet at least half are two or younger. At any rate, the fact that all of these kids existed was what led to the scheduling of the party, which we parents were quite happy for.<br />
The sixth floor &#8212; the new part of the office &#8212; was chosen for the venue. The large boardroom was co-opted for gingerbread man decorating and crafts, the main space for what ended up being punch-clown tackling, with a large comfy chair set aside for the Big Man.<br />
The kids rapidly multiplied, until the point where I think there may have been almost more kids than adults &#8230; though there have been more adults acting like kids after a while.<br />
When Santa arrived (Santa was a friend of a friend who does this professionally), the kids went crazy &#8230; and Choo Choo almost never left his side, utterly desperate for, well, not so much a present as just talking to him. Quite the reverse of Monkey, who was terrified of Santa for the first three and a half years of life.<br />
Monkey, interestingly, was the first one called up. She happily hopped up on his lap, talked a bit, got her present, and got down (with a hurried &#8220;thank you&#8221;) before going off to find out what the present was. (For the record, &#8220;Santa&#8221; was brilliant at finding things the kids seem to love.)<br />
Poor Choo Choo then had to endure most of the other kids coming next, one after another. She sat, enthralled, desperately eager to get on his lap. I managed to drag her away after a little while to drink more of her juice, when suddenly Santa produced the present. Choo Choo was off my lap in the blink of an eye, and raced over to Santa as fast as she could. She happily jumped up, and promptly asked for a &#8220;plane&#8221;.<br />
I have no idea where this &#8220;plane&#8221; thing was coming from. It&#8217;s now what she wants for Christmas. She was moderately disappointed at the <em>Stella and Sam</em> book she got instead.<br />
Party over, we headed home so Alex and I could shower and change for the next event of the day, her office Christmas party. Grandma appeared shortly after 5:00, which was about the time I dropped dinner on the table for them, mostly so they could eat and not bother Alex and I long enough that we could get ready for going out.<br />
We were gone just before 6:00, stopped at the hospital for Alex to get the tickets, and at the Ceili&#8217;s at Southland before 6:20. We sat at a table with Sarah, one of Alex&#8217;s regular co-workers, and Casey, who was one of the co-workers until she left to work at the new South hospital. It was the best move, since it was a good chance for us to chat with people we already knew.<br />
We left by 9:00.<br />
But lest ye think we were done &#8230; think again. Our destination? Toys &#8216;R Us. And not one, but two of them &#8212; one less than five minutes from the restaurant, and the other way up in the north. We didn&#8217;t get home until nearly 11:45. I got to bed a half-hour later after taking Grandma home.<br />
Sunday. Today. Yet more stuff.<br />
Mostly me doing my Christmas shopping, notably picking up things for Alex, and picking up the Playmobile toys for the girls that Grandma and I had found on Friday.<br />
And then we went to Zoo Lights.<br />
We&#8217;ve done this many times before, but this year we opted to try something a little differently. We opted to try going by C-Train, now that the new West LRT is open, and happens to run from here out to the Zoo. It seemed like a good idea, and we were &#8212; at least initially &#8212; excited to try out the new route.<br />
For the record, the trip is a minimum of 35 minutes (45 if you happen to <em>just</em> miss the train, which we did on the outbound). And although it was only -3, it somehow felt quite a bit colder, which we all seemed to notice. Thankfully the kids were well-bundled, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad for them.<br />
We got home at 9:00, well after some people&#8217;s bedtimes.<br />
Like mine. Or at least, that&#8217;s what it feels like. &#8216;Cuz after all this, I feel really tired.<br />
Sleep. Need sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four fun-filled days</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=four-fun-filled-days</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 03:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dim sum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Four fun-filled days"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and notably you, Monkey.<br />
The last four days have been a lot of fun. Maybe even too much fun. Both of us are pretty pooped. You went to bed and for the first time in a long while, there wasn&#8217;t hours of chatter from your room. I think you pretty much passed out. I won&#8217;t be too far behind you, I think, but I do wish to describe the fun that we&#8217;ve shared.<br />
&#8216;Cuz, frankly, I&#8217;m not sure how the heck I survived it all&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2688"></span>First off was Canada Day. This year, Mommy and I decided to try a visit at Heritage Park. If you got there early enough, you got a free pancake breakfast. It seemed like a fun thing to do. And it probably would have been more fun if it had been a few degrees warmer &#8212; it was rather chilly for the first day of July.<br />
Still, you had a lot of fun. Once we&#8217;d gobbled down the pancakes, we went and got ride tickets. You swung on a vintage ship-styled swing, rode the big steam train around the park, went on the paddlewheeler out in Glenmore Reservoir (although you barely stopped moving the entire time, necessitating me following you around the entire time), and went on the merry-go-round (you demanded to ride the white horse).<br />
You ate a pretzel, and drank some frozen lemonade with me. We saw the farm animals (you mooed at the cows, and nearly had your bright red Crocs eaten by a misguided horse). Then we went through Gasoline Alley. By this point, you were tired and got fairly cranky, so we all opted to go home.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762441701(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762451847(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762453683(square)[/flickr]<br />
Mommy wanted to go visit with Grandpa for a week, and had to take Choo Choo with her. (Choo Choo&#8217;s still nursing, so she goes wherever Mommy goes.) But &#8230; well, Monkey, all me to be rather honest for a moment &#8212; travelling with you lately requires a lot of high-test drugs to keep people calm. Either you or us, it doesn&#8217;t matter. But Mommy travelling with you and Choo Choo wasn&#8217;t even discussed as an option, and Mommy really wanted to go without all of us in tow. (You&#8217;ll understand this years from now, when you have a near-3 year old.)<br />
Of course, what all that means is, it was just you and me, kid. And we got off to it before Mommy and Choo Choo&#8217;s plane had taken off.<br />
Our first stop was the Galaxie Diner on 11th St., not far from Grandma&#8217;s house. There we enjoyed a filling breakfast, because we had a long day of chasing trains ahead of you. I hadn&#8217;t chased a train since before you were born, and I was itching to go out and take pictures. I figured you might like to see a big train in motion, and when my friend Graham told me CP 2816 was going out to Banff on 2 July, I couldn&#8217;t resist.<br />
After breakfast, we went home just long enough to get a few things together (like my camera), and then we went searching for our first place to wait. I originally thought of a place known as Keith, which is roughly where Stoney Trail crosses the Bow River. But as we came down Sarcee Trail towards the highway, I spied an even better location: where the train tracks cross 32nd Ave NW. It would give me an easy access for photography, a decent backdrop, and not far from the highway to get back out again.<br />
We ended up having to wait longer than I would have liked. One thing you&#8217;ll learn, kiddo, is that when you chase trains, you have to be patient and wait. A lot. Even though Graham was sending me text messages on the train&#8217;s status, it didn&#8217;t come quickly. We saw a freight train have to wait for CP 2816, too. But eventually, we got the note that she was heading west. Before long, we could hear its whistle echo through the valley. It came towards us, barrelling along as fast as it could, belching out black smoke.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762469809(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763109230(square)[/flickr]<br />
For a moment, I saw myself in you. When I was your age (maybe a little older), your granddad (my daddy) used to take my family (Nana, Auntie Cathy, and me) to the train tracks near our house, to watch another steam locomotive &#8212; CN 6060 &#8212; come racing by, huge clouds of black smoke filling up the sky. It used to scare the hell out of me. Of course, I look back at that now and I feel really glad that I did see that &#8212; it&#8217;s a fond memory. I hope maybe one day, it is for you, too.<br />
We hit the road and headed out to a place out towards the mountains called Ozada. You were asleep before we were outside city limits, and slept all the way there. Ozada is on the Stoney Indian reserve, and is one of Canadian Pacific&#8217;s old stations for servicing steam locomotives. (The concrete pylons for the coaling and water towers are still visible.) Today, it&#8217;s little more than a siding in the middle of nowhere, just off the highway. And we waited there because Graham had told me CP 2816 would be stopping there for servicing as well.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762477071(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762477937(square)[/flickr]<br />
We were not disappointed. We saw the train come in slowly, pass by, and stop in the siding. After it had passed, we drove to the other end of the siding, and watched it race westward. (The train was about two hours late, so they had a reason to move quickly.) We drove out to the highway, and saw the train&#8217;s smoke as we drove by it on the highway. We saw some other people we&#8217;d seen back in Calgary stop at the side of the highway to take more pictures.<br />
Finally, we stopped in Banff, and waited about halfway between the station and Bankhead. We had to wait a long, long time before we saw CP 2816&#8217;s lights. As CP 2816 was going on show at the station, the train stopped again not far from us for one last servicing before going in. This gave us a fantastic view, although the whistles did give you a bit of a scare &#8212; they were quite loud.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762480609(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763119200(square)[/flickr]<br />
After meeting up with Graham at the station (it seemed only fair to thank him in person for the information), we had lunch at Bruno&#8217;s, and then headed back to Calgary. You slept from Canmore all the way home.<br />
On Saturday, you and I went to the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market, mostly so you could go to the jumping castle &#8212; probably your most favourite thing in town (after me, of course). You ate your mixed berry crepe almost as fast as I could eat my ham and cheese crepe. I swear it&#8217;s the only thing you eat quickly &#8212; everything else requires a pry bar and a shovel&#8230;<br />
When I asked what you wanted to do next, you said: &#8220;I want [to see the] giraffes!&#8221; So off we went to the zoo. We went though the dinosaurs, then over to the giraffes, zipped by the gorillas, and spent a lot of time at the playground (you love the playground, there). Then it was into the Australian  pavilion  (I was devastated to find that the nocturnal animal area is permanently closed), through the monkey house, and then over to the elephants (where we had hot dogs), zipped over to the carousel (just opened), before going through the Canadian Wilds (where you were completely obsessed with the prairie dogs).<br />
[flickr]photo:4763125998(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762491661(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762511327(square)[/flickr]<br />
For dinner, I took you to a Japanese restaurant. I found that your chopstick skills had degraded quite a lot &#8212; we&#8217;ll have to work on that. But you ate half of the edamame, a couple of avocado rolls, and even a piece of hamachi sashimi (well, it was nigiri sushi, but it was just plain easier to give you just the fish). You wouldn&#8217;t touch the miso soup (I&#8217;ll work on that, too). For your first shot, I was very proud of you.<br />
The next morning, we walked over to the #2 bus stop. You were ecstatic about riding the bus. I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s from singing <em>The Wheels On The Bus</em> so much.   We went to the Silver Dragon restaurant, where we met up with my friend Tamara and her husband, Dan. There we ate dim sum (Mommy was rather annoyed that we went without her). It was so good. You ate buns, and pork dumplings, and quite a lot of deep fried squid. Yes, you ate squid. I kid you not. Mind you, as I&#8217;ve said to others, the squid tastes a lot like scrambled eggs. So I told you it was scrambled eggs. You couldn&#8217;t get enough.<br />
Following dim sum, you and I walked along the river over to Eau Claire Market (which really isn&#8217;t a market anymore &#8212; it&#8217;s mostly businesses and empty store space &#8212; nothing like it used to be), where you and I saw Toy Story 3. I cried a bit. You seemed to like it a lot, though. Especially anything with Woody.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762516489(square)[/flickr]<br />
In fact, you like Woody and Jesse (the Yodelling Cowgirl) so much, and because the Calgary Stampede is just around the corner, we walked over to Stephen Avenue afterwards to try and get you a cowgirl outfit. You&#8217;ve got the boots and jeans, but you need a hat and a shirt. Sadly, we were less than successful &#8212; no-one seemed to have a cowgirl shirt in your size.<br />
On the way home, much to our luck, we ran into Grandma on the bus (she was coming to our house, anyway &#8212; we just had really good timing). You had some fun with Grandma while I went off to get something for us to eat for dinner.<br />
In fact, I&#8217;m so tired from all of this excitement that it&#8217;s taken me a while to write all of this. But I hope you had fun, Monkey. I know I did.<br />
And now, I need to go to bed. &#8216;Cuz I&#8217;m really, really, <em>really</em> tired.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2688</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
