<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>volcanoes &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/volcanoes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 15:53:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>12 things I miss about Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 15:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s just shy of three months since we left Costa Rica. Many people still ask us what it&#8217;s like to be back, if we&#8217;re happy to be back, and if we&#8217;ve acclimatised yet. There&#8217;s no quick or easy answer to all of that, as we&#8217;re not dealing with something as simple as changing from one &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "12 things I miss about Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s just shy of three months since we left Costa Rica. Many people still ask us what it&#8217;s like to be back, if we&#8217;re happy to be back, and if we&#8217;ve acclimatised yet. There&#8217;s no quick or easy answer to all of that, as we&#8217;re not dealing with something as simple as changing from one temperature to another. As anyone will tell you, moving to an entirely different country (outside of North America) involves more than a physical location. Costa Rica was more than just a place, it was a way of life, and an experience that has changed the way I live now.<br />
Almost right away, we missed some things, though most of that was due to the roughly 40 degree Celsius shift in temperature. Other things soon made themselves known, each time with the all-too-familiar pang of loss and regret.<br />
But like when we moved down to Costa Rica, this is just something we&#8217;ll have to get used to.<br />
<span id="more-2629"></span>Now just to be clear, there are two parts to this: things I miss, and things that I should miss but don&#8217;t (at least, not yet). I&#8217;m splitting it up this way just to avoid some of the obvious questions that are bound to appear. C&#8217;mon, I know you guys a little bit, y&#8217;know&#8230;</p>
<h3><strong>Things I Miss</strong></h3>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Fresh fruit</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">As I&#8217;d mentioned a few times before, Costa Rica has fresh fruit. I know that sounds like an utterly silly statement, but unless you&#8217;ve been to a tropical country, you have no concept what fresh fruit is really like. None. Even the best organic produce you get at your local hippie market doesn&#8217;t hold a sniff to the stuff I got at the farmer&#8217;s markets in Costa Rica. The &#8220;reject&#8221; bananas (the &#8220;good&#8221; ones are all exported) were sweeter and lusher than any banana I&#8217;ve ever had here, the strawberries were worth killing over, and the papayas so good that I might never be able to eat them again (seriously).</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Unbelievable greenery</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I live in Calgary, where it barely rains. We get a nice green spring, but usually by mid-July everything&#8217;s starting to dry out. When fall hits, the primary colour is brown. We get white in the winter, at least when the snow is covering the aforementioned brownness.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">In Costa Rica, it&#8217;s green. Always. Everywhere. Even on the tops of volcanoes, it&#8217;s green. There&#8217;s no effort for it to be green &#8212; that&#8217;s just the way it is. It happens naturally. No additives, no preservatives. It&#8217;s <em>overwhelmingly green</em>. There&#8217;s no comparison for the green. And now that brown has fully set in up here, I find myself missing it more than ever.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Volcanoes (but not earthquakes)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Speaking of volcanoes, I&#8217;ve had a thing for geology since I was a kid, and love seeing volcanoes. Especially at a distance (the active ones, any way). I&#8217;ve been fortunate to see a few volcanoes, notably in Hawaii, but also in Costa Rica (and went up Poas just a couple of days before a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/01/hell-of-a-good-scare/">6.2 earthquake levelled a nearby town</a>). There aren&#8217;t any decent volcanoes in Canada, all of them are either dormant or entirely extinct.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Speaking of earthquakes, I rather like Calgary. It&#8217;s extremely stable. Not necessary free of tremors, but far enough to avoid anything nasty. I like that.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Price includes taxes</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">One pet peeve I always had with the North American pricing system was that the price you see is rarely the price you pay. Taxes are thrown on top, and usually service fees on that, too.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">In Costa Rica, IVI (the tax) is rolled into everything, including your restaurant menu prices (divided into two columns). There&#8217;s no question what something costs, even if the price is in $USD (which it sometimes is, depending on how deep you&#8217;ve dived into tourist areas). I miss that kind of transparency.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Sun in the morning</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Although it bugged me at the time, I now officially miss sun in the morning. The sun is still rising here, and when my alarm goes off it&#8217;s still dark. It&#8217;s something I came to appreciate a lot, as it really made things much nicer. That said, I&#8217;m going to be very happy for the late evening sun come June&#8230;</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Not wearing pants</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Costa Rica, duh, is warm. So I rarely ever wore pants &#8212; shorts were my mainstay for a year and a half. I hate wearing pants. I hate wearing shoes (instead of sandals). And I really, really, <em>really</em> hate wearing socks.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Monkeys (and wildlife in general)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">No, I&#8217;m not saying I don&#8217;t like seeing deer, or moose, or anything else common in our northern tracts. But I do miss seeing wild parakeets, vibrantly colourful birds, and especially the monkeys roaming the treetops. There&#8217;s nothing like monkeys up here, save for zoos.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Driving with the window down &#8230; all year</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I only realised this last weekend, but man I miss driving with the window down! You can&#8217;t do that up here when it&#8217;s 20 below! (Well, I suppose you could, but then you&#8217;re just asking for trouble.) There&#8217;s nothing like being able to go down a street at any time of the day or night, with the window down. That kind of fresh air is just amazing.<br />
<strong></strong></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Dos Piños (and ice cream)</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px"><strong></strong>Dos Piños is the major dairy producer in Costa Rica, and makes pretty much everything that you can make from milk. Of particular note were their ice cream products. I don&#8217;t know what it is, but Costa Rican ice cream (Dos Piños and Pops, at least that I found) is fantastic. It&#8217;s wonderfully creamy, and not filled with a lot of crap (which seems common in North American ice creams). It got to the point where I was having one a day, on walks with Jason and Ed.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">Batidos</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">A &#8220;batido&#8221; is (more or less) a blended fruit drink. Not with ice &#8212; just fruit, mixed with either water or milk. (Milk was my favourite version.) I know I can make them here with whatever fruit I get my hands on, but as you already know (from my first item), it&#8217;s just not the same without fresh Costa Rican fruit. I liked batidos for the fact that it was fruit, it was tasty, and often filling. It was a great alternative to syrupy drinks, or even a coffee if I wasn&#8217;t in the mood.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">You&#8217;re from Canada? So am I!!</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">This one sounds silly, but it&#8217;s true &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing like finding a fellow Canuck (or insert your own nationality, I&#8217;m sure the same is true of other countries) when you&#8217;re abroad. I&#8217;ve been fortunate to have this happen in a few places, and even made some friends that way. It&#8217;s not to say that I can&#8217;t make friends with my fellow Canucks up here, but meeting someone abroad and sharing your experiences is very different than striking up a conversation while on a bus.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">My friends</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Last, but probably most importantly, I miss my friends. The people I knew well, who I worked with, the ones who lived near me, the ones who shared in the experience, the people who asked how I was and were a significant part of my life, and especially the ones so kind as to drive me to and from work every day. I feel exceedingly distant from them now, not just in distance, but because I might never see some of them ever again.<br />
<strong></strong></p>
<h3><strong>Things I Don&#8217;t Miss (Yet)</strong></h3>
<p>Now you&#8217;re probably wondering why some things didn&#8217;t appear in that list. Well, there are a few things that I don&#8217;t miss, at least not yet.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The heat</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I have never liked the heat, at least not for long periods of time. Once in a while, for a couple of hours, I can hack. Even full days are a bit much for me, and dragging that out into weeks? HA! Not a chance. Strange as it sounds, I&#8217;ll take the cold over the heat any day.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Just so long as I can visit the heat once in a while&#8230;</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The constant temperatures in the valley</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">The Central Valley in Costa Rica is consistent in the way you can&#8217;t even imagine. 27 degrees Celsius is the daily high, and 15 degrees is the daily low. Every day. <em>Every</em>. <em>Single</em>. <em>Day</em>. (It does vary a little bit from time to time, but the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mode_(statistics)">mode</a> is pretty much 27/15.)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Now, I know what you&#8217;re thinking: that sounds heavenly! You never have to stare at weather forecasts! But you also never get to see seasons like we do up here. I missed fall and spring (and especially winter). You can handle only so much perfection before you start to go a little wonky, lemme tell ya.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The beaches</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">I know, I know, again you&#8217;re thinking I&#8217;m totally batty (and maybe I am). But I don&#8217;t really miss the beaches. That&#8217;s not to say I don&#8217;t like beaches &#8212; I love &#8217;em! But going to the beach was never trivial, and involved far more effort than I care to think about. So much so that, well, now I look back and I think that while I&#8217;m glad to have gone, I don&#8217;t really have any burning desire to visit another one anytime soon.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The beer</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Okay, first off, I loved <a href="http://www.imperialcerveza.com/">Imperial</a>. Truly. But Costa Rica has a limited selection of beer, and about half of them are pretty darn close to the same thing with a different label. Up here, I can lose <em>hours</em> staring at a beer menu (yes, there is such a thing as a beer menu), or standing in the refrigerated room at any of the billion-or-so liquor stores in Calgary, trying to decide what to try next. That&#8217;s a level of selection I missed dearly while I was in Costa Rica, and am very happy to have it back.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px">The coffee</h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Before you freak out, there&#8217;s a really simple reason why I don&#8217;t miss Costa Rica coffee: we brought a lot of it back home with us. When we run out? Well, that&#8217;s another blog post&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/03/12-things-i-miss-about-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2629</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A (wet) birthday vacation</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-wet-birthday-vacation</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 04:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, I just turned 37 &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit. It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A (wet) birthday vacation"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/07/im-not-old/">I just turned 37</a> &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit.<br />
It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I doubt you&#8217;ll ever see that much rain ever again.<br />
<span id="more-1464"></span>The planning for this little sojourn was long, convoluted, and more than a little painful. Especially given all that I was looking for was a few days away from Santa Ana, to see something new in Costa Rica, and to spend time with my family &#8212; something I don&#8217;t get to do nearly enough of, which is something I deeply regret with each passing day.<br />
Ultimately, it was decided that we&#8217;d go to Arenal. This would be your second time to the area, and Mommy and my third trip. (It will likely be our last for a very long time. I&#8217;m now officially quite tired of Arenal.) I had told Nana that she&#8217;d get to see a volcano (and hopefully see it erupt at night), that we&#8217;d stay at a really nice place, and that the Arenal area was fantastic.<br />
Given <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/">our previous trip to Arenal</a> (and the one before that), it seemed a fairly decent and honest thing to say. It would appear, however, that Uncle Murphy had also come along for the ride. You remember Uncle Murphy &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/04/dear-murphy-fuck-off-and-die/">he&#8217;s the one who takes our plans and ruins them every time</a>.<br />
The trip up was reasonably nice. You fell asleep along the way, despite playing with Mommy quite a lot, somewhere around the Los Angeles cloud forest. Nana was watching all the hills and valleys, lush with rainfall, while I watched for all the lunatic drivers. I&#8217;m not used to driving such distances during the week &#8212; I&#8217;m usually at work worrying about network traffic, not oncoming cars.  You woke up only after a short pee break somewhere north of La Tigra.<br />
We arrived in La Fortuna somewhere around 14:00, and I rather foolishly thought it would be a good idea to check in to our hotel first, rather than do the smart thing, which was eat. You will learn, Monkey, that your father is often none-too-bright and does some really stupid things. (Mommy will remind you of this quite often, I&#8217;m sure.) We finally got to the restaurant somewhere near 14:30, and didn&#8217;t eat until nearly 15:00.<br />
Given that your father (that would be me) had hoped for a really nice dinner that evening, it wasn&#8217;t exactly the wisest thing. I made it even less wise when we went in search of the ice cream shop Mommy and I had found when we&#8217;d first gone to Arenal in 2005 for Mommy&#8217;s birthday. It wasn&#8217;t where we thought it would be (it had moved), but it was nice. We put you in a little kid&#8217;s ride that looked like a double-decker bus. You didn&#8217;t like it one bit.<br />
Returning to our hotel &#8212; the <a href="http://arenalparaiso.com/">Arenal Paraiso</a> (where we had a nice little two-suite cabin, ironically number #404) &#8212; both you and I went down for a short nap. You were a little overdue, and I was plain wiped. (The last many weeks of work have sapped much of my energy, prompting the time off, and the drive had taken a big punch out of me, too.) Mommy woke us up at 17:00.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737015049[/flickr]<br />
I had decided that we would eat at The Springs, a new hotel that had opened in the Arenal area only eight months earlier. My friends (and co-workers) Mark and Denise had stayed there a month or so ago, and swore the quality couldn&#8217;t be beat. They neglected to also tell us the state of the road, which was something near &#8220;unpassable&#8221;. (It&#8217;s a wonder they could build the place with roads that bad.) The three kilometre(-ish) trip took nearly 20 minutes, and was very bumpy.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737020375[/flickr]<br />
The hotel is right out of Disney World in terms of engineering, marvel, appearance, and professionalism. (Hopefully by the time you actually read this, Monkey, you&#8217;ll have been to Disney World and have some idea what the heck I&#8217;m talking about.) Due to my previous mistake, I didn&#8217;t get the dinner I wanted. Instead, we had the buffet (this was mostly to benefit your current eating habits, I should point out). It was very good, and the service was beyond outstanding.<br />
(A note to anyone thinking of going to the Arenal area: If you can afford it, <a href="http://www.thespringscostarica.com/">I highly recommend The Springs Resort and Spa</a>, it is truly amazing.)<br />
That night, as we all laid in bed, Uncle Murphy arrived to join us. Along with near-three solid days of torrential rain. It was also the first of three very sleepless nights for me.<br />
The next morning, we drove down to the restaurant for dinner. We drove because the rain would have soaked us to the bone, and because Nana would have had trouble walking that far on a rain-slicked road. The buffet was typical Costa Rican, with gallo pinto, fruit (papaya, pineapple, and watermelon), scrambled eggs, and various breads. Mommy, Nana, and I each had two cups of coffee.<br />
The problem was what to do with our day. It was, after all, raining quite a lot. So we decided the only thing to try was do some shopping. We headed into La Fortuna, hitting a woodwork studio, children&#8217;s clothing store, two or three souvenir shops, and you and Mommy ran up and down a ramp three times. The rain becoming quite the hindrance, we returned to the car to seek more adventure.<br />
Again with the brilliant planning, I thought we&#8217;d search out a German bakery that I&#8217;d read about in the Tico Times a few months ago. All I knew was that it was west of Fortuna along the shores of Lake Arenal. Which, in theory, is enough. And based on what I saw on maps, looked to be pretty straight-forward.<br />
Right?<br />
Well, one thing Costa Rica maps are notorious for is the lack of detail &#8212; notably when the map indicates a straight (or relatively straight) line, but the actual road is weavy and windy, and what should take no more than 30 minutes ends up being an hour-long trip. So about 20 minutes into the trip, we turned around and headed back. (Mommy had a massage appointment at 13:00, and we didn&#8217;t want her to miss it.)<br />
Instead, I (again, using my ever-so-powerful intellect) decided that we&#8217;d do lunch at the Arenal Lodge, which was just before the road over the dam. The rain kept pouring, and we were traveling up a steep, wet, mossy, and windy road barely three kilometres long that took us about 10 minutes to travel. Thankfully, we have four-wheel drive on our little Suzuki.<br />
Lunch was rather disappointing. The Lodge might be a neat place (it&#8217;s VERY out of the way), but the food is something less-than-desirable in my book. (My caesar salad was watery and lacking in flavour, and my ceviche tasted too much like fish and not enough like ceviche.) And it rained. A lot. To the point where when it was time to leave, I went to get the car rather than subject the three of you to walking through it.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737820576[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737825284[/flickr]<br />
While Mommy went to her massage, you and I went to splash around in the pool. It would be the only time you and I would go swimming over the last five days, sadly. I had hoped for much, much more than that. When Mommy returned, we all headed back up to the cabin so you could have a nap.<br />
Mommy got a recommendation for a restaurant downtown in La Fortuna called <a href="http://www.donrufino.com/">Don Rufino</a>. From the outside, it&#8217;s not the fanciest-looking place &#8212; in fact, it looks like every other bar in La Fortuna. But the food &#8230; the food! I was beside myself. I ordered a tuna dish that came with jumbo shrimp. Even though there were no vegetables, I was in heaven. (I&#8217;d been wanting a tuna for a very long time.) I think the only one who wasn&#8217;t over the moon with their dinner was you, Monkey.<br />
It rained all through dinner, all that night, and right into the next morning.<br />
We had thought that it might be fun to take Nana out to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>. Which was a risky venture, given the rain, but there&#8217;s very little to do in Arenal that doesn&#8217;t involve going outside. The drive involves a 8-9 kilometre-long, very rutted, very pot-holed, very bumpy road. Nana wasn&#8217;t particularly thrilled with it. (You almost fell asleep twice.) But once again, Mommy and my &#8220;Rain Luck&#8221; kicked in, and for the time we were at the Conservatory, it didn&#8217;t rain. We even learned a few more things thanks to a couple of volunteers from Seattle who could give us a bit more information we didn&#8217;t have last time.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737830482[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737834892[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737047843[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737055589[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737855464[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737087559[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3740775171[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3741617198[/flickr]<br />
It was raining by the time we got back to the main road. Mommy and I had booked a zip-line for that afternoon, but somewhere 12:45 became 13:15 (or vice versa) and we ended up missing our trip. It rained all that afternoon. In fact, while you were napping, the rain came down so hard that the gutters overflowed and we literally had waterfalls come off the roof. I became horribly depressed about the weather, missing the zip-line, not being able to do anything else, not being able to sleep, and so forth.<br />
[flickr]photo:3741594030[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was at Don Rufino again, not having any other better idea (and I&#8217;d ruled out eating at the hotel). It was the bright spot of my day. You didn&#8217;t eat at all.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737094433[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737893582[/flickr]<br />
Rain. All night.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737902800[/flickr]<br />
The next morning Mommy and I were supposed to go on our re-booked zip-line. But the non-stop rain was putting that to an end, once and for all. Despite being here a year, I have yet to actually zip-line through the canopy. At the rate I&#8217;m going, I might never get a chance.<br />
I was so put off by the weekend that I basically forced us to breakfast, so we could check out and leave. I had no desire to spend another minute in the rain. The only stop we made heading out of town was so Nana could get a couple of gifts for those back home.<br />
Had the rain not actually stopped as we&#8217;d headed south, I might not have had my coup de grace in bad ideas and passed right by the Fortuna Waterfall. However, with the break, I thought there might be a salvageable moment in the weekend.<br />
Sorry Monkey, your father will never learn.<br />
After you travel up the half-paved, half-bumpy road to the waterfall park&#8217;s parking lot, you pay US$10 each, and then walk along &#8220;600 metres of well-maintained path&#8221; to the observation point. What they do not tell you, in any way, is that the path includes a 100+ metre drop into the canyon, down one of the toughest staircases I&#8217;ve ever climbed. Nana (rather wisely) gave up only 1/5 of the way down. Mommy decided that she couldn&#8217;t go any futher than about 40 metres down before she stopped &#8212; she and you never got to the bottom to see the waterfall up-close. I was there for a mere five minutes before going back up to rejoin you.<br />
[flickr]photo:3744396992[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743603157[/flickr]<br />
For the record, you didn&#8217;t climb the stairs. We carried you. Why the heck we thought it was a good idea to bring you when Nana was at the top is beyond me. Instead, we lugged 20 kilos of wringling dead-weight up and down wet stairs.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737910724[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3737124555[/flickr]<br />
Worst. Idea. Ever.<br />
By the time I got the top again, my heart pounded so hard I could hear it, my chest was heaving, and my knees were so weak I was terrified that they&#8217;d give out and I&#8217;d drop you. About the only thing I had going for me was my pig-headedness to not giving up. I could barely walk. (Today, my legs are so sore I can barely climb stairs at all.)<br />
The rain started up again as we hit the road south to San RamÃ³n. You fell asleep not long after.<br />
At this point, Mommy took over decision-making, and wisely took us to a place neither you or Nana had been to before &#8212; Villa Blanca. Mommy and I had gone there for Mommy&#8217;s birthday in January, and she had gone again with her friend Erin back in May. Although it meant an extra 20 minute drive along another windy (but not nearly as bumpy) road, we arrived at a cloud-filled and peaceful place.<br />
For the first time in days, I actually felt good. It was quiet and calm. All I wanted to do was sit on a bench and let the clouds drift over me, taking away all the crappy feelings that had been building up for weeks.<br />
Lunch was, as expected, fantastic. You even ate most of your lunch, and even a little bit of Mommy&#8217;s.<br />
The drive home was marked only by the usual retinue of morons on the Pan American who don&#8217;t understand the concept of lanes or allowing others to pass freely when you&#8217;re driving too slowly. (Mommy was not pleased at my driving, and rightly so.) We got home in one piece.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737937674[/flickr]<br />
I tried to make dinner that night &#8212; pupusas. They were pretty lousy, unfortunately. There&#8217;s gotta be a different technique that I need to learn. You didn&#8217;t eat anything, again. I was the only one who actually seemed to eat dinner &#8212; either everyone else wasn&#8217;t hungry, or my dinner was horrible.<br />
For my last day off before going back to work, we&#8217;d decided to try going into San José. But at breakfast, you would barely eat anything you normally like &#8212; even toast &#8212; and you made it sound like you were having tummy problems. You and Mommy returned home, while Nana and I went into the city.<br />
I took Nana to the Central Market, where I&#8217;d last been about a year ago. I wound her through the narrow aisles, through little stalls selling just about everything imaginable (and a few unimaginable), before stopping at the Central Market Café. This is where Jason, Mark, and I had stopped for coffee (I had hot chocolate, not yet having started to drink coffee) while on our tour. Nana and I both bought coffee. I would later buy the torilla press we&#8217;d been looking for.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743790614[/flickr]<br />
Leaving the market, we went down Avenida Central towards the Plaza de Cultura, where we went to the Gran Hotel for lunch. My poor ceviche at the Arenal Lodge was redeemed by possibly the best ceviche I&#8217;ve yet had, while Nana had a fried Cambenbert and strawberry sauce tapas. Spying the dark clouds that suggested rain, we headed into the Museo de Oro for an hour or so.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743022225[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743826248[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743033867[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743848398[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743053189[/flickr]<br />
The rain, for once, didn&#8217;t come. When we came back out, it was only to walk back to the car and drive back home again.<br />
Mommy and I made pizza for dinner, which was very good. You barely ate your corn on the cob or the pizza (both were favourites), which still worries us greatly.<br />
So ends my birthday vacation. I wish I could say I had a better time, Monkey, but I&#8217;ll be honest &#8212; spending time with you, Mommy, and Nana were my shining points. Otherwise, it was a pretty lousy time. Had I known the weather would be that bad, I&#8217;d have suggested we just stay here at home.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743072335[/flickr]<br />
It&#8217;s time for me to go to bed (you&#8217;ve been asleep for about 2.75 hours already). Hopefully tonight I&#8217;ll catch up on some of the sleep I&#8217;ve been missing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend at Tabacon</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-at-tabacon</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend at Tabacon"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active Arenal volcano, and dinner and a splash at the <a href="http://www.tabacon.com/">Tabacon Hot Springs</a>.<br />
At the time we&#8217;d been there, it was highly magical. We&#8217;d seen lava (in the form of red-hot tumbling rocks) rolling down the side of the mountain, the clouds of steam rolling through the trees illuminated by the carefully-placed lights. It was something to behold.<br />
Ever since then, Alex had wanted to go back. Rack up Surprise Weekend in Costa Rica #3.<br />
<span id="more-1096"></span>We left Saturday just after lunch, taking a route up through Naranjo, Cuidad de Quesada (also known as San Carlos), and then angling west through La Fortuna. This was not exactly an ideal route, since it&#8217;s a national highway &#8212; despite the insane amount of curves present in the road &#8212; which means a lot more (slow) truck traffic.<br />
We arrived around 16:30 (it&#8217;s about a 3-3.5 hour drive, albeit a very nice drive) and checked in right away. A nice room (with air conditioning), two on-site <a href="http://www.cafebritt.com/">Cafe Britt</a> stores (one in the hotel, the other in the hot springs facility), and a couple of very nice restaurants.<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+hotel+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was when we found out how expensive Tabacon can be. Although the room rate for the weekend wasn&#8217;t too bad (technically less than the one at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/">Ylang Ylang</a>), it does not include any meals (whereas Ylang Ylang covered breakfast and dinner). A $75 buffet bill said that we were in for a pricey weekend.<br />
That&#8217;s the first myth of Tabacon &#8212; very nice hotel, but far too-expensive food for the quality that you get. The second myth is that the hot springs open at 8:00 in the morning. Which is true &#8212; they do, but you&#8217;ll find the water levels in the river are practically non-existent, as the water is diverted to fill the swimming pools, which starts around 9:00. So you can&#8217;t really use the hot springs until at least 10:00.<br />
On Sunday, we went out for an excursion to find a butterfly farm (Alex had promised Mi Pequeña Niña that we&#8217;d go see butterflies). We had to drive to the south side of Lake Arenal to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>, which took us on a very picturesque journey around the volcano. Which &#8212; apparently a sign of good luck &#8212; was mostly free of clouds for once. Many photos were taken.<br />
[flickr]tag:arenal+volcano+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The Butterfly Conservatory is near the end of a very rough road, off of a bumpy and rocky gravel road, off of another dirt road. (Driving back onto pavement after all that was a joy.) It sits atop a hill that provides &#8212; without question &#8212; one of the finest views of the Arenal volcano. This would be an exceptional place to take pictures at night during an eruption, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that driving there in the dark is a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢.<br />
The tents that contain the butterflies are down in a valley (a former cattle ranch turned into a reforestation project, after it was realised that putting cattle on volcanic soil is also a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢), which pretty much eliminated all breeze, and turned it into a bit of a boiler. Everyone was sweating profusely. But the butterflies were in significantly larger numbers than at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/">Spirogyra</a> &#8212; and some species that we hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+butterflies+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Luckily, we&#8217;d gained a tour guide part-way through the second (of four) butterfly tent, who not only showed us the butterflies and their names (given her limited English and our even more-limited Spanish), but also played with Mi Pequeña Niña while Alex and I snapped pictures). Sadly, I never did get her name, so all I can say is &#8220;Thanks, whomever you are!&#8221;<br />
Butterfly Conservatory also has a little frog habitat with some of the native Costa Rican frogs. Our guide was kind enough to bring the non-poisonous ones to the front of their enclosures so we could see them more closely. Otherwise, it would have been a bit hard to see them at all.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+frogs+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Naturally, Alex and I visited the hot springs whenever we could &#8212; what else would be the point of staying at Tabacon if we didn&#8217;t? Alex also took advantage of the five-star spa there, and hasn&#8217;t stopped talking about it yet. (I have to admit, it does sound wonderful.)<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+waterfall+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Even MPN got a chance to try the hot waters, while Alex was at her massage. Yes, I took my daughter into 39 degree Celsius water. And she loved it. I tried her in the cooler pools first, just to make sure, but when I slowly put her into the hot pool, it must&#8217;ve felt like heaven for her &#8212; she splashed around like a seal. The bridge overlooking the pool was soon filled with spectators. We might as well have been the featured attraction at Sea World.<br />
This is normal, by the way &#8212; it&#8217;s rather absurd the amount of attention MPN attracts down here.<br />
Monday being a holiday in Costa Rica (Independence Day), we took a leisurely return Monday afternoon, going through San Francisco and San RamÃ³n instead of San Carlos and Naranjo. This is the route that we had travelled (in the other direction) 3.5 years ago with Interbus on our way to Arenal. But Alex and I didn&#8217;t remember a thing, something we feel pretty guilty about. Alex claims that it was culture shock at the time. I think I can live with that.<br />
We stopped only twice &#8212; once to feed MPN (and have a Coke), and another at a gift shop we&#8217;d stopped at with Interbus 3.5 years ago. The only other place in the area that we knew of. It was weird because we didn&#8217;t really recognise it, but we did remember it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2862455883(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Sadly, this weekend cost a lot more than I&#8217;d budgeted for, so we&#8217;re not likely to do anymore long-distance trips for a while. (Besides which, we&#8217;re out of long weekends until Christmas). Of course, there&#8217;s still stuff around us for day trips, so stay tuned for more adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pictures from Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=pictures-from-hawaii</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hawaii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hilo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/04/11/pictures-from-hawaii/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I haven&#8217;t had a chance to finish with the blog entries yet (editing is such sweet fun), but I do at least have the gallery of photos from our last Hawaii trip up for viewing. The full list will appear in the various blog entries. Enjoy!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I haven&#8217;t had a chance to finish with the blog entries yet (editing is such sweet fun), but I do at least have the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/hawaii-big-island-2007/">gallery of photos from our last Hawaii trip</a> up for viewing. The full list will appear in the various blog entries.<br />
Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">691</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
