<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>chicago &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/chicago/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 16:05:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>It&#039;s the end of the world as we know it&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 16:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8230;and I feel, well, okay. Maybe not necessarily &#8220;fine&#8221;. Critical Mass has done a bit of a reorganisation. I emphasise &#8220;a bit&#8221;. Mostly because this is not the radical shifts we&#8217;ve seen in the past. I think this is my third or fourth reorganisation since starting with Critical Mass back in 2000 (admittedly, I&#8217;m losing &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "It&#039;s the end of the world as we know it&#8230;"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;and I feel, well, okay. Maybe not necessarily &#8220;fine&#8221;.<br />
Critical Mass has done a bit of a reorganisation. I emphasise &#8220;a bit&#8221;. Mostly because this is not the radical shifts we&#8217;ve seen in the past. I think this is my third or fourth reorganisation since starting with Critical Mass back in 2000 (admittedly, I&#8217;m losing track), and this is the most minor change we&#8217;ve had.<br />
At least when you look at the big picture.<br />
<span id="more-971"></span>In short, no promotions, no demotions. Just changes in role and responsibility. Which, when you think about it, is the real purpose of a reorganisation: shuffle the existing chart to align with your needs. And our needs are global. We have production offices in Calgary, Chicago, Toronto, and London. Costa Rica starts up in 30 days.<br />
In our old system, it was becoming hard to handle all that. We had department VPs who had to spread their influence across many offices. Control was all centralised at Calgary, which while we thought it was good for ensuring standards and practises, tended to impose controls on the other offices, which was detrimental to their operation.<br />
So now we&#8217;ve got independent offices. Each have General Managers, four lead people from each of the former departments (Creative, Technology, Planning, and Operations), and their own controls. They still report to Critical Mass Global Operations (aka Head Office aka Calgary), but the influence of old is greatly lessened.<br />
We&#8217;ve effectively given them all much more rope, and more room for success. We&#8217;ve also likely created more competition. I just hope it remains the healthy kind.<br />
The trick out of all of this is that we don&#8217;t have our over-arching leadership at the department level. It&#8217;s going to be up to the office leads to ensure that communication remains. The last thing we need is to turn into our competition where the individual offices have no clue what the others are doing. It&#8217;s a lousy way to learn when you can&#8217;t/don&#8217;t talk to each other.<br />
There is one part in all of this I don&#8217;t like. Allard Losier, my 8-year leader, mentor, devil&#8217;s advocate, prank target, talk show host, Defender of the Right and Just, and friend is leaving. I can&#8217;t even begin to rhyme off the things I&#8217;ve learned from him over the years, and there&#8217;s no way to calculate the huge effect he&#8217;s had on my career development. An era officially comes to and end with his departure. To the few of us multi-year veterans still left in the (now former) Technology department, this is a hard loss. It also puts the onus on us to ensure that we live up to the expectations, to the things we still believe are right.<br />
We&#8217;re going to miss you Allard. Just so you know.<br />
It&#8217;s (a bit of) a new world. I&#8217;m going to be a part of it, even if at a distance. But I can say that if this goes the way I&#8217;m told it will go, we should see some new and exciting things come from Critical Mass in the coming months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">971</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech Summit, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-summit-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 05:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/12/tech-summit-day-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Tech Summit, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Day 2 got off to a lousy start. I was sick. Nastily so. At first, I thought it was a hangover (I might have had &#8212; perhaps &#8212; one beer too many last night). But I realised very quickly that this was not, in fact, a hangover. I&#8217;ve had my share of them, I know how they affect me, and I know how to handle them.<br />
This thing &#8212; whatever it was &#8212; knocked me flat on my back and sent me back to bed for the rest of the morning. Fortunately, I didn&#8217;t feel like I missed too much.<br />
<span id="more-902"></span>The day was spent completing the tasks from yesterday, and working to our department strategy. That meant debate. And a lot of it. But when you&#8217;re changing the way you work, you&#8217;re more concerned with change, rather than status quo. Still, it does raise blood pressure in a few.<br />
At the end of the day, we started to try define the qualities and responsibilities of Technology Directors. It&#8217;s harder than it sounds. Especially since those of us who are Technology Directors have found that we don&#8217;t always see things the same way. It&#8217;s why Cory and I proposed the exercise in the first place.<br />
Afterwards was the Technology Lead event: we got to go see Da Bulls. (That would be the Chicago Bulls NBA franchise, in case you completely missed the late 1980s of Saturday Night Live.)<br />
I&#8217;d never been to a basketball game before. I wasn&#8217;t sure what to expect, and honestly believed that I wouldn&#8217;t really like it. I&#8217;m not a sports nut. I like hockey, and I used to love baseball, but I don&#8217;t really follow sports in any appreciable way. My last stint at a football game was underwhelming (I left the game early), and wondered how bored I&#8217;d be at this one.<br />
Turns out that you don&#8217;t get the option. The game is &#8212; likely due to television contracts &#8212; very ADD-oriented. Every so often (likely about the time of a commercial break), they game stops and there&#8217;s dancing (the cheerleaders went through three costume changes), games (Benny the Bull &#8212; the Bulls&#8217; mascot &#8212; had his birthday and several of the other NBA mascots came out to celebrate), random t-shirt throwings, and these weird little CG &#8220;races&#8221; on the JumboTron.<br />
All at the same time.<br />
No, I&#8217;m not kidding.<br />
It was hard to figure out what you should be looking at. It was almost confusing.<br />
But &#8212; I&#8217;ll give it this &#8212; it was entertaining. The Bulls lost, but it was easy to miss that fact.<br />
Afterwards, we had to figure out how to get from the United Center back to our hotel. Easier said than done. Couldn&#8217;t find a taxi. Anywhere. And when we did, they were all taken.<br />
The 11 of us traipsed down West Madison, Bill nearly freezing a jacket not made for the cold weather (he had literally flown in from Costa Rica and had not planned on such frigid temperatures) and all of us sliding around in the slush and snow (Chicagoans appear to not want to shovel walkways or sidewalks).<br />
Aside from a 1.5 hour stop at the Third Rail bar to &#8220;warm up&#8221;, we walked most of the way back. Scott, Allard, Sep, and Joe were the first to bail out when we finally saw a cab. Bill, Torin, Johnathan, and Cory took the second cab a couple of blocks later. Dave took a cab (he had a long way to drive home). Only Reid and I walked the entire way back (his apartment is barely a block from the hotel).<br />
And now, to bed. It&#8217;s been another long day. Looking forward to going home. I have a pair of babies at home that I miss dearly.<br />
[flickr]tag:chicago+february+&#8221;12&#8243;+2008@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">902</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech Summit, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=tech-summit-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 06:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/11/tech-summit-day-1/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tech Summits are dicey things. Sort of like trying to catch a greased pig. You can see it, you can describe it, but it&#8217;s a pain to pin down and hold still. It has a life of its own and just as soon as you get your head wrapped around it, the damn thing&#8217;s gone &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Tech Summit, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech Summits are dicey things. Sort of like trying to catch a greased pig. You can see it, you can describe it, but it&#8217;s a pain to pin down and hold still. It has a life of its own and just as soon as you get your head wrapped around it, the damn thing&#8217;s gone and wriggled off.<br />
And we&#8217;re just through Day 1&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-901"></span>We started the day by flying to Chicago. It&#8217;s one of our three primary offices, and we try to rotate amongst them. For us in Calgary, it&#8217;s just shy of 3 hours of flying, including a long delay waiting to leave Calgary and the near-45 minute approach to Chicago.<br />
We started just after noon, and worked through until about 17:30 CT. The discussions and exercises raised a lot of good questions &#8212; ones that I&#8217;m glad we&#8217;re asking and answering. But they also raise a lot more questions. Namely, how the heck do we get all this to work? But hey, it&#8217;s only Day 1.<br />
This is the first time I&#8217;ve been in Chicago in about three years, and only my second time. I still love this city. It&#8217;s an interesting place, and has actual architecture &#8212; something Calgary is grossly lacking. Utilitarianism has taken over, and everything looks boring and far too useful for reason. Here, form still reigns, and even the new buildings look like someone wanted it to look nice first, and be useful second.<br />
But I digress&#8230; I&#8217;m not here to tour Chicago. Just work here. For a couple of days.<br />
We met the rest of the Technology team here after &#8220;work&#8221; was over at 17:30. Pizza and beer. And werewolves.<br />
Yes, werewolves.<br />
<a href="http://www.eblong.com/zarf/werewolf.html"><em>Werewolf</em> is an odd game</a> borne from the early days of BarCamp. And I have to admit, it&#8217;s an evil amount of fun. Especially when you&#8217;ve had maybe one beer too many. I&#8217;m never going to live down my stint as moderator, though.<br />
Afterwards Allard, Dave, Torin, Reid, and myself trucked down Michigan Ave to the John Hancock Center to get a higher view of Chicago. Despite some rather rigid staff who wouldn&#8217;t let me wander into vacant areas to take pictures, I managed to get a few shots from on high.<br />
Tomorrow, we continue the discussions&#8230;<br />
[flickr]tag:chicago+february+11+2008@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/tech-summit-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">901</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Chicago</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/in-chicago/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=in-chicago</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/in-chicago/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 20:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/11/in-chicago/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I&#8217;m back in Chicago again. Currently in the &#8220;Missile Command&#8221; meeting room (all the meeting rooms here are named after video games). We&#8217;re staying at the Hard Rock Hotel (pretty much right across the street from the office). And meetings are about to begin. Wish me luck&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&#8217;m back in Chicago again. Currently in the &#8220;Missile Command&#8221; meeting room (all the meeting rooms here are named after video games).<br />
We&#8217;re staying at the Hard Rock Hotel (pretty much right across the street from the office). And meetings are about to begin.<br />
Wish me luck&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/in-chicago/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">900</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Up-coming travel</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=up-coming-travel</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 20:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[england]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inverness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/22/up-coming-travel/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it. So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months. First, the family is off to Scotland &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Up-coming travel"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love travelling &#8212; I honestly believe that I don&#8217;t do enough of it. Always makes me feel more energised, and sitting on my duff all day long really makes me pine for it.<br />
So I&#8217;m lucky to be getting around a bit in the next few months.<br />
<span id="more-894"></span>First, the family is off to Scotland again. This time, more Scotland than England. And no Ireland. Allen and Alex want to visit Iona. A week on a small rural island with ancient churches. I can&#8217;t think of a better place for a photo essay, myself. Then off to the Inverness area (hello, Nessie!), through York for a couple of days (a <em>whole day</em> in the National Railway Museum!), then home again. That&#8217;ll be early April.<br />
And, yes, El Bebe is coming with us. Not sure how this is going to work &#8212; both Alex and I are a bit apprehensive about the time difference. Alex has trouble with the shift &#8212; I can only imagine how the wee one will handle it. We&#8217;ve heard that this is the best time to travel with children, so they (kind of) get used to it. But it does mean we can&#8217;t move at my preferred break-neck pace. Instead of going right to Iona, it&#8217;s going to take two days from the time we land. I can hack that, though.<br />
Next up is a business trip to Chicago, which is actually first in the list, coming up in the second week of February. The Technology Department leadership (which includes me) will be trying to figure out our long-term plans and aspirations. It&#8217;s going to be an interesting session.<br />
Finally &#8212; at least currently on the radar &#8212; is a weekend in Las Vegas. I&#8217;m going down for Tamara&#8217;s wedding. That&#8217;s the second weekend in March. I haven&#8217;t been there in 12 years, so this should make for an interesting experience.<br />
I can&#8217;t wait to get back on the road again!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/up-coming-travel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">894</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes-Benz meetings, going home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-going-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mercedes-benz-going-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-going-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2005 04:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/04/mercedes-benz-going-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite having the room to myself, I was really groggy when I got up this morning. I know it wasn&#8217;t a result of last night, though, as I didn&#8217;t feel any worse for wear. I showered, packed, and checked out (using the television interface &#8212; I don&#8217;t go to the front desk unless I have &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-going-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mercedes-Benz meetings, going home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite having the room to myself, I was really groggy when I got up this morning. I know it wasn&#8217;t a result of last night, though, as I didn&#8217;t feel any worse for wear. I showered, packed, and checked out (using the television interface &#8212; I don&#8217;t go to the front desk unless I have to). Running into Jamie on the way down, the two of us hiked directly over to the Tribune building. We didn&#8217;t get a chance to go to the office for email.<br />
<span id="more-407"></span>I feel really out of touch. I had hoped to have email access while we were in Chicago, but outside of the Critical Mass office, the connection has been abysmal. Not to mention that the Hyatt charges for its access (cheap bastards!) and there&#8217;s no wireless access in the meeting room. Actually, that&#8217;s not entirely true. There is an internet connection, which the presentation laptop used. We connected that to Casey&#8217;s AirPort hub, which (in theory) would have given us all access. Even then, only the presentation laptop was able to work. I&#8217;m not sure why the rest of us (including Casey) were deprived. I wrestled with that sucker for a couple of hours without success.<br />
The first order of business was making up the presentation to the group of our misdirected escapades of last night. Originally, we were going to wing it, but one of the groups (who hit the Sears Tower) had gone completely overboard with their presentation. So we amped ours up a bit with a PowerPoint presentation and bottles of water. At least we didn&#8217;t feel quite so lame. And I managed to plug the Client-Side Rearchitecture a bit.<br />
The morning meetings zipped by fairly quickly, and we broke into small groups at lunch (all impromptu) to discuss whatever points we needed to discuss. Rich and I had an agenda to talk to Lark about the Client-Side Rearchitecture so we can get the project moving. Luckily, both Rich and I are fairly good at steering conversations, and it wasn&#8217;t long before we were actively babbling about it. This was key, since Rich and I had some outstanding questions we needed answered before we could start moving ahead on the next chapter.<br />
The meetings ended right on time &#8212; they had to &#8212; at 16:00. This was the great divide for us, as those of us from out-of-town had to catch flights back home. The New York Critical Mass staff hurriedly ran out the door, as their flight was among the first. The Mercedes team was next, followed by the Calgary Critical Mass group. Those of us heading back today, that is. Benno, Casey, Christine, and Rich are hanging out in Chicago tomorrow before coming back on Sunday.<br />
Cabs were easy to hail on the street. Szabo, Mark V., and I hopped in a cab and were off. The traffic was already getting bad. Although our flight wasn&#8217;t until 19:00, there was a lot of concern that we would be running late. Chicago is a big city, and there&#8217;s a lot of distance from the downtown core to O&#8217;Hare.<br />
The three of us talked marketing on the way back. Four years ago, I wouldn&#8217;t have been able to do this. I&#8217;d have just sat there, quietly, minding my own beeswax. Having been in the business as long as I have, though, I&#8217;ve picked up enough knowledge to speak wisely of it. Especially when to tell the difference between a good ad and a bad ad.<br />
Take a BMW billboard we saw. The caption read: &#8220;Never use a rest stop. Again.&#8221;<br />
Simple, but vague. This is because you won&#8217;t want to get out of the car? Or perhaps it goes so fast that you&#8217;ll get where you&#8217;re going before your bladder gets too full? Or perhaps there&#8217;s a built-in toilet in the seats? That led to a conversation of catheters (commonly used for sporting events), and Mark V. wondering how popular catheters would become if Apple made them. I already know what they&#8217;d called the product, too:<br />
The iPee.<br />
Check-in was straight-forward. A swipe of the passport, and our profiles appeared. Mark V. couldn&#8217;t secure an exit row, though, and we were all delegated to middle seats for our return flight. (The joys of a Friday evening flight.) Security was a bit of a nasty clog, but soon we were in the open and headed for our gate. Mark V. was behind me, but we somehow lost Szabo. We found the gate was completely full (another flight was just about to board and leave), so sat at an adjacent empty section. Bill and Jules found us soon after, followed by Mabel and Jamie. Szabo eventually reappeared. I held guard while the others found food &#8212; some remarkably poor pizza. Beggars cannot be choosers.<br />
The flight to Minneapolis was mostly forgettable. (I&#8217;ve already forgotten it.) The guy next to me slept. We had a quick sprint within the Minneapolis to find our new flight. The wait wasn&#8217;t long &#8212; not even close to consider the $7 wireless charge. The flight was cramped and hot. All of us were packed into middle seats. Jules, Bill, and Szabo managed to weasel their ways into window, aisle, and first-class seating. Lucky bastards.<br />
I was happy to get off the plane in Calgary. It had snowed since our departure. Minus 11. No biggie, really. Immigrations was fun, especially since I was following Bill and Mabel through the same gate. When I got to the customs officer, I handed her my papers:<br />
&#8220;There&#8217;s a few of us.&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Huh?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;I&#8217;m with the two you just passed through.&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Web design firm?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Yep.&#8221;<br />
&#8220;Welcome back.&#8221;<br />
Now, dear reader, this is where my journey should have ended, with a cab ride home. But I thought I&#8217;d be the fiscally responsible employee and take a cab. But no, I felt public transit would be suitable. So I took the bus and then the C-Train. Along the way I think I witnessed just about even level of intoxication and ill behaviour before finally abandoning my transfer to the train that would take me to Sunnyside and walked the rest of the way. I was tired, cold, and miserable. I ain&#8217;t doing that again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-going-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">407</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes-Benz meetings, team building</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mercedes-benz-team-building</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2005 04:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/03/mercedes-benz-team-building/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Allard and I hit the restaurant in the main atrium for breakfast, joined shortly thereafter by Christian and a very tired-looking Jules. Powdered eggs aren&#8217;t exactly the breakfast of champions. Jules has been up late working on presentations for today. Allard and I are thankfully exempt from any actual presentations. We&#8217;re more or less along &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mercedes-Benz meetings, team building"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Allard and I hit the restaurant in the main atrium for breakfast, joined shortly thereafter by Christian and a very tired-looking Jules. Powdered eggs aren&#8217;t exactly the breakfast of champions. Jules has been up late working on presentations for today. Allard and I are thankfully exempt from any actual presentations. We&#8217;re more or less along for the ride.<br />
Actually, me more than Allard. Allard, at least, is the Technical Director. He needs to be there because the client knows who he is. He needs to be there because some of MBIT will be there. Why do *I* need to be there? Well, I can&#8217;t say for sure, because I really don&#8217;t know, but I think it comes down to the Client-Side Rearchitecture project that I&#8217;m spearheading, and that Allard won&#8217;t be here tomorrow (he&#8217;s only here for a day).<br />
<span id="more-406"></span>We hit the office briefly, just long enough for a quick email check and my morning run at the comics. We were starting at 9:00, and soon we were off &#8212; just across the road, mind you &#8212; to the Chicago Tribune building. The Tribune is one of Chicago&#8217;s oldest and most respected newspapers. Its head office is a massive neo-gothic edifice hovering near the shore of the Chicago River. It&#8217;s not huge, at least by modern standards. The outside is adorned with ornate stonework, flying buttresses (or at least would be, were they on the ground), and even has 500 stones from various places around the world (and the moon).<br />
The inside is almost as impressive as the outside. The main lobby is condensed (the footprint is about the size of a regular squash court), but with a high, wood-lined ceiling, and etched stonework (containing a variety of quotes by a lot of people I don&#8217;t know). This is the sort of stle that used to be put into buildings. Everything is pre-fab, now. They just don&#8217;t make &#8217;em like they used to. Opposite the doors is the security desk. The building is secure &#8212; you can&#8217;t enter without an employee or guest pass. We went to the desk, one at a time, got our guest passes, and found our way to the elevators to take us to the meeting rooms.<br />
The Huron meeting room is in the second sub-basement. No windows. No fresh air. Complete, total, and utter isolation from everything. In theory, a great location for a meeting. (In reality, it&#8217;s a tad harsh.) The Mercedes team was a bit late arriving, no doubt due to traffic (air and ground). Before long, we were set up and ready to roll.<br />
First up on the agenda were introductions. Most of us knew the rest, either through previous meetings or through email and phone conversations. When you have over 40 people in a room, it often helps to know who each person is, what they do, and how they&#8217;re going to contribute to everything. One at a time, we went around, saying our names and what we did. It was Jerry, Critical Mass&#8217; CEO, who had the best opening:<br />
&#8220;Hi, my name is Jerry, and I&#8217;m an alcoholic.&#8221;<br />
I&#8217;d been waiting for *years* to hear someone say that during introductions. I&#8217;d debated many times on saying it, myself, but had never got up the gumption to do so. &#8216;Course, now that someone has said it, I&#8217;ll have to refrain from using it for a while, lest someone think I&#8217;m trying to copycat Jerry.<br />
The meetings were long and a little dull. The same can be said of any meeting I attend that I&#8217;m not directly involved in. In fact, I&#8217;ve been known to fall asleep in them. (I nodded off at one point during today&#8217;s.) Why? I&#8217;m not sure. Could be stimulation, or more importantly, the complete lack thereof. It doesn&#8217;t even matter how much sleep I get. I found university exceptionally hard, because few of the professors really cared about the students, and preferred to ramble on and on about whatever topic they liked talking about. (Thankfully, I had a number of professors who were quite engaging.) It might explain why my marks weren&#8217;t exactly stellar.<br />
The meetings ended with the introduction of the team building event. Last year, we engaged in the Amazing Freeze (see [[The Amazing Freeze]]), which I found to be quite directed. This one was much more free-form. We didn&#8217;t really have the same level of competition, either. This time, we split into groups (four to five people, not unlike last year), and were given a topic upon which to &#8220;research&#8221;. My team (Andrew, Eric, Jules, Lark, and myself) received &#8220;Integration of Experience&#8221;.<br />
If you&#8217;re looking at that and wondering what on Earth that means, you&#8217;re not alone. The five us were thinking the same thing.<br />
Our first stop was the hotel. We wanted to dump off our bags (laptops, and in Lark&#8217;s case &#8212; her bags, she hadn&#8217;t checked in yet) and get changed for the dinner after the event (we were told to dress nicely). We met in the lobby along with a couple of the other teams (we weren&#8217;t the only ones with the idea) and rolled out.<br />
We had been given several potential locations to go to in the process of working out our topics. They included the Sears Tower, Millennium Park (not be mistaken with Calgary&#8217;s skatepark), the Zoo, and Navy Pier. We decided that we didn&#8217;t want to run into the other teams, and chose the John Hancock Tower, the little brother to the Sears Tower. We piled into two cabs (Andrew and I in the first; Eric, Lark, and Jules in the second), and promptly lost track of each other.<br />
Yeah. So not a way to start off a team-building event.<br />
The problem is that our cabs didn&#8217;t really coordinate with each other. Our cab stopped on the north side of the building, while the other cab stopped on the south. We looked all over for each other, but never caught sight while we were at ground level. Andrew and I decided we&#8217;d hit the Observation Desk in a vain effort to find them. Even doing what Andrew called a &#8220;Keystone Cop&#8221; (starting at the same point, walking in opposite directions, meeting at the opposite side), we couldn&#8217;t find them. Back down to the ground floor, we tried the 96th floor, which has a bar. Tucked away in a dark corner, we found them.<br />
Eric had spied a sign outside of the Contemporary Art Museum a couple of blocks away on the way to the tower. We hiked over, and the four of them posed in front of the &#8220;Experience&#8221; sign while I took the picture. A strange sculpture of a Yugo towing a trailer, jacknifed vertically, gave us the inspiration for Jules playing the role of Superman.<br />
From there, we walked over to the Water Tower, one of Chicago&#8217;s landmarks. The Water Tower sits in a traffic island. One side is north-bound traffic, the other south-bound. To the east is a large sandstone building (which was related to the tower at one point in its history). From what we could tell, it was a pumping station. Curious to see if it was still a pumping station, we peered in the windows. This lead us to our epiphony.<br />
Integration of Experience: Every municipality of any size needs water. It&#8217;s one of our basic needs. The infrastructure that supplies that water is complex and so necessary that deprivation of mere hours can be troublesome. The water pumping station was old &#8212; probably dating back to the earlier days of Chicago. It&#8217;s definitely 1800s or earlier. Yet the equipment inside is much newer &#8212; maybe only a couple of decades older. Somewhere along the line, they had to rip out the old equipment and insert the new without depriving downtown Chicago one of its primary puming stations. And so we have our integration of experience: without the ability to integrate the old and the new, a lot of people would have had a lousy experience.<br />
Hey, we&#8217;re a marketing company. We&#8217;re paid to bullshit well.<br />
We celebrated our successful venture with drinks at &#8220;Iron&#8221; Mike Dytka&#8217;s bar, a few blocks away. After the libations, the five of us crammed ourselves into a very small cab (it certainly felt like that in the backseat &#8212; Eric, the Chicago native, sat in front) and we found our way to Marche, a very chic little joint west of downtown. It&#8217;s in the old warehouse district, now completely refurbished into the chic restaurant district.<br />
Marche was described as being French. I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s a particularly accurate description, since it doesn&#8217;t really look or feel French. I&#8217;d say more nouveau cuisine than anything else. The interior matched the style of the food &#8212; eclectic and funky, and making use of the features inherent to the building. High ceilings were decorated, the old elevator shaft doors decorated (or removed entirely). The inner courtyard to the complex (which we could see through windows) still bore the names of the companies that had once lived here.<br />
Like I said before, Chicago has a lot of history. I could come to love this city.<br />
Returning to the hotel after dinner, we adjourned to the BiG Bar, the lounge in the atrium of the Hyatt. It runs the full width of the atrium, about 100 metres or so. Along the glass wall that looks out onto Wacker St. and the Chicago River were four levels of various kinds of booze. It looks very impressive on first glance; when you look closer, you&#8217;ll see that there are duplicates.<br />
A small group of us grabbed a table and began to settle in for a nightcap. Martinis &#8212; chocolate ones &#8212; were the main order for the first round. I have to admit that I didn&#8217;t particularly like the one I had (I&#8217;ve had much better), and switched to a beer afterwards. Elenor and Mabel went for what I can only call a bad idea: the BiG martini. A 48 fluid ounce, gut-busting monster that shocked the both of them. I don&#8217;t think anyone had really realized just how humungous this drink was going to be.<br />
Oops.<br />
A live band took to the stage, playing some of the great Motown tunes, only very badly. (Well, not really badly, but I&#8217;ve heard them much better.) Christine, already quite into the groove, decided that she was going to run up on stage and dance very badly &#8212; y&#8217;know, to fit in with the music. Mabel declared that she was following. Taro, just to make things interesting, bet Mabel $50 that she couldn&#8217;t. So the two of them pranced off to prove Taro wrong.<br />
At first, it looked like Taro&#8217;s bet was safe, as the musician nearest to the edge of the stage wasn&#8217;t about to let them up. A couple of songs later, though, we heard a distinctly familiar, albeit quiet, &#8220;Hi!&#8221;. We turned around to see Mabel leaping into the air, trying to speak into a microphone that was a good two feet higher up than the top of her head (the musician was quite tall). Returning triumphant, Taro presented Mabel with her winnings.<br />
The betting didn&#8217;t end there. Next up, Mabel was then challenged to drink the remaining 47 oz of the drink she had left. In less than two minutes. This caused a huge round of &#8220;you gotta be kidding!&#8221; laughter. Mabel, of course, stepped up to the challenge.<br />
Using her hands, she scooped out all the ice in the drink (there was quite a bit of it), and the clock started. You&#8217;ve never seen such a serious look on someone trying to drink so much so fast. We joked that Benno was falling in love. I held mostly-official time by the clock on my cell phone. Christine recorded the entire event for posterity with her digital camera. We all egged Mabel on.<br />
One minute, 45 seconds. With a belch to boot.<br />
The table rotated its compliment a few times before Mabel convinced Benno to go clubbing. The rest of us carefully backed out and made a run for the elevators to our rooms. We still have another day of meetings to live through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-team-building/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">406</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mercedes-Benz meetings, Calgary to Chicago</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2005 05:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illinois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/02/02/mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I hate waking up before 6:00. There&#8217;s just something fundamentally wrong with it. Today, though, it was necessary. Today, I fly to Chicago. Was ready for my 6:30 pickup. Allard was collecting me for the trip to the airport. I wasn&#8217;t sure if he was going to show up on time, since we&#8217;d had no &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mercedes-Benz meetings, Calgary to Chicago"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hate waking up before 6:00. There&#8217;s just something fundamentally wrong with it. Today, though, it was necessary. Today, I fly to Chicago.<br />
Was ready for my 6:30 pickup. Allard was collecting me for the trip to the airport. I wasn&#8217;t sure if he was going to show up on time, since we&#8217;d had no actual solid confirmation of the pickup. At 6:25, I started formulating a backup plan, in the event that Allard was running a little late. His car appeared in front of my house at 6:30, right on the nose, saving me additional grief.<br />
<span id="more-405"></span>Why are we going to Chicago? Every year, usually in January, are the annual kick-off meetings. This is when the account team gets together with Mercedes-Benz USA&#8217;s team and goes over the high-level plans for the year. It&#8217;s also a chance to do some team-building (important when your teams are a couple thousand kilometres and two time zones apart). Normally, these meetings are held in Calgary, but due to the rather frigid temperatures of last year (see [[The Amazing Freeze]]), a more central (and likely warmer) location was chosen: Chicago.<br />
Due to the distance, Mark and I weren&#8217;t originally considered for the group to go. It&#8217;s expensive to send people out that way, as we have to pay for airfare, hotels, food, and so forth. The Critical Mass team is considerably larger than the Mercedes-Benz team, and we want to keep costs low. However, due to the fact that Allard has to leave tomorrow night (the meetings go until Friday afternoon), there is a bit of a desire for some additional technical team presence. That, and we want to try and push the Client-Side Rearchitecture project as much as possible.<br />
This is the first time I&#8217;m be on an actual business trip since 2000, when I went to Cincinatti for the Eukandoit.com project (see [[Live from Cincinnati]]). I don&#8217;t count the Search Engine Strategies conference in August as a real business trip &#8212; that was more of a glorified, all expenses paid vacation. (Okay, yes, I did learn a lot, but that&#8217;s not the point.) I wasn&#8217;t really looking forward to this trip (mostly because I don&#8217;t have a lot to contribute), but I know it will be information and useful.<br />
Allard and I checked in and ran through U.S. Immigration. I was half-expecting problems, after hearing all the stories of all the problems our staff has had trying to cross the border for work. As I&#8217;m realizing, so long as you&#8217;re there for meetings, it&#8217;s not a problem. It&#8217;s only when you&#8217;re going down there to *work* that you have a problem. We crossed the border and headed to security.<br />
Allard proclaimed, as we neared the security lines, that he usually zips through without trouble. For once, Murphy was following someone else, and they immediately pulled him over to randomly inspect his bags. I headed to the x-ray machines. It was the usual: jacket, carry-on bag, pull out the laptop, run through the metal detector, Allard, in the line next to me, not only set off the detector, but had to remove his shoes, had his bags thorough poked around in, and even got the dreaded full-body pat-down.<br />
Serves him right for saying he always zips through security.<br />
Christine, Casey, and Rich were on a different flight, with United Airlines. They had a direct flight to Chicago (the bastards!) while the rest of us poor plebes (Allard, the two Marks, Mabel, Jules, Bill, Jamie, and myself) had to take a two-legger with Northwest. Our first leg went to Minneapolis, and the second to Chicago. The first flight had been an Airbus A319, a comfortable, partly-full flight. The second leg was a DC-9, which was a little more full, relatively-speaking.<br />
Although I&#8217;d been to Minneapolis before, on my way to Cincinatti, I didn&#8217;t really remember the airport. It was much more appealing this time, since I was travelling in a group (which, I have to say, is a lot more fun), and I didn&#8217;t have to run around trying to find a moved flight. We grabbed lunch at Chili&#8217;s Too (a grilled chicken sandwich) before heading for our flight to Chicago.<br />
The flight to Chicago was short, barely over an hour. Approaching Chicago was interesting. I&#8217;ve never been there before, and had no idea what to expect. It&#8217;s a big city, about the size of Toronto. We could see the airport as we approached it, and while it looked close to the city, I could tell that we&#8217;d have a bit of a drive into the downtown core.<br />
Dad used to travel a lot in his line of work, and went through Chicago periodically (he once met Mr. T and got his autograph &#8230; for my sister), and told me about how large it was. I expected a grand environment with vaulted ceilings, bright lights, shiny surfaces, and glitzy storefronts. Instead, it&#8217;s like walking through a series of low-roofed tunnels. How the mighty perceptions fall&#8230; However, O&#8217;Hare is HUGE. While I only got a quick glance at it, there is no question about it holding several records for being a large and busy airport.<br />
Walking through the airport, Mark (the Account Manager) mentioned that we should give Stuart a call in Montreal. (Mark used to work with Stuart at Parallel and at McCann in Calgary.) Give him a ring at, say, 3:00 in the morning and scream:<br />
&#8220;Hey Padley, you suck!&#8221;<br />
I had to laugh, mostly because I knew the only one who would appreciate that any less than Stuart would be Therese.<br />
Allard, Jamie, and I hopped in the first cab to downtown. From O&#8217;Hare, it&#8217;s about a 30 minute drive to downtown, providing you don&#8217;t get caught in too much traffic. (I almost wish, though, that we could have taken the CTA trains, which run to O&#8217;Hare. I don&#8217;t know why Calgary hasn&#8217;t got that plan on the books &#8212; every major city should run light rail to their airports.) At the time of day (approximately 14:30), traffic inbound is fairly light, and rush hour outbound is just beginning (or at least that&#8217;s how it seemed). We chatted amongst ourselves (the cabbie probably wondered what we were babbling about &#8212; I often wonder if they understand the conversations that go on behind/beside them), and I looked out the window to see what we were passing.<br />
Chicago is an old city. It&#8217;s been around since the late 1600s (in one form or another), and it shows. As you near the downtown core, the highway runs right next to (or possibly through the middle of) neighbourhoods that have been around for maybe a hundred years or more. Beautiful old buildings, some left over from a more industrial era, some probably still in the midst of production, spitting distance from working-class brownstone houses. Heavy iron bridgework is everywhere.<br />
If you haven&#8217;t already guessed, I&#8217;d never been to Chicago before. It&#8217;s one of those cities that I&#8217;d always been moderately curious about, but didn&#8217;t really feel any pressing need to visit. Even before we got to the hotel, I&#8217;d made up my mind that I need to come back here when I have more time. This is a vibrant city with a lot of history. And one thing Chicago definitely has in volumes over Calgary is architecture. Chicago boomed in the 1920s, and it does very well &#8212; there is a tremendous abundance of gothic, neo-gothic, and art deco styles. Many buildings here are from a time when form was just as important as function &#8212; maybe even moreso. Today&#8217;s modern buildings lack the grace and elegance of the days of yore. I often wonder if I was born a few decades too late, as I seem to want to live in a world where art deco is still popular, where steam rules the rails, and where the bizarre complexities of our modern world rarely affected the average person. Odd, since I regularly try to live on the cutting edge of today.<br />
The Hyatt Regency is a massive hotel &#8212; I&#8217;ve never quite seen one its size (outside of Las Vegas, anyway). It&#8217;s got two 35 storey towers (the East and West), joined by bridges and linked by a large glassed atrium. It&#8217;s not very ostentatious (at least from the outside), but it is comfy.<br />
Allard and I are sharing a room. But only for one night &#8212; Allard has to go back to Calgary tomorrow. Since I&#8217;m here for two nights, I&#8217;m checking in and getting the keys. It&#8217;ll be the only expense I incur on this trip, if I can help it. Cabs here don&#8217;t seem to take credit cards, and since I&#8217;m out of American cash, I&#8217;ll be bumming rides as much as possible.<br />
We dumped our bags at the room and headed downstairs to meet up with the rest of the group in the reception area. Then it was off to the Critical Mass Chicago office, about a five-minute walk away. To get there, we walked down Wacker St. to Michigan Ave. This crosses over the Chicago River, passing both the Wrigley building and the Chicago Tribune building. Both are classic examples of 1920&#8217;s glory. Oh, how I wish Calgary had anything like those!<br />
The Realty Tower, a modern 12-storey building across the street from the Chicago Tribune building houses the Critical Mass office. We have only about a dozen people there, so the space is shared with another Omnicom company that deals primarily in print. Jerry, Critical Mass&#8217; CEO, has the corner office to himself. Christine, Rich, Casey, and Melanie were already in one of the meeting rooms. Benno had also arrived from Toronto, having had to take a detour to get his passport renewed (he&#8217;s a Japanese citizen) before entering the United States.<br />
Jules, Andrew, Allard, and I took up shop in a boardroom in the far corner of the office. It took us a moment to connect to the wireless network, and were soon checking in on events of the day (that we&#8217;d partly missed). Allard, Jules, and Andrew came and went. The advantage of being the straggler on this show is that not much is expected (or demanded) of me. So I could stay put and get some email sent. Andrew came back after a while, and it was just the two of us. And it was us who were privy to the funniest thing that I&#8217;ve heard in a long time.<br />
Neil (our Sr. VP of New Business) had popped in the room for a moment to chat, and was on his way out when he ran into Rich. I couldn&#8217;t see Rich from where I was, but I could hear him. He was having difficulty with some of the office equipment. (Rich doesn&#8217;t come to the Chicago office all that often.) He was trying to photocopy a page.<br />
&#8220;How long does it take for this thing to make a copy?&#8221;<br />
There was a pause of a second or two, before Neil, in his ever-chipper, happily matter-of-fact manner, replied:<br />
&#8220;That&#8217;s a printer!&#8221;<br />
I could not see Rich&#8217;s face, but Andrew did &#8212; the look of tired frustration is one he&#8217;ll not forget anytime soon. It took me many minutes to stop giggling (let alone laughing) about the error.<br />
We had a quick staff meeting, mostly to get everyone there on the same page for what we had to do. Some of us were going out for pizza, while others had to stay in and finish up presentations. But no matter what, we all had to be at Second City at 19:15 for the show. Those who had to remain behind were identified, and the rest of us shuffled off to the hotel (to drop off our laptops).<br />
Along the way from the office to the restaurant, I got a history lesson from Stephanie. She lived in Chicago for seven years, and has the same Cliff Claven gene I do. She told us about how the Wrigley building was built by the Wrigley chewing gum company (same name as on Wrigley park). The guy sold chewing gum only after laundry soap had failed. She mentioned the Chicago Tribune tower has pieces of rock from the Taj Mahal, the Berlin Wall, the Great Wall of China, the Great Pyramids, and even a moon rock embedded in its walls. And the one that impressed me most: the US Army Corps of Engineers reversed the flow of the Chicago River to combat pollution. Now how&#8217;s that for obscure bits of trivia?<br />
The destination was a place called Gino&#8217;s East. This is a Chicago institution, home of one of the best deep dish pizzas in the city. And it is darn tasty, not to mention filling (two slices, and I was done). It&#8217;s also a bit of an odd place. Having moved to their current location only a couple of years ago (the old location was too small, so they took over the vacant Planet Hollywood building), I simply couldn&#8217;t believe all the graffiti on the inside. This is one of the neat things about Gino&#8217;s East &#8212; almost every surface of every wall, table, chair, mirror, window (you&#8217;re not allowed to draw on the TV, though) is covered in graffiti. Not the bold paint that you&#8217;ll see on alley walls, but writing. Lots of it. So much that it&#8217;s often difficult to make any of it out. If nothing else, the place has ambiance.<br />
Second City is a legend. Most of the biggest names in comedy in the last 30 years have come through here. SCTV, one of the great Canadian television comedy shows. Chicago&#8217;s Second City is the original, and probably the largest one. I&#8217;d never been to the one in Toronto, and coming to the original is one tremendous opportunity.<br />
We saw a show called &#8220;Red Scare&#8221;. It was a group of six actors: three men, three women. This was a play made of short skits, less than 10 minutes apiece (and usually shorter). It was particularly funny considering how the word &#8220;red&#8221; used to denote &#8220;communist&#8221;, and the fear that came along with it. Today, &#8220;red&#8221; refers to all the red states from the last election, and how neo-conservatism is running rampant throughout the United States. I find it interesting that the entertainment field loves picking on the &#8220;majority&#8221;.<br />
We all sat in the stage right side, against the wall. Jamie, Mel, and I drank red wine and enjoyed the oddball antics. Except for the &#8220;Coach Cancer&#8221; skit, the majority of it was hilarious. We even stuck around for the post-show improv routine (the usual skits based on a word from the audience, and the &#8220;change&#8221; routine).<br />
There was no night out for us beyond this. We returned to the hotel to settle in. It&#8217;s an odd experience staying in the same room as your boss. Given, Allard and I have a great relationship &#8212; he&#8217;s a strong leader, and is very flexible. I&#8217;ve been very fortunate to work with him. Still, it&#8217;s odd.<br />
Thankfully, we have separate beds&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/02/mercedes-benz-calgary-chicago/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">405</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
