<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>kona &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/kona/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 20:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Pictures from Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=pictures-from-hawaii</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hawaii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hilo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/04/11/pictures-from-hawaii/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I haven&#8217;t had a chance to finish with the blog entries yet (editing is such sweet fun), but I do at least have the gallery of photos from our last Hawaii trip up for viewing. The full list will appear in the various blog entries. Enjoy!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I haven&#8217;t had a chance to finish with the blog entries yet (editing is such sweet fun), but I do at least have the <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/hawaii-big-island-2007/">gallery of photos from our last Hawaii trip</a> up for viewing. The full list will appear in the various blog entries.<br />
Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/04/pictures-from-hawaii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">691</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Timeshare Sales, Beach Day and Royal Kona Luau</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 07:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hawaii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/03/31/hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alex wanted a beach day. And beach day we had. Well, once we sat through a rather lengthy time share sales pitch, anyway. That was part of the deal from the activity purchase. USD$100 off the total price if we sat through a &#8220;presentation&#8221;. They&#8217;re never just presentations. They&#8217;re geared to one thing and one &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Timeshare Sales, Beach Day and Royal Kona Luau"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex wanted a beach day. And beach day we had.<br />
Well, once we sat through a rather lengthy time share sales pitch, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-694"></span>That was part of the deal from the activity purchase. USD$100 off the total price if we sat through a &#8220;presentation&#8221;. They&#8217;re never just presentations. They&#8217;re geared to one thing and one thing only: effectively con you into purchasing something you really don&#8217;t need.<br />
For the record, the sales pitch is very convincing. Take what you spend on an average vacation. Multiply it by 25. Tack on inflation (be liberal and say only 2%). It comes out to a rather large chunk of change. Ours came out to the price of our house.<br />
That&#8217;s the first trick: slap you in the head with a paddle and get you to seriously think about how much you&#8217;re spending. Of course, these sorts of presentations are always set up in places where you&#8217;re spending a lot of money because the area is expensive. There&#8217;s a reason why you&#8217;ll find dozen of these things in Honolulu &#8230; and none in Death Valley.<br />
Next comes the advantages of signing up with the program. All the features of 5-star resorts, free access to any of the Wyndham properties (Wyndham was the company), concierge, full kitchens, bla bla bla.<br />
They play off the need for people to feel like they live more richly than they are. The appeal of saving money and getting to stay in places that should be normally above their means is an awfully hard thing to pass up.<br />
Thankfully, reality pervades in our lives. We don&#8217;t travel around the United States, so most of the properties are not in our travel plans. Now or ever (more than likely). Also, you need to book places like this far in advance. Alex and I don&#8217;t plan enough in advance because it ruins spontaneity. As for cost &#8212; we stay as cheaply as we can, and splurge only once in a while. We don&#8217;t go all out. Most of the cost of our trips goes to airfare.<br />
It takes a lot to tell them &#8220;no&#8221;. If you try to say &#8220;no&#8221;, they immediately get into financing plans. Thankfully, our agent gave us an out from the beginning, saying she didn&#8217;t want to hear &#8220;maybe&#8221;, only &#8220;yes&#8221; or &#8220;no&#8221;, and be as truthful as we could. The answer was &#8220;no&#8221;. It took a couple of hours, but we got out.<br />
Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it wasn&#8217;t a waste of time. It was actually an interesting experience to see how these things operate. Who knows, maybe if we find the right sort of vacation property company, we might sign up. But it&#8217;s going to offer us far more than just the continental United States and a sole property in Canada.<br />
Returning to the hotel, we went for lunch at the grill before camping out for the afternoon on the grounds. Alex took shelter in shade to read. I went swimming in the bay.<br />
Only problem is that you need to keep an eye out for the Hawaiian Green Turtles that frequent the area. They don&#8217;t bite, but they&#8217;re endangered. And touching them is a serious no-no. They don&#8217;t know this however, and will come right at you because they&#8217;re not afraid of you.<br />
This is what drove me to rent a mask so I could see under the water. (If I&#8217;d been smart, I&#8217;d have gotten flippers, too.) Smart move, too, because the bay was full of all sorts of interesting sea life, including those cute colourful little fishes you see on the Discovery Channel.<br />
We headed to the Royal Kona Resort for about 17:00. Given that our last luau was perhaps the best in Hawaii (the Smith Family Luau on Kauai), this had a lot to live up to. We got our shell leis, access to non-stop drinks, and proceeded to mingle.<br />
The luau space is not huge, but adequate to the need. And the shoreline offers a wonderful view of the setting sun. The imu pit was a huge dirt mound, not nearly as fancy as the concrete and stone pits at Smith&#8217;s.  It did the effective cooking job, at least.<br />
The entertainment was pretty good, I must admit. The host is adequately cheesy, but without being horrible. The band loud without being obnoxious. And as always, there&#8217;s at least one member of the all-Polynesian revue who looks as white as the pure driven snow.<br />
The trees are well-arranged (whether or not it was intentional, I have no idea), the tables were a little cramped, but it wasn&#8217;t hard to see the show and mingle with everyone. I can imagine what it must be like on a busy night, though. The fire dancer was solid. Like the show we saw in Honolulu last year, there had to be a screen between him and the audience.<br />
Back at the hotel, we endulged in another evening of Law &amp; Order. Seems to be on TV all the time here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/hawaii-2007-timeshare-sales-beach-day-and-royal-kona-luau/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">694</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aloha from Hawaii</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/aloha-from-hawaii/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=aloha-from-hawaii</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/aloha-from-hawaii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 22:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hawaii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost luggage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/03/30/aloha-from-hawaii/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yeah, I know &#8212; why am I on a computer if I&#8217;m on vacation? Relax, I have good reason. Our house is now effectively sold, and for whatever reason we&#8217;ve been unable to fax properly from Hawaii back to Calgary. Very odd, indeed. However, when you need to communicate with your realtor and faxes don&#8217;t &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/aloha-from-hawaii/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Aloha from Hawaii"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yeah, I know &#8212; why am I on a computer if I&#8217;m on vacation?<br />
Relax, I have good reason. Our house is now effectively sold, and for whatever reason we&#8217;ve been unable to fax properly from Hawaii back to Calgary. Very odd, indeed. However, when you need to communicate with your realtor and faxes don&#8217;t work, you resort to whatever &#8220;official&#8221; form of communication they suggest. In this case, email.<br />
Hence the computer. But given the trouble we&#8217;ve had, I&#8217;m sticking out for a few minutes to make sure it went through.<br />
<span id="more-685"></span>It&#8217;s already day 4, and I&#8217;m only just getting into a vacation now. Day 1 was spent trying to get here. Delayed departure due to weather, nearly missed the connecting flight in Denver, mechanical problems in Honolulu put us late into Kona. And my bag? Yeah, left behind in Denver.<br />
Hint to United Airlines: If a plane comes in late, allow time for bags to be sent through properly. And when someone calls in to ask about the whereabouts of their bag, don&#8217;t lie to them, either.<br />
Day 2 was finding my bag. Ugh.<br />
Day 3 we went up and down the coast a bit before going out on a &#8220;dinner cruise&#8221;. The locals refer to it as a &#8220;booze cruise&#8221;. Not great when you can&#8217;t drink. And there&#8217;s a very loud bridal party.<br />
Today, we went to a timeshare presentation. No, we didn&#8217;t buy one (if we&#8217;d had the money, we would have, though). It took $100 off our activities cost, so we couldn&#8217;t say &#8220;no&#8221;.<br />
Anyway, time&#8217;s almost up and there&#8217;s been no bounce with the email, so I presume all is good. Back to trying to forget about computers for a few more days&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/aloha-from-hawaii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">685</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Down in South Kona</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/down-in-south-kona/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=down-in-south-kona</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/down-in-south-kona/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2007 06:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hawaii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/03/30/hawaii-2007-down-in-south-kona/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ah, there&#8217;s nothing like waking up on a sunny day. Even better, there&#8217;s nothing like clean underwear. After a hearty breakfast, we made an effort to do two things: Book a dinner cruise (they&#8217;re usually fun) Book a luau (same reason) This led us to Amanda, the Expedia Local Expert. I had no idea these &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/down-in-south-kona/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Down in South Kona"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, there&#8217;s nothing like waking up on a sunny day. Even better, there&#8217;s nothing like clean underwear.<br />
After a hearty breakfast, we made an effort to do two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Book a dinner cruise (they&#8217;re usually fun)</li>
<li>Book a luau (same reason)</li>
</ol>
<p><span id="more-690"></span>This led us to Amanda, the Expedia Local Expert. I had no idea these things existed. Apparently they&#8217;re all over Maui. Technically, a Microsoft employee who knows a lot about the area, gets you good rates on the otherwise expensive activities, and can suggest a few things to check out.<br />
She would also sell us on swimming with dolphins (&#8220;they swim right up to you&#8221; if you&#8217;re pregnant) and booked us in with some presentation thing to knock off USD$100 off our activity bill. I sense &#8220;timeshare&#8221;, but we&#8217;ll see.<br />
Booking in hand, we went south in search of &#8230; stuff. If I&#8217;m gonna fly 7,000 kilometres, I want to see more than just the hotel. Especially if there&#8217;s historical stuff in the area. I can&#8217;t sit on a beach for more than a few hours without going loco.<br />
My goal? Pu&#8217;uhonau o Honaunau, a place of refuge. According to the books, any violation of <em>kapu</em>, ancient Hawaiian law, was met with one punishment: death. Since that tends to put a damper on things like living a long life, someone had the sense to create places of refuge where people could attempt to escape (they weren&#8217;t easy to get into, since that would defeat the purpose of <em>kapu</em>), and get absolution for whatever crime they committed. If they died in the attempt, well, they were sentenced to die anyway, right?<br />
There&#8217;s only one road to get there. And it took a while. Along the way we stopped in Kainaliu, one of many little towns that sprung up during Hawaii&#8217;s agricultural burst in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. They&#8217;re the last refuge of the old general stores, which dot the road south from Kailua.<br />
Old theatres. Interesting little stores. Donkey Balls. (Not joking. They&#8217;re chocolate-covered macadamia nuts. But I love the name.) And even Dog the Bounty Hunter. (Well, Da Kine Bail Bonds, anyway.) Alex nearly freaked, though the shock took a mile or two to set in.<br />
Lunch was a real pain. We couldn&#8217;t get into <a href="http://www.coffeeshack.com/">The Coffee Shack</a> that Amanda had recommended &#8212; too full. So went in search of other things. Not open. Not appropriate. Not food (minor issue, really). We stopped at the Painted Church along the way. A very neat place.<br />
I thought, rather naively, that Pu&#8217;uhonau o Honaunau might have food. So we drove the 10 minutes to the park, only to find out it didn&#8217;t. We had to double-back almost a half hour back to The Coffee Shack, which finally had space.<br />
It&#8217;s a neat place that has a killer view off the patio. Decent food, if a bit pricey. Killer desserts. And you get to watch geckos while you eat. How cool is that?<br />
Following our repast, we went all the way back to <a href="http://www.nps.gov/puho/">Pu&#8217;uhonau o Honaunau</a>. We managed to sneak in without paying due to a wad of confusion the first time we went there.<br />
It&#8217;s a lot more desolate than I would have thought. Mind you, all the Hawaiian heiau I&#8217;ve seen so far are pretty &#8230; well, plain. There&#8217;s not much beyond the walls. The wooden buildings are long gone, so the only sign of anything important is the stuff built of solid rock.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long, needing to run back to the hotel to change and catch a bus downtown for the Captain Bean&#8217;s Cruise. It looks great on paper. But it&#8217;s got another name the locals use: The Booze Cruise. If only we&#8217;d known&#8230;<br />
The bus, a Roberts Hawaii bus, arrived on time. A couple of older folks and us got on, only to have to wait for another party. A bachelorette party. A loud bachelorette party. I could only seeing this going from bad to worse.<br />
The barge, effectively what the boat is, awaited us at the pier. We checked in, got our boarding pass (kinda hokey), two drink tickets (one each), and had our photos taken.<br />
The area is made mostly of square tables set into the floor, where you eat and watch the entertainment. Although there is an upstairs, passengers aren&#8217;t allowed up there. Too bad, really, since it would have been a nice reprieve from the band. Good, but a little too loud for me.<br />
It was a smooth cruise, taking about two hours. Sometimes didn&#8217;t even remember we were on a boat. The food was pretty good, too, but the corn was way overcooked. We were pretty happy when we got back to our hotel.<br />
The bachelorette party tried to pick up two of the male dancers on board. They were super-loud on the way back (the lives of the party).<br />
I must be getting old&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/03/down-in-south-kona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">690</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
