<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>new years eve &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/new-years-eve/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:07:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The kids&#039; first New Years Eve</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-kids-first-new-years-eve</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 23:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years tea]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3618</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Okay, to be fair, Monkey is now 10, and Choo Choo is rapidly approaching 8. They&#8217;ve seen &#8220;new years eve&#8221; a few times, but they&#8217;ve been more the family-friendly type. Staying up to midnight is the new thing. The only time they&#8217;ve ever been up past midnight is because of travel, and that&#8217;s always been &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The kids&#039; first New Years Eve"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, to be fair, Monkey is now 10, and Choo Choo is rapidly approaching 8. They&#8217;ve seen &#8220;new years eve&#8221; a few times, but they&#8217;ve been more the family-friendly type. Staying up to midnight is the new thing. The only time they&#8217;ve ever been up past midnight is because of travel, and that&#8217;s always been a bit of a struggle.<br />
Last night, for the first time ever, they watched a clock tick from 23:59 of one year to 00:00 of another. Honestly, they fared better than I did.<br />
And that, my friends, is not a good sign.<br />
<span id="more-3618"></span><br />
Alex was working, so it was just the three of us. An &#8220;extreme cold&#8221; weather warning was on its third or fourth day (honestly, I&#8217;d lost track), where the ambient temperature was in the mid-minus-20s, before you tacked on the wind chill. The City of Calgary wisely cancelled their outdoor events, as did a number of other cities across Canada (including Ottawa&#8217;s somewhat-gut-punch cancellation of a final 150th event).<br />
Although the City still had their family indoor event (with a &#8220;ball drop&#8221; at 9pm), I didn&#8217;t feel like fighting the kids out the door, very bundled up, to wait for a C-Train downtown, to be too warm with too many other people (and likely way past the fire department&#8217;s safety limit), to cheer, and then come home again. So we ordered pizza and watched movies.<br />
At 21:50, I went to the internet and pulled up the live video feed of Times Square as they approached midnight EST. Without the glorious commentary of the various American broadcasters (NBC&#8217;s feed on YouTube was just the video), the event was pretty bland. Even Monkey had to ask:</p>
<blockquote><p>Wait. <em>This</em> is what people get all excited about? Just to go &#8220;woo hoo&#8221;? This is stupid.</p></blockquote>
<p>For years, I&#8217;d kinda wondered the same thing, silently. I mean, there&#8217;s a small part of me that would like to see Times Square at New Years for myself, just once, solely for the spectacle. But if NBC&#8217;s unaided feed was indicative of what it&#8217;s really like &#8230; maybe I&#8217;ll just watch at a distance and be happy with that.<br />
And, really, Monkey is right. We celebrate for what, exactly? Surviving the year? We roll a calendar just as winter has begun (at least in the northern hemisphere; I think those south of the equator have it way better, here), and still have months of freezing winds and ice to suffer through. And at the end of it, all we&#8217;ve really done is give us a few weeks of cursing ourselves for selecting &#8220;2017&#8221; from drop-down lists.<br />
None of the stupidity of 2017 has gone away. It&#8217;s still there, and will continue to still be there. It&#8217;s like having Biff Tanner banging us in the forehead, shouting &#8220;Hey! McFly!&#8221;. We still have to suffer through that.<br />
My resolution? As much as I suffer not having close contact with most of my friends, I think one of the things I must do this year is limit, or at least filter my social media. There&#8217;s too much negativity, and no matter how much I try to let it roll off, the stink remains and ultimately weighs me down. I find it no end of ironic that while my <a href="https://www.insights.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Insights</a> review says I&#8217;m not empathetic, the bullshit of the world eats away at my soul.<br />
But, as the saying goes, one day at a time. I spend too much worrying about my future, rather than the things I do today that will make that future unfold. So let&#8217;s focus on today, and let tomorrow come as it must.<br />
Which is what we did today: New Years Tea, which we&#8217;ve managed to avoid on New Years Day for a few years, largely due to Alex&#8217;s work schedule, and an apparent misunderstanding about Fairmont Palliser; until this year&#8217;s instance, we didn&#8217;t think the Palliser did afternoon tea at all. It&#8217;s no Banff Springs, and I really did want to do Chateau Lake Louise this year, but at least it&#8217;s New Years Day, which is the day I prefer to do this, not a couple of days before or after.<br />
What will tomorrow bring? I can guess, but that would be negative. Rather, I&#8217;ll just deal with it &#8230; <em>tomorrow</em>. Today, I write. Because that&#8217;s what I need to do to prepare my future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2018/01/the-kids-first-new-years-eve/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3618</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Years Tea, 2012</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/new-years-tea-2012/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-tea-2012</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/new-years-tea-2012/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 06:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2977</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[This year, we continued with our burgeoning tradition of having afternoon tea on 1 January. In our previous two years, we ventured into the mountains to the Banff Springs, which boasts one of the best afternoon teas I&#8217;ve had. But this year, we weren&#8217;t in the Banff area &#8212; we&#8217;re currently hanging out with Alex&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/new-years-tea-2012/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Years Tea, 2012"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year, we continued with our burgeoning tradition of having afternoon tea on 1 January. In our previous two years, we ventured into the mountains to the Banff Springs, which boasts one of the best afternoon teas I&#8217;ve had. But this year, we weren&#8217;t in the Banff area &#8212; we&#8217;re currently hanging out with Alex&#8217;s parents in Maple Ridge. Oh, what to do, what to do&#8230;<br />
Thankfully, there&#8217;s a Fairmont hotel here, too, and the tradition continues fairly readily. So with enough advance notice, we reserved a space, and made arrangements to have the tradition carry on. The only question was who would be our guests this year?<br />
Well, it&#8217;s not like we don&#8217;t know anyone in the Lower Mainland&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2977"></span>Last year we had (sadly) gone on without a guest, so this year we made an extra effort to have someone join us. Because the first year had been a(n old) friend of mine, we went with one of Alex&#8217;s friends, Sandra. They&#8217;ve known each other pretty much ever since Alex moved back to Calgary (and strongly believe &#8212; though as of yet proven definitively &#8212; that they&#8217;re distantly related), and it was a perfect chance to invite close friends (who also happen to have kids).<br />
The Fairmont Hotel Vancouver is one of the mainstays of downtown Vancouver. I&#8217;d only ever been in it once before, ages ago, for a quick drink one evening. It shows its age a bit, I think, and is not quite as nice as the Banff Springs (in my opinion). But it was the only Fairmont hotel in town that did afternoon tea (there is another, but tea is not offered), and thus our best option.<br />
(Okay, to be fair, our best option was to go to the Empress in Victoria &#8212; which had been my first hope &#8212; but the act of getting to Victoria was definitely much more convoluted and the potential guest list much shorter. One day, however, I will have my tea at the Empress!)<br />
Our drive into Vancouver was one that filled me with excitement. I love Vancouver, I truly do. It&#8217;s taken me years to really appreciate the vibrance of the buildings, the communities, the myriad of curious shops, all blended with the water and the mountains. Near-13 years ago, when I left Vancouver, I swore I&#8217;d never return. Today, I find myself desperately trying to find a way to come back. (And I may &#8212; more on that, later&#8230;)<br />
Going off of old memories, I turned our rented minivan (not my choice of vehicle, I should note, and I will <em>never</em> rent one again &#8212; I loathe these vehicles) off Highway 1 onto the Grandview Highway for the trip into the city. It took us past many of the small communities and lush, green parks that I&#8217;d remembered only poorly, and realised just how much I&#8217;d missed them. We turned down Kingsway and then onto Main St, before zigging across Terminal to Quebec (which turns into Expo Bvld, and then into Pacific Bvld), which I realised after a few moments wasn&#8217;t the way I&#8217;d planned to go (I&#8217;d actually meant to go on the Georgia viaduct).<br />
The mistake, however, let me zip into Yaletown for a gander at where I&#8217;d spent two years living (part of) my life. It was where Radical Entertainment had been located, and I&#8217;d spent many hours of every day either in the office, or walking the areas around it coming to and from work, or going to lunch with co-workers. I knew I wouldn&#8217;t see the same neighbourhood, but I guess nothing really prepares you for the suddenness of seeing something that&#8217;s been evolving for nearly a decade. The last time I&#8217;d been there was to have a beer with my friend Greg, the day before our respective weddings (he was married the same day).<br />
Then it was up Homer to Georgia, and the final task: find a place to park. And, more importantly, one I could get in with a minivan (easier said than done; parallel-parking that bastard was not something I wanted to attempt). It took nearly 10 minutes to find an underground lot at the Scotiabank Theatre building at Burrard and Smithe. We walked up Burrard to Robson, and &#8212; having noticed the advertisments while looking to park &#8212; went into the soon-to-be-closing HMV.<br />
The HMV at the corner of Robson and Burrard was an icon. Three floors of heaven &#8230; at least for me, at the end of the 1990s, before Apple killed off the music stores. (That is not an attack on Apple, by the way. Apple was just the one who made it happen. Music stores&#8217; death was a given the day the MP3 format was first used.) I remember the HMV from those days past as a place I could lose hours in: perusing the racks on the main and upper (half) floor, looking for things that would sound great, but usually to see what CDs were in the 2 for $20 bins. Downstairs was the massive DVD section; another massive use of my time (and money).<br />
As we walked in the door, passing one of the clerks bearing massive signs on posts, held over their heads in &#8220;the end of the world is near&#8221;-style with &#8220;store closing &#8211; up to 70% off&#8221; emblazoned in massive letters, I couldn&#8217;t help feel a pang of remorse. I am one who has contributed to the loss of such stores. I lamented the closing of the massive 4-floor A&amp;B Sound in downtown Vancouver (a building that remains empty to this day, surprisingly enough), despite being just as at fault for buying music online (though I freely admit at the time that I was still buying CDs in large quantities). I even commented to Monkey to look carefully, as she&#8217;ll not see another store like this again in her life. It is truly a dying breed.<br />
We arrived at the Hotel Vancouver just before noon, and found ourselves the first to arrive in the lounge for tea. A set of five round tables had been moved into a long row, twelve chairs arranged around the row in preparation for our party. A large artificial tree, coated liberally with artificial snow, occupied a point in the centre of the room, next to our tables. The bar was to one side, the 12-foot arched windows into the alley entrance for valets and taxis to the other.<br />
Nicole, (&#8220;Tia Nicole&#8221; to the kids, &#8220;Nikki&#8221; to just about everyone else) was the first to arrive, having survived her New Years Eve intact. Sandra and her brood arrived not long afterwards (although Amir was unable to attend, having been called into the hospital). Grandpa and Granny arrived a while later.<br />
The tea was &#8230; well, perhaps a little disappointing, compared to how the Banff Springs delivers it. There, the tea is wheeled out to you so you may sniff at the loose tea before ordering. The view is unmatched, with looking down the Bow River valley. The food is served on china, using silver frames to separate the three levels of sandwiches and cakes. The Hotel Vancouver cannot match the view, sadly; the menus looked a little too tattered. And while the food was still high-quality, it just somehow seemed lacking. Perhaps I&#8217;m too spoiled from Banff?<br />
The company, however, was welcome, and (thankfully) all of the kids were well-behaved. It was by far our largest gathering, and I was a little worried that it might get out of hand. But even the arrival of the harpist, who was immediately beset by all the kids (and Monkey desperately trying to pluck the strings in such a way that looked like she might rip them out of the frame) was tame, and we left without a single broken anything. (Well, maybe a resolution or two related to diet, but that&#8217;s not my problem&#8230;)<br />
With Tia Nicole in tow, we braved HMV for a deal or three before heading out of downtown. Our trip back, however, was indirect, as Alex and I had a side trip we needed to do. Last night, after our New Year&#8217;s Eve dinner sans kidlets, we went driving out to Port Moody. To look at houses.<br />
We&#8217;re thinking of moving to the west coast. We&#8217;re not sure when, but the move itself is an eventuality. The question is &#8220;where&#8221;. Alex would just as soon move in next door to her parents (okay, okay, slight exaggeration). Me? Houseboat on False Creek. As you can see, there&#8217;s a bit of a discrepancy we have to deal with. The last time Alex was out here (back in June, when I was mired in a week-long slog just before a site launch), she&#8217;d &#8220;discovered&#8221; Port Moody as a strong potential option. It&#8217;s on the West Coast Express line, fairly easy to get to Maple Ridge, and has one of the region&#8217;s hospitals. It&#8217;s also on the water, and the views there are really quite nice.<br />
So last night we drove around a bit. What was out there? What was for sale, and could we even hope to afford anything? Would we even like it? With Christmas lights, the place does look very inviting, but the darkness (and it was dark!) obscures much. We had to come back in the daytime to get a better idea.<br />
And the idea is &#8230; well, it&#8217;s looking good. We even found a house that we like (location especially), which lends credence to the thought. The hard part, really, is knowing &#8220;when&#8221;. That&#8217;ll come down to Alex finding a position that will work for her as a primary motivator &#8212; I&#8217;m a little easier to deal with, employment-wise.<br />
But that&#8217;s for another year &#8212; I doubt it will be this one, or even next year. There is much that needs to happen, and many things we need to do between now and then. But we can start to think and plan.<br />
Like for next year &#8230; where are we doing tea, and who&#8217;s coming?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/new-years-tea-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2977</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2010-a-year-in-review</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2829</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Man, it feels like a year ago since I last wrote one of these &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;) 2010 was the year we made contact &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2010, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, it feels like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/">a year ago since I last wrote one of these</a> &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;)<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_(film)">2010 was the year we made contact</a> &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named Choo Choo. It was a year I changed my career outlook (yes, again), and found that I&#8217;m not (completely) useless. This was a year of family, for me, and that&#8217;s perhaps the most important aspect.<br />
But despite all that, I hesitate to call it &#8220;a year of change&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2829"></span>Got me as to why, though. Let&#8217;s be honest, there were a lot of changes, not the least of which are the ones noted above. But at no time did I feel like this is a sudden (and possibly unwanted) shift in my life. It actually feels like things are more settled this year, despite the apparent upheaval, than in previous years. Maybe one day I&#8217;ll make some sense of that little quandary.<br />
In the meantime, let&#8217;s review 2010:</p>
<ul>
<li>Began the year with tea at the Banff Springs, seeing my friend Sonny for the first time in about 15 years</li>
<li>Started working with some old friends at a new(er) company, Evans Hunt</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton for a &#8220;surprise&#8221; weekend (mostly for Monkey) and spent a great morning in the waterslides with her</li>
<li>Celebrated my Nana&#8217;s 97th birthday, which would also sadly be her last</li>
<li>Found out that I&#8217;m K+, my kids are K+, and my wife is anti-K</li>
<li>Spent many a sleepless night worrying about Choo Choo before she was born</li>
<li>Though originally disheartened, came to love and be thrilled by the 2010 Winter Olympics in Canada, and felt the massive pride for the successes of our athletes
<ul>
<li>Yes, I Twittered obsessively during the Men&#8217;s Hockey gold medal game</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bought our first flat-screen TV, to go along with our Apple TV</li>
<li>Welcomed my youngest, (code)named Choo Choo to our world</li>
<li>Watched Monkey&#8217;s first Easter egg hunt</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;ve got something called &#8220;narrow angles&#8221; in my eyes, and got laser surgery in both of them</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller, and visited the Royal Tyrell</li>
<li>Guided (albeit not as well as I could have) the technical launch of my first all-Drupal website: VisitCalgary.com</li>
<li>Experienced the abject terror of losing your child in a mall</li>
<li>Said &#8220;thank you&#8221; to my Nana &#8212; I never say &#8220;goodbye&#8221;</li>
<li>Went on my first train chase with Monkey</li>
<li>Went to dim sum a couple of times, but not nearly enough</li>
<li>Introduced Monkey to sushi &#8212; I think she likes it</li>
<li>Went to Heritage Park a couple of times, and even saw Thomas the Tank Engine (hey, I&#8217;m a parent <em>and</em> I like trains, it&#8217;s a win-win)</li>
<li>Went to the Zoo lots (it helps to have a pass)</li>
<li>Saw a few movies, but not enough for my liking (the favourite of the year was Toy Story 3, and no, not just because I&#8217;m a parent)</li>
<li>Went on the first Great Family Roadtrip:
<ul>
<li>Overnighted in Medicine Hat, AB; Whitewood, SK; Moosimin, SK; and Swift Current, SK</li>
<li>Went to Winnipeg</li>
<li>Went to some place east of Camper, out in the middle of nowhere, as part of Alex&#8217;s family reunion</li>
<li>Stopped off in Regina, Moose Jaw, and Portage La Prairie</li>
<li>Drove the whole way and back again, and the kids didn&#8217;t seem to mind at all</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got diagnosed with a hernia (yay, me)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 3rd birthday, her first in Canada (beyond the day she was born, that is)</li>
<li>Finally got right ticked off with Shaw&#8217;s horrid home internet service, and switched over to Telus &#8230; we&#8217;ll see how it all goes</li>
<li>Did some kitchen renovation:
<ul>
<li>Installed a new sink and tap</li>
<li>Tore out the Florida ceiling</li>
<li>Installed new lighting</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had new windows installed in the house</li>
<li>Returned to being a developer, rather than a pure manager (I&#8217;m still adjusting to this one)</li>
<li>Took Monkey out on her first real Hallowe&#8217;en</li>
<li>Grew a moustache for Movember (my first, and last time)</li>
<li>Went to the Currie Barracks location of the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market almost every weekend for a year, until the location finally (and sadly) closed in December</li>
<li>Went on our first family flight out to Abbotsford, to spend Christmas in BC</li>
<li>Visited with some old friends from Radical Entertainment</li>
<li>Went to downtown Vancouver for the first time in about five years, and remembered how much I love it there</li>
<li>Had my first green Christmas in many, many years</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains</li>
</ul>
<p>Whoof. That&#8217;s a lot for one year. Can&#8217;t wait to see what 2011 throws at me. Bring it, New Year &#8212; I&#8217;m ready for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year&#039;s Tea, 2011</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-years-tea-2011/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-tea-2011</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-years-tea-2011/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 06:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2827</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I gotta tell ya, kids, 2010 was a pretty wild year. I know a lot of people who keep telling me that the years &#8220;just fly by&#8221; and before you know it, another year&#8217;s gone. The year past was definitely a change for our family, in many, many ways. (And I&#8217;d like to think that &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-years-tea-2011/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Year&#039;s Tea, 2011"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I gotta tell ya, kids, 2010 was a pretty wild year. I know a lot of people who keep telling me that the years &#8220;just fly by&#8221; and before you know it, another year&#8217;s gone. The year past was definitely a change for our family, in many, many ways. (And I&#8217;d like to think that most of them were for the better, so I&#8217;m not going to try and figure out the split &#8212; I prefer to remain blissfully naive on this one.)<br />
This is our &#8220;new&#8221; tradition. Mommy and I decided it would be tradition after <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/">having such a wonderful time with my old friend Sonny, having afternoon tea</a>. Suddenly, it seemed just perfect to have tea every New Year&#8217;s Day. The question now, of course, is where to have tea. Last year, it was at the Banff Springs Hotel. This year, mostly for simplicity, we did the same.<br />
Next year? Well, that&#8217;s a whole 364 days of Anything-Can-Happen!<br />
<span id="more-2827"></span>Despite the fact that Mommy and I stayed up to midnight to ring in the New Year (something we hope you&#8217;ll start doing with us in the years to come), rising this morning was &#8230; well, surprisingly painful. Somewhere along the line, I&#8217;d slept &#8220;funny&#8221; and right screwed up my right shoulder. (It still hurts, some 14 hours later.) That&#8217;s about when Mommy and I definitively decided we weren&#8217;t just going to New Year&#8217;s Tea &#8212; we were also going to the Hot Springs for a soak.<br />
Bundled into the car, we pulled out of Calgary just before 10:30. It was a bit later than we wanted, but it still gave us time before our 13:00 tea time. Or it would have been more time, had it not been for the blowing snow&#8230;<br />
Somewhere past Ozada, I began to notice the wind. Until today, I&#8217;d never personally come across the problem of our mostly-trusty Jetta having issues with the wind. But it was getting buffeted, not really sliding or drifting (as my Mini was sometimes prone to) so much as feeling the shoves. Added to that was the snow the wind was kicking up. It wasn&#8217;t whiteout conditions, but I quickly found myself with one eye searching for the lines on the road and the other eye on the idiots around us content to pass at what I considered unsafe speeds given the weather conditions. I think Mommy was worried enough for all of us.<br />
The wind and snow was all gone by the time we&#8217;d passed Dead Man&#8217;s Flats, and we were soon at the Banff Park gates, getting our new annual pass. (We didn&#8217;t go into the mountains enough in 2010. That&#8217;s something Mommy and I intend to rectify this year.) Some 20 minutes later, we were unloading from the car in the Upper Hot Springs parking lot.<br />
Now, Monkey, you and I are of the same blood &#8212; neither of us are particularly fanatic about hot water. As for you, Choo Choo, you and Mommy seem to enjoy it quite a lot. I know the water there today wasn&#8217;t hot enough for Mommy. It was only 38 degrees; Mommy prefers something around 42 degrees. But it was just right considering the outside temperature was -16 &#8230; and not counting the windchill.<br />
The soak felt good, and we marvelled at the steam freezing to our heads. Swimming through the thick steam was sometimes like wading through a dream, having people and details seem out of reach until you get close and the details come clear.<br />
One advantage of the hot water is that we tend not to notice the cold so much on our way back to the car. We were a few minutes late for our tea time, but the Rundle Lounge was mostly empty, only two other tables already occupied. We were seated in almost the same place we sat last year.<br />
The service, admittedly, was not up to par for Fairmont, and I was a bit surprised. There were only two people serving about 15 tables, and they seemed pulled in too many directions. Always professional, but sometimes hard to get their attention, and it took a while to get a second pot of tea. But nothing to prevent us from going back next year.<br />
I must say, Monkey, you made me very, very proud today. Although you were fidgety (let&#8217;s keep in mind that you are only three years old), you behaved absolutely wonderfully! You didn&#8217;t scream or whine (as you are frequent to do at home), you ate very nicely, and compared to the five year old at the table next to us, you were a perfect angel. Clearly, Mommy must be teaching you well, &#8216;cuz y&#8217;ain&#8217;t learning none of this from me&#8230;<br />
We left just after 15:00, and were heading out of town before 15:30. Both of you were dead asleep before we&#8217;d even passed through downtown Banff.<br />
Once again, it was a wonderful way to spend New Year&#8217;s Day. I hope next year is even better, since you&#8217;ll be able to try all of this stuff, too, Choo Choo. Until then, I wish you both the happiest of dreams.<br />
And maybe let Mommy and Daddy sleep in tomorrow? Please?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-years-tea-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2827</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year&#039;s Eve in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/new-years-eve-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-eve-in-costa-rica</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/new-years-eve-in-costa-rica/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 02:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fireworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1201</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We might not have spent Christmas in Costa Rica this year, but we sure as heck spent New Years here. Not that we went out for any sort of partying, I should say &#8212; things in Costa Rica are a little different than back in North America.   Up north, it&#8217;s about the party &#8212; &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/new-years-eve-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Year&#039;s Eve in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We might not have spent Christmas in Costa Rica this year, but we sure as heck spent New Years here. Not that we went out for any sort of partying, I should say &#8212; things in Costa Rica are a little different than back in North America.  <br />
Up north, it&#8217;s about the party &#8212; everyone goes out, whoops it up, suffers through the hangover the following day. Here, it&#8217;s a chance for family to be close together (most of the bars close at 23:00, apparently) and shoot off fireworks.  <br />
Yes, fireworks. Remember, it&#8217;s still warm here.  <br />
<span id="more-1201"></span>We&#8217;d heard about the fireworks, but in truthful honesty, we didn&#8217;t really know what that meant. When I was a lad, it meant that come Canada Day, your parents went to the corner store, stocked up on roman candles, sparkers, Burning Schoolhouses (and snakes, if you were into that sort of thing), and everyone had a grand time firing off burning ejecta into the sky.  <br />
Of course, paranoid safety regulations (instead of the much-preferred common sense) led to Canucks not being able to get fireworks much anymore. You still can, but it ain&#8217;t easy. And most of them are pretty pathetic, if you ask me. If you want to see anything really good, you end up being at the mercy of your local municipality to organise something, or travel to a fireworks competition.  <br />
Or buy a lot of stuff black market, run out to the middle of a field where it&#8217;s hard to be caught, set &#8217;em off, and run before the cops show up.  <br />
Reason #15 why I love Costa Rica? No regulations on fireworks: Buy what you want, set it off whenever you want. Even if it means well past midnight. Or at least that&#8217;s the way it seems to be.  <br />
Things started here last night around 20:00, when we heard our first bangs. Some of them were mere noisemakers &#8212; lob something explosive in the sky, it makes a loud bang with a short burst of light. That&#8217;s it. No sparkly things, no whizzing, no streaks. But then the larger, more colourful ones started appearing all around. By 21:30, I was marching up the hill to see what I could see.  <br />
It wasn&#8217;t much, but it was clear that New Year&#8217;s Eve in Costa Rica is a bright affair. At least, what I could see. Our condo complex has <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/3108937554/">an amazing view of part of the Central Valley</a>, and it&#8217;s easy to see a huge swath of the area to the north of us. There were the odd pops here and there, a few bright lights, and the odd whiz. Given, it was still pretty early, but revellers were getting started.  <br />
I retreated to the condo for a while, not wanting to fill the memory card on my camera with idle shutter-clicking. I had a feeling that midnight might be something else.  <br />
Despite Alex nearly falling asleep, we watched the ball drop in New York City at 23:00 (we have an NBC station from the Big Apple &#8212; yay satellite television!), which was really neat to watch as we&#8217;d seen the ball&#8217;s location only three days earlier. We&#8217;d seen all the people, and had a real idea of what Time Square must be like with everyone waiting for midnight. But they were much colder than we&#8217;d been, and I was glad to still be wearing my shorts.  <br />
Just after 23:30, I marched back up the hill to wait for midnight in Costa Rica. Although Alex went to sleep (she kept the window and blinds open), I was not alone &#8212; many families had also come to the hilltop to wait for the event. Sure enough, it wasn&#8217;t long before more and more large fireworks could be seen and heard. Over the mountains, I&#8217;m certain something large was happening in Escazu &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t see the fireworks, but the flashes and the banging carried over pretty well.  <br />
Down in downtown Santa Ana, someone had gathered together a lot of firepower, and it was brightening up that part of the sky, too. To the west of us, one of the developments kept throwing up great big bursts of colour. To the north, I could see seemingly random stars appearing over the streetlights.  <br />
But those were nothing compared to what happened at midnight. Well, actually, just after midnight. The exactness of midnight isn&#8217;t a big concern in Costa Rica. As with all things time-related, punctuality doesn&#8217;t seem to be that big of a concern.  <br />
At midnight, everyone who had something left lit the fuse. Suddenly, the whole valley seemed to erupt with brilliant reds, greens, whites, purples, yellows, and blues. Banging, popping, whirling, whizzing, and cracking could be heard from nearly every direction (including behind us, up a wooded hill!), and the 30-odd kilometres across the valley to the other side.<br />
  [flickr]photo:3158504896(small)[/flickr]<br />
I snapped as many pictures as I could, all the while looking around in amazement. I felt bad for not bringing Alex up. Next year, for sure. Just when I thought it was all over, and I started to head back to the apartment, our complex seemed to realise it was after midnight, and started setting off their stuff. As it turned out, it was our downstairs neighbours. And they had quite the powderkeg of firepower.  <br />
The banging woke &#8212; to no surprise &#8212; woke Mi Pequeña Niña. Apparently, in a panicked screaming. Alex brought her to our bed, where the two of them watched the flashes and explosions until I returned. We had to wait until they finally ran out of gunpowder-enhanced goodness before we could all consider going to bed.  <br />
The revelling continued unabated, though. We went to sleep still listening to pops and bangs, seeing the odd flash.  <br />
I can&#8217;t wait until next year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/new-years-eve-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1201</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 04:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/12/31/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day. So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas in Oakville with Chris and Kaz, New Years with Alex"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had hoped to go some place warm for the Christmas holidays this year. I wanted to put Christmas lights on a palm tree. I wanted to make sandmen. I wanted nothing more to worry about than getting a sunburn on Boxing day.<br />
So naturally, I ended up arriving at Pearson International Airport at 6:30 on the morning of 23 December, catching the end of a nasty two-day snowstorm. There&#8217;s poetic justice in this, somewhere.<br />
<span id="more-480"></span>Due to the weather, Cathy (wisely) opted not to come and get me at the airport. Instead, I took a limo (for the extra five dollars, it was worth the comfort) out to Oakville. Since Cathy had to go into work, and I didn&#8217;t have a key to her house, I went to Mom&#8217;s place instead. Cathy had already called her to let her know I was coming, before I called her to let her know I was coming.<br />
I made myself a light breakfast, and then let the red eye flight catch up with me, passing out in Mom&#8217;s bed with my jacket over my head to block out light and sound. Mom and I hung out for a while, then went and ran some errands, concluding with a very lousy lunch at the Tim Horton&#8217;s at the former Trafalgar Village (I have no idea what it&#8217;s called now). The place used to be a Burger King years ago, and was pretty lousy then, too.<br />
I eventually ended up at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s, dumping my things off before the four of us congregated at Mom&#8217;s again for dinner. Ribs, one of my favourites.<br />
During dinner, I decided it was time to let my family know that things were about to change for me. I stated: &#8220;Official annoucement time!&#8221; and declared that they not make any plans for 27 August 2005. This is the day Alex and I will be married. No-one was particularly surprised, and everyone seemed happy about it. This, of course, made me feel happy about it, because I was getting more than a little anxious about the whole thing. Blessings are what I needed most. The happiness I already had.<br />
&#8216;Twas the day before Christmas, and I had a few things left to do, most of which was buying a couple of last-minute presents (most notably for Craig, whom I was having trouble finding). This brought Cathy and I to Oakville Place, barely a kilometre from their house.<br />
Since Oakville Place was first built, I&#8217;d hated it. Originally, I disliked it because of the 100-odd stores in the mall, over 80 of them were dedicated to women&#8217;s fashions. For a teenaged boy, this was about as interesting as &#8230; well, a mall full of stores that had no interest to me. In later years, I came to revile it due to its marked resemblance to a two-storey strip mall. It was meant to look bright and wonderful, but its design left much to be desired.<br />
Recently, Oakville Place underwent a significant overhaul, culminating with a complete change of food courts (the old one is gone, a new, larger one is on the second floor in the new &#8220;wing&#8221;), several new stores (including &#8212; GASP! &#8212; an HMV), and a few other changes. The pit in the centre under the clock has been gone many a-year, but following it are the two fountains that used to exist at either end of the main section under the stairs. The stores are actually nicer than I remember (with a few exceptions), and it feels more like a mall than an oversized women&#8217;s fashion store.<br />
Dinner that night was not at Mom&#8217;s or at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s. For this, we would travel across town to Mark and Darla&#8217;s. This was the first time that I would see Mark and Darla&#8217;s home (completed; I saw it over a year ago &#8212; see [[CBC TV 50th Anniversary VIA Rail train: Reunion]]). I hadn&#8217;t really seen them since Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding.<br />
Mark had invited us over for Christmas Eve dinner, which would be roast beef and yorkshire pudding (which Cathy would make, following the time-honoure recipe that came with the roast pans Dad bought in the States eons ago). This, I looked forward to. I *love* roast beef, especially when prepared by those passionate about it.<br />
Mark and Darla&#8217;s home is quite beautiful. Very tastefully decorated, and already full of the smells of dinner. We were a bit late in arriving, which meant that dinner was well on the way to being ready. Also in attendance were Julie and Dave, whom I hadn&#8217;t seen for almost as long as the last time I saw Mark and Darla. We settled into conversation before we were called to the dinner.<br />
The first round was a smashing corn chowder. That was followed by the roast beef, onions and parsnips, yorkshires, mashed potatoes, and peas. Dessert was a mousse cake from &#8220;La Petit Gateau&#8221;, which is either a really neat little pastry shop, or an in-joke about a supermarket that I never got filled in on. Either way, all was very tasty. Mark went all out.<br />
Even moreso when Cathy, Mom, and I recognized what Mark wore around his neck. When Mark was first going to Appleby College, it was Dad who had taught Mark how to tie a tie. When we were cleaning out Dad&#8217;s things after his death, Cathy had given Mark one of Dad&#8217;s trademark paisley ties. It was this tie that Mark wore over dinner. Given how the meal turned out, I would hedge to bet that Dad had shown up just to give a little advice.<br />
Following dinner was a game &#8212; Scene It. This neat little game includes a DVD that you use as part of the questions. Mark had played it before, but the rest of us had not. We split into four teams: Mark, Darla and Julie (Dave had gone to bed, a victim of a 38-hour day), Cathy and Craig, and Mom and myself. Owing to a series of fortunate rolls and good questions, Mom and I finished the game when the others were about half-way through. (I hate to say it, but they were up against a movie geek. I really wonder how Chris, Stuart, and I would fare against each other.) The others finished neck-in-neck.<br />
Cathy, Craig, and I would stay up a bit late that night, talking about generally nothing (Cathy blaring loud music) before we all went to bed.<br />
Mom arrived around 9:00 the next morning for Christmas day. Her only stipulation was that she wanted to be home before 13:00 to make the turkey. This would not be a problem. A new tradition was started with present unwrapping. In previous years, &#8220;Santa&#8221; (which was usually me) would hand out a present to each person, who would then unwrap it in turn. This year, Cathy and Craig instituted the &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; rule. Basically, they said &#8220;1-2-3&#8221; and everyone unwrapped. The 1-2-3s got progressively faster as the unwrapping progressed.<br />
Interestingly enough, most of the presents I got weren&#8217;t just for me &#8212; they were also for Alex. They included a picnic backpack (as opposed to a basket), a picnic blanket with inflatable headrests, a flashlight, and walkie-talkies. It wouldn&#8217;t be the only time I would regret Alex not being able to come out to Ontario. (She was at her father&#8217;s place in Ruskin.)<br />
Breakfast was a mom-saver: bread, eggs, cream cheese, and a lot of maple syrup. It cooked while we unwrapped. Mimosas washed it down well.<br />
Mom left just before 11:00 for home, while Cathy, Craig, and I wandered around the house. Hamilton Dave (formerly Scarborough Dave) arrived not long afterwards. He was joining us for dinner that night. The last time I&#8217;d seen him was at Cathy and Craig&#8217;s wedding (see [[Cathy and Craig&#8217;s Wedding]]).<br />
The gifts kept coming. Dave received a clock from Cathy and Craig for his boat. In exchange, Cathy and Craig received heated cups for their car. This precipitated a test, where Craig took the remote thermometer, some hot water, and placed the mug in his car to see what would happen. (It works, for the record, but keeps the temperature rather than raise it.) Julie and Dave stopped by for a beer before heading onto other parts for the day.<br />
Dinner was at Mom&#8217;s. It seemed odd to be having dinner there, though I can&#8217;t really tell you why. Maybe because it&#8217;s not the house on Gatestone, where I&#8217;d had so many Christmas dinners before. Hopefully, Christmas dinner will be at our place next year!<br />
We got back and played Possumopoly (a parody of Monopoly based on the <em>Red Green</em> TV show). Craig is plain evil. We played until Dave pretty much passed out from all the beer.<br />
Boxing day was all about the board games. Cathy, Craig, and I played from noon almost all the way through until we went to bed. (It takes a long time to place the Ontario Trivia game.) More visitors passed through, including Mark and Darla. Walkie talkies were tested as Craig went out for supplies at the local convenience store. Pizza was our only other interruption.<br />
The next day, Mom and I went out for Greek for lunch. We then did a little shopping (including presents for Chris and Kaz &#8212; books on Canada, a subtle hint for him to move back). The party that night was the fifth (and hopefully final) wedding party for the two of them (see [[Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#8217;s Wedding]] and [[Turning Japanese Again, Reception Party in Chiba]]). I was literally the token white guy. Therese and Stuart couldn&#8217;t make it as they&#8217;d only arrived in town 10 minutes before the party started, and wanted to visit with family. Gerry was also in the area, but lines were crossed and our paths weren&#8217;t. I would miss out on Gerry&#8217;s presence this time around (Chris would catch up with him a couple days later).<br />
Oddly enough, none of these absences really bothered me &#8212; it gave me a lot of time to chat with Chris and Kaz. And joke with Kaz about being so cold. And I did get a chance to talk with Gerry the next morning.<br />
Chris, Kaz, and I met up with Stuart and Therese for dim sum the next morning. I picked up Chris and Kaz from Chris&#8217; parents&#8217; place, a rental while they wait for their new house to be built. It&#8217;s weird not seeing them in the house I knew. Weirder still was seeing Aidan, Therese and Stuart&#8217;s daughter. It&#8217;s still hard to believe my friends are reproducing. She&#8217;s a doctor (in psychiatry) and he&#8217;s an art director for a major ad firm. We&#8217;ve somehow all grown up. It&#8217;s kind of creepy, actually.<br />
Therese looked like herself again, assumedly due to the lack of a parasitic organism inside her. Stuart looked tired, but the new &#8216;do helped. Kaz wanted to smuggle Aidan back to Japan. We ate and talked for a long time. But eventually we had to part ways. I had to go home. I dropped Chris and Kaz at Clarkson station, not knowing when I&#8217;d see them next.<br />
I thought I&#8217;d done a great packing job, only to realize that I&#8217;d forgotten a few things. I had to steal a duffel bag from Craig to get it all home. Steak and Caesar salad &#8212; a Sowrey favourite &#8212; was my last supper before the flight. Despite a full, uncomfortable flight, Alex was waiting for me when I got back.<br />
I realized how much I&#8217;d missed her for the last few days. It was a realization that she is <em>The One</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/12/christmas-in-oakville-with-chris-and-kaz-new-years-with-alex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">480</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
