<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>huntsville &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/huntsville/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 04:07:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A Middle Ontario wedding</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-middle-ontario-wedding</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 04:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/07/08/a-middle-ontario-wedding/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My friend Kathryn got married this weekend. A truly wonderful event that forced my hand to leave the comfort of my familiar Cowtown (and miss the opening of the Calgary Stampede) to visit rural Ontario and experience the joyous event. I gotta say, probably the most relaxful weekend I&#8217;ve had in &#8230; well, a really &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Middle Ontario wedding"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/kathryn-and-andreas-wedding/">My friend Kathryn got married this weekend.</a> A truly wonderful event that forced my hand to leave the comfort of my familiar Cowtown (and miss the opening of the Calgary Stampede) to visit rural Ontario and experience the joyous event.<br />
I gotta say, probably the most relaxful weekend I&#8217;ve had in &#8230; well, a really long time.<br />
<span id="more-766"></span>It started with a fairly hectic departure on Thursday afternoon. Alex drove me to the airport, I had to run out to a flight, which although I made with a bit of time to spare, ended up being late no thanks to the caterers. (In other words, less food on the plane than there should have been.)<br />
And although I flew Air Canada &#8212; [[Air Canada sucks|perhaps my least favourite airline]] &#8212; I had a really good experience. I was pleasantly surprised. Still, I&#8217;ll fly WestJet because I like it. Arrived in Toronto, checked into the airport Sheraton, and had a good night&#8217;s sleep.<br />
The following day, I picked up my rental car, and proceeded to drive out to Beaverton. The Ford Focus has been a decent car, though I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d run out and buy one. It&#8217;s okay, but far from perfect.<br />
The drive took my through stomping grounds not trampled in many years. I turned north in Whitby (having accidentally gone as far as Oshawa) up Highway 12.<br />
As soon as I felt I was out of the urban area, I turned off the air conditioning, rolled down the windows, and turned my iPod to play nothing but <em>The Tragically Hip</em>. It&#8217;s been years since I did this. I&#8217;d been thinking of it for a couple of weeks, and it was a thoroughly liberating experience to blare over 15 years&#8217; of music as I blasted through the plains of rural Ontario. How I missed the experience.<br />
Along the way, I found a few abandoned rail lines (I need to figure out which they were), back roads, and small towns I&#8217;d never been to (or through). <a href="http://www.beavertononlakesimcoe.com/">Beaverton </a>itself is a rather interesting little place, and the sort of place you would buy a small cottage for weekend (or summer) escapes. This is where Andrea&#8217;s parents have retired to, though they&#8217;re not even in Beaverton proper, prefering more remote locations.<br />
I actually got lost finding the place. Well, not lost per se, but I definitely overshot  where I needed to be by 15 clicks or so. Rather embarrassing for someone  who would normally pride themselves on knowing where they were and where they were going. (See, hon, I&#8217;m saying I was wrong. Take note of this!)<br />
Imaging driving up a corduroy road. Weeds standing shoulder high. No ferris wheel rusting off in the distance, but there&#8217;s not much else. Suddenly, there&#8217;s a break in the bush at the side of the road. The path is full of stones turned white from age and abuse. It looks like danger to go down it. At the end is a clearing with a gorgeous brick farmhouse, manicured lawns, and enough clear cut grass to park cars.<br />
This is where all the fun took place. And it was only as I came into the  yard that I realised something I had not thought of before:<br />
Would I know anyone there?<br />
It dawned on me that aside from Kathryn&#8217;s family &#8212; who barely recognised me in the 12-odd years since I last saw them &#8212; I didn&#8217;t know anyone. I was one of the oldest friends Kathryn had there. If not the oldest. I feel old just <em>thinking </em>about it! But as I talked with Maureen &#8212; Kathryn&#8217;s mom &#8212; I spied the names of Gerry and Sam, mutual friends whom I&#8217;d met through Chris years ago. (Gerry and I had done a trans-Canada trip back in 1997, and I went their <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/gerry-and-sam/">wedding in 2001</a>.)<br />
At least I wasn&#8217;t alone.<br />
Although I was uncomfortable in the heat (not as bad as [[Je suis en Paris, Jour Trois!|Paris last summer]]), the ceremony was wonderful, the food excellent, and I had a great time catching up with my old friends. It had been a very long time since I&#8217;d had a good chat with Gerry and Sam. Just made me remember why I like them so much.<br />
The night carried on and soon dinner was over, the dancing begun, and the mosquitoes were out in swarms. We lathered up with repellent to prevent severe blood loss, but even that wasn&#8217;t enough for some.<br />
I met up with Marika, Kathryn&#8217;s friend for many years [[Kathryn comes for a visit|whom had stayed at Chris&#8217; and my apartment back in 2001]]. She in turn pointed out Bryce, whom I&#8217;d met the night of the Camelot show.<br />
Insert singing dolls here.<br />
I had to leave around 22:00, as I still had 90 minutes to drive. I wasn&#8217;t going back towards the airport, but up to Huntsville to hang out with my family for the rest of the weekend. (I figured I had to make the most of the time.)<br />
I said goodbye to Gerry and Sam, which seemed such a shame &#8212; I rarely get to see or chat to them and leaving so soon just seemed so wrong. I was sorry to say goodbye to Kathryn as well, since I&#8217;d barely had a chance to talk to her. I wasn&#8217;t the furthest away to come (Marika beat me &#8212; she came from Vancouver), but it&#8217;s still hard to see someone only a short while.<br />
The drive up to Huntsville was punctuated by road signs I could barely read, drivers who seemed to not know where they were going, and the need for high beams so I could see in the intense black of the northern Ontario night. At the end, Craig was waiting for me with a beer.<br />
In a weird way, it was sort of home. In a very confused, fast-paced, intense, and long-distance way, that is.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603438536698, tag: 2007+july[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/a-middle-ontario-wedding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">766</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Up at the cottage</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=up-at-the-cottage</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 03:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/07/08/up-at-the-cottage/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, I had the chance to go stay with my sister and brother-in-law&#8217;s cottage near Huntsville, ON. It&#8217;s been a long time since I was last there, and it was good to see my family one last time before it expands again by one. I really need to get out there more often. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Up at the cottage"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, I had the chance to go stay with my sister and brother-in-law&#8217;s cottage near Huntsville, ON. It&#8217;s been a long time since I was last there, and it was good to see my family one last time before it expands again by one.<br />
I really need to get out there more often.<br />
<span id="more-767"></span>Aside from the additional sleep (the beds are comfy, and there&#8217;s no distractions &#8212; except for stomping toddlers, and flushing toilets), it&#8217;s good to get away from cities to remember what it&#8217;s like to be &#8220;away from it all&#8221;.<br />
The cottage country mentality in Ontario is a tough one to understand if you&#8217;ve never lived there. Everyone wants to get away from Toronto on a regular basis. For some, it&#8217;s just living outside of Toronto. For others, it&#8217;s getting away from the Golden Horseshoe, to experience something unique and different.<br />
About three hours is your limit for effectiveness. Less than that, and you&#8217;re not far enough away. Toronto extends (almost) from its shores on Lake Ontario all the way to Barrie. If you can&#8217;t pass Barrie, you&#8217;re at risk of being a subdivision. Everything else needs to be further.<br />
That puts you in the Muskokas. That&#8217;s three hours (ish) away. It&#8217;s a long haul, without being truly annoying. Well, if you&#8217;re on your own, anyway. With bawling toddler, that might be another issue. For me, no biggie.<br />
Besides, I got to be with my family. I don&#8217;t see them nearly enough, and being with Cathy, Mom, Craig, and Tori was a great time. I wished Alex could have been with us, but Alex isn&#8217;t really in a state to fly that far &#8212; it&#8217;s a tough slog when you&#8217;re 35 weeks pregnant. Heck, it&#8217;s almost a tough slog for me!<br />
It&#8217;s almost time for me to head back to Alberta, but I thought I&#8217;d toss in a few pictures of the weekend just past&#8230;<br />
[flickr]set:72157603442812417,tag:2007[/flickr][flickr]set:72157603438559316,tag:2007[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/up-at-the-cottage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I want to go home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=wanna-go-home</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2002 06:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oakville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/14/wanna-go-home/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been on the road far too long. Last night was Thanksgiving dinner up at the cottage. Good food, family, friend (there was only one), and good times. Even better sleep, in my old bed (since co-opted for use in the loft). Mom and Cathy drove me down to the airport. We made a side &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I want to go home"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been on the road far too long.<br />
Last night was Thanksgiving dinner up at the cottage. Good food, family, friend (there was only one), and good times. Even better sleep, in my old bed (since co-opted for use in the loft).<br />
Mom and Cathy drove me down to the airport. We made a side trip to see a rather uninteresting antique dealer in Gravenhurst. Aside from that and a couple of bathroom breaks, we made Pearson in a fairly good time.<br />
We grabbed a late lunch at Swiss Chalet. I checked my luggage after eating, and we switched to the bar.<br />
Even though I was at the airport, boarding pass to Calgary in hand, I didn&#8217;t really feel like I was going anywhere. I was in a bar with my family, as I&#8217;ve been (a few too) many times this year.<br />
Mom and Cathy were soon off for Oakville, leaving me to wait for my flight. (We left early to beat the returning weekend traffic. We left perhaps a little too early.)<br />
I waited at gate B20 for about an hour, reading Wired. Nothing out of the ordinary (at least for me, lately). Even when WestJet staff started yelling for passengers (the microphone to the PA system wasn&#8217;t working), there was no rush. For me, it&#8217;s all routine.<br />
I think I&#8217;ve actually travelled too much this year.<br />
But as I boarded the plane and took my seat, a feeling of reserved relief crept upon me. I&#8217;m going home. My month and a half abroad is ending in a few short hours. Tonight I will sleep in my own bed in my own home. I will see my cats. (Tomorrow, I&#8217;ll have to go back to my job &#8212; hey, it can&#8217;t all be roses.)<br />
I&#8217;m tired. Take me home. Please.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/wanna-go-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">249</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halifax to Huntsville</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=halifax-huntsville</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2002 06:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car rental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halifax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntsville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nova scotia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ontario]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/12/halifax-huntsville/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I hate alarms. Especially when they go off while you&#8217;ve still got an hour of darkness left of the night. I had an early flight to Toronto, though, and wasn&#8217;t keen on missing it. I had packed the night before, so all I had to do was shave, shower, dress, and throw all my bags &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Halifax to Huntsville"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hate alarms. Especially when they go off while you&#8217;ve still got an hour of darkness left of the night. I had an early flight to Toronto, though, and wasn&#8217;t keen on missing it.<br />
I had packed the night before, so all I had to do was shave, shower, dress, and throw all my bags in the trunk of my rented car. Checking out was trivial, just the way I like it. Then it was off to the airport.<br />
Now here&#8217;s where either my unbelievably good sense of direction, or my unbelievable stupidity, shows through. Most normal people would ask where the airport is and how to get there. Not me. I decided I could find it based on the solitary sign I&#8217;d seen on the Highway 102/103 interchange yesterday. Oh, I should mention that it was still dark when I entered the highway, and the radio was calling for dense patches of fog &#8230; about 10 seconds before I ran into one myself.<br />
So I drove north. I wasn&#8217;t sure if I was even going to the correct airport. (I didn&#8217;t know how many airports were in the Halifax area.) For a short time, I considered turning off to get directions. But something kept me going. I found my way to the airport, though. The correct one, at that!<br />
One of these days, this behaviour is going to get me into trouble. Big trouble.<br />
Checking in was fast, as was picking up the seafood feast I was bringing back to Ontario. Five lobster, two pounds of mussels, and a pound of scallops. And so help me, none of it cooked in butter. (Not counting sautéing the onions and garlic for the white wine sauce.) The box the seafood came in, however, needed to be taken on the plane. Along with my two carry-on bags. This was over my limit, and a bit of worry. Luckily, the plane was only about three-quarters full. The staff didn&#8217;t stop me.<br />
Toronto came quickly, and I was soon waiting in the baggage claim with my three carry-ons. My duffle bag was the first bag off. My knapsack was significantly later. As I exited baggage claim, my mother came in the main doors. Five minutes later mom, Cathy, and I were on our way north.<br />
I was goaded into coming back to Ontario for Thanksgiving. I wanted to go home to Calgary. I&#8217;ve been away for a month and a half, and I want adjustment time. But somewhere in the back of my mind, staying for a couple of days in Huntsville seemed like a good idea. I gave into pressure and decided to come in. However, I&#8217;ll probably only see the airport, the highway, and the cottage. I doubt I&#8217;ll see anything else, or anyone else.<br />
The ride north was uneventful, save for the Teeming Thousands who were similarly heading north. The traffic, according to Cathy, wasn&#8217;t too bad though. On long weekends during the summer, you simply just don&#8217;t go up on Saturday&#8217;s. It&#8217;s just shy of declaring insanity. When we hit the Highway 69/Highway 11 split, the traffic lightened. The rest of the trip wasn&#8217;t so bad.<br />
At Orillia, I convinced Cathy that we needed to stop for lunch. I hadn&#8217;t eaten a thing since leaving Halifax, and it was now 3:00pm according to my stomach. This meant, of course, a stop at Weber&#8217;s &#8212; an institution in this part of Ontario. Virtually everyone who&#8217;s driven this stretch of highway more than once has eaten at Weber&#8217;s. And for good reason: it&#8217;s fast, fresh, and good.<br />
We were in Huntsville about an hour later. After a quick stop for beer (I&#8217;m a picky drinker), we made the long trek out to the cottage. It&#8217;s a bit of a hike &#8212; a lot longer than I remembered from my last journey out here (see [[Visit to Ontario, Cottage in Huntsville, Thanksgiving Dinner, Algonquin Park]]). But the cottage was as I remembered it. The outside, anyway. Cathy and Craig (mostly Craig) have put in a huge amount of renovation. It&#8217;s not done yet, but one day it&#8217;s going to be the smartest-looking small cabin on Lake Vernon.<br />
Craig was already there, having been doing yard work for most of the day. Bear and Kylie (both dogs) raced out of the woods to greet us. Within minutes of being inside, I started to feel a little more relaxed. I still wanted to go home to Calgary, though. I guess all this travel has just left me feeling a little tired.<br />
The renovations were awesome. The kitchen was totally different, the floor all tiled, and the bathroom looked almost totally new. (Well,it practically is.) Still, some work was still needed, including the walls of the living room and dining room, and the downstairs. But one thing at a time.<br />
Dave arrived not long after, Chuckie (Dave&#8217;s dog) in tow. Anne and Rebecca arrived not long after. We chatted and made fun of each other until it was time to get cooking. Which was when the lobster pot finally got to a boil &#8212; after being on the burners for about three hours.<br />
Lobsters: about 10 minutes. Mussels: about 7 minutes. Scallops: about two minutes. Time to eat it all: about an hour and a half. But worth it, if for no other reason than it cleared out the memory of the scallops I had in Lunenburg. We had no room for dessert.<br />
The fun continued after dinner as we resumed making fun of each other. I didn&#8217;t participate as much, being quite tired from everything (and the alcohol not helping much). It was a good time, but I didn&#8217;t really feel all that relaxed. I still wanted to go home. Maybe tomorrow, I won&#8217;t feel so uptight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/halifax-huntsville/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">248</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
