<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>hotels &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/hotels/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 05:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>New Year&#039;s Tea</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-years-tea</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 05:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2498</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The New Year is always a reason for change. It&#8217;s always a reason to do something differently than you&#8217;ve done before. It&#8217;s a time when people hold to ages-old traditions, and make efforts to start new ones. It&#8217;s a time to look back on the past, and look towards the future. And frankly, it&#8217;s a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New Year&#039;s Tea"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New Year is always a reason for change. It&#8217;s always a reason to do something differently than you&#8217;ve done before. It&#8217;s a time when people hold to ages-old traditions, and make efforts to start new ones. It&#8217;s a time to look back on the past, and look towards the future.<br />
And frankly, it&#8217;s a darn good reason to make a little trip out to Banff to see old friends.<br />
<span id="more-2498"></span>Internet phenom Twitter really hit it big in 2009. (I would like to say I knew about Twitter from the beginning, but held off on getting account until the Web 2.0 conference in 2008.) Coincidentally, it was a time when many other people joined Twitter, bringing it to the masses and making it the media darling it has become.  It also allowed previously ordinary people and/or small groups to become much more visible on a person-to-person level.<br />
This is how I came across my old friend, <a href="http://sonnyjelinek.posterous.com/">Sonny Jelinek</a>.<br />
Sonny and I go way back. And I mean &#8220;way&#8221; as in &#8220;preschool&#8221;. We both went to St. Cuthbert&#8217;s preschool, back in the mid-1970s. We went to the same kindergarten, elementary, mid, and high-school. We were on the same soccer team (his family&#8217;s company was the sponsor). We were in the same Cub Scout troop. We were even on the same swim team in high school.<br />
And then, like everyone else in high school, we dropped off each other&#8217;s radar for nearly two decades. It was for no other reason than everyone going their own way. Sonny&#8217;s way took him further out of the circles the rest of us migrated into &#8212; I periodically traipsed across others &#8212; taking him as far as southern California.<br />
He now heads up his family&#8217;s business &#8212; <a href="http://www.jelinek.com/">Jelinek Cork</a> &#8212; and is the chair of the Oakville Chamber of Commerce. Considering he&#8217;s (about) the same age as me, that&#8217;s not anything to sneeze at. Compared to him, I have to admin that I do feel a little inadequate.<br />
Through Twitter, Sonny and I exchanged not just greetings, but found out that we were going to be in close proximity to each other. He and his wife Michelle were coming out to Banff for New Year&#8217;s, which seemed an opportunity that we simply couldn&#8217;t pass up.<br />
Instead of the old standby &#8212; drinks at some bar &#8212; I suggested we do something a little different: <a href="http://www.fairmont.com/banffsprings/GuestServices/Restaurants/AfternoonTea.htm">Afternoon Tea at the Banff Springs Hotel</a>.<br />
The Banff Springs, like the other Fairmont hotels, carries on the traditions first held when they were Canadian Pacific hotels, founded by Scotsmen who had the tradition of British high tea. If you&#8217;ve never had high tea, it&#8217;s something I highly recommend. And if you get a chance to do so at a Fairmont hotel, you&#8217;ll be experiencing some of the best in the world. (I can say that, having had tea in a few places outside of North America.)<br />
We arrived in the Rundle Lounge around 13:45, the time Sonny had managed to reserve. It didn&#8217;t matter than we hadn&#8217;t seen each other in over 18 years &#8212; the time seemed to nearly vanish. We looked older, wiser, and (hopefully a lot more mature), but recognition came pretty quickly for both of us. Spouses and The Monkey were introduced.<br />
First question? After graduation, what happened next?<br />
We had our tea for nearly three hours. That&#8217;s how good a time we had. Our servers wafted in and out like the scent of tea from the pots we drank, neither interrupting nor competing for attention. The trays of scrumptious sandwiches and cakes were more than we could eat (I think they&#8217;ve actually gotten better since our last time) &#8212; The Monkey had an entire tray all to herself.<br />
My biggest regret with the event was something that many of you will find shocking: I utterly forgot to take a picture. I only realised it as we drove away from the Banff Springs, headed back to Calgary. Quite the oversight, sadly.<br />
Alex and I remarked as we headed down the Trans Canada that having tea on New Years Day seemed special for a few reasons, not the least of which was having tea with old friends. But it&#8217;s a nice event. It&#8217;s quiet, peaceful (except for having to chase The Monkey all over the place, as she&#8217;s rapidly becoming a poster child for Ritalin), and thoroughly enjoyable way to bring in the new year. (Probably even moreso if you&#8217;re still recovering from the previous night&#8217;s events.)<br />
Alex and I have declared this to be our new tradition: New Year&#8217;s Tea. We&#8217;ll be there, a year from today, enjoying the fantastic view, and having a wonderful time.<br />
Who wants to join us?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/new-years-tea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2498</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The trip home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/the-trip-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-trip-home</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/the-trip-home/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airplanes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2249</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, we&#8217;re home now. I know it doesn&#8217;t seem like it to you, because you&#8217;ve lived in three different homes since you were born. But this house, the one in Calgary (where we&#8217;re currently adjusting to serious sub-zero temperatures and drying out) is a home we hope you&#8217;ll come to know and love. It&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/the-trip-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The trip home"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, we&#8217;re home now. I know it doesn&#8217;t seem like it to you, because you&#8217;ve lived in three different homes since you were born. But this house, the one in Calgary (where we&#8217;re currently adjusting to serious sub-zero temperatures and drying out) is a home we hope you&#8217;ll come to know and love.<br />
It&#8217;s not Costa Rica. It&#8217;s not always warm. It&#8217;s not filled with the sounds of parakeets, or tropical rainstorms, or filled with Spanish-speaking voices. This is the Great White North. It&#8217;s chilly for most of the year, leaves are seen for only five months, and the only monkeys you&#8217;ll see are at the zoo. It&#8217;s going to be an adjustment for you, and for Mommy and I, too.<br />
It was a long road to get here.<br />
<span id="more-2249"></span>The weekend before we left was a tough one. We had a lot of packing and cleaning to do before we could hand our keys back over to the apartment&#8217;s owner. After the fiasco with our previous apartment (no, Avalon, I have not forgotten you and the $1,500 you stole from us), Mommy and I wanted to make absolutely certain that there was nothing that would get in our way.<br />
On Sunday, we left our last Costa Rican apartment, with help from Jason and Jenn Hale, and headed out to the Best Western Irazu. There, despite the hotel completely losing our reservation, we got a room with a nice bed for our last two nights in Costa Rica. We ate at the Denny&#8217;s there. It was a transition we needed, I think, a way of preparing for the day to come.<br />
That day was Tuesday the 8th. It began at 4:00, when the alarm got us from our sleep (and you woke up with extreme difficulty). We ate at the Denny&#8217;s one last time, gathered our bags (and put Asia in her carrying bag), then boarded a bus for the airport. Checking in took probably three times longer than it should have, possibly due to the cat, and I&#8217;m convinced the clerk was brand new. Then came immigration (where they checked the &#8220;export&#8221; papers we had for you), and security (where they checked the export papers for Asia).<br />
The flight was late leaving, by about 40 minutes. Murphy&#8217;s final little poke, I think. Soon, we were rolling down the runway, and the floor of the Central Valley disappeared beneath us as we lifted into the sky. I mumbled a little &#8220;adios, Costa Rica&#8221; as we drifted into the clouds. You took almost no notice at all. Asia was panicking.<br />
The flight was about 3.5 hours to Houston. You slept a little, watched most of WALL-E on the iPod, and then wrestled both Mommy and I as we tried to get you buckled in for the landing. You would have nothing to do with either of us, and the screaming was enough to bring everyone to tears. Mommy held you tight as we landed. We would later hear from the flight attendants that your reaction is common amongst your age group.<br />
Houston was surprisingly fast, all things considered. Immigration, zipped through customs (our bags were checked the whole way through), and security once again. We ate lunch at Ruby&#8217;s, I took Asia out for an hour in the pet relief area, we watched the rest of WALL-E and a couple episodes of Backyardigans. The five and a half hours disappeared fairly quickly, and you fell asleep while I held you for takeoff. You slept probably half of the flight to Calgary. (Which was wise, because a microwaved cheese dog is really not something you want to eat for dinner.)<br />
Calgary was -18 upon arrival. &#8220;Chilly&#8221; is putting it mildly, since it was over 18 degrees when we&#8217;d left Costa Rica earlier that morning. Immigation took a while due to a very long lineup and having to go to the Customs desk to declare Asia&#8217;s papers for entry, as well as our stuff that&#8217;s being shipped from Costa Rica. It was almost 22:45 before we got to the Delta hotel, which is thankfully at the airport. It was our first run outside.<br />
Your Great Aunt Brenda became a major hero, leaving us a package with a new pink parka for you (and gloves), as well as gloves and hats for Mommy and I. We spent little time settling, preferring to go right to bed. You had a queen bed all to yourself.<br />
Be it ever so freezing, there&#8217;s just no place like home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/the-trip-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2249</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A (wet) birthday vacation</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-wet-birthday-vacation</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 04:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1464</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, I just turned 37 &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit. It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A (wet) birthday vacation"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, if your memory is any good, you should remember the last few days for the rest of your life. And not because you got to spend five uninterrupted days with your dad (remember, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/07/im-not-old/">I just turned 37</a> &#8230; I&#8217;m not old), or even because Nana is here for a visit.<br />
It&#8217;s &#8216;cuz I doubt you&#8217;ll ever see that much rain ever again.<br />
<span id="more-1464"></span>The planning for this little sojourn was long, convoluted, and more than a little painful. Especially given all that I was looking for was a few days away from Santa Ana, to see something new in Costa Rica, and to spend time with my family &#8212; something I don&#8217;t get to do nearly enough of, which is something I deeply regret with each passing day.<br />
Ultimately, it was decided that we&#8217;d go to Arenal. This would be your second time to the area, and Mommy and my third trip. (It will likely be our last for a very long time. I&#8217;m now officially quite tired of Arenal.) I had told Nana that she&#8217;d get to see a volcano (and hopefully see it erupt at night), that we&#8217;d stay at a really nice place, and that the Arenal area was fantastic.<br />
Given <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/">our previous trip to Arenal</a> (and the one before that), it seemed a fairly decent and honest thing to say. It would appear, however, that Uncle Murphy had also come along for the ride. You remember Uncle Murphy &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/04/dear-murphy-fuck-off-and-die/">he&#8217;s the one who takes our plans and ruins them every time</a>.<br />
The trip up was reasonably nice. You fell asleep along the way, despite playing with Mommy quite a lot, somewhere around the Los Angeles cloud forest. Nana was watching all the hills and valleys, lush with rainfall, while I watched for all the lunatic drivers. I&#8217;m not used to driving such distances during the week &#8212; I&#8217;m usually at work worrying about network traffic, not oncoming cars.  You woke up only after a short pee break somewhere north of La Tigra.<br />
We arrived in La Fortuna somewhere around 14:00, and I rather foolishly thought it would be a good idea to check in to our hotel first, rather than do the smart thing, which was eat. You will learn, Monkey, that your father is often none-too-bright and does some really stupid things. (Mommy will remind you of this quite often, I&#8217;m sure.) We finally got to the restaurant somewhere near 14:30, and didn&#8217;t eat until nearly 15:00.<br />
Given that your father (that would be me) had hoped for a really nice dinner that evening, it wasn&#8217;t exactly the wisest thing. I made it even less wise when we went in search of the ice cream shop Mommy and I had found when we&#8217;d first gone to Arenal in 2005 for Mommy&#8217;s birthday. It wasn&#8217;t where we thought it would be (it had moved), but it was nice. We put you in a little kid&#8217;s ride that looked like a double-decker bus. You didn&#8217;t like it one bit.<br />
Returning to our hotel &#8212; the <a href="http://arenalparaiso.com/">Arenal Paraiso</a> (where we had a nice little two-suite cabin, ironically number #404) &#8212; both you and I went down for a short nap. You were a little overdue, and I was plain wiped. (The last many weeks of work have sapped much of my energy, prompting the time off, and the drive had taken a big punch out of me, too.) Mommy woke us up at 17:00.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737015049[/flickr]<br />
I had decided that we would eat at The Springs, a new hotel that had opened in the Arenal area only eight months earlier. My friends (and co-workers) Mark and Denise had stayed there a month or so ago, and swore the quality couldn&#8217;t be beat. They neglected to also tell us the state of the road, which was something near &#8220;unpassable&#8221;. (It&#8217;s a wonder they could build the place with roads that bad.) The three kilometre(-ish) trip took nearly 20 minutes, and was very bumpy.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737020375[/flickr]<br />
The hotel is right out of Disney World in terms of engineering, marvel, appearance, and professionalism. (Hopefully by the time you actually read this, Monkey, you&#8217;ll have been to Disney World and have some idea what the heck I&#8217;m talking about.) Due to my previous mistake, I didn&#8217;t get the dinner I wanted. Instead, we had the buffet (this was mostly to benefit your current eating habits, I should point out). It was very good, and the service was beyond outstanding.<br />
(A note to anyone thinking of going to the Arenal area: If you can afford it, <a href="http://www.thespringscostarica.com/">I highly recommend The Springs Resort and Spa</a>, it is truly amazing.)<br />
That night, as we all laid in bed, Uncle Murphy arrived to join us. Along with near-three solid days of torrential rain. It was also the first of three very sleepless nights for me.<br />
The next morning, we drove down to the restaurant for dinner. We drove because the rain would have soaked us to the bone, and because Nana would have had trouble walking that far on a rain-slicked road. The buffet was typical Costa Rican, with gallo pinto, fruit (papaya, pineapple, and watermelon), scrambled eggs, and various breads. Mommy, Nana, and I each had two cups of coffee.<br />
The problem was what to do with our day. It was, after all, raining quite a lot. So we decided the only thing to try was do some shopping. We headed into La Fortuna, hitting a woodwork studio, children&#8217;s clothing store, two or three souvenir shops, and you and Mommy ran up and down a ramp three times. The rain becoming quite the hindrance, we returned to the car to seek more adventure.<br />
Again with the brilliant planning, I thought we&#8217;d search out a German bakery that I&#8217;d read about in the Tico Times a few months ago. All I knew was that it was west of Fortuna along the shores of Lake Arenal. Which, in theory, is enough. And based on what I saw on maps, looked to be pretty straight-forward.<br />
Right?<br />
Well, one thing Costa Rica maps are notorious for is the lack of detail &#8212; notably when the map indicates a straight (or relatively straight) line, but the actual road is weavy and windy, and what should take no more than 30 minutes ends up being an hour-long trip. So about 20 minutes into the trip, we turned around and headed back. (Mommy had a massage appointment at 13:00, and we didn&#8217;t want her to miss it.)<br />
Instead, I (again, using my ever-so-powerful intellect) decided that we&#8217;d do lunch at the Arenal Lodge, which was just before the road over the dam. The rain kept pouring, and we were traveling up a steep, wet, mossy, and windy road barely three kilometres long that took us about 10 minutes to travel. Thankfully, we have four-wheel drive on our little Suzuki.<br />
Lunch was rather disappointing. The Lodge might be a neat place (it&#8217;s VERY out of the way), but the food is something less-than-desirable in my book. (My caesar salad was watery and lacking in flavour, and my ceviche tasted too much like fish and not enough like ceviche.) And it rained. A lot. To the point where when it was time to leave, I went to get the car rather than subject the three of you to walking through it.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737820576[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737825284[/flickr]<br />
While Mommy went to her massage, you and I went to splash around in the pool. It would be the only time you and I would go swimming over the last five days, sadly. I had hoped for much, much more than that. When Mommy returned, we all headed back up to the cabin so you could have a nap.<br />
Mommy got a recommendation for a restaurant downtown in La Fortuna called <a href="http://www.donrufino.com/">Don Rufino</a>. From the outside, it&#8217;s not the fanciest-looking place &#8212; in fact, it looks like every other bar in La Fortuna. But the food &#8230; the food! I was beside myself. I ordered a tuna dish that came with jumbo shrimp. Even though there were no vegetables, I was in heaven. (I&#8217;d been wanting a tuna for a very long time.) I think the only one who wasn&#8217;t over the moon with their dinner was you, Monkey.<br />
It rained all through dinner, all that night, and right into the next morning.<br />
We had thought that it might be fun to take Nana out to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>. Which was a risky venture, given the rain, but there&#8217;s very little to do in Arenal that doesn&#8217;t involve going outside. The drive involves a 8-9 kilometre-long, very rutted, very pot-holed, very bumpy road. Nana wasn&#8217;t particularly thrilled with it. (You almost fell asleep twice.) But once again, Mommy and my &#8220;Rain Luck&#8221; kicked in, and for the time we were at the Conservatory, it didn&#8217;t rain. We even learned a few more things thanks to a couple of volunteers from Seattle who could give us a bit more information we didn&#8217;t have last time.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737830482[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737834892[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737047843[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737055589[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737855464[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737087559[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3740775171[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3741617198[/flickr]<br />
It was raining by the time we got back to the main road. Mommy and I had booked a zip-line for that afternoon, but somewhere 12:45 became 13:15 (or vice versa) and we ended up missing our trip. It rained all that afternoon. In fact, while you were napping, the rain came down so hard that the gutters overflowed and we literally had waterfalls come off the roof. I became horribly depressed about the weather, missing the zip-line, not being able to do anything else, not being able to sleep, and so forth.<br />
[flickr]photo:3741594030[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was at Don Rufino again, not having any other better idea (and I&#8217;d ruled out eating at the hotel). It was the bright spot of my day. You didn&#8217;t eat at all.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737094433[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3737893582[/flickr]<br />
Rain. All night.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737902800[/flickr]<br />
The next morning Mommy and I were supposed to go on our re-booked zip-line. But the non-stop rain was putting that to an end, once and for all. Despite being here a year, I have yet to actually zip-line through the canopy. At the rate I&#8217;m going, I might never get a chance.<br />
I was so put off by the weekend that I basically forced us to breakfast, so we could check out and leave. I had no desire to spend another minute in the rain. The only stop we made heading out of town was so Nana could get a couple of gifts for those back home.<br />
Had the rain not actually stopped as we&#8217;d headed south, I might not have had my coup de grace in bad ideas and passed right by the Fortuna Waterfall. However, with the break, I thought there might be a salvageable moment in the weekend.<br />
Sorry Monkey, your father will never learn.<br />
After you travel up the half-paved, half-bumpy road to the waterfall park&#8217;s parking lot, you pay US$10 each, and then walk along &#8220;600 metres of well-maintained path&#8221; to the observation point. What they do not tell you, in any way, is that the path includes a 100+ metre drop into the canyon, down one of the toughest staircases I&#8217;ve ever climbed. Nana (rather wisely) gave up only 1/5 of the way down. Mommy decided that she couldn&#8217;t go any futher than about 40 metres down before she stopped &#8212; she and you never got to the bottom to see the waterfall up-close. I was there for a mere five minutes before going back up to rejoin you.<br />
[flickr]photo:3744396992[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743603157[/flickr]<br />
For the record, you didn&#8217;t climb the stairs. We carried you. Why the heck we thought it was a good idea to bring you when Nana was at the top is beyond me. Instead, we lugged 20 kilos of wringling dead-weight up and down wet stairs.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737910724[/flickr]  [flickr]photo:3737124555[/flickr]<br />
Worst. Idea. Ever.<br />
By the time I got the top again, my heart pounded so hard I could hear it, my chest was heaving, and my knees were so weak I was terrified that they&#8217;d give out and I&#8217;d drop you. About the only thing I had going for me was my pig-headedness to not giving up. I could barely walk. (Today, my legs are so sore I can barely climb stairs at all.)<br />
The rain started up again as we hit the road south to San RamÃ³n. You fell asleep not long after.<br />
At this point, Mommy took over decision-making, and wisely took us to a place neither you or Nana had been to before &#8212; Villa Blanca. Mommy and I had gone there for Mommy&#8217;s birthday in January, and she had gone again with her friend Erin back in May. Although it meant an extra 20 minute drive along another windy (but not nearly as bumpy) road, we arrived at a cloud-filled and peaceful place.<br />
For the first time in days, I actually felt good. It was quiet and calm. All I wanted to do was sit on a bench and let the clouds drift over me, taking away all the crappy feelings that had been building up for weeks.<br />
Lunch was, as expected, fantastic. You even ate most of your lunch, and even a little bit of Mommy&#8217;s.<br />
The drive home was marked only by the usual retinue of morons on the Pan American who don&#8217;t understand the concept of lanes or allowing others to pass freely when you&#8217;re driving too slowly. (Mommy was not pleased at my driving, and rightly so.) We got home in one piece.<br />
[flickr]photo:3737937674[/flickr]<br />
I tried to make dinner that night &#8212; pupusas. They were pretty lousy, unfortunately. There&#8217;s gotta be a different technique that I need to learn. You didn&#8217;t eat anything, again. I was the only one who actually seemed to eat dinner &#8212; either everyone else wasn&#8217;t hungry, or my dinner was horrible.<br />
For my last day off before going back to work, we&#8217;d decided to try going into San José. But at breakfast, you would barely eat anything you normally like &#8212; even toast &#8212; and you made it sound like you were having tummy problems. You and Mommy returned home, while Nana and I went into the city.<br />
I took Nana to the Central Market, where I&#8217;d last been about a year ago. I wound her through the narrow aisles, through little stalls selling just about everything imaginable (and a few unimaginable), before stopping at the Central Market Café. This is where Jason, Mark, and I had stopped for coffee (I had hot chocolate, not yet having started to drink coffee) while on our tour. Nana and I both bought coffee. I would later buy the torilla press we&#8217;d been looking for.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743790614[/flickr]<br />
Leaving the market, we went down Avenida Central towards the Plaza de Cultura, where we went to the Gran Hotel for lunch. My poor ceviche at the Arenal Lodge was redeemed by possibly the best ceviche I&#8217;ve yet had, while Nana had a fried Cambenbert and strawberry sauce tapas. Spying the dark clouds that suggested rain, we headed into the Museo de Oro for an hour or so.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743022225[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743826248[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743033867[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743848398[/flickr] [flickr]photo:3743053189[/flickr]<br />
The rain, for once, didn&#8217;t come. When we came back out, it was only to walk back to the car and drive back home again.<br />
Mommy and I made pizza for dinner, which was very good. You barely ate your corn on the cob or the pizza (both were favourites), which still worries us greatly.<br />
So ends my birthday vacation. I wish I could say I had a better time, Monkey, but I&#8217;ll be honest &#8212; spending time with you, Mommy, and Nana were my shining points. Otherwise, it was a pretty lousy time. Had I known the weather would be that bad, I&#8217;d have suggested we just stay here at home.<br />
[flickr]photo:3743072335[/flickr]<br />
It&#8217;s time for me to go to bed (you&#8217;ve been asleep for about 2.75 hours already). Hopefully tonight I&#8217;ll catch up on some of the sleep I&#8217;ve been missing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/07/a-wet-birthday-vacation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1464</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visiting Villa Blanca</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/visiting-villa-blanca/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=visiting-villa-blanca</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/visiting-villa-blanca/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 14:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alajuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1235</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Alex&#8217;s birthday was yesterday (she just turned 29, in case you&#8217;re keeping track &#8230; &#8216;cuz we&#8217;re not), and as tradition holds, she got to choose where we went to celebrate.   Well, at least it&#8217;s a tradition we&#8217;re going to try to restart and keep going, anyway.   She did some reasearch and chose a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/visiting-villa-blanca/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Visiting Villa Blanca"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alex&#8217;s birthday was yesterday (she just turned 29, in case you&#8217;re keeping track &#8230; &#8216;cuz we&#8217;re not), and as tradition holds, she got to choose where we went to celebrate.  <br />
Well, at least it&#8217;s a tradition we&#8217;re going to try to restart and keep going, anyway.  <br />
She did some reasearch and chose a place up in the cloud forest called <a href="http://villablanca-costarica.com/">Villa Blanca</a>. The pictures we saw online of the place looked nice, but as we&#8217;ve found a few times &#8212; the pictures often look better than the real thing.  <br />
It was nice to find an exception to the rule.  <br />
<span id="more-1235"></span>Finding this place was not so much difficult as it was an adventure. Thankfully, Allen and Jean were down for a visit (nicely timed, I should add), so they offered to take Mi Pequeña Niña for the weekend while we took off. It would be the first time both of us were separated from her &#8220;just &#8216;cuz&#8221;.  <br />
After kissing the wee one goodbye (it took a bit of prying to get Alex to actually leave), we headed out to Highway 1, and bore west to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_RamÃ³n,_Costa_Rica">San RamÃ³n in Alajuela</a>. This was not our destination &#8212; just a point where we ceased travelling west and turned north.  <br />
The instructions we had to get to Villa Blanca were typically Costa Rican &#8212; lots of landmarks with too much information. It would have been easier if we were just told to drive north out of San RamÃ³n, following the signs to the Arenal Volcano (for some reason, Costa Rica loves to point out where the volcanoes are), then turn when we got to Los Angeles.  <br />
Of course, we didn&#8217;t know that we turned in Los Angeles, because there&#8217;s no way to know that the village is called &#8220;Los Angeles&#8221;. As usual, there are almost no signs for the small villages you pass through. I have yet to understand why.  <br />
As we exited San RamÃ³n, we headed into quasi-familiar territory. We&#8217;d been on the road twice before, once in 2005 driving north to Arenal (a trip that neither Alex or I remember particularly well), and once a few months ago driving south from Arenal. This time, I knew where we were. Alex didn&#8217;t &#8230; right until we got to the gift shop.  <br />
This would be our third visit to this particular place, and it&#8217;s actually one of the better gift shops I&#8217;ve been in. Not too much hokey stuff, and the prices (although meant for tourists) aren&#8217;t outrageous. I found another monkey shirt for myself (MPN loves monkeys on my shirts &#8212; I need <em>more </em>monkey shirts), and Alex acquired shirts for her and MPN.  <br />
We knew we were going to have to turn off the road when we got to the &#8220;double speed bumps next to the police station&#8221; (although this sounds really vague, it&#8217;s a good description for what you&#8217;ll find), but we didn&#8217;t know what it was going to be like.  <br />
The road we turned onto was narrow (barely two cars wide &#8212; and I mean without any space between the cars), potholed, and paved using what had to have been either substandard asphalt or substandard road-making machines.<br />
Every so often, a road sign let us know that we had to keep driving &#8230; and to watch out for cattle and other cars, and to drive with our headlights on. This might seem like something rather odd to put on a sign, but in the cloud forest, this is just sage advice.  <br />
The cloud forest is a term to refer to the weather patterns in the area. Clouds don&#8217;t actually grow here, but the area is often mired in clouds. Not fog &#8212; that&#8217;s very different &#8212; I mean clouds. You can see them rolling over the hills. It&#8217;s not due to altitude so much as it is the way the weather forms. The area is usually shrouded in clouds, particularly this time of the year.  <br />
I know what you&#8217;re thinking: Wow, that sounds really drab.  <br />
It&#8217;s anything but. The area here is greener than anything else outside of a rainforest, and has its own type of forest that is &#8212; duh &#8212; watered by the endless stream of clouds running through it. Spanish moss covers most of the trees, and collects moisture that drips down to the ground. It&#8217;s very symbiotic.  <br />
We drove until we ran out of road, and came to the entrance of Villa Blanca itself. Villa Blanca is surrounded by the Los Angeles Private Biological Reserve, though it&#8217;s not easy to tell where one ends and the other begins.  <br />
There aren&#8217;t many buildings inside Villa Blanca. The most notable are the wedding chapel (built in 1997, with a wonderful ceiling made of hand-painted tiles), and the main building that contains the lounge, restaurant, movie theatre (sadly out of service at the time), gift shop, and game room. The other buildings are mostly the cabinas (they are like miniature craftsman-style homes), and a couple of INBio ranger offices tucked into the woods.  <br />
You can only drive to the parking lot. After that, you&#8217;re on foot.  <br />
Clouds socked in all around us when we arrived, but we were treated to an almost-angelic parting while we ate lunch (our room wasn&#8217;t ready yet). I saw in another picture that from Villa Blanca &#8212; likely on the very rare clear days &#8212; you can see all the Arenal volcano.  <br />
[flickr]photo:3227608532[/flickr]<br />
The cabina &#8212; number 28 &#8212; was right out of the 1930s craftsman homes. Fantastic. Wonderful. Comfy. I immediately regretted not being there for more than one night. But I was okay with that &#8212; I was already missing Mi Pequeña Niña quite badly. (As was Alex, but I chose not to say anything as not to make her feel worse.)  <br />
We walked through a jungle path in the afternoon, which wrapped around the edge of the property through a very green and very mossy forest. We saw several hummingbirds (thankfully, hummingbirds aren&#8217;t carniverous &#8212; those things would be nasty if they craved blood), and a lot of very damp trees.<br />
[flickr]photo:3239814344[/flickr]<br />
Including one called a &#8220;snot tree&#8221;. No joke.  <br />
[flickr]photo:3226771563[/flickr]<br />
Along the way, we got bitten several times by &#8230; well, we&#8217;re not sure by what. They weren&#8217;t mosquitoes &#8212; we would have felt them, and the bite mark left was missing flesh. Yet we never felt a thing. It was very strange. None of the staff seemed to know what they were, either.  <br />
That evening, we went for a &#8220;Nocturnal Nature Walk&#8221;, which runs through one of the &#8220;guides-only&#8221; paths at Villa Blanca. We started at around 18:00, when the sun had effectively set, and all walked out with flashlights in hand, to see what we could see.  <br />
The guide, whose name sounded like &#8220;Graybing&#8221;, was very familiar with the local flora and fauna, and was able to identify just about everything we saw. He knew the species, what they were like, how they mated, and eating habits. He also make sure that we didn&#8217;t touch any animal we found (some insects secrete poisons that cause serious rashes or even cyanide, and disturbing the animals is just generally bad).  <br />
Alex found the first curiousity of the night &#8212; a lightning bug that glowed a green light you would normally associate with a little green LED. Then it was onto a jungle trail that you could walk in about 20 minutes. It took us almost 90 minutes, because we went step-by-step, searching for anything. Several insects, five types of frogs, and a lot of questions.  <br />
The meals at the restaurant were fantastic, and reasonably priced given the monopoly on food service (you&#8217;re 30 minutes from Los Angeles, and it&#8217;s not a road you want to travel at night). The staff are very nice and fluent in English (handy for tourists, and even for us since we had a few questions regarding the menu).  <br />
The way back home was marked with lunch at the restaurant next to the gift shop south of Los Angeles, and a detour through Palmeres south to Atenas. That was right through the middle of the Palmeres Festival, which we&#8217;d forgotten about until we were stuck in the middle of it.  <br />
The Palmeres Festival is similar to the Calgary Stampede, at least insofar as the midway and the parking jockeys are concerned. Only that the jockeys here are so agressive that they chase your car in hopes you&#8217;ll go into their lot. Crazy people, I tell ya&#8230;<br />
The road from Palmeres to Atena is marked with many signs that read: &#8220;Curvas Peligras Adelante&#8221; (dangerous curves ahead). &#8220;Hairpin&#8221; doesn&#8217;t quite cut it, and going at any speed above 25 km/h is just asking for trouble.  <br />
Once in Atenas, we continued east back to home, a route we&#8217;re slightly familiar with from our trip to Punta Leona back in July.  <br />
Overall, it&#8217;s a highly recommended place in my books, and Alex and I would love to try go back to Villa Blanca again. With or without MPN is another question&#8230;<br />
[flickr]set:72157613154922776[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/01/visiting-villa-blanca/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1235</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend at Tabacon</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-at-tabacon</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 14:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butterflies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1096</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend at Tabacon"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Alex and I first came to Costa Rica 3.5 years ago, we went on a little packaged tour. The tour included a two-night (possible three-night &#8212; Alex and I are struggling to remember which it was) stay in the Arenal area. Our first afternoon/night included a hike around the south side of the active Arenal volcano, and dinner and a splash at the <a href="http://www.tabacon.com/">Tabacon Hot Springs</a>.<br />
At the time we&#8217;d been there, it was highly magical. We&#8217;d seen lava (in the form of red-hot tumbling rocks) rolling down the side of the mountain, the clouds of steam rolling through the trees illuminated by the carefully-placed lights. It was something to behold.<br />
Ever since then, Alex had wanted to go back. Rack up Surprise Weekend in Costa Rica #3.<br />
<span id="more-1096"></span>We left Saturday just after lunch, taking a route up through Naranjo, Cuidad de Quesada (also known as San Carlos), and then angling west through La Fortuna. This was not exactly an ideal route, since it&#8217;s a national highway &#8212; despite the insane amount of curves present in the road &#8212; which means a lot more (slow) truck traffic.<br />
We arrived around 16:30 (it&#8217;s about a 3-3.5 hour drive, albeit a very nice drive) and checked in right away. A nice room (with air conditioning), two on-site <a href="http://www.cafebritt.com/">Cafe Britt</a> stores (one in the hotel, the other in the hot springs facility), and a couple of very nice restaurants.<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+hotel+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was when we found out how expensive Tabacon can be. Although the room rate for the weekend wasn&#8217;t too bad (technically less than the one at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/">Ylang Ylang</a>), it does not include any meals (whereas Ylang Ylang covered breakfast and dinner). A $75 buffet bill said that we were in for a pricey weekend.<br />
That&#8217;s the first myth of Tabacon &#8212; very nice hotel, but far too-expensive food for the quality that you get. The second myth is that the hot springs open at 8:00 in the morning. Which is true &#8212; they do, but you&#8217;ll find the water levels in the river are practically non-existent, as the water is diverted to fill the swimming pools, which starts around 9:00. So you can&#8217;t really use the hot springs until at least 10:00.<br />
On Sunday, we went out for an excursion to find a butterfly farm (Alex had promised Mi Pequeña Niña that we&#8217;d go see butterflies). We had to drive to the south side of Lake Arenal to the <a href="http://www.butterflyconservatory.org/">Butterfly Conservatory</a>, which took us on a very picturesque journey around the volcano. Which &#8212; apparently a sign of good luck &#8212; was mostly free of clouds for once. Many photos were taken.<br />
[flickr]tag:arenal+volcano+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The Butterfly Conservatory is near the end of a very rough road, off of a bumpy and rocky gravel road, off of another dirt road. (Driving back onto pavement after all that was a joy.) It sits atop a hill that provides &#8212; without question &#8212; one of the finest views of the Arenal volcano. This would be an exceptional place to take pictures at night during an eruption, if it weren&#8217;t for the fact that driving there in the dark is a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢.<br />
The tents that contain the butterflies are down in a valley (a former cattle ranch turned into a reforestation project, after it was realised that putting cattle on volcanic soil is also a Really Bad Ideaâ„¢), which pretty much eliminated all breeze, and turned it into a bit of a boiler. Everyone was sweating profusely. But the butterflies were in significantly larger numbers than at <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/butterflies-and-getting-lost/">Spirogyra</a> &#8212; and some species that we hadn&#8217;t seen before.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+butterflies+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Luckily, we&#8217;d gained a tour guide part-way through the second (of four) butterfly tent, who not only showed us the butterflies and their names (given her limited English and our even more-limited Spanish), but also played with Mi Pequeña Niña while Alex and I snapped pictures). Sadly, I never did get her name, so all I can say is &#8220;Thanks, whomever you are!&#8221;<br />
Butterfly Conservatory also has a little frog habitat with some of the native Costa Rican frogs. Our guide was kind enough to bring the non-poisonous ones to the front of their enclosures so we could see them more closely. Otherwise, it would have been a bit hard to see them at all.<br />
[flickr]tag:butterfly+conservatory+frogs+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Naturally, Alex and I visited the hot springs whenever we could &#8212; what else would be the point of staying at Tabacon if we didn&#8217;t? Alex also took advantage of the five-star spa there, and hasn&#8217;t stopped talking about it yet. (I have to admit, it does sound wonderful.)<br />
[flickr]tag:tabacon+waterfall+september+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Even MPN got a chance to try the hot waters, while Alex was at her massage. Yes, I took my daughter into 39 degree Celsius water. And she loved it. I tried her in the cooler pools first, just to make sure, but when I slowly put her into the hot pool, it must&#8217;ve felt like heaven for her &#8212; she splashed around like a seal. The bridge overlooking the pool was soon filled with spectators. We might as well have been the featured attraction at Sea World.<br />
This is normal, by the way &#8212; it&#8217;s rather absurd the amount of attention MPN attracts down here.<br />
Monday being a holiday in Costa Rica (Independence Day), we took a leisurely return Monday afternoon, going through San Francisco and San RamÃ³n instead of San Carlos and Naranjo. This is the route that we had travelled (in the other direction) 3.5 years ago with Interbus on our way to Arenal. But Alex and I didn&#8217;t remember a thing, something we feel pretty guilty about. Alex claims that it was culture shock at the time. I think I can live with that.<br />
We stopped only twice &#8212; once to feed MPN (and have a Coke), and another at a gift shop we&#8217;d stopped at with Interbus 3.5 years ago. The only other place in the area that we knew of. It was weird because we didn&#8217;t really recognise it, but we did remember it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2862455883(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Sadly, this weekend cost a lot more than I&#8217;d budgeted for, so we&#8217;re not likely to do anymore long-distance trips for a while. (Besides which, we&#8217;re out of long weekends until Christmas). Of course, there&#8217;s still stuff around us for day trips, so stay tuned for more adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/weekend-at-tabacon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1096</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A revenge-free Montezuma</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-revenge-free-montezuma</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 18:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puntarenas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1035</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Mother&#8217;s Day in Costa Rica doth not come in May, like we&#8217;re used to in North America. Here, it&#8217;s 15 August. This is the day (so I&#8217;ve read) that the Virgin Mary ascended to Heaven, and given that this is a very Roman Catholic-centric society, Christian Holy Days are holidays. That means El DÃ­ ­a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A revenge-free Montezuma"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mother&#8217;s Day in Costa Rica doth not come in May, like we&#8217;re used to in North America. Here, it&#8217;s 15 August. This is the day (so I&#8217;ve read) that the <a href="http://www.newadvent.org/cathen/02006b.htm">Virgin Mary ascended to Heaven</a>, and given that this is a very Roman Catholic-centric society, Christian Holy Days are holidays. That means <a href="http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C3%ADa_de_la_madre">El DÃ­ ­a de la Madre</a> takes on extra importance here. Down here, it really is a religion.<br />
Which is good for me, believe it or not. You see, back in May, I royally screwed up and really blew Alex&#8217;s first Mother&#8217;s Day by doing &#8230; well, nothing. At least nothing of note. Not exactly a wise thing to do on a mother&#8217;s first Mother&#8217;s Day. I had some serious <span style="text-decoration: line-through">sucking</span> making up to do.<br />
<span id="more-1035"></span>My plan? Another surprise weekend. And given that it was a long weekend, it was a good chance to go a bit further than before and see something new and interesting. So I started hunting around for interesting places to go. Originally, it was to head out to Arenal &#8212; a place we&#8217;ve both been to and like. But I couldn&#8217;t get a good room.<br />
I stumbled across a beach resort called <a href="http://www.ylangylangresort.com/">Ylang Ylang</a>. Not the nicest website, sadly. (I should offer them services in return for a week&#8217;s stay or something. To take pictures for the website, of course.) But they had two major offerings listed on their website:</p>
<ol>
<li>Candlelit dinners</li>
<li>Hammocks &#8220;everywhere&#8221;</li>
</ol>
<p>The tricky part is getting there. Ylang Ylang is in <a href="http://www.nicoyapeninsula.com/montezuma/">Montezuma</a>, a small remote former fishing village on the Nicoya Peninsula. There are two &#8220;overland&#8221; routes: One that takes you to Puntarenas where you board a ferry to Paquera, and one in a loop over the north end of the Gulf of Nicoya (which is about 5-6 hours longer).<br />
This was the first real test of the Suzuki for distance. By 9:00am, we were packed and hitting the road for Montezuma. Well, almost. We had to stop at MÃ¡s Por Menos for some supplies. While Alex shopped, I had to make a quick return trip home to get the forgotten stroller, which is when I found out that my keycard no longer worked, necessitating a long conversation with the security guard in broken Spanish.<br />
But I digress.<br />
My biggest worry for the trip out was running into another <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/u-turns-are-illegal-in-costa-rica/">jerk cop who wanted to give me a hard time</a> for not having any metal license plates on my car. At the moment, I have the official permit that says I can drive my car, but no plates. This is &#8220;normal&#8221; in Costa Rica and you see a couple cars a day like this. The joys of backlogs of paperwork. Still, after my last run-in, I didn&#8217;t want to go through the trouble with a disgruntled infant.<br />
The trip to <a href="http://www.puntarenas.com/puntarenas/">Puntarenas</a> is barely 80 kilometres. But it takes about two hours to drive, thanks largely to the Costa Rican highway system, which is just shy of pathetic. Unlike the countries to the north and south of Costa Rica, the highways here are in perpetually poor state and simply not well-designed. They snake all over the mountains rather than cutting through them (or under them) to alleviate the dangerous hairpin turns and really dangerous nighttime traversals.<br />
On a map, <a href="http://maps.google.com/?ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.980009,-84.823637&amp;spn=0.04421,0.06712&amp;t=h&amp;z=14">Puntarenas doesn&#8217;t really look that long of a spit of land into the Gulf</a>, but it still took over 20 minutes of driving to finally get to the end, where we found the line for the Paquera ferry. Being a long weekend, it was a long line. We climbed out and were heading up the line to buy a ticket when a very sweaty young man by the name of Marcos (who spoke surprisingly good English) told us to stay with the car.<br />
This is how we found out how the process works:</p>
<ul>
<li>When you arrive for the ferry, you wait for a ferry employee to come to your car and give you a vehicle classification ticket. Our car, for example, was &#8220;Vehiculo Liviando&#8221;, basically a sedan.</li>
<li>You take said ticket to the ferry ticket wicket, where you purchase your boarding. You buy for the car as well as its occupants &#8212; two adults, in this case (kid ride for free!)</li>
<li>You return to your car and drive onto the ferry</li>
</ul>
<p>Marcos was a particularly nice guy. The two of us chatted on the way up the line to the ticket booth, at which point he told me to move the car to a small parking area (it was a rocky dirt lot) and told me to wait for him there. Because he &#8220;liked [our] baby&#8221;, he was going to let us cut into the line to make sure we got on the ferry.<br />
When people say that Ticos are nice, they&#8217;re not kidding. They are nice. Far too nice. They make Canadians look like assholes, they&#8217;re so nice.<br />
The ferry itself looked little more than one of those smaller ferries they use in BC for the short island hops with low traffic: a car deck, with a smaller deck above it for walk-on pedestrians. The ship was deceptively small, and had a &#8220;hidden&#8221; lower deck that cars drove into (through hatches on the main deck). This is where we parked. It&#8217;s dark, dank, stiflingly hot (which isn&#8217;t much of a stretch &#8212; all of Puntarenas is stiflingly hot compared to Santa Ana), and once all the cars are in, cramped. The upper deck is air-conditioned, but you could barely tell.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774939432[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774938298[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774937502[/flickr]<br />
The trip over is about an hour and a quarter. Then it&#8217;s back in your car, and away you go &#8230; to try not get lost. (Remember, Alex didn&#8217;t know where we were going, so I was going off a half-memorised map and some road signs.) And off we went.<br />
The distance from Paquera to Montezuma is about 30-40 kms. Which takes an hour to drive. Like the rest of Costa Rica, the roads are windy, so you can&#8217;t drive quickly. The last 7 kilometres from Cobano to Montezuma are some of the worst roads I&#8217;ve seen outside of Mongolia. The last 500 metres are down a 18% grade unpaved rocky hill with a near-hairpin turn at the bottom.<br />
Fun. Reason #158 we bought a 4&#215;4.<br />
You are rewarded, however. Although Montezuma has probably more hotels than homes, it&#8217;s so quaint that you don&#8217;t even really see the hotels. There are no chains to be seen in Montezuma &#8212; and it&#8217;ll likely be a long, cold day in Hell before that happens.<br />
There are basically three main roads in Montezuma &#8212; the &#8220;highway&#8221; that runs all the way down the coast, one road that runs perpendicularly towards to the only other road in Montezuma, running parallel to the highway for a little over two blocks, connecting the two main parts of Playa Montezuma. The tallest building doesn&#8217;t even come to the height of the trees, and the newest-looking thing is a Coca-Cola sign hanging over one of the stores.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774085179(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774936972(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774934712(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
In other words, a little slice of quaint paradise.<br />
We pulled into <a href="http://www.elbanano.com/elsanobanano.html">El Sano Banano</a>, an odd-named hotel that is the parent owner of Ylang Ylang (the latter being decidedly more upscale, although still insanely less expensive than a comparable place in North America). I ran in to &#8220;check-in&#8221; (you do Ylang Ylang check-in at El Sano Banano), then drove around the back to get to the parking lot. You can&#8217;t drive to Ylang Ylang &#8212; there&#8217;s a shuttle for you. The parking lot has a 24-hour guard.<br />
The shuttle arrived about 30 minutes later. A Land Rover Defender. I know what you&#8217;re thinking: &#8220;Boy, isn&#8217;t that pretentious?&#8221; It&#8217;s not (just) about being pretentious &#8212; it&#8217;s about being functional and appropriate. The drive from El Sano Banano is not far &#8212; only a 10-minute walk, really &#8212; but it&#8217;s over a beach with rocky outcroppings, and carrying bags that far ain&#8217;t easy. An ordinary car wouldn&#8217;t make it, let alone something like a golf cart.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774031253(small)[/flickr]<br />
We soon found something interesting about Ylang Ylang &#8212; unlike virtually every other place that we&#8217;ve been to in Costa Rica so far, almost every single person at Ylang Ylang speaks very good English. And are extremely friendly (moreso than regular Ticos). Our driver (I&#8217;m going to call him &#8220;Carlos&#8221; because I honestly forget his name) constantly tried to make Mi Pequeña Niña giggle (which isn&#8217;t that hard, and is very rewarding &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing like baby laughter).<br />
We arrived with a pair of women who were also from Santa Ana &#8212; teachers from NYU at a satellite school. I think Jason, Mark, and I met their students <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/">a few weeks ago in Bar Amigo</a> when we were out scouting Santa Ana. They were staying in the room right next to us.<br />
The room, incidentally, was down a 250-metre tiled path through the beach-front forest to a 3-storey, 6-room (the upper rooms are two-storey lofts) building. Ylang Ylang doesn&#8217;t have a lot of available rooms &#8212; maybe 15 in total. You couldn&#8217;t have more than 45 people there at any time, even with triple occupancy in the larger rooms. It&#8217;s a big space, and you don&#8217;t feel even remotely cramped.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774106193(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774954666(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774122541(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
The room had two double beds with mosquito nets above them. It&#8217;s the rainy season right now, which seems to mean that you aren&#8217;t likely see mosquitoes much, actually. And although <a href="http://www.fitfortravel.scot.nhs.uk/destinations/malariamaps/costarica.htm">Costa Rica is in the &#8220;malaria zone&#8221;</a>, Ingrid (one of my co-workers) has lived here most of her life, been all over the country, been bitten by countless mosquitos, and doesn&#8217;t know a person who&#8217;s had malaria.<br />
(That&#8217;s not in any way a defence, more a statement of fact and a lessening of my mother&#8217;s blood pressure that we might be getting a nasty disease here.)<br />
No air conditioning. That part wasn&#8217;t so good. Ylang Ylang is more environmentally-conscious than most places I&#8217;ve been to, and I guess A/C isn&#8217;t one of their preferred items. There were two ceiling fans at least. No glass on the windows (and no screens beyond the shutters) meant a constant fresh-air supply, and some airflow through the room. Also, a very clear (and sometimes loud) serenade of the surf on the adjacent beach.<br />
We ate dinner early the first night &#8212; we had to get food into our child before she had a total meltdown. She ate most of a plate of spaghetti (cutting noodles for children is not easy). I can&#8217;t for the life of me remember what Alex ate. As for me, I had probably the best blackened tuna I have ever eaten in my life. I&#8217;ve had many &#8220;blackened&#8221; meals in my day ever since <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/1996/04/road-trip-southwest-new-orleans/">first sampling one in New Orleans</a>. But never one that good. I&#8217;m sorry, Nawlins, but this chef actually out-did you. I&#8217;m still in awe days later.<br />
Sleep was rough the first night. Too hot (we were getting adjusted to the temperatures on the coast) and the surf was a bit too loud for my liking. Fortunately, the kid slept well. At least until 5:15. That&#8217;s when we had our wake-up call.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774153357(small)[/flickr]<br />
A howler monkey.<br />
Fortunately, I knew what a howler monkey sounded like &#8212; our first trip to Costa Rica back in 2005 featured a little hike around the back of Arenal Volcano, and a howler monkey serenade. Loud buggers. Especially at 5:15, less than 20 metres from your glass-less window. Everyone was up for the day at that point. Going back to sleep simply wasn&#8217;t an option.<br />
Because breakfast wasn&#8217;t served until 7:00 (and we were there pretty much on the dot), there was a signficant amount of distraction needed so Mi Pequeña Niña didn&#8217;t meltdown from lack of food. Fortunately, a beach makes for a great distraction.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774099171(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774097061(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774964112(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774962698(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774971738(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774972240(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
We wandered into Montezuma after the morning nap to get a better look. I wasn&#8217;t really surprised when we realised that we had already seen the entire village when we&#8217;d arrived the day before. Montezuma is small, quaint, and at the time not heavily populated. A lot of English is spoken there, though &#8212; it must attract a lot of North Americans. (I was told later it&#8217;s known by the locals as &#8220;Montefuma&#8221; for all the marijuana smoke &#8212; something that must come out in the high season. High season. Get it? HAH! I kill me&#8230;)<br />
We wandered into a couple of stores, MPN was fawned over by a number of people (it happens a lot) before we went to a small place called Organics for lunch. Think of a nice bistro-style open-air restaurant run by vegans. That&#8217;s pretty much what this place was. Good food, though. Probably the best nachos I&#8217;ve ever had (not cornmeal chips &#8212; something else entirely different), and an amazingly flavourful black bean dip. I tried to feed an avocado sandwich to the Wee One, getting almost as much avocado on me as in her.<br />
By the time we headed back to Ylang Ylang, the tide had come all the way in and pushing the stroller was almost impossible (the hard-packed sand is only available at lower tides). I ended up dragging it most of the way back. I was dripping sweat. It was so hot that an afternoon nap wasn&#8217;t an option &#8212; the blood-curdling screaming was enough of a sign of that.<br />
Hence, a dip in the pool. Although the ocean there is fantastic (the temperature of a nice, warm bath), the surf made going in not an option with MPN. The pool more than sufficed, and three of us swam for close to 45 minutes. The coolness also restored our core body temperatures, allowing the afternoon nap to actually take place.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774116929(small)[/flickr]<br />
Alex rocked in the many hammocks, read one of the Babysitter&#8217;s Club books (she loved &#8217;em as a youth, and loves them still for the quick readability), while I traipsed around in the ocean. On one of my trips back to make sure MPN was still asleep (about two hours all told), a troop of white-faced capuchins were running across the reception building, crossing over to trees and carrying on only as monkeys can.<br />
Fortunately, no poo-throwing.<br />
Curious little buggers, they came right down close to the pool area to see if there was food or anything shiny (they&#8217;re great thieves). One of them came quite close down a palm leaf and gave Alex and I a bit of a scare. You&#8217;re never really sure if one of these things might jump on you, and capuchins aren&#8217;t exactly the cleanest of animals to have jump on you.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774859976(small)[/flickr]<br />
It wouldn&#8217;t be our only run-in with capuchins that day. When the Wee One finally woke, I took her out to the restaurant area to have a snack while Alex got a good back massage (to make up for the el crapo one she got at Punta Leona a couple of weeks ago). One of the capuchins noticed that I was carrying a banana as I walked down the path, babe in arms. It came right down on a branch mere feet away. I shooed it and made a break for the restaurant, just in case it got grabby.<br />
Well, be darned if it didn&#8217;t race back up that tree to see where I was going, then run from tree-top to tree-top following us, across the restaurant&#8217;s roof and climbed down one of the supports to wait for us. Darn sneaking things. Cute, yes, but a little needy. I shooed it away again.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774164871(small)[/flickr]<br />
The restaurant staff, of course, saw all this and laughed. The capuchins play here a lot, and people encourage it, so things are a little less-natural than perhaps they should be. Monkeys ain&#8217;t stupid, though &#8212; people are. One of the restaurant staff even demonstrated the capuchins&#8217; desire for bananas for us (there was also another family with young kids from LA), by taking an older banana (quite brown) and coaxing one such monkey from a nearby palm tree.<br />
It almost came out for the entire banana, but the kids shrieked and scared the monkey. Broken in half and given in two portions tossed out on the grass, the monkey was a little more brave.<br />
[flickr]photo:2775144806(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774282729(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Dinner was again fantastic. While Mi Pequeña Niña downed most of a very tasty quesadilla, I went through a wonderful Thai-style teriyaki tuna. (I&#8217;m struggling to remember what Alex had. I think my food thoroughly distracts me. I know she had chicken, but I&#8217;m darned to remember what exactly.)<br />
Just as we put the Wee One to sleep, it started to rain. Little did we know, but a storm was rolling in across the country. It rained all night. Heavily. No night photography for me in Montezuma &#8212; I&#8217;ll just have to go back! The rain pounded through all the trees, even drowning out the nearby surf.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774874214(small)[/flickr]<br />
The storm was pretty big, and the next morning the damage was clear &#8212; about 1/5th of the sand on the beach had been washed out. (Carlos would later explain that this is normal, and happens in September and October every year.)<br />
[flickr]photo:2774935368(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:2774092431(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
At 9:00, the Defender took us back to El Sano Banano, where we loaded up the Suzuki for the ride home. Alex stopped in the store to pick up some supplies (baby food, &#8220;just in case&#8221;), and some postcards. A couple last pictures, and we headed back up the even-more-treacherous hill. Thankfully, we have a 4&#215;4 &#8212; going up in anything else wouldn&#8217;t be so easy, I think. The road back was quite muddy.<br />
[flickr]photo:2774520851(small)[/flickr]<br />
Having no idea what time the ferry actually left from Paquera, there was the possibility of us missing it. As cars started to whip past us quite quickly, I began to think that maybe they were racing for the ferry, too. But driving quickly in what was turning into another torrential downpour didn&#8217;t strike me as a good idea &#8212; straight roads here are a rarity.<br />
We got to the ferry line after loading had started. Alex stayed with the car while I raced off to get a ticket. The line was vastly unorganised and excruciatingly slow, and I had some lady behind me who constantly kept bumping into me &#8212; a pickpocket&#8217;s technique &#8212; though nothing was lifted (I keep my rear pockets devoid of anything). I managed to get the tickets to Alex just as she arrived at the front of the line to drive on. I slapped the tickets into the ticket-collector&#8217;s hands, but instead of getting back in the car, he directed me to walk on &#8212; the long way. I had to run to catch up with Alex on the main deck.<br />
It rained part of the trip back. But Puntarenas was sunny and warm. Originally thinking we might stop there for lunch, we opted to hit the road and find something along the way. At Esparza, I pulled off at a roadside diner-like establishment that seemed to be a major stopping point for buses. We both opted for a casado con pollo (a typical Tico dish with rice, beans, shredded cabbage or lettuce, and chicken), feeding some of it to Mi Pequeña Niña.<br />
I don&#8217;t know if it was all the buses that were stopping, or if it was Esparza, or my own imagination, but I began to get a little nervous about our car. People were getting too close to it. One jerk even cuddled up to it, looking like he might try to rip off the antenna.<br />
There&#8217;s a problem in Costa Rica, mostly with rental vehicles. People puncture holes in the tires, then follow you until you pull over because of the flat. They offer to help you, and steal all your luggage. I don&#8217;t know how common this is, but most of the travel books and rental agencies warn you about it. (Avis&#8217;s insurance won&#8217;t cover the tires, no matter how much you get.) We ended up racing through the end of our meal to get back to our new car before something bad happened.<br />
Turned out it was just that the guy was a jerk.<br />
Not long after we left Esparza, the rain hit again. It was raining pretty much everywhere on Sunday, and heavily. Even for the rainy season, it was a lot. All the way over the mountains, it poured. Even creeks were racing with all the water. A tractor-trailer with a short container load even flipped on one of the many hairpin curves. A sure sign that the driving should be done with due care.<br />
We stopped only once on our way back, when Alex spotted wooden toys for sale at the side of the road. I&#8217;d spotted little trucks, but she&#8217;d seen the rocking horses. After a short double-back, we picked one of them up. It&#8217;s Mi Pequeña Niña&#8217;s first birthday on Friday, and we wanted to get her something nice. I think it was a great idea.<br />
Once we got past Grecia, the trip was pretty easily. I&#8217;ve done that part of the Panamerican so much that I almost have it memorised. We stopped at the Auto Mercado for groceries (running into Jason and Jen, and raving about Ylang Ylang to them) before heading home. I&#8217;ve lost faith in Auto Mercado, as their produce is beyond sketchy (a bunch of bad bananas and a bad mango all in one shot?). MÃ¡s Por Menos seems to be better, and Fresh Market is usually the best (and most expensive).<br />
Home in the rain, and it rained all night. The Lago even flooded yesterday at the complex, and they were fixing the overflow drain this morning.<br />
The next adventure? Don&#8217;t know yet. Maybe a return to Arenal, maybe a flight out to Tortuguero (the drive is not easy or short), maybe just little trips around the area. We&#8217;ll see.<br />
But stay tuned&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/a-revenge-free-montezuma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1035</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend in Punta Leona</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-in-punta-leona</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 23:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puntarenas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainforests]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1026</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I had promised Alex that the second weekend we were in Costa Rica would be spent away from our apartment. I just had to find the right place to go. So I spent a fair bit of time working out the location, time to get to the location (because any estimates of travel time here &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend in Punta Leona"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had promised Alex that the second weekend we were in Costa Rica would be spent away from our apartment. I just had to find the right place to go. So I spent a fair bit of time working out the location, time to get to the location (because any estimates of travel time here are usually way off once you leave the #1), cost, and whether or not they had massages.<br />
Yes, that is a consideration in her (and hence my) world.<br />
In the end, I decided on Punta Leona. This would be our first surprise weekend in Costa Rica, and it would seem the first surprise weekend in &#8212; we fear &#8212; two years! Turned out to be not too bad.<br />
<span id="more-1026"></span>I ducked out of work a couple of hours early on Friday. I knew the trip was going to be about two hours, and I also knew the traffic going through Lindora (where our current office is) tends to be pretty evil towards the end of the day. I zipped home, packed up the remaining parts that weren&#8217;t already packed, and the three of us took to the road.<br />
Getting to the highway &#8212; the Panamerican highway #1 &#8212; takes about 30 minutes from where we are in traffic. It&#8217;s far from a straight route. Once we got to the highway, we still had to contend with a bit of traffic between where we got on (near CervecerÃƒ ­a Costa Rica S.A. &#8212; CCR, which makes Imperial beer) and the airport (there&#8217;s a traffic light) and a couple of areas where the highway narrows to a single lane as you head west.<br />
By this point, Alex was already well into the game of rhyming off places that we could go. Normally, when we did this back in Canada, she was much better at it. But Alex isn&#8217;t attuned to Costa Rican geography yet (nor am I, for the record), so the game wasn&#8217;t as lively as usual.<br />
We drove until we got to Highway 3, which heads to Atenas. This is the &#8220;fastest&#8221; route to Jaco, which is the destination often used to help guide people.<br />
If you look on the map, <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=+Costa+Rica&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.841686,-84.460831&amp;spn=0.372773,0.478592&amp;z=11">the road from the junction of the #1 and the #3 all the way down to Punta Leona</a> looks reasonably nice. A little curvy in a few places, but overall nice. It&#8217;s about as misleading as a cigarette salesman. The road is 74 kilometres, packed into a straight-line distance of about 50 kilometres. That&#8217;s how much it weaves. The curves are tight, the valleys are deep, having a manual transmission is a God-send, and all the little one-lane bridges slow you down.<br />
The information to find Punta Leona suggested (look for the sign, you can&#8217;t miss it). Well, folks, at dusk it&#8217;s pretty darn easy to miss the sign. It was almost dark by the time we got there (in just over two hours, I should add), and the massive PUNTA LEONA sign isn&#8217;t lit at that point. It&#8217;s not a town &#8212; it&#8217;s a resort.<br />
This threw me a little. I thought Punta Leona was a town, and the hotel was a resort in the town. Nope. It&#8217;s its own little world. Security is high (you need to have a reservation or invitation to come in after 5pm), and it&#8217;s isolated. The drive from the front gate on the highway all the way down to the hotel area is 15 minutes through bamboo forests and the jungle.<br />
Yes, jungle.<br />
Punta Leona is built into a rainforest. It&#8217;s one of the neatest things I&#8217;ve yet seen for a hotel. It&#8217;s a resort &#8212; a timeshare, so far as I can tell &#8212; and the construction puts it very close to two beaches: Playa Mantas and Playa Blanca. Technically, you can&#8217;t own a beach in Costa Rica (that&#8217;s what I understand), so Punta Leona still has to provide access to the beaches &#8212; they&#8217;re public property.<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña was beyond hungry. Over two hours in a car was more than enough for her, and she wanted out. Alex had to get into the back seat for the last 1/3 of the trip to try and keep the wee one happy. By the time we&#8217;d turned off the highway and were driving down the 15 minutes of road, it was just &#8220;GET ME OUTTA HERE&#8221;.<br />
Jungle everywhere, but almost impossible to see. It was dark, and in the jungle, it gets dark quickly. We checked in, got our key and tried to go directly to dinner. But the restaurant doesn&#8217;t open until 19:00, so we opted to put everything in the room first. By the time we were done, the restaurant was open. I think we were the first to arrive.<br />
The next morning, we finally got a good look at our little slice of heaven. We stayed in the Selvamor suites, which are little huts amidst the giant rainforest trees. After a bite of breakfast and a nap (for the baby, not us), we wandered down to the pool area for a morning of splashing around.<br />
I should note that this is the baby splashing around, not us. She doesn&#8217;t know how to swim yet, and isn&#8217;t in water wings just yet. So she needs us to keep her head above water.<br />
We returned to the buffet for lunch, as we didn&#8217;t really have anything for Mi Pequeña Niña to eat. The afternoon was much slower, with another nap, and some wandering around for Alex and I. (Yes, we leave our child in the room to sleep alone. The door is locked, and we&#8217;re very confident in the way she sleeps.) We ended up being caught in a tropical downpour.<br />
Before dinner, we drove out to Playa Blanca (walking there would have taken well over an hour) to watch the sunset. Sadly, the weather was against us and there was no sun to be seen. It would appear we have to wait a while longer before we can see another fantastic Costa Rican sunset again. It won&#8217;t be long, I&#8217;m sure.<br />
At dinner, we met a rather interesting couple from &#8212; of all places &#8212; Calgary, who were on their 12th time visiting Costa Rica. Mi Pequeña Niña, as with every meal it seems, attracted attention from virtually every restaurant staff and from most of the nearby tables. There&#8217;s something about a blonde-haired, blue-eyed baby that doesn&#8217;t stop smiling that seems to get people happy.<br />
Punta Leona, as I&#8217;ve already said, is surrounded by jungle. This includes all the jungle creatures that live there, including leaf-cutter ants, a couple kinds of raccoons (one of which looks like a slightly longer version of the one we&#8217;re most familiar with back in Canada), all sorts of birds, squirrels, and supposedly monkeys (but we didn&#8217;t see or hear any).<br />
It&#8217;s also filled with stupid tourists who feed those animals human food. That bothered me a lot. I hate it when it happens in Canada, and there&#8217;s stiff penalties for doing it. Here? Well, it&#8217;s a blind-eye situation.<br />
Following breakfast the next morning, I zipped back out to Playa Blanca to get some pictures in the daylight, while Alex and the Wee One went to the playground. Then the three of us began a much slower drive home.<br />
The route back was oddly harder than the route out. Some of the road signs aren&#8217;t particularly clear, and twice I had to turn around to re-join the right road. Alex caught me the first and third times, I caught myself the second. I&#8217;m sure with more practise at driving here, I&#8217;ll be able to read the signs a little more easily.<br />
We stopped twice. Once at this place called Mirador Something-Or-Other, which is almost at the border of Atenas and San Mateo along a windy strip of road that makes the Trans Canada between Field and Golden look like a straight, flat line. The view was spectacular &#8230; and the service exactly the opposite. We had something to drink and left.<br />
The second place was in an area with a number of small restaurants in Atenas. Alex chose one place that was as typÃƒ ­co as food gets in Costa Rica, but with a menu that featured English so we knew what we were eating. Mi Pequeña Niña ate a significant portion of my arroz con pollo (rice with chicken) and most of my steamed vegetables. She rather liked the rice, and couldn&#8217;t get enough. Noted, for future meals!<br />
Arriving at home, I started to feel that it was &#8230; home. I&#8217;m almost living here (the work visa is the only thing preventing me from saying that I am living here), and our apartment is starting to feel like home. This is good. &#8216;Cuz it&#8217;s gonna be a long couple years if I don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;ve got a home to go to.<br />
[flickr]tag:puntaleona+august+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]tag:atenas+august+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1026</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-in-costa-rica</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 05:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=974</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Years ago, I used to think business travel was glamourous. You got to go to far-flung places, see different things, and engage in activities you just don&#8217;t do at home. Then I started going on business trips. I learned fast that the enjoyment is only so deep. Worst experience was [[Live from Cincinnati&#124;Cincinnati in 2000]]. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Years ago, I used to think business travel was glamourous. You got to go to far-flung places, see different things, and engage in activities you just don&#8217;t do at home. Then I started going on business trips. I learned fast that the enjoyment is only so deep.<br />
Worst experience was [[Live from Cincinnati|Cincinnati in 2000]]. Second, and only because I was utterly exhausted by the end (the trip itself was very helpful) was [[Je suis en Paris!|Paris in 2006]]. (As I learned, when you travel to Europe, you end up with 18-20 hour days, because you&#8217;re trying to stay sync&#8217;d with the home office.)<br />
But today hasn&#8217;t exactly been a slice, either. And just because I&#8217;m currently in Costa Rica <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=Santa+Ana,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+Costa+Rica&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;cd=2&amp;geocode=0,9.933607,-84.184196&amp;t=h&amp;ll=9.945418,-84.189987&amp;spn=0.002859,0.003659&amp;z=18&amp;iwloc=addr">doesn&#8217;t mean I&#8217;m sitting on a beach</a>.<br />
<span id="more-974"></span>I woke up at 3:50. That&#8217;s AM, as in &#8220;before most sane people wake up&#8221;. I was at Jason&#8217;s house by 4:30. We were at the airport by 5:00. Along with &#8212; it seemed &#8212; all the Japanese tourists in Canada. Very strange. Check in, customs, security, and wait for the flight.<br />
Roughly four hours to Houston. And then a six hour wait. There are no direct flights from Calgary to San Jose, Costa Rica. You have to fly through somewhere. And with costs being what they are, that means Houston. There are worse places to be stuck for six hours, but frankly, any six-hour stint in an airport is enough to drive you batty.<br />
About 45 minutes before our flight boarded, we met up with Mark. Mark&#8217;s day has been considerably easier, as he didn&#8217;t have to wait nearly as long. Flights from Chicago are much more reasonable. The three of us boarded our flight to San Jose &#8212; another 3.25 hour journey.<br />
I should point out by this point that it was 18:15, and I&#8217;d been up quite a lot longer than I&#8217;d like, and wasn&#8217;t feeling particularly happy about the next leg of the trip. I wanted a nap. Badly.<br />
The flight, like the one before it, had a few bumpy parts (especially the landing &#8212; I was certain the pilot had blown out one of the tires), iffy food (we were actually fed, though), and not-so-great movies (or more importantly, they weren&#8217;t ones I wanted to watch).<br />
But it was on that flight that it hit me. The announcements were no longer in just English. Now I heard Español, too. I need to learn Spanish. It sounds weird, but this all sounded fine on paper sitting comfortably 5,000 kilometres to the north. But here, now, sitting in my hotel room, this is something different.<br />
Tengo que hablar Español. Especially if I have any hope of survival.<br />
Anyway&#8230;<br />
Arrival (bumps aside) was easy. Going to the States on business merits proctological examination. Here, we could have brought in an entire company and no-one would have been the wiser. In typical Tican form, we were immediately hit upon by a guy willing to take us to his hotel. Disappointed that we already had reservations elsewhere, he still drove us. For $6 each. Probably a bit on the expensive side, but we&#8217;re here, and that&#8217;s all that matters.<br />
Tomorrow, we house-hunt. This should be interesting&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">974</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On my way home</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=on-my-way-home</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 07:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[westjet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/10/on-my-way-home/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me. It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On my way home"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, the wedding&#8217;s done, Tamara and Dan are wed, and pretty much everyone is pooped. The bridal party was out late the night before, the groom&#8217;s group was fairly tired, and I&#8217;m just beat from all the running around. My feet are killing me.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t the shortest wedding I&#8217;ve been to, but it was definitely more expedient than most of the ones I&#8217;ve seen. That said, it was still a lovely ceremony.<br />
<span id="more-910"></span>I followed Tamara most of the day, her unofficial tied-to-the-hip photographer. Hair, make-up, nails, ceremony preparation, and post-professional pictures, before all heading off to dinner. I was fortunate enough to be treated almost like the wedding party without actually being one of them. It was nice to be considered in such a way, especially when it wasn&#8217;t really place.<br />
Yes, Tamara cried. So did I. (I cry at every wedding.) It&#8217;s hard not to when things turn out that well. The wedding chapel at the Mandalay Bay might be a bit &#8220;assembly line&#8221;-ish, but it&#8217;s really a nice way to have weddings. It&#8217;s definitely not your stereotypical Vegas chapel. Not an Elvis to be seen.<br />
Following the ceremony and the post-professional pictures, we all went to Chinois at the Forum Shops. It&#8217;s a Wolfgang Puck restaurant. Very tasty. Our &#8220;private room&#8221; was a great balcony overlooking the mall itself. It wasn&#8217;t loud at all, and much rejoicing was had.<br />
But now I stand in Maccaran International, awaiting my flight home at 2:10. Yes, that&#8217;s 02:10, as in AM, after midnight. I land in Calgary just before 6, then head right into work. Yes, I&#8217;m insane. But you already knew that.<br />
So to the newly-minted couple, I offer only my best hopes and wishes for life, love, and happiness. The minister was right &#8212; there is no gambling in love. There are no &#8220;ifs&#8221; or &#8220;in case of fires&#8221;. There is compromise and understanding, but love has a way of making that almost easy. May your remaining days in Las Vegas be full of fun and rest (you guys need it), and we all look forward to seeing you in Calgary.<br />
Congratulations my friends. And thank you for letting me be a part of your day in the sun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/on-my-way-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">910</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Vegas</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-in-vegas</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 21:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casinos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[las vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nevada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/08/back-in-vegas/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back in Vegas"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been nearly a dozen years since I was last (and first) in Las Vegas. (See [[Road Trip of the Southwest United States, Mesa Verde Cave Dwellings, Grand Canyon, and Arrival in Las Vegas]].) It&#8217;s been a long time, and this city has changed a lot since I was here last. And not all for the good, I should say.<br />
If you&#8217;ve watched CSI, you&#8217;ve seen a stylised version of Las Vegas. And it ain&#8217;t the one that&#8217;s here. This is half gambling, half drunken idiots, half shopping, half selling sex, with some shows tossed in for fun.<br />
Yes, I know that adds up to well more than 100%. But this is a city of excesses.<br />
<span id="more-909"></span>Why am I here? My friend Tamara is getting married. It&#8217;s hard having been Tamara&#8217;s friend for the last year. Technically, I&#8217;m her boss. So I have to keep a &#8220;respectful distance&#8221;. Which sucks, since I&#8217;ve known her nearly eight years &#8212; nearly three of which we were housemates. We know each other pretty well. But I can&#8217;t act around her the way I would normally at work, since it might cast a light of favouritism.<br />
But when she asked me to come to her wedding, there was no question. None. Well, except whether or not Alex and the Wee One would come. As it is, they didn&#8217;t, and I&#8217;m running solo. Yeah, I know what you&#8217;re thinking: woo hoo, a weekend in Sin City for Geoff!<br />
I have a 7-month old and a wife, both of whom I love more than life itself. Do you really think I&#8217;m going to do something stupid?<br />
Besides, I&#8217;m too old to drink to the point of being sick (which I saw more than once yesterday), I never gamble with my money &#8212; only my life, and frankly I really don&#8217;t want to find out what weird diseases the hookers in this city pass around.<br />
That was a part of this city I&#8217;d forgotten about. It&#8217;s not just the newspaper box-like containers that distribute catalogues for hookers (no, I&#8217;m not kidding), it&#8217;s all the people who stand along the sidewalks, picking off all the guys (solo or in groups) to hand them cards. They flick them in their fingers like a nervous poker player. But instead of a royal flush, it&#8217;s a royal &#8230; well, y&#8217;know. It&#8217;s pathetic to see, and I actually feel sorry for these people.<br />
The Vegas of old where everything is cheap is long gone, too. Everything here is insanely expensive. It was $15 just to travel the 1.5 kms from the airport to my hotel. And that was moving pretty darn zippily, I might add. Meals are insanely expensive, too. Although I managed to find the Tea House in the Imperial Palace. A roast beef meal with all-you-can-drink lemonade for $20 with tip. At the newer hotels, that&#8217;s just your drink.<br />
I&#8217;m staying at the Tropicana, in a hotel room that hasn&#8217;t seen a renovation in about three decades. The maintenance hatch to the bathroom plumbing is rusting at the edges, the silicone seals have dried and peeled away, and the sink doesn&#8217;t drain worth a damn. The bed must be wrapped in plastic from what I could feel.<br />
Tamara and Dan, by comparison, are in the 18th floor of the Mandalay Bay. Their place is bigger and nicer than most of the apartments I&#8217;ve stayed in. It&#8217;s almost criminal. But they&#8217;ve never been here before, so they&#8217;re allowed the experience. Besides, it&#8217;s their wedding, right?<br />
I spent today shopping. Clothes for the Wee One, a trinket or two for Alex. I tried to find a cheap camera flash for me, but be darned if there isn&#8217;t a single freakin&#8217; camera store closer than a $20 cab ride. I&#8217;ve done enough cab rides for now. I&#8217;ll stick to the monorail.<br />
Tonight is the &#8220;night before&#8221;. Tamara and her crew are going to the Stratosphere to have fun. Dan&#8217;s at a show until 22:00 or so, so I&#8217;ll run around and get some night pictures (would you expect any less of me?)<br />
Well, only 1 minute left on this internet cafe computer, so I&#8217;ll wrap up this entry. Tomorrow&#8217;s the wedding, so with luck I&#8217;ll hammer something more out. And yes, pictures will come once I can get them all uploaded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/back-in-vegas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">909</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
