<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>evans hunt &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/evans-hunt/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 23:32:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Evans Hunt Sick Day 2013</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/evans-hunt-sick-day-2013/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=evans-hunt-sick-day-2013</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/evans-hunt-sick-day-2013/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 23:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[They say that when you put enough people in close proximity for long periods of time, their biological rhythms come into synchronicity. People start thinking the same, they pick up each other&#8217;s habits and nervous ticks &#8230; and of course catch each other&#8217;s colds. And &#8230; uh &#8230; we all got terribly, terribly ill and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/evans-hunt-sick-day-2013/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Evans Hunt Sick Day 2013"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>They say that when you put enough people in close proximity for long periods of time, their biological rhythms come into synchronicity. People start thinking the same, they pick up each other&#8217;s habits and nervous ticks &#8230; and of course catch each other&#8217;s colds. And &#8230; uh &#8230; we all got terribly, terribly ill and declared to everyone that we weren&#8217;t able to work for the day. Planned a couple of weeks in advance. In unison.<br />
Okay, yes, we all played hookie. We had a good reason. We&#8217;re helping out <a href="http://banffnorquay.com/">Mt. Norquay</a> with some of their marketing needs. And who are we to pass up an opportunity to experience our client&#8217;s business while taking a much-needed day off to go skiing?<br />
Though &#8230; is it worth mentioning that I haven&#8217;t been near a ski hill in about 25 years?<br />
<span id="more-3240"></span>I met Allard just after 7:00 on the east side of 69th St., and from there we went to pick up Bill, followed very shortly after by breakfast for 35 from Tim Horton&#8217;s. Allard&#8217;s declaration to arrive at Canada Olympic Park (now officially known as WinSport), where we met with everyone else, boarded our bus, and hit the road into a foggy morning.<br />
It was the first time I&#8217;d ever turned north off the Trans Canada at Mt. Norquay Road &#8212; I&#8217;d always gone south into Banff Townsite. And a slow, winding route up the side of the mountain brought us to a near-empty parking lot.<br />
This, incidentally, is the reason we went on a Wednesday: mid-week attendance is low (a common problem at ski resorts, so I gather). This allowed us to have a room to ourselves, easy access to the runs (not a single line-up), and gloriously quiet. It also allowed us to get rentals quickly (Norquay does a brilliant job of group events, I have to say). Well, those of us who needed rentals &#8212; there were several people who were already on the hills before I&#8217;d even managed to figure out where the rentals were to be found.<br />
I&#8217;d not worn ski boots in &#8230; well, a long time. The last time I&#8217;d worn them, flipped-up collars were still cool, and neon clothing was considered fashionable. Ski boots, from what I can recall, weren&#8217;t that hard to get on, and I have some vague memory that they were about as tight as a slightly-small pair of ice skates. &#8216;Course, that could be just the fact that I was 15 (do the math, folks) and a lot more supple than I am now. I broke a sweat just trying to get my foot in the first boot. I needed help to get the buckles done up.<br />
We soon found our instructors (there seven of us &#8212; four going for snowboarding, and three of us for skiing), and went off to &#8230; the bunny hill. This was at the bottom of the much-larger hills behind us, the first time that I&#8217;d ever seen &#8220;alpine&#8221; ski runs. They were big. Like, scary big.<br />
Oh, yeah, I should also mention that I was actually more than a little scared going skiing again. Age aside, I remembered very well that the last time I&#8217;d skied I still had big trouble with control. I couldn&#8217;t turn to the right and my ability to stop was horrid (so bad, in fact, that I&#8217;d had to wipe out to slow down &#8230; I broke the ski, and thankfully not myself). Many years later, on a much bigger hill, I started to wonder if this was such a wise idea&#8230;<br />
Life is not lived if you never try. (Right?) So I joined Eric (who&#8217;d not skiied before) and Kirk (a 25-year snowboard veteran who wanted to try something different) with our Japanese instructor (honestly, it just sounds funny &#8212; she was fantastic), and re-learned what I&#8217;d supposedly learned all those years before.<br />
It took a lot more effort than I thought it would. The hardest part was realizing that the ski was &#8212; shockingly &#8212; <em>slippery</em>. I&#8217;m still amazed that I didn&#8217;t fall over. Thankfully, I took poles, which were helpful, if not a bit of a crutch. They helped me move, and stay stable enough to get on the crazy carpet (basically, a conveyor belt to take us up the bunny hill) and get off at the top.<br />
The hardest part was the stance. You have to stand just so on skis so you can turn and stop yourself. Or, as is my history, lose control and careen into Very Bad Things<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />. And there are a lot more trees on Mount Norquay than there are on the hills in Ontario, lemme tell ya.<br />
After about five passes on the bunny hill, Kirk graduated to the real hill, while Eric and I kept doing bunny hill runs. Both Eric and I had trouble with control on our turns, and setting us loose on a much steeper hill was begging for trouble without a bit more confidence. But three more passes, and two more with our instructor, and we were on the chairlift heading our way up.<br />
Was I worried? Yeah, maybe a little. But not remotely as much as when I&#8217;d gotten off the bus a couple of hours earlier. Our instructor had done a brilliant job setting us up for the basics. And we had a couple of minutes of discussion before we got to the top. And then we looked down.<br />
Man, that hill looks a lot steeper when you&#8217;re at the top.<br />
And away we went. Slowly, turning (and avoiding other, much faster skiers), we started down. I went side-to-side on the track (easily 25 metres wide), turning in a path that would almost look like parallel lines connected with (very rough) semi-circles all the way down. The instructor and Eric followed soon after. We went back up.<br />
By this point, my feet were in agony. The boots were too tight, and my feet not accustomed to that sort of equipment. I was looking forward to getting out of them.<br />
My next run, I found myself going straighter. And I don&#8217;t mean in terms of side-to-side straightness, I mean more &#8220;straight down&#8221;. My nice, parallel lines had become noticeably angled. About half-way down, the instructor had stopped to wait for us. She waved me on. At the bottom, Eric and Kirk suggested that I have a &#8220;problem with speed&#8221;. To which they were utterly correct &#8212; I do, which is how I got into so much trouble the last time I went skiing.<br />
So of course, on our last run, I went even faster. (Idiot.) We went down a different run &#8212; on the other side of the bunny hill &#8212; which was slightly steeper. And my slightly-foggy goggles didn&#8217;t notice the drop. And I lost control. And let my pole stick into the snow. And I kind dropped my chin onto the top of said pole.<br />
And that&#8217;s it. Honestly. I lucked out in ways I still can&#8217;t comprehend. I should&#8217;ve had, like, an injury or something. But instead it was more of a wake-up call to SLOW DOWN a bit, and take it easier. Which I did, all the way back down to the rental office to drop most of my equipment off.<br />
Getting the boots off? Almost as hard as getting them on, and infinitely more comfortable.<br />
Over lunch we all discussed our various exploits. Jim had managed to find powder somewhere off in the corners. Others had done runs down the moguls (which we could see from our room in the chalet, and it looked positively terrifying from my perspective), while others had gone over on other hills. Colin was the sole non-skier, and had spent his morning on the snow tubes, which was my destination after lunch.<br />
The tubes were built at the end of the mogul run, and were six long slides on which you&#8217;d ride innertubes (well, commercialized versions with handles and a full bottom). You had to haul said innertube to the top of the runs (the crazy carpet was without power for some reason), which was a much harder climb than any of us were willing to believe &#8212; I was winded by the time I got to the top. But the trip down was worth it.<br />
Peita and her family (who&#8217;d snuck up separately) were there as well, and they made a few runs before heading home. Marek joined us for two runs before he declared it &#8220;too much work&#8221; and headed back to skiing. Eric, like myself, had abandoned skiing and found the slides a blast. Colin also returned for a few runs before the two of us opted for a drink at the nearby patio.<br />
We sat in plastic Muskoka/Adirondack chairs and watched as people screamed down the tube slides. Screaming aside, it was a nice day to sit back and relax a bit &#8212; something both of us admitted was difficult to do at home. Then Colin noticed the chairlift next to the patio &#8230; people were getting off, sans skis, at the bottom. He immediately declared that we needed to go up.<br />
The chairlift brought us up to Norquay&#8217;s old tea house, which is the highest point at the resort. It&#8217;s a gorgeous view from up there, even if it was snowing, reducing our visibility. (I imagine the top of Sulphur Mountain is better, if only because it&#8217;s at the very top of the mountain, whereas the tea house is only on the east slope.) It was very peaceful up there.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2013/03/evans-hunt-sick-day-2013/snowing/' title='Snowing'><img width="300" height="224" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Snowing-300x224.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3381" alt="Snowing" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/8540116478/">Geoff S.</a><br />
We got back to the chalet just after 3:00, and remained there until it was time to go. We piled onto the bus and headed into Banff for dinner at the Elk and Oarsman. We dominated the back room, and likely the entire bar&#8217;s volume level to boot.<br />
Then it was back on the bus for our return to Calgary, watching <em>Big Trouble In Little China</em>. The driver got us back in what seemed to us a record time. Something, I think, we all preferred. I was home just after 9:00, and attempted to write this blog entry. I fell asleep from exhaustion, barely a paragraph in.<br />
All said and done, it was  a brilliant day. And, thankfully, injury-free. Two days later, I&#8217;m still a bit sore (shovelling snow the morning after was much harder than usual), though nothing terrible. But I do have one small problem.<br />
I think I like skiing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/03/evans-hunt-sick-day-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Blitzkrieg</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=christmas-blitzkrieg</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Christmas Blitzkrieg"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I have those moments when I think I&#8217;ve gotten too old, and I think I&#8217;m starting to feel like my age, I&#8217;m thankful for sudden sustained bursts of activity that remind me that, really, I just lead a much duller life than I used to, and my exhaustion is usually due to lack of sleep than from trying to do too much.<br />
Heck, it even makes me feel a bit young! Ish. Sort of.<br />
Except for the prolonged yawning, anyway.<br />
<span id="more-3199"></span>Tuesday evening, I went on a mission to find &#8220;Santa&#8221; presents for Monkey and Choo Choo, for a party Evans Hunt was holding for all the company&#8217;s children. I failed miserably for them (Alex would later prove to be a much better Santa in this regard), though it wasn&#8217;t a total wash for Christmas as a whole.<br />
Wednesday night was wrapping, notably a batch of presents from my sister that came in sans trimmings and trappings. My folding skills got a dusting off.<br />
Thursday was the Evans Hunt End of the World / Last Pitch party, our annual fest with clients and spouses. I honestly feel like I leave these parties too early, and I miss out on the good stories. I got the backfill the following day, and was moderately relieved to have missed some of the trouble.<br />
Friday was something slightly different, but very exciting (for me). Along with Tamara, Adrian, and Barb, I went to go see <em>The Hobbit: An Expected Journey</em>. It had been 11 years (I&#8217;d thought it only 10 at the time, but I just double-checked) since Tamara, Adrian, myself, and a couple of others had sat and waited for hours in the hallways at the Famous Players Chinook theatre (now Scotiabank Cineplex) to wait for the opening night of <em>The Lord of the Rings: Fellowship of the Ring</em>. A lot has happened in those years since&#8230;<br />
Eleven years later, I still love movies like that: long, and epic.<br />
I passed out nearly as soon as I got home, mostly due to exhaustion. (I&#8217;d also been running around before getting to the theatre, trying to find a Car2Go that I could actually get into &#8212; their system has been having issues for a couple of weeks, now.)<br />
Saturday morning was a blur of surreptitious present wrapping for the afternoon&#8217;s Santa visit, helping/forcing the kids to clean up the basement, making breakfast, and something else that I now forget. Then it was a blur of lunch-making, dressing (notably the kids in their nice dresses), and then loading into the car for the trip down to Evans Hunt for the party.<br />
This was the first office party for kids that I&#8217;ve ever attended, at any company. For reasons I&#8217;m sure someone much smarter than me could explain, Evans Hunt employees have a statistically high number of kids under the age of 10, and I&#8217;m willing to bet at least half are two or younger. At any rate, the fact that all of these kids existed was what led to the scheduling of the party, which we parents were quite happy for.<br />
The sixth floor &#8212; the new part of the office &#8212; was chosen for the venue. The large boardroom was co-opted for gingerbread man decorating and crafts, the main space for what ended up being punch-clown tackling, with a large comfy chair set aside for the Big Man.<br />
The kids rapidly multiplied, until the point where I think there may have been almost more kids than adults &#8230; though there have been more adults acting like kids after a while.<br />
When Santa arrived (Santa was a friend of a friend who does this professionally), the kids went crazy &#8230; and Choo Choo almost never left his side, utterly desperate for, well, not so much a present as just talking to him. Quite the reverse of Monkey, who was terrified of Santa for the first three and a half years of life.<br />
Monkey, interestingly, was the first one called up. She happily hopped up on his lap, talked a bit, got her present, and got down (with a hurried &#8220;thank you&#8221;) before going off to find out what the present was. (For the record, &#8220;Santa&#8221; was brilliant at finding things the kids seem to love.)<br />
Poor Choo Choo then had to endure most of the other kids coming next, one after another. She sat, enthralled, desperately eager to get on his lap. I managed to drag her away after a little while to drink more of her juice, when suddenly Santa produced the present. Choo Choo was off my lap in the blink of an eye, and raced over to Santa as fast as she could. She happily jumped up, and promptly asked for a &#8220;plane&#8221;.<br />
I have no idea where this &#8220;plane&#8221; thing was coming from. It&#8217;s now what she wants for Christmas. She was moderately disappointed at the <em>Stella and Sam</em> book she got instead.<br />
Party over, we headed home so Alex and I could shower and change for the next event of the day, her office Christmas party. Grandma appeared shortly after 5:00, which was about the time I dropped dinner on the table for them, mostly so they could eat and not bother Alex and I long enough that we could get ready for going out.<br />
We were gone just before 6:00, stopped at the hospital for Alex to get the tickets, and at the Ceili&#8217;s at Southland before 6:20. We sat at a table with Sarah, one of Alex&#8217;s regular co-workers, and Casey, who was one of the co-workers until she left to work at the new South hospital. It was the best move, since it was a good chance for us to chat with people we already knew.<br />
We left by 9:00.<br />
But lest ye think we were done &#8230; think again. Our destination? Toys &#8216;R Us. And not one, but two of them &#8212; one less than five minutes from the restaurant, and the other way up in the north. We didn&#8217;t get home until nearly 11:45. I got to bed a half-hour later after taking Grandma home.<br />
Sunday. Today. Yet more stuff.<br />
Mostly me doing my Christmas shopping, notably picking up things for Alex, and picking up the Playmobile toys for the girls that Grandma and I had found on Friday.<br />
And then we went to Zoo Lights.<br />
We&#8217;ve done this many times before, but this year we opted to try something a little differently. We opted to try going by C-Train, now that the new West LRT is open, and happens to run from here out to the Zoo. It seemed like a good idea, and we were &#8212; at least initially &#8212; excited to try out the new route.<br />
For the record, the trip is a minimum of 35 minutes (45 if you happen to <em>just</em> miss the train, which we did on the outbound). And although it was only -3, it somehow felt quite a bit colder, which we all seemed to notice. Thankfully the kids were well-bundled, so it wasn&#8217;t too bad for them.<br />
We got home at 9:00, well after some people&#8217;s bedtimes.<br />
Like mine. Or at least, that&#8217;s what it feels like. &#8216;Cuz after all this, I feel really tired.<br />
Sleep. Need sleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/12/christmas-blitzkrieg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3199</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, A Year In Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2011-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 07:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2011, A Year In Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I like long years. Really. Yes, I complain about when things seem to drag out far longer than they should, or if I&#8217;m busting my arse far harder than I think I should. That&#8217;s part of being human, no? In the end, though, I like long years because I get to look back and not worry about how quickly time has flown by. Time should never fly by quickly &#8212; it means I&#8217;ve missed something, and &#8230; well, darn it, I just hate missing things!<br />
This last year was a big one for me in one major way: it was a redefinition of my professional existence. Since the end of 2009, I&#8217;ve transformed from a professional manager to a &#8230; hmm &#8230; well, my title (however formal it needs to be) is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but that belies a lot of what I do every day, and just using &#8220;web developer&#8221; or &#8220;programmer&#8221; &#8212; even with a &#8220;Senior&#8221; prefix &#8212; completely understates the reality. This year was really about taking all the skills and knowledge I&#8217;d acquired as a leader, and merging that back into my day-to-day development practices.<br />
And that, as the saying goes, was only the tip of the iceberg&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2980"></span>I did a LOT of work. I did so much, in fact, that my contracting business is gone. Doors closed, windows shut, lights off. Permanently. I had to make a very painful call to realise that I need to focus on the three most important things in my life: my family. (There&#8217;s three of them, in case you were wondering.) To focus on them means to remove all other distractions inasmuch as is possible, and still earn a paycheque along the way (helping to support said family, of course).<br />
Add to that Alex&#8217;s return to work after nearly four years off as a Professional Mom, working evening shifts. That meant more time as a Professional Dad, whether I liked it or not. (And I like it, really. Except for dinner time. Suddenly, I have nothing but sympathy for my parents when I was a kid.) It&#8217;s adjustment, it&#8217;s growth.<br />
As a result of all of this, many things suffered. My hobbies (what few I have) were shelved &#8212; even my desire to blog waned dramatically, with more than a couple of blogless months. My TV watching fell to an all-time low, and I can count on one hand the number of movies I saw in the theatre (coincidentally, also the number of movies I watched during the Christmas break at home through iTunes). My health has also been &#8230; unattended, with a noticeable increase in girth and an unhealthy increase in my beer consumption (since decreased, thankfully).<br />
But if you were to ask me if I was &#8220;unhappy&#8221;, I&#8217;d have to say &#8220;no&#8221;. Every day, my kids remind me why I&#8217;m proud to be their dad. Every day, I get a challenge in my job. Every day, I enjoy life, even if it&#8217;s only for a few moments. To say I&#8217;m &#8220;unhappy&#8221; would be a disservice (if not an outright insult) to my daily existence, and those around me.<br />
To that end, I can safety state that I&#8217;ve:</p>
<ul>
<li>Been into Banff National Park on a few occasions &#8212; both warm and cold &#8212; but nowhere near enough for my liking</li>
<li>Picnicked as much as we could, but again nowhere near enough for what we could have done</li>
<li>Enjoyed the first brew from Calgary&#8217;s new Village Brewery</li>
<li>Did some renovation work in the kitchen (and planned more renovation work for this year)</li>
<li>Retaught myself the fundamentals of being a (web) developer, and merged that with the skills and knowledge of a technology director</li>
<li>Lamented as I saw Choo Choo seem to grow by leaps and bounds, going from my little baby girl to a walking, talking toddler</li>
<li>Finally accepted the truth, and got glasses</li>
<li>Came to understand my father in ways I never thought possible, and really wished that he could be here today to see how his son (kinda) grew up</li>
<li>Accepted the reality that I will only ever be a father of two beautiful girls &#8212; there will never be a third offspring</li>
<li>Watched in horror as Canada succumbed to fear mongering and elected a government that refuses to listen to its own people (a terrifyingly global trend in 2011)</li>
<li>Mourned the loss of one of Canada&#8217;s best politicians since Pierre Trudeau, the Honourable Jack Layton</li>
<li>Experienced my first general anesthesia to get my hernia repaired &#8230; boy, I do <em>not</em> want to go through that again!</li>
<li>Drank way too much coffee (yes, folks, that is possible)</li>
<li>Similarly, also drank too much beer (yes, also possible, though admittedly it tasted really good at the time)</li>
<li>Launched more projects in one year than I had launched during my busiest five years (combined) at my previous company</li>
<li>Took Monkey on the SUPER SECRET MONKEY SURPRISE &#8212; a short trip on CP 2816</li>
<li>Took Monkey to the Stampede, and realised to my delight (or possible horror, not sure yet) that she loves rides, especially roller coasters</li>
<li>Also got the Mother of All Headaches while at the Stampede&#8230;</li>
<li>Travelled to Ontario to visit with my family</li>
<li>Spent a lot of time swimming in the lake with Monkey and my nieces</li>
<li>Rode another steam train in Huntsville</li>
<li>Visited with some old and dear friends (especially Stuart and Therese)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 4th birthday, and Choo Choo&#8217;s first birthday</li>
<li>Also rode on the Heritage Park steam train</li>
<li>Travelled to Red Deer to see the Backyardigans live (oh, the things parents must do&#8230;)</li>
<li>Travelled once again to the West Coast for post-Christmas and New Year&#8217;s celebrations</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s other stuff I did, but my blog was so light on content in 2011 that &#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure. Sure, I can try to read Twitter, but I used that in lieu of my blog, so there&#8217;s a few thousand tweets I&#8217;d need to go over. That&#8217;s a little too much. So if I&#8217;m making any resolution this year, it&#8217;s to write more blog posts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/01/2011-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Annual Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-annual-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 20:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry for the long silence, folks. I&#8217;ve been a very, very busy boy the last couple of months, and &#8230; well, writing hasn&#8217;t really been a high priority for me. Family, as always, comes first, with my job (which provides for said family) a very close second. Sanity has eeked its way into third place &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Annual Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the long silence, folks. I&#8217;ve been a very, very busy boy the last couple of months, and &#8230; well, writing hasn&#8217;t really been a high priority for me. Family, as always, comes first, with my job (which provides for said family) a very close second. Sanity has eeked its way into third place &#8230; and anyone who knows me also knows how much attention <em>that&#8217;s</em> getting as of late. Writing is in fourth, which is a very sad last in terms of actual attention.<br />
So why now? Well, let&#8217;s go back to that second point. Today is my first anniversary of (full-time) work with Evans Hunt. While I had been kicking around here since January of last year, the full-time aspect is more recent, and in this case, also important&#8230;<br />
&#8230;it&#8217;s Annual Review Day.<br />
<span id="more-2968"></span>Unlike in my previous company, reviews here are very informal. Basically, you go to lunch with your department head (in my case, Allard) and one (or both) of the principals (Dan and Bill). You talk, you listen, you chat, you reminisce, and if it&#8217;s a particular bad review, I imagine you&#8217;d slink off to a bar following lunch and promptly get hammered&#8230;<br />
After the requisite mock-disparaging  comments, we engaged in what I would have (in my previous company) described as the single most glowing review I&#8217;ve ever received. And considering what I&#8217;ve done in the last 12 months, that is actually a point of note: I&#8217;ve gone from being a high-fallutin&#8217; managerial-type who used to do real work and who spent most of his time in Outlook, to someone who was setting up web servers, writing XML parsing code, and pulling together disparate data feeds into a unified views. In short, getting shit done.<br />
For the record, I highly value and appreciate Bill and Allard&#8217;s commentary and feedback. But I was suprised &#8212; if taken a bit aback &#8212; that there wasn&#8217;t much in the way of &#8220;constructive&#8221; feedback. In ye olde days, that was the list of things you should really &#8220;stop&#8221; doing, and start doing differently. The one that would stand out for most around here is my &#8220;passion&#8221; (I use the term loosely) towards the things I believe in. I tend to come across &#8230; well, kind of like <a href="http://youtu.be/xP1-oquwoL8?t=30s">Nicholas Cage in some of his more livid moments</a>. But around here, it&#8217;s an <em>asset</em>.<br />
There&#8217;s a point of comfort in that. I&#8217;m ancient in this business. I&#8217;m 39, and been doing this sort of work for nearly 17 years. If I haven&#8217;t done it myself, I&#8217;ve seen it and probably know someone who helped build it. I&#8217;ve gone from custom-build-everything to near-LEGOâ„¢ assembly of projects. I, like nearly everyone here at Evans Hunt, am a veteran. And veterans, as it happens, really have no time or patience for the crap that often occurs in our industry. Because we&#8217;ve dealt it. We&#8217;ve swam in it, in many cases, and somehow we&#8217;ve emerged, perhaps not smelling of flowers, but definitely not of the very effluence in which we felt we were drowning. So for a company to tolerate my idiosyncracities as a benefit (or at least tolerate it) is pretty significant in my books.<br />
And yet, the lack of the kind of criticism I used to receive seemed &#8230; odd. I&#8217;m still not quite sure what to make of it. I suppose, in part, it&#8217;s due to our size &#8212; we&#8217;re a small company, only about 36 people, so our fewer individualities tend to stand out better against the noise that comes from having many more personalities. We have to accept them, even encourage them, because that&#8217;s what makes things tick around here. Personalities go a long way to defining your working relationship with someone. Normally, I&#8217;d be getting input like &#8220;work better with project managers&#8221;, and &#8220;say &#8216;yes&#8217; more often to designers&#8221; (that&#8217;s a paraphrase, by the way &#8212; the actual feedback was more along the lines of &#8220;constructive dialog&#8221;).  Here? &#8220;Please, keep on being you.&#8221;<br />
Chalk up another phrase to add to the &#8220;Ways To Make People Feel Awesome&#8221; list.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long year here. We&#8217;ve done a lot, and there&#8217;s still a lot to do in the remaining two months. And that&#8217;s a good thing &#8212; better busy than bored, I say. And somewhere in all of that, maybe there&#8217;s room to push a bit more.<br />
&#8216;Cuz, really, I just don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;m doing my job right until someone&#8217;s calling me names.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/11/the-annual-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2968</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The need for the Big Picture</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-need-for-the-big-picture</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 12:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Saturday, my wife Alex and I went out on our own. (We manage to do this every couple of weeks thanks to Alex&#8217;s mother, who comes over to watch the kids so we can behave more like adults for a while.) On our little excursion, we spontaneously decided to go up the Calgary Tower, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The need for the Big Picture"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Saturday, my wife Alex and I went out on our own. (We manage to do this every couple of weeks thanks to Alex&#8217;s mother, who comes over to watch the kids so we can behave more like adults for a while.) On our little excursion, we spontaneously decided to go up the Calgary Tower, for no other real reason than to take a look.<br />
The sun was getting low in the sky, and the horizon was nearly completely obscured by haze (likely due to the city drying out from a few days of light-to-heavy rain). The shadows cast through the downtown were fantastic, the trees (most of which now have leaves) and the fields of grass were bright green, and light glinted off the glass of a hundred skyscrapers.<br />
And I realised &#8212; almost surprisingly &#8212; that from way up there, Calgary really does look quite beautiful.<br />
<span id="more-2945"></span>It seems like a weird statement, so let me elaborate. Like with over 95% of Calgary&#8217;s population, I&#8217;m not usually afforded a high-level view of Calgary &#8212; all I ever see is the dirt and chaos present at the ground level, where the work is being done. It&#8217;s messy, things don&#8217;t always go right, and I sometimes find myself wanting to scream at brick walls (screaming at actual people would have the same overall effect) for things to get better. Progress is hard to see, and my little corner(s) of Calgary seem just as ugly and insignificant as they always do.<br />
From on high (a bit of a joke, admittedly, since there are plenty of buildings much higher than Calgary Tower, now), it&#8217;s very different. Calgary looks different. The choking dust of construction is harder to see, the traffic mayhem isn&#8217;t as prevalent (it was also 20:45 on Saturday evening), and even the barebones of The Bow building (Encana&#8217;s new headquarters, still under construction) have a certain industrial appeal.<br />
Yep, there&#8217;s a business angle to this, too. &#8220;The Big Picture&#8221; is one that is often used, as is &#8220;Forest for the Trees&#8221;. It&#8217;s the same principle &#8212; at a low enough point, you can&#8217;t see the larger collection. You&#8217;re in the proverbial weeds, dealing with the problems that need to be solved. It&#8217;s ugly and often frustrating work, and down there it&#8217;s almost impossible to see how things will get any better.<br />
I think that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s necessary for everyone &#8212; not just management &#8212; to take those necessary steps backwards/upwards to see what they&#8217;re doing contributes to the whole. To see what&#8217;s going on, how everyone&#8217;s tasks feed into a larger entity. Especially in cases where there are dozens or hundreds of people involved, those on the ground need to witness for themselves what else is going on around them.<br />
Why? Two reasons, I think. First: understanding. People get tired, people get complacent, and often people end up getting angry because they can&#8217;t see past where they are. Knowing how others are doing, and how their own personal work may affect others can help focus tasks more effectively. Second: job satisfaction. Similar in nature, yes, but a separate effect &#8212; it&#8217;s almost surprising how much someone can feel that much better knowing how even a seemingly menial task can achieve a milestone.<br />
For me, right now, I can safely say that it&#8217;s easy for me to see the big picture at Evans Hunt. My project teams are less than 10 people in total, and often under 5. It&#8217;s very easy to take a step back and see what&#8217;s going on. Heck, I rarely even need to get out of my seat for that!<br />
In former lives, it was much more difficult, and I remember the struggle to see what was happening around me, let alone across the company. And I know I wasn&#8217;t the only one in that situation &#8212; the gossip and rumours (however accurate) often spawned around a need to fill in the missing gaps.<br />
So I offer this to you, dear readers: if you feel stuck, struggling to understand, maybe even lost, take time to find the highest possible observation deck in your town or city (most have something). Plan to go there about an hour or so before sunset, and take the time to look around. Look at the buildings you pass every day, look towards your home (even if you can&#8217;t see it), find the place you work. Look for the things that you see each and every day and tend not to give them a second (or even first) thought. See how different they look from up above.<br />
Reflect on that perspective &#8212; it&#8217;s an important one. On the next work day, see if you can find something similar in your daily life. Talk to a manager, to an executive (if you can), other people in other departments. Try to recreate that sense of wholeness that you felt looking down from above. Understand not only how you play your part, but also how everyone else factors in as well.<br />
Maybe then, things won&#8217;t seem so haphazard and chaotic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-need-for-the-big-picture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New life at Evans Hunt</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-life-at-evans-hunt/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=new-life-at-evans-hunt</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-life-at-evans-hunt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 06:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year ago, I was a &#8220;free agent&#8221; of sorts. I had gone self-employed, and had started to live in the world of contracts, invoices, expenses, and running around without adequate amounts of personal injury insurance. Not that I&#8217;d had to stray far &#8212; I started the year working for a small local agency almost &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-life-at-evans-hunt/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "New life at Evans Hunt"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A year ago, I was a &#8220;free agent&#8221; of sorts. I had gone self-employed, and had started to live in the world of contracts, invoices, expenses, and running around without adequate amounts of personal injury insurance. Not that I&#8217;d had to stray far &#8212; I started the year working for a small local agency almost entirely staffed with ex-Critical Massers.<br />
Evans Hunt looked like an ideal little home for me. A place where I didn&#8217;t have to worry about establishing myself, having to build up major amounts of credibility, and not really having a clue where I stood. Not to mention that when working in the contract field, it was always good to know that you were going to get paid, eventually. It was, for all intents and purposes, as close to &#8220;perfect&#8221; as I thought it could get.<br />
Then they made the most grievous of errors: they hired me full-time.<br />
<span id="more-2833"></span>I kid. I can do that, because they know me, and I know them. I&#8217;ve mentioned it before, but of the 35-ish people who work at/for/with Evans Hunt, more than 2/3s of us had all worked for Critical Mass once upon a time, and most of that 2/3s had worked with each other, to boot. That&#8217;s kind of the premise of Evans Hunt, though &#8212; hire who you know, and who you can trust.<br />
Trust is a major part of the office. It&#8217;s unspoken, but clear from the way things happen. My favourite example of this was a day back in the summer (when I was still a contractor) when I realised that three of the four principals of the company were all out on vacation. There wasn&#8217;t a single worried frown in sight. Everyone knew what had to be done, and life went on.<br />
I&#8217;m one of the senior technology people, now. My official title is &#8220;Solutions Lead&#8221;, but if anyone asks me, I&#8217;ll just say something like &#8220;Resident Know-It-All&#8221; or &#8220;The Geek&#8221; (think of The Gimp from <em>Pulp Fiction</em>). It makes more sense, I think. I&#8217;ve been around the block too many times to fit into the confines of a title.<br />
But, then, that&#8217;s a great thing about working for a small company again &#8212; the title is only what&#8217;s on the business card. My job, simply put, is to get things done. Whether that&#8217;s coding CSS, or doing content entry, or prepping images for use on the site, or writing user guides, or talking to clients about how to solve their problems, or poking holes in approaches to make things better, it doesn&#8217;t matter. Nothing&#8217;s above or below me, and there&#8217;s a huge amount of freedom in that.<br />
So it&#8217;s no end of irony that I almost didn&#8217;t stay with Evans Hunt. A few months ago, I was a debatable point. I wasn&#8217;t a developer &#8212; I was the rough equivalent of an unskilled lead. Until then, all I had done was attempt (and could be argued whether or not I succeeded) to help guide a fairly complex website. And that, in the grand scheme of things, wasn&#8217;t much. Evans Hunt knew it, and so did I.<br />
Second chances are good things. I&#8217;ve had a few of them, and I&#8217;ve been thankful for each and every one. My second chance was in October. The question, simply put, was: &#8220;Do you want to develop?&#8221;<br />
It wasn&#8217;t an easy question for me to answer. Truth is, I didn&#8217;t know. I had led myself to believe that I wanted to direct. I had done it for a few years and had come to like it a lot. I had developed, of course, but hadn&#8217;t really found the pleasure I had once known, so I had assumed I didn&#8217;t like programming anymore and had strayed away.<br />
So being asked to &#8220;go back&#8221;, admittedly, scared me a bit. No, that&#8217;s not right &#8212; it scared me a <em>lot</em>. What if I failed? <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/10/the-development-in-my-life/">What if I couldn&#8217;t do it anymore?</a> What if the ability was gone and &#8230; and all I was good for was drawing pretty diagrams and telling people to &#8220;have faith&#8221; that we&#8217;d find a way to implement the unknown and near-impossible? Okay, slightly undercutting what I used to do, but I couldn&#8217;t go back to doing that.<br />
Second chances are a good thing. A little lost sleep, more reading than I think I&#8217;ve done since university, and more than a few late-night pots of tea (I avoid coffee after 15:00, if I can help it), and things began to click again. And, more importantly, I found what I thought I&#8217;d lost &#8212; the love of what I do. Better still, it was stronger and more polished than before, because years of looking down on the process has helped me really understand and appreciate how to make things better.<br />
It&#8217;s now almost the end of January, and I&#8217;ve been full-time at Evans Hunt for nearly three months. I&#8217;d like to think that I&#8217;ve made a positive influence on things, and that my depth and breadth of experience is paying off not just for me, but for the company as a whole.<br />
So what&#8217;s in line for me? A lot, by the looks of it. I&#8217;ve got my hands in nearly ten different projects, nearly half of which are either new projects, or significant work on existing clients. I&#8217;ve been asked to consult on things that I might not even be working on, just because I have that experience. I&#8217;m even given trusted information, with the knowledge that I immediately forget what I saw or heard.<br />
Trust, as they say, is a two-way road. You can&#8217;t give it if it isn&#8217;t received, nor can you accept it if it isn&#8217;t given, and the lack of trust in either direction pretty much ensures a lack of faith.<br />
I have trust. And I have faith. Especially in me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/new-life-at-evans-hunt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2833</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2010, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2010-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearChooChoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Man, it feels like a year ago since I last wrote one of these &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;) 2010 was the year we made contact &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2010, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Man, it feels like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/">a year ago since I last wrote one of these</a> &#8230; oh, wait.  (Yes, it&#8217;s a stupid joke. You should know me by now&#8230;)<br />
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_(film)">2010 was the year we made contact</a> &#8230; wait, sorry, wrong catchline. 2010 was the year my family welcomed new members, notably my youngest, a daughter (code)named Choo Choo. It was a year I changed my career outlook (yes, again), and found that I&#8217;m not (completely) useless. This was a year of family, for me, and that&#8217;s perhaps the most important aspect.<br />
But despite all that, I hesitate to call it &#8220;a year of change&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-2829"></span>Got me as to why, though. Let&#8217;s be honest, there were a lot of changes, not the least of which are the ones noted above. But at no time did I feel like this is a sudden (and possibly unwanted) shift in my life. It actually feels like things are more settled this year, despite the apparent upheaval, than in previous years. Maybe one day I&#8217;ll make some sense of that little quandary.<br />
In the meantime, let&#8217;s review 2010:</p>
<ul>
<li>Began the year with tea at the Banff Springs, seeing my friend Sonny for the first time in about 15 years</li>
<li>Started working with some old friends at a new(er) company, Evans Hunt</li>
<li>Went to Edmonton for a &#8220;surprise&#8221; weekend (mostly for Monkey) and spent a great morning in the waterslides with her</li>
<li>Celebrated my Nana&#8217;s 97th birthday, which would also sadly be her last</li>
<li>Found out that I&#8217;m K+, my kids are K+, and my wife is anti-K</li>
<li>Spent many a sleepless night worrying about Choo Choo before she was born</li>
<li>Though originally disheartened, came to love and be thrilled by the 2010 Winter Olympics in Canada, and felt the massive pride for the successes of our athletes
<ul>
<li>Yes, I Twittered obsessively during the Men&#8217;s Hockey gold medal game</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bought our first flat-screen TV, to go along with our Apple TV</li>
<li>Welcomed my youngest, (code)named Choo Choo to our world</li>
<li>Watched Monkey&#8217;s first Easter egg hunt</li>
<li>Found out I&#8217;ve got something called &#8220;narrow angles&#8221; in my eyes, and got laser surgery in both of them</li>
<li>Went to Drumheller, and visited the Royal Tyrell</li>
<li>Guided (albeit not as well as I could have) the technical launch of my first all-Drupal website: VisitCalgary.com</li>
<li>Experienced the abject terror of losing your child in a mall</li>
<li>Said &#8220;thank you&#8221; to my Nana &#8212; I never say &#8220;goodbye&#8221;</li>
<li>Went on my first train chase with Monkey</li>
<li>Went to dim sum a couple of times, but not nearly enough</li>
<li>Introduced Monkey to sushi &#8212; I think she likes it</li>
<li>Went to Heritage Park a couple of times, and even saw Thomas the Tank Engine (hey, I&#8217;m a parent <em>and</em> I like trains, it&#8217;s a win-win)</li>
<li>Went to the Zoo lots (it helps to have a pass)</li>
<li>Saw a few movies, but not enough for my liking (the favourite of the year was Toy Story 3, and no, not just because I&#8217;m a parent)</li>
<li>Went on the first Great Family Roadtrip:
<ul>
<li>Overnighted in Medicine Hat, AB; Whitewood, SK; Moosimin, SK; and Swift Current, SK</li>
<li>Went to Winnipeg</li>
<li>Went to some place east of Camper, out in the middle of nowhere, as part of Alex&#8217;s family reunion</li>
<li>Stopped off in Regina, Moose Jaw, and Portage La Prairie</li>
<li>Drove the whole way and back again, and the kids didn&#8217;t seem to mind at all</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Got diagnosed with a hernia (yay, me)</li>
<li>Celebrated Monkey&#8217;s 3rd birthday, her first in Canada (beyond the day she was born, that is)</li>
<li>Finally got right ticked off with Shaw&#8217;s horrid home internet service, and switched over to Telus &#8230; we&#8217;ll see how it all goes</li>
<li>Did some kitchen renovation:
<ul>
<li>Installed a new sink and tap</li>
<li>Tore out the Florida ceiling</li>
<li>Installed new lighting</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had new windows installed in the house</li>
<li>Returned to being a developer, rather than a pure manager (I&#8217;m still adjusting to this one)</li>
<li>Took Monkey out on her first real Hallowe&#8217;en</li>
<li>Grew a moustache for Movember (my first, and last time)</li>
<li>Went to the Currie Barracks location of the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market almost every weekend for a year, until the location finally (and sadly) closed in December</li>
<li>Went on our first family flight out to Abbotsford, to spend Christmas in BC</li>
<li>Visited with some old friends from Radical Entertainment</li>
<li>Went to downtown Vancouver for the first time in about five years, and remembered how much I love it there</li>
<li>Had my first green Christmas in many, many years</li>
<li>Didn&#8217;t ride nearly enough trains</li>
</ul>
<p>Whoof. That&#8217;s a lot for one year. Can&#8217;t wait to see what 2011 throws at me. Bring it, New Year &#8212; I&#8217;m ready for you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/01/2010-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2829</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visit Calgary: You&#039;re Very Welcome!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evans hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we returned from Costa Rica, our plans had been pretty simple: take off the month of December to get settled, and then head back to work in January. Plans changed shortly after arriving back home, and suddenly I found myself without a job. Bills still had to be paid, food purchased, and because we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Visit Calgary: You&#039;re Very Welcome!"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When we returned from Costa Rica, our plans had been pretty simple: take off the month of December to get settled, and then head back to work in January. Plans changed shortly after arriving back home, and suddenly I found myself without a job. Bills still had to be paid, food purchased, and because we live in a city that is far too unfriendly to public transit, we also had to buy a car.<br />
A few years ago, this probably would have put me into a panic. And a few years ago, it would have been just me to worry about. Now I have a wife and two kids (well, one at the time, and one on the way) to support. Really, that should have put me off the deep end. Having lived through a significant amount of adversity over the last couple of years, though, I found myself not even concerned about the prospect of unemployment.<br />
I attribute that to having kept contact with just the right people.<br />
<span id="more-2681"></span>And so it came to pass that on 5 January, I walked into a meeting room on the 2nd floor of 805 10th Ave SW, and sat at a table with nine other people. <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/status/7422595138">Nine people I already knew.</a> Nine people I&#8217;d already worked with before at another company. I couldn&#8217;t help but smile.<br />
I was working &#8212; and still work &#8212; for the <a href="http://www.evanshunt.com/">Evans Hunt</a> Group, a small interactive marketing agency made up, largely, of former employees of Critical Mass. The principals of the company, Dan Evans and Bill Hunt, were both my managers at Critical Mass at one point or another, and Bill had been the one who started up the Costa Rica operation. My long-time mentor and also former Critical Mass manager, Allard Losier, is the technical lead, and the one who really convinced me to come in.<br />
[flickr]photo:4685617342(small)[/flickr]<br />
That conversation had occurred at the Cabin Cafe on Bow Trail and 45th St. SW, on 22 December. He and I had sat down over a coffee (two, in my case), and had a long conversation about events of the last 18 months, and potential events for the future. I hadn&#8217;t made any decisions at that point, although there had been heavy hinting at coming in to work for Evans Hunt, and I was rather enjoying the not-working aspect of my life.<br />
The conversation had really shown me the things that I had really missed over the previous 18 months: mentorship and trust. I had <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/05/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-we-know-it/">lost my mentor when Allard had left Critical Mass</a> shortly before I went to Costa Rica. And I had felt since about that time that there hadn&#8217;t been much trust in me, and always felt on the defensive. Going anywhere else was &#8230; well, it needed to be the right place.<br />
My project &#8212; the reason I was brought in &#8212; was to help Tourism Calgary with their website. The project, at least at a high level, was pretty simple: site overhaul. (Yes, at the high level, that&#8217;s all it is. Once you start going down in the levels, you really find out what kind of trouble you&#8217;re creating for yourself.) My job? Lead the tech team, work with the PM, and help deliver the final product. Time was originally pegged at about three months, and we&#8217;d see where things would go from there.<br />
I didn&#8217;t get a consulting agreement for three weeks. Normally, that would probably freak most people out entirely, my Mom being one of them. From her perspective, which I totally understood, I was working without any legal backup, and was likely to get screwed somewhere along the line. From my perspective, I wasn&#8217;t working for a company &#8212; I was working with friends. Friends I trusted, and who trusted me. People I knew wouldn&#8217;t pull anything shifty, so long as I didn&#8217;t do the same.<br />
That level of trust has permeated my now five-month tenure here at Evans Hunt. Knowing that the right people are there, that the right things will happen when they need to. All of that led us to the launch of our newest little baby, <a href="http://www.visitcalgary.com/">VisitCalgary.com</a>. Today, I supported Jim at a presentation by Tourism Calgary to the tourism industry at the Glenbow Museum (chosen because of Calgary&#8217;s recent bout of inclement weather &#8212; originally, it was supposed to be outside), and got to see the reaction first-hand of the very people we&#8217;re trying to support.<br />
And that&#8217;s when it really hit me. I&#8217;m not working for some massive multi-national conglomerate. I&#8217;m working for a group who&#8217;s trying to bring in tourists to the city I live in, to bring in money to the businesses that exist in the city I live in, to support the families of the people who work for the companies in the city I live in. I had disconnective issues working with American and European vendors for a very long time, partly because they never really affected me in any way. But this? This, I can get behind.<br />
It&#8217;s been a long project, and a little harder than I&#8217;d thought it be. The site, for the record, runs on Drupal. (For those of you unfamiliar, I suggest checking it out. Very powerful tool, Drupal.) I approached the project with a lot of confidence, believing that we&#8217;d be cruising along in no time. That&#8217;s when reality hit me.<br />
Drupal wasn&#8217;t at all like any content management system I&#8217;d ever worked with. And as a result, I was giving bad directions. It wasn&#8217;t until we started to engage Brian, one of Evans Hunt&#8217;s developers, that I began my Drupal education. A content management system, it is not. As Brian put it, it&#8217;s a content management framework. Yeah, I know, I know &#8212; splitting hairs, right? Not really.<br />
In every other CMS I&#8217;d spent significant time with, the rule of thumb was to build your templates first, and then embed the CMS functionality into them to build out the site. But with Drupal, you do it the other way around &#8212; let Drupal define the structure, and then make it look pretty afterwards. We lost time because of my direction.<br />
Thankfully, we also had some very talented developers. The first up was <a href="http://openhouseconcept.com/about">Lorne of Open House Concept</a>, who was the initial developer, and was the core layout guru. <a href="http://www.katokalen.com/">Kalen</a> jumped on not long after to work on templates, and then buzzed back in towards the end of the project in a weird little game of leap-frog. <a href="http://portfolio.brianc.info/">Brian</a> joined the project, which got us pointed in the right direction again (notably, correcting my oversights), and we brought on <a href="http://seeboriscode.blogspot.com/">Boris</a> to help us with the backend data synchronisation.<br />
It sounds like a lot of people, but in truth we only had three developers running at any one time. And considering I can barely code my way out of a paper bag, I am truly amazed at what the four of them did to get this site out the door. Especially considering that the office is just finishing a near two-month renovation, which had us working remotely from our PM-extraordinare January&#8217;s house for over a week.<br />
And yes, there were a lot of hours put into this project. They kept us working late, and more than a couple of weekends. This is where, in the past, I would lament the time away from my family. But this is also where that aforementioned trust comes in. Working from home is encouraged (assuming you don&#8217;t need to be in the office), and working at hours that suit your schedule is not a problem (provided you get your work done). End result: long hours, but still got be a family man.<br />
So, damn right I&#8217;m a happy camper. All told, I would say this has been one of my more favourite projects, and I&#8217;ve had a few doozies to compete with, too.<br />
And, really, you can never go wrong working with friends. (And yes &#8212; <em>with</em>, not for.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/06/visit-calgary-youre-very-welcome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2681</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
