<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>humour &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/humour/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 06:08:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Rudolph the red-nosed, genetically-altered, reindeer subspecies</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 06:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3518</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[We all know the song. We&#8217;ve all seen the 1964 Rankin-Bass television special. In our Western culture, we have a story of an underdog, recognized one foggy Christmas Eve for a trait that only he possessed, which saved Christmas as we know it. And thus Rudy the Red-Beaked Reindeer went down in history. But we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Rudolph the red-nosed, genetically-altered, reindeer subspecies"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know the song. We&#8217;ve all seen the 1964 Rankin-Bass television special. In our Western culture, we have a story of an underdog, recognized one foggy Christmas Eve for a trait that only he possessed, which saved Christmas as we know it. And thus <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPCvyJod0WM" target="_blank">Rudy the Red-Beaked Reindeer</a> went down in history.<br />
But we live in an enlightened age. We like to know why things happened, not just how. And if you listen to that story &#8212; even if you take the Bumble and such into account &#8212; there&#8217;s just too darned much that we&#8217;ve missed. Where&#8217;s the reality check, huh? Oh, you&#8217;re going to throw that Santa thing at me? Sure, okay, now you&#8217;re just being dismissive. We have to face facts, folks. There&#8217;s more to this song. Way more.<br />
Rudolph wasn&#8217;t a hero. He was a convenient freak of nature.<br />
<span id="more-3518"></span><br />
Life on Earth is replete with bizarre creations that regularly defy explanation: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platypus" target="_blank">platypus</a>, the <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/mantis_shrimp" target="_blank">mantis shrimp</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aye-aye">aye-aye</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/09/absurd-creature-of-the-week-naked-mole-rat/">naked mole rat</a>, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VGBs-8qlGzM">blob fish</a>, the <a href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/64804/10-intense-facts-about-giant-weta">giant weta</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/10/absurd-creature-goblin-shark/" target="_blank">goblin shark</a>, the <a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/03/absurd-creature-week-water-bear/" target="_blank">tardigrade</a>, and Donald Trump&#8217;s hair, to name but a few. Despite all of these strange things that don&#8217;t really seem to possible, they&#8217;re all a result of evolution: small changes over eons that have brought about the forms we see today. (Well, except maybe Trump&#8217;s hair. The science on that thing makes quantum entanglement look easy.)<br />
And, honestly, reindeer kind of fall into that category, too. Lest we think they&#8217;re just smaller versions of moose, reindeer (specifically <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mountain_reindeer">Rangifer tarandus tarandus</a></em>, though it could be readily argued that Santa&#8217;s &#8220;tiny&#8221; reindeer were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peary_caribou"><em>R.Â t. pearyi</em></a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Svalbard_reindeer"><em>R. t. platyrhynchus</em></a>) have some rather interesting biological traits of their own. For example, because they live in low-light conditions for a good portion of the year, <a href="http://kids.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/frym.2015.00018" target="_blank">reindeerÂ can see in the ultraviolet</a>. The ability to fly is an admittedly undocumented trait at this point, but then reindeer aren&#8217;t as closely studied as, say, pandas (and we&#8217;re pretty sure they don&#8217;t fly).<br />
So let&#8217;s look at a specific individual. Yes, the one that the song claims was the most famous of all (yet starts by asking if you remember him; honestly, that&#8217;s like asking if you&#8217;ve ever heard of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amitabh_Bachchan">Amitabh Bachchan</a>). Now we can assume that, protuberances aside, Rudolph was a fairly ordinary reindeer. After all, there&#8217;s no mention of any other part of his anatomy, or any psychological ticks that developed by being socially outcast by an unsympathetic and uncaring herd (and if you believe the TV special, Santa to boot).<br />
No, Rudolph was famous for having a glowing nose, and apparently nothing else. (The ability to fly is moderately debatable, as historic records don&#8217;t outright say that the reindeer flew, only that they drove &#8220;To the top of the porch! to the top of the wall!&#8221;.Â Though there is a note that they &#8220;flew like the down of a thistle&#8221;, it&#8217;s worth noting that such flight is at the discretion of the wind. But I digress&#8230;) So let&#8217;s focus on Rudy&#8217;s shnozz.<br />
Reindeer have, by nature, <a href="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/02430/reindeer-1_2430746b.jpg">a large, wet nose covered with soft hairs</a>. There&#8217;s nothing on there that looks particularly <a href="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-496823.html">like a light bulb</a>. Which, really, is okay, since bioluminescence doesn&#8217;t use incandescence or plasma-based fluorescence in the way we light our homes. In nature, this is usually a result of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bioluminescence">a chemical reaction in a living organism that gives of a burst of light</a>. The kicker here is that most of that colour tends to come in the blue-green spectrum, which is a far cry from red (there are a few fish that produce red light, but last I checked, reindeer weren&#8217;t aquatic &#8230; though I am told that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W-oFqCVNnbM">they&#8217;re better than people</a>).<br />
That doesn&#8217;t rule out a red nose, however. Like I said, reindeer noses are big &#8212; the full width of their snout, easily the size of a human fist, even in the smallest of reindeer subspecies. So what? Well, those noses are full of blood vessels. Ever shine a light through your hand? You bet: it&#8217;ll turn red. Now, would it be the colour of holly, as suggested by <a href="http://kids.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/frym.2015.00018#ref10">Barbara Hazen</a>? That might be a tough one, but perhaps if Rudolph were active, which would increase blood flow, it could happen? I think a bigger question is: was Rudolph capable of producing this light on his own, or did he have an unfortunate infection of bioluminescent bacteria? (It might be possible to dismiss the latter, as that appears to be a largely marine-based scenario.)<br />
It likely means it was the result of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luciferase" target="_blank">luciferase</a>Â reactionÂ (I love that name), which is not naturally found in mammalian cells. So amongst an <a href="http://www.daclarke.org/Humour/santa.html" target="_blank">unknown subspecies of extremely fast-moving reindeer</a>, we have a further subspecies with bioluminescence.<br />
Wait.<br />
Is it just me, or does this sound like &#8220;Santa&#8221; is pulling anÂ <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Island_of_Doctor_Moreau" target="_blank">Island of Doctor Moreau</a></em>, here? Maybe his herd of reindeer weren&#8217;t just looking down on Rudolph, but were miffed that he was Santa&#8217;s new favourite? Hey, it&#8217;s entirely possible that the Association of Flying Reindeers, Local 25 pressured Rankin-Bass to make Santa look bad (it&#8217;s not like he can fire them or something &#8212; really, what&#8217;s Santa gonna do without his reindeer, anyway?)<br />
Okay, back to the honker. Rudolph supposedly had a nose bright enough to cut through even the thickest fog.Â Well, therein lies the real question: was it as bright as a lightbulb? The brightest known bioluminescent organism is theÂ <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pyrophorus_noctilucus"><em>Pyrophorus noctilucus</em></a> (appropriately named the Headlight Elater), which produces roughly 1.5 times the brightness of a heavily overcast day. That thing is a mere 30 mm in size, and the glowing part is only a portion of that. So if you throw that much brightness into something about 0.05 sq metres &#8230; well, it would certainly be more than enough to light up a room. But a sky? The direction in which your heading? And would be it be focused light a headlight, or radiate in all directions?<br />
It&#8217;s considered &#8220;foggy&#8221; when visibility is limited to 1,000 metres, which is quite a distance. Presumably, the fog of &#8220;that&#8221; Christmas (it&#8217;s unstated, and I frankly don&#8217;t feel like diving through historical weather records) was much, much worse. But we&#8217;ll give them the benefit of the doubt (hey, Santa&#8217;s old, how well can the old fart see?), and say that it&#8217;s a couple dozen metres.<br />
I&#8217;ve driven in fog that thick. I was lucky to break 80 km/h (it was a 100 km/h highway) for fear of driving off the road. My headlights were more of a burden than a benefit, making the fog glow rather than showing me where I was going. Mind you, that was white-yellow light, which doesn&#8217;t penetrate as well asÂ <em>red</em> light. And, in theory, you&#8217;d see better.<br />
Except thatÂ <em>they&#8217;re flying</em>. And to make it around the world,Â <em>they&#8217;re flying really, really, really fast</em>. Honestly, the only reason airplanes have lights is because there&#8217;s a heap of rules that say they have to have them for visual contact with other planes. Otherwise, they&#8217;re useless. So what possible use could Rudy&#8217;s nose be once they&#8217;re airborne?<br />
Simple: The nose was a ruse. It was obvious, so people picked on it. But that wasn&#8217;t what made Rudolph truly special. It was the fact that Rudolph had a strongÂ magnetoreception. This isn&#8217;t fiction, folks, <a href="http://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev.ph.46.030184.003101?journalCode=physiol">this stuff&#8217;s been studied for over 30 years</a>! This is how birds migrate. Even large mammals like roe deer can sense differences in field strength, and that&#8217;s a cousin genus to reindeer. So maybe Dr. Santa Moreau went a few steps further, and mixed the gene pool a bit to increase his herd&#8217;s capabilities. Hey, stir the pot enough, and it&#8217;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cousin_marriage#Genetics" target="_blank">possible to get a few biological oddities</a>&#8230;<br />
There&#8217;s also the minor issue of communication. Let&#8217;s assume, for the moment, that the reindeer and Santa are capable of surviving a trip of speeds over 1000Â kilometresÂ <em>per second</em> (that&#8217;s escape velocity from the Milky Way galaxy, in case you were wondering; the New Horizons probeÂ movesÂ at a comparatively pokey 16.26 km/s) &#8212; maybe there&#8217;s a previously unknown bow shock effect that protects them and somehow doesn&#8217;t annihilate anything nearby &#8230; like houses &#8212; how the hell does Santa tell Rudolph + Co. where to go, or how do the reindeer tell Santa that they&#8217;ve arrived?<br />
And, for that matter, how did Dr. Santa ever graft the right genes to make reindeer talk? And suddenly, I think we&#8217;re onto something.<br />
The milk and cookies. It&#8217;s not a &#8220;thank you&#8221; to the man in red who comes bounding down your chimney. It&#8217;s a <em>sacrificial offering</em>, people! We&#8217;ve been keeping him away for centuries. I&#8217;ll bet he&#8217;s lactose and gluten intolerant. People who miss that point? Santa went all Dr. Moreau on them, and made them into his reindeer.<br />
So if you happen to hear hooves pounce all over your rooftops tomorrow night, set a big, roaring fire, and lock your doors. You&#8217;d better watch out, you&#8217;d better not make a sound, you&#8217;d better cock your guns &#8212; I&#8217;m telling you why! &#8212; Santa Moreau is coming to town!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/12/rudolph-red-nosed-genetically-altered-reindeer-subspecies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3518</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>True story</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=true-story</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2158</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[As you know, I&#8217;m going to be moving back to Calgary in December. The exact timing for that is still being determined, but let&#8217;s just go with the broad stroke: we have a lot of stuff that needs to be done as part of moving back. One of those things &#8212; rather obvious to anyone &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "True story"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you know, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/09/o-canada-my-home-and-native-land/">I&#8217;m going to be moving back to Calgary in December</a>. The exact timing for that is still being determined, but let&#8217;s just go with the broad stroke: we have a lot of stuff that needs to be done as part of moving back.<br />
One of those things &#8212; rather obvious to anyone who&#8217;s ever been responsible for their own utilities &#8212; is making sure that the electricity, gas, and water are put back in our names. And there&#8217;s no time like the present to do the research about services, plans, companies, and so forth.<br />
<span id="more-2158"></span>One obvious choice, at least in Calgary, is <a href="http://www.enmax.com/">Enmax</a>. It&#8217;s a city-owned utility that provides electricity (its original function), water, and has a license to also distribute gas (we&#8217;ll ignore, for the moment, that the &#8220;distribution&#8221; is exceedingly virtualised). I&#8217;ve used Enmax for every house I&#8217;ve lived in (at least within Calgary), and having everything on one bill is a big plus.<br />
Add to that the desire to have green energy, I also wanted to look into their <a href="http://www.enmax.com/greenmax">Greenmax</a> programme, as it&#8217;s something I&#8217;d like to support (at least until I can afford my own solar panels). As I started hunting around in the site, I came across something that made me genuinely laugh:</p>
<blockquote><p>If your mailing address is outside of North America, please contact us at 310-2010 (toll free in Alberta) to verify details.</p></blockquote>
<p>If you&#8217;re wondering why I&#8217;m laughing, it&#8217;s because of the &#8220;310&#8221; number. It doesn&#8217;t work outside of Alberta (at least so far as I know). It&#8217;s also a real misnomer because it doesn&#8217;t include an area code, either. Certainly, there&#8217;s an assumption that you somehow know that Calgary&#8217;s area code is &#8220;403&#8221;, but too much assumption becomes presumption.<br />
At any rate, <a href="http://twitter.com/sowrey/statuses/3809821233">I found this so humourous, I tweeted it</a>. Go on, follow the link. I&#8217;ll wait.<br />
Now you might be wondering what the heck the &#8220;#&#8221; is in that content. If you&#8217;re not familiar with <a href="http://twitter.com/">Twitter</a>, you&#8217;ve probably never seen a hashtag. That&#8217;s what the &#8220;#&#8221; is. <a href="http://hashtags.org/">Hashtags enable someone to search</a> for tweets (a post in Twitter), so they can follow an event, for example. In the case of companies, it&#8217;s handy to flag them specifically.<br />
The &#8220;#fail&#8221;? Well, that&#8217;s a note that something is wrong. Possibly horribly wrong. It&#8217;s half-Twitterese, and half-internet geekery.<br />
Now, I&#8217;d posted that tweet figuring that I&#8217;d never hear anything of it. It&#8217;s one of those things with Twitter &#8212; you expect, if anything, for your friends to make smarmy comments about the things you say and do. (Yes, <a href="http://twitter.com/humantorch">@humantorch</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/jthale">@jthale</a>, and <a href="http://twitter.com/froosh_ca">@froosh_ca</a>, I&#8217;m looking at you. Jerks.)<br />
Well, apparently, Enmax is much further into this internet thing than I was giving them credit for. Someone was watching the <a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23enmax">#enmax hashtag</a>. Someone saw it. And they showed it to their marketing consultant. The marketing consultant&#8230; well&#8230;<br />
He doubled over laughing.<br />
Why?<br />
Because <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/dan-evans/2/81/593">Dan</a> knows me &#8230; very well. (Dan used to be the President of <a href="http://www.criticalmass.com/">Critical Mass</a> &#8212; he&#8217;s now a principal of <a href="http://www.evanshunt.com/">The Evans Hunt Group</a> &#8212; Â and was even my direct boss for a while.)<br />
Dan dropped me a line with the correct 877 number. And I suspect that he had some influence on the copy in Enmax&#8217;s website, because I can&#8217;t find the original quote anymore (it used to be on <a href="https://www.enmax.com/Energy/Res/Moving/Open+new+account.htm">Enmax&#8217;s Sign Up page</a>).<br />
[Insert singing dolls here.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/true-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Los Terribles 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/los-terribles-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=los-terribles-2</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/los-terribles-2/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 19:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2153</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, Monkey, you&#8217;ve hit the period of your life that Mommy and I kind of hoped you&#8217;d side-step. Until recently, you showed every sign of being a Perfect AngelÃ¢â€žÂ¢ and not following lock-step with most other children. But perhaps we were being too naÃƒÂ¯ve, too optimisitic. After all, despite my initial (self-mocking) perspective on your &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/los-terribles-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Los Terribles 2"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, Monkey, you&#8217;ve hit the period of your life that Mommy and I kind of hoped you&#8217;d side-step. Until recently, you showed every sign of being a Perfect AngelÃ¢â€žÂ¢ and not following lock-step with most other children. But perhaps we were being too naÃƒÂ¯ve, too optimisitic. After all, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_8G14u2-4Os">despite my initial (self-mocking) perspective on your conception</a>, you&#8217;ve pretty much blown through every expectation.<br />
In fact, up until a couple of weeks ago, you seemed pretty much hell-bent on being the perfect child. I had visions of you always coming to us for permission to watch TV or use the computer, letting us know the moment you found something on the internet that you shouldn&#8217;t be seeing, letting us know before you go outside to play with your friends, looking for approval before even <em>thinking</em> about dating, letting us help decide where you go for university&#8230;<br />
Well, kiddo, based on your behaviour the last weekend, I&#8217;ll be lucky if you let me watch <em>Backyardigans </em>with you. Yeesh.<br />
<span id="more-2153"></span>Okay, I exaggerate (a little). I know Mommy has a better grasp of all this, but I&#8217;m struggling with your ability shift from angel to demon in a mere breath. For example, the mere suggestion that we need to change your diaper (when you don&#8217;t want it changed) elicits screaming, struggling, and a couple of minutes&#8217; worth of &#8220;mommy!&#8221; crying.<br />
Which, of course, isn&#8217;t really crying, you&#8217;re just being overly dramatic. You&#8217;ve done the Drama Queen thing for &#8230; well, probably over a year now. I can&#8217;t remember when you started exactly, but it&#8217;s pretty obvious: crying, but without tears. It&#8217;s just a desire for intervention. I only ever hear the &#8220;mommy&#8221; version of it, of course. I wonder if Mommy ever hears a &#8220;daddy&#8221; version?<br />
Then there&#8217;s dinner time. While you eat breakfast with the zeal of a vaccum cleaner (most days), and you tend to eat lunch quite well, lately dinner seems to be a battle of wills. We make dinner, and then the screaming starts. It could be because we&#8217;re taking you away from something you&#8217;re playing with, or particularly badly, if you&#8217;re watching TV (which you normally don&#8217;t do before dinner). If you&#8217;re screaming before we put you in your high chair &#8230; well, it&#8217;s a good 10 minutes of you struggling, and crying, and carrying on until you finally calm down and pick at your food. Which, at least in my experience, is the best that we&#8217;ll get.<br />
I should also mention that you&#8217;ll flip back to being an angel the moment you get something you want. (It&#8217;s kind of eerie, actually.)<br />
The funny thing is, I remember being like you. In particular, I remember one July when Nana took me with her to the grocery store at Trafalgar Village. My birthday was coming up (I&#8217;m not sure what year, but I couldn&#8217;t have been older than 5), and I latched onto some tiny, 3cm square Â plastic waffles on strings that <em>had</em> to be in the gift bags for the kids coming to my party. I think Nana nearly lost it, shortly after I threw my tantrum.<br />
So no, I&#8217;m not going to say that you&#8217;re acting &#8220;badly&#8221;. That&#8217;s just not fair. You&#8217;re being human. You&#8217;re starting to define the things you want, in the way you want them. I&#8217;m having trouble with that, because there are things that I want you to do (or eat) that you don&#8217;t want. It&#8217;s the classic battle of the wills. And short of a blender, a feeding tube, and enough rope to keep you tied down, there&#8217;s not a lot I can do about it.<br />
(It&#8217;s a joke. Of course <em>I would never</em> tie my poor darling daughter down for anything. Yeesh. Sickos.)<br />
I hope that, one day, you can forgive your father for his lack of patience. I know this is a learning time for you, and having your parents interrupt your happiness just doesn&#8217;t sit with you. (Like, at all.) But we&#8217;re still going to do things that you hate (even if you don&#8217;t know what &#8220;hate&#8221; is), and we&#8217;re still going to have our little tÃƒÂªte-ÃƒÂ -tÃƒÂªtes.<br />
Just know that there will always be the unconditional love, the endless hugs, the kisses, and the tickling (I&#8217;ll never give up the tickling, just so you know &#8212; I&#8217;ll be 95 years old and still trying to get you to laugh).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/los-terribles-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2153</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WALL-E: What is Disney-Pixar not telling us?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 15:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1933</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I had an epiphany this morning as I waited for my carpool. I don&#8217;t know why it came to me, it just did. I can&#8217;t even remember how I got onto the thought. But as I stood there, I had the clear vision: There are no old people on the Axiom. I&#8217;ve seen WALL-E now &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "WALL-E: What is Disney-Pixar not telling us?"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had an epiphany this morning as I waited for my carpool. I don&#8217;t know why it came to me, it just did. I can&#8217;t even remember how I got onto the thought. But as I stood there, I had the clear vision:<br />
There are no old people on the <em>Axiom</em>.<br />
<span id="more-1933"></span>I&#8217;ve seen <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0910970/">WALL-E</a></em> now about 30 times. That&#8217;s a bit of a guess, mind you. I&#8217;ve seen it not just because it&#8217;s an awesome movie, but because it&#8217;s Monkey&#8217;s favourite thing after the Backyardigans. (She&#8217;ll either ask for &#8220;Ya-yas&#8221; or &#8220;Wally&#8221;, and rarely anything else.) I have no problem when she wants to watch it, so the two of us will sit and watch.<br />
When you watch something enough, you begin to notice little things that had previously escaped notice. And in this case, it came after my mind apparently was chewing away subconsciously. Although Buy &#8216;N Large advertised the Axiom with an eldery woman on a hover chair, 700 years later the <em>Axiom</em> seems devoid of anyone past their 30s. No grey hairs. No wrinkles.<br />
Okay, yes, I&#8217;ll grant you that in their &#8220;big baby&#8221; states, humans might keep their youth longer, but human biology wouldn&#8217;t likely weed out the aging process.<br />
My take?<br />
It&#8217;s a <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074812/">Logan&#8217;s Run</a></em>-meets-<em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070723/">Soylent Green</a></em> thing. When someone turns 30, their hover chair dumps them into into a processor to end up as the next day&#8217;s special. Â Seriously! Did you see any greenhouses? Why is all the food ingested through a straw?<br />
Maybe Pixar should make a really cool darker prequel, where the previous captain discovers the truth, and races through the ship on his hover chair, yelling:</p>
<blockquote><p>Stop eating! Your Sexcentennial Cupcake-In-A-Cup is made of people! <em>IT&#8217;S MADE OF PEOPLE!</em></p></blockquote>
<p>They could even use Charleton Heston&#8217;s voice.<br />
C&#8217;mon, it&#8217;d be great.<br />
Come to think of it&#8230; Did anyone see any children or teenagers, either? Hmm&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/09/wall-e-what-is-disney-pixar-not-telling-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sowrey&#039;s Law</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/sowreys-law/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=sowreys-law</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/sowreys-law/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 01:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murphy's law]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1156</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Your firewall will explode once your (formerly poor) internet connection is stablised. Â  (Tip o&#8217; the hat to Ginger.)]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Your firewall will explode once your (formerly poor) internet connection is stablised. Â </p></blockquote>
<p>(Tip o&#8217; the hat to <a href="http://gingerkoolick.blogspot.com/">Ginger</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/11/sowreys-law/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1156</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Network Connection</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-network-connection</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 18:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1148</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something. Â  For me, it&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Network Connection"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With all the problems we&#8217;ve been having down here, you eventually start to become inspired to find an outlet, a way of bringing forth all your frustrations and desires into a singular vision. For some, it is art, for others it&#8217;s the urge to beat the living crap out of something. Â <br />
For me, it&#8217;s music. Â <br />
<span id="more-1148"></span>Feel free to sing along. I&#8217;m sure <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSFLZ-MzIhM">you know the tune</a>&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Where are there so many drops in our network<br />
Out into the internet?<br />
Our network is simple, really quite basic,<br />
But which I daily reset.<br />
So we&#8217;ve been told by our service provider<br />
We&#8217;ll just have to wait and see.<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me. Â 
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">Who said that ATM was a good system?<br />
Bandwidth gets shared too far.<br />
All it takes is just one jerk to tie up the router<br />
And then you can&#8217;t send your TAR. Â <br />
What&#8217;s so amazing &#8217;bout tech that&#8217;s so aging<br />
When fibre was just meant to be?<br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me. Â 
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">It&#8217;s down whenever it rains,<br />
I think it&#8217;s going to be tragic&#8230;
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">We&#8217;ve been promised fibre for over a month now,<br />
I hope it comes any day.<br />
Then we&#8217;ll surf the internet without an outage,<br />
And upload without delay.<br />
We&#8217;ll have our own servers and not be dependent<br />
On our Calgary family. Â <br />
Someday we&#8217;ll find it, the network connection,<br />
The routers, the servers, and me! Â 
</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">La, la la lee la da do, la aw crap, the friggin&#8217; thing&#8217;s out again&#8230;</p>
<p>With apologies to Paul Williams, Kenneth Ascher, and Kermit the Frog.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/the-network-connection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1148</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Funny things in emails</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=funny-things-in-emails</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=976</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I got into a fairly typical email exchange with Paul, one of our Release Engineers. Since I&#8217;m no longer on Rolex, I wanted to be taken off the email lists. This was how it went down: Me: Hey Paul, Now that Torin&#8217;s running the Tech show, can you pull me from the Rolex Monitoring alias, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Funny things in emails"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got into a fairly typical email exchange with Paul, one of our Release Engineers. Since I&#8217;m no longer on Rolex, I wanted to be taken off the email lists. This was how it went down:<br />
Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hey Paul,<br />
Now that Torin&#8217;s running the Tech show, can you pull me from the Rolex Monitoring alias, please?<br />
*sniff*<br />
Thanks,<br />
G.</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-976"></span>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>No. You will forever get paged.<br />
MUAHH HAHAHAHAHAHA</p></blockquote>
<p>Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>I don&#8217;t get paged. Just emails. And they get dumped into a folder I barely read.<br />
Nyah nyah nyah nyah nyah nyahhhhhhhhhhhhh</p></blockquote>
<p>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>Well since I now control the alias&#8230; and I know your cell number &#8230; well you do the math.</p></blockquote>
<p>Me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Well, since I&#8217;m moving to Costa Rica and you don&#8217;t have my Costa Rican cell number &#8230; go right ahead. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f61b.png" alt="ðŸ˜›" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p></blockquote>
<p>Paul:</p>
<blockquote><p>EPIC FAIL <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f641.png" alt="ðŸ™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/funny-things-in-emails/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">976</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How much of the internet is a waste of time?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/20/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[So the other day, one of my coworkers starts laughing about how there&#8217;s this video out there, two somewhat-scantily clad women with tinfoil-wrapped boxes on their heads, doing a choreographed &#8220;dance&#8221; to Daft Punk&#8217;s Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger. Then it hit me. Someone &#8212; namely these two people &#8212; had to spend a considerable amount &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How much of the internet is a waste of time?"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So the other day, one of my coworkers starts laughing about how there&#8217;s this video out there, two somewhat-scantily clad women with tinfoil-wrapped boxes on their heads, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cva_sGN_0VA">doing a choreographed &#8220;dance&#8221;</a> to Daft Punk&#8217;s <em>Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger</em>.<br />
Then it hit me.<br />
Someone &#8212; namely these two people &#8212; had to spend a considerable amount of time creating this. Thinking up the idea, practising it, filming it (with however many takes to get through the mistakes and undoubted laughter), and editing it.<br />
Then it really hit me.<br />
How much of the stuff out there is a complete waste of time?<br />
<span id="more-912"></span>Maybe this is just me. Lately, I feel as if I&#8217;ve got almost no time at all. I get up, I go to work, run myself ragged all day, sprint home to spend (maybe) 90 minutes with my child before bedtime (including feeding the Wee One while eating myself, and sometimes making dinner), then make up the last couple of hours trying to tie of other things that need doing. And back to bed. Rinse. Repeat.<br />
No video. No fancy dance routines. No costumes. I&#8217;m lucky to listen to music in the spare minutes at work. Where the heck do people get time for this stuff?<br />
Examples that come to mind:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hKoB0MHVBvM">Diet Coke and Mentos</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.icanhascheezburger.com/">LOLCats</a></li>
<li>Let&#8217;s give a conservative estimate of 80% of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/">Youtube</a>, to name but one of many such sites<a href="http://www.youtube.com/"><br />
</a></li>
<li>People who write <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/category/rants/">really long blogs that really mean nothing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>By &#8220;useless&#8221;, I mean &#8220;adding no significant difference to the advancement of human knowledge&#8221;. Given, my definition. But the point&#8217;s the same: how much of the stuff out there on the &#8216;net is actually useful?<br />
For the record, I count myself in the list of useless &#8212; most of this website (with a few <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2006/08/15/calgary-transit-sucks/">notable</a> <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2004/04/27/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/">exceptions</a>, which seem to regularly show up on the popular posts lists) is useless. (It could even be argued that most of my job is useless by the same token, but I&#8217;m not going to go there right now, since that will get me very depressed.)<br />
So, the question is asked, and I&#8217;m curious to know what others think: How much is useless?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">912</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>80th Oscars</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/80th-oscars/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=80th-oscars</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/80th-oscars/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 05:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academy awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/02/24/80th-oscars/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, the annual Oscars show has come and gone again. And I almost missed it this time! It was by mere fluke that I happened to come across the E-Talk Red Carpet pre-show tonight. If I hadn&#8217;t caught it during a brief pause in my harried running around, I might have missed the show. Not &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/80th-oscars/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "80th Oscars"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, the annual Oscars show has come and gone again. And I almost missed it this time! It was by mere fluke that I happened to come across the E-Talk Red Carpet pre-show tonight. If I hadn&#8217;t caught it during a brief pause in my harried running around, I might have missed the show.<br />
Not that I really would have missed much, admittedly. I have to admit, it was one of the more boring years.<br />
<span id="more-904"></span>Jon Stewart is a good host, but I really do miss the years like with Billy Crystal. Corny as it sounds, a good musical opening number that pokes fun at the biz was always interesting to watch.<br />
There were a few surprises, but all-in-all no shockers. I feel kind of bad for George Clooney, though. I&#8217;m sure he did a great job in <em>Michael Clayton</em> (haven&#8217;t seen it yet), but you have to wonder if he swore a blue streak when he saw Daniel Day-Lewis&#8217; name show up on the nomination. I mean, that&#8217;s just gotta suck.<br />
I miss the old days, where people weren&#8217;t confined to two minutes of talking time, where the presenters would do political postulation, where the outfits were outrageous (<em>cough</em>Cher<em>cough</em>), and the show was almost more about spectacle than self-congratulations.<br />
But hey, this might be my last watched Oscars for a while. Life has a way of getting in the way of traditions, and probably the only reason I watched this year was because Alex and the Wee One were out of town. Next year will definitely be different.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/02/80th-oscars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">904</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dirty Jobs Drinking Game</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 19:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/12/06/the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Everyone thinks their job sucks. It can be for any number of reasons. But there&#8217;s one guy out there who looks for the dirty jobs. The ones that no-one really wants to do, but does anyway. The ones where if the job wasn&#8217;t done, the world would (in many cases) come to a halt. They&#8217;re &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Dirty Jobs Drinking Game"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone thinks their job sucks. It can be for any number of reasons. But there&#8217;s one guy out there who looks for the dirty jobs. The ones that no-one really wants to do, but does anyway. The ones where if the job wasn&#8217;t done, the world would (in many cases) come to a halt. They&#8217;re dangerous, often nauseating, and usually done by people far more interesting than we&#8217;d ever believe.<br />
That&#8217;s what <a href="http://www.discovery.com/">Discovery Channel</a>&#8216;s <em><a href="http://dsc.discovery.com/fansites/dirtyjobs/dirtyjobs.html">Dirty Jobs</a></em> is all about. If you haven&#8217;t watched it, <a href="http://dsc.discovery.com/video/index.html?playerId=203711706&amp;categoryId=210013706&amp;lineupId=935463420">you really should check it out</a>. It&#8217;s one of the few decent things on television, and one of only three shows that I&#8217;ll go out of my way to watch (the other two being Dirty Jobs&#8217; sibling, <em><a href="http://dsc.discovery.com/fansites/mythbusters/mythbusters.html">Mythbusters</a></em>, and <a href="http://abc.go.com/primetime/pushingdaisies/">ABC&#8217;s <em>Pushing Daisies</em></a>).<br />
But there&#8217;s something about Dirty Jobs&#8217; host, <a href="http://dsc.discovery.com/fansites/dirtyjobs/bio/bio.html">Mike Rowe</a>, and the way he handles the content of the show, that really adds another layer. Namely, poo.<br />
<span id="more-869"></span>If you&#8217;ve seen the show, you know what I&#8217;m talking about. And to that end, you might have thought the same thing Alex thought of: there really needs to be a drinking game behind all this. So we bring you our version of the Dirty Jobs Drinking Game. (There is <a href="http://kwc.org/blog/archives/2006/2006-09-07.dirty_jobs_drinking_game.html">one other I know of</a>, but I wanted to add some complication to it &#8212; what&#8217;s the point of having a drinking game if it&#8217;s easy to do?)</p>
<h4>The Rules</h4>
<ol>
<li>Something alcoholic is preferred, but you can go with pop (soda) or chocolate milk if you have to. Otherwise, it&#8217;s just not as funny.</li>
<li>No pausing the show to drink. If things come fast and furious, you need to keep up. So keep a good stock of liquids at the ready.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t pre-watch the episode. That&#8217;s just taking the fun out of it. Repeats are fine, since few have actually memorised anything. (And after running through this, you&#8217;ll likely want to forget it anyway.)</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re the last one standing, you&#8217;ve got a Dirty Job of your own. But don&#8217;t call Mike &#8212; I&#8217;m pretty sure he&#8217;ll pass.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Drinking Definitions</h4>
<ul>
<li>Drink &#8211; a sip of wine or hard alcohol, swig of beer</li>
<li>Shot &#8211; 1/3 glass of wine, shot glass of hard alcohol, 8 oz beer (technically over 1/2 a North American bottle, but 1/2 will do for ease-of-comparison)</li>
<li>Chug &#8211; a glass of wine, 3 shots of hard alcohol, a complete beer (yes, this seems somewhat lighter on the beer crowd, but that carbonation does pack a wallop)</li>
</ul>
<h4>The Conditions</h4>
<p>This is broken down not just by amount to drink, but by what&#8217;s said/going on. You&#8217;ll understand why after your third beer&#8230;</p>
<h5>What Mike Says</h5>
<p>Drink when:</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;I&#8217;m Mike Rowe&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Poo&#8221;</li>
<li>Any derivative of &#8220;poo&#8221; (e.g. &#8220;crap&#8221;)</li>
<li>Says &#8220;You&#8217;ve never seen the show, have you?&#8221; when someone suggests that whatever Mike&#8217;s about to do is easy/routine</li>
<li>Makes a derogatory comment about his (in)ability to use a piece of equipment that he&#8217;s used in a previous episode</li>
<li>Makes a comment about his own crew</li>
<li>&#8220;You&#8217;re a dirty man/woman&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Shot when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Swears</li>
<li>Make a comment about the size of tools/equipment used by someone he&#8217;s working with</li>
<li>Makes a comment about Dave, the producer</li>
<li>&#8220;I love this job&#8221;</li>
<li>Makes a comment about needing to take a shower at the hotel that evening</li>
</ul>
<p>Chug when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Screams/yells as a result of being &#8220;attacked&#8221; by vermin</li>
<li>Uses a swear in lieu of &#8220;poo&#8221; (e.g. &#8220;shit&#8221;)</li>
</ul>
<h5>What Mike Does</h5>
<p>Drink when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Conned into eating something that&#8217;s edible, but not necessarily ideal (e.g. raw oysters, cow feed)</li>
<li>Has to catch/trap an animal</li>
</ul>
<p>Shot when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Falls into/onto poo (manure, guano, cowpies)</li>
<li>Loses some article of clothing as a result of what he&#8217;s doing (e.g. footwear, hat)</li>
<li>Eats something that while technically edible, not even the workers around him would touch (e.g. crab meal)</li>
<li>Sings</li>
<li>Is scared to death of trying to catch/trap the animal</li>
<li>Has to collect semen samples (double if the animal is bigger than Mike)</li>
<li>Has to insert his finger/hand/arm to determine sex or otherwise &#8220;assist&#8221; a natural process</li>
<li>Gets visibly ill, but without actually up-chucking</li>
</ul>
<p>Chug when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Eats poo (accidentally, often due to flinging or splattering)</li>
<li>Sings the Dirty Jobs theme song (yes, there is one)</li>
<li>Vomits (only done this once that I&#8217;ve seen)</li>
</ul>
<h5>What Happens to Mike</h5>
<p>Drink when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gets sprayed with something (e.g. water, mud, concrete) but not poo</li>
<li>Gets hit by a piece of equipment</li>
</ul>
<p>Shot when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gets bitten/pinched by an animal (double if it draws blood)</li>
<li>Gets hit with poo</li>
<li>Gets spat on by an animal</li>
<li>Gets stuck in the ground he&#8217;s walking on (double if the ground is made of poo)</li>
</ul>
<p>Chug when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gets poo&#8217;d on by an animal</li>
</ul>
<h5>What Happens to Those Around Mike</h5>
<p>Drink when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mike gets upstaged by the guide/guest/demonstrator</li>
<li>Crew appears on screen</li>
</ul>
<p>Shot when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mike gets upstaged by a kid</li>
<li>Crew gets more than just a passing mention, including being heard on-camera</li>
<li>Crew nearly gets hit by something Mike is doing</li>
<li>Equipment is damaged/destroyed (double)</li>
<li>Mike intentionally trips/fells one of the crew</li>
</ul>
<p>Chug when:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mike gets upstaged by an animal</li>
<li>Crew is in an accident, with damage/destruction to equipment</li>
</ul>
<h4>And Finally</h4>
<p>Because poo seems to play such a large part of things that happens on Dirty Jobs, any time the word &#8220;poo&#8221; is mentioned (especially by Mike), not only follow the conditions above, but you must also yell &#8220;POO&#8221;!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/the-dirty-jobs-drinking-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">869</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
