<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cats &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/cats/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 13:20:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>T-minus one week and counting</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/t-minus-one-week-and-counting/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=t-minus-one-week-and-counting</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/t-minus-one-week-and-counting/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 13:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One week from &#8230; well, right now, our plane leaves Juan Santamaria Airport, bound for Houston. If all our cards fall into place (which, so far, they are &#8212; I just hope they keep falling!), we&#8217;ll leave in good order. We&#8217;re not perfect yet, but we&#8217;re getting there. The biggest point, really, is still the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/t-minus-one-week-and-counting/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "T-minus one week and counting"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One week from &#8230; well, right now, our plane leaves Juan Santamaria Airport, bound for Houston. If all our cards fall into place (which, so far, they are &#8212; I just hope they keep falling!), we&#8217;ll leave in good order. We&#8217;re not perfect yet, but we&#8217;re getting there.<br />
The biggest point, really, is still the car. Sigh. <span id="more-2245"></span>Our list now looks like this:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Cancel our CableTica service</span></li>
<li>Sell our car (currently trying, and having no luck at all)</li>
<li>&#8220;Cancel&#8221; our phone (aka give it back to the company)</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Pack up the stuff we&#8217;re taking with us on the plane</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Have the rest of our stuff packed and shipped by slow banana boat (and I&#8217;m not really kidding about that &#8212; it probably is a banana boat)</span> (Technically not done yet, but this starts in about 40 minutes.)</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Arrange for our utilities in Calgary (gas, electricity, water)</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Organise the times/dates for moving our stuff out of storage and back into our house</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Arrange for plane tickets</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Arrange for hotels for moving (we have to stay at least one night in CR and one night in Calgary), and it they have to take cats</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Get a rental car</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Then buy a car in Calgary</span> (technically not done yet, but we&#8217;ve found a car and made arrangements with the dealer, and could buy it as soon as we arrive)</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Figure out how to get what money we&#8217;ve managed to save up north so we don&#8217;t try carrying it across the border (read: bad idea)</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Arrange for documentation to prove that we can take our daughter out of Costa Rica (no, I&#8217;m not kidding &#8212; Temporary Residents need this for some bizarre reason, even if both parents are present)</span></li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Make sure we can get our cat back into Canada (read: find all the documentation we had from 18 months ago)</span></li>
<li>Clean our apartment top-to-bottom</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Give away what we&#8217;re not taking back to friends (and other organisations)</span></li>
<li>Say &#8220;goodbye&#8221; to the people we&#8217;ve come to know very well over the last year and a half (this is going to truly suck)</li>
<li><span style="text-decoration: line-through">Make sure we have clothes that are cold-weather appropriate (at least until all of our other clothing is out of storage)</span></li>
</ul>
<p>This list is looking much better than it did a week ago. That&#8217;s not to say it came easily. There&#8217;s way too much stress involved with organising a relocation company that doesn&#8217;t seem to talk to itself or offer appropriate customer service (in my opinion, anyway). All part of the &#8220;fun&#8221;, though, right?<br />
Oh, and <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/">we&#8217;ve also had to get more documentation for the cat</a>,which we hadn&#8217;t been aware of. Thankfully, living here has made us realise that if you&#8217;re doing something without official government approval, chances are you&#8217;re doing it wrong.<br />
(Oh, and if you&#8217;re looking at this on Facebook and thinking it looks like there&#8217;s nothing done, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2009/11/t-minus-one-week-and-counting/">check out the original</a>. Facebook drops the formatting.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/12/t-minus-one-week-and-counting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2245</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking a pet from Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 20:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It figures, just when we thought we&#8217;d started to have everything figured out, we hit another snag. (There&#8217;s always another snag.) This time, it&#8217;s with Asia, our cat. Our problem is not with Canada &#8212; all they need is a valid rabies vaccination, which we have. Our problem is not our airline (Continental) &#8212; we &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Taking a pet from Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It figures, just when we thought we&#8217;d started to have everything figured out, we hit another snag. (There&#8217;s always another snag.) This time, it&#8217;s with Asia, our cat.<br />
Our problem is not with Canada &#8212; all they need is a valid rabies vaccination, which we have. Our problem is not our airline (Continental) &#8212; we already have a reservation that allows us to take our cat. Our problem is with Costa Rica.<br />
I&#8217;m so not surprised.<br />
<span id="more-2243"></span>It hit us about a week or so ago that merely leaving the country with Asia wasn&#8217;t just a matter of having the airline say a pet was okay. There was the matter if we had documentation saying that she was okay. Wendy, our super-awesome travel agent, managed to find out that Continental needed a letter from a vet saying that Asia was fit to fly. No biggie.<br />
So Alex trucked over to the veterinarian (conveniently located at the front of our condo complex) to get that sorted out. That&#8217;s when the complications came in. It wasn&#8217;t just as simple as a letter from the vet. Oh, no, that would be too easy. How quickly we forgot how much Costa Rica loves its bureaucracy!  (Keep in mind that it took us over a year to get our temporary residency.)<br />
No, to leave Costa Rica means that we need to have an export permit to take Asia. Export. Like she&#8217;s a Costa Rican product or something. This isn&#8217;t quite as bad as the fact that we also had to get a similar legal document so we could leave with our two year-old daughter! (That one has me at a level of disbelief that I can&#8217;t even fathom.)<br />
[Insert rising panic here.]<br />
This is not something you want to discover with a mere 11 days (now 10) remaining until you leave. Down here, things never happen quickly, and the word &#8220;urgent&#8221; (as spoken by a North American) never translates well.<br />
Alex got the vet started on getting us a certificate, which could take &#8212; and I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; a week. This could get uuuuugly. We don&#8217;t have the luxury of delaying even a single day going home. We have too many things lined up to start the morning after we arrive, and the balls are already well in motion. I&#8217;m not saying we&#8217;re going to abandon Asia here (we&#8217;re not, just to make that abundantly clear), but it&#8217;s not going to make me in any way happy if things don&#8217;t go according to plan.<br />
We even went through calling 10 different hotels before we could find one that would allow pets of any kind. That&#8217;s enough of an annoying snag. This current one is borderline catastrophic. (CATastrophic. Cat. Get it? Ha!)<br />
I hate moving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/11/taking-a-pet-from-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to bring a pet into Costa Rica: Simplified</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, so a while back I was having kittens (pun intended) about bringing Asia into Costa Rica. Mostly because I simply could not seem to get a straight answer from anyone about the proper process. It was driving me batty. So, to anyone bringing in their (small) dog or cat (this might also work for &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to bring a pet into Costa Rica: Simplified"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so a while back I was having kittens (pun intended) about bringing Asia into Costa Rica. Mostly because I simply could not seem to get a straight answer from anyone about the proper process. <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/">It was driving me batty.</a><br />
So, to anyone bringing in their (small) dog or cat (this might also work for rabbits, but don&#8217;t expect success with gerbils or hamsters or any form of rodent; and it&#8217;s a one-way trip for all birds, you can&#8217;t take them out again) into Costa Rica, allow me to present the (current) process. It&#8217;s really easy.<br />
<span id="more-1005"></span></p>
<ol>
<li>Check with your government&#8217;s agricultural agency (the Ministry of Agriculture in Canada, for example) and find the International Health Certificate. (There is an American equivalent from the Department of Agriculture, but I&#8217;m not sure what it&#8217;s called.) Print it out.</li>
<li>Go to your vet, and ensure that your cat/dog has all their most recent vaccinations. Get documentation about all of it. It&#8217;s important, you&#8217;ll need it when you arrive. You&#8217;ll also need the vet to fill out the specifics of the aforementioned International Health Certificate, which they also need to sign.</li>
<li>In Canada (I can&#8217;t say for certain with the United States), you&#8217;ll need to schedule an appointment with the Ministry of Agriculture to have them sign the document as well, and stamp it to make it official. This is necessary &#8212; without this form, your pet will not be joining you.</li>
<li>Bring the pet with you on the plane in a carrier that fits under the seat. Not all airlines will do this anymore &#8212; Continental Airlines still does. Air Canada does not. This way, you can be assured that the pet is with you when you arrive, and does not go automatically into quarantine.</li>
<li>When you arrive in customs, you need to go to the Agricultura desk (it&#8217;s easy to see) and have them look over the papers. Provided you are not bringing the animal in for resale (e.g. it&#8217;s not merchandise), it&#8217;s a quick stamp, a scribble in the register, and you&#8217;re free to go &#8212; no duty required.</li>
</ol>
<p>Notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>If your pet does not fit under the seat and/or must travel cargo (with you on the same flight), the process might be the same, provided you can collect your pet with your luggage. I&#8217;m not sure, as I didn&#8217;t see any other pets there.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;re bringing in animals for resale, expect to pay a duty.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/how-to-bring-a-pet-into-costa-rica-simplified/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1005</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enroute with the cat</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=enroute-with-the-cat</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 20:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, we&#8217;re on our way. I was up until almost midnight last night packing. Was originally thinking three bags, but went down to two. Which is good, because apparently I&#8217;d have been denied the third bag. As it stands, the backpack was overweight by three lousy pounds, so I got stuck with an extra bag &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Enroute with the cat"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, we&#8217;re on our way. I was up until almost midnight last night packing. Was originally thinking three bags, but went down to two. Which is good, because apparently I&#8217;d have been denied the third bag. As it stands, the backpack was overweight by three lousy pounds, so I got stuck with an extra bag fee and an overweight fee.<br />
Where the heck did all these fees come from? It even costs me $100 to get the cat on the plane. Three and a half hours later, I&#8217;m in Houston, with a cat in a bag. Tried letting her out at the &#8220;Pet Relief Area&#8221; over in Terminal B, but all she wanted to do was hide in the tropical plants. I&#8217;m not even sure if she relieved herself at all.<br />
Lunch was at Ruby&#8217;s, while Asia watched people go by. She&#8217;s been exceedingly good, and hasn&#8217;t had one freak-out as a result of all this. Whether or not she&#8217;s still in one piece when we get to our hotel in Costa Rica is another question.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/enroute-with-the-cat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1003</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bringing my cat into Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re bringing Asia with us. Not the continent; she&#8217;s our cat. We don&#8217;t want to part with her. She&#8217;s a wonderful pet and truly part of the family. She was our first baby before Mi Niña Pequeña came along. Giving her up is just not an option. Getting her through the border is the trouble. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Bringing my cat into Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re bringing Asia with us. Not the continent; <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2142575972/in/set-72157603438169851/">she&#8217;s our cat</a>. We don&#8217;t want to part with her. She&#8217;s a wonderful pet and truly part of the family. She was our first baby before Mi Niña Pequeña came along. Giving her up is just not an option.<br />
Getting her through the border is the trouble. Mostly because there is no de facto source of information on how this is done properly. What I have found is confusing and very contradictory. For someone who is going to be spending 12 hours with an annoyed kitteh (LOLCat spelling) &#8212; she might be stuck in that cage the entire time &#8212; I need to know that getting into the country isn&#8217;t going to kill her.<br />
Or me.<br />
<span id="more-982"></span>On <a href="http://www.sailcharbonneau.com/Sailing%20With%20Pets/QuarantineImport.htm">three</a> <a href="http://www.costarica.com/Trip-Planning/Travelers-Info/Pets%10Animals/">separate</a> <a href="http://www.costarica.com/Blog/2006_09_01_archive.html">pages</a>, I found that it really boils down to needing the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>A pet health certificate (that includes the original rabies vaccination document) provided by my vet, and signed by (in Canada, anyway) the Ministry of Agriculture.</li>
<li>A personal letter stating the value of my cat. (Highly debatable, since Asia was a stray, and her &#8220;value&#8221; was the adoption fee.) I think this is mostly if you went out of country to buy a pet, then came back in.</li>
<li>Proof of payment of the Pet Customs Duty. This is related to the previous item (I think), and is not always applicable.</li>
<li>A Pet Quarantine Permit issued by the Ministerio de Agricultura y Ganaderia (Ministry of Agriculture and Animal Control).</li>
</ul>
<p>The last one is the catch. Apparently, you can&#8217;t get that unless you&#8217;re in Costa Rica. But you need the papers from your vet to get the permit. And you can&#8217;t get the pet through the border without the permit. Seems very chicken-and-egg in nature (segue: &#8220;chicken and egg&#8221; is a bad metaphor; the egg came first, long before the chicken evolved).<br />
Colour me worried.<br />
So I did more digging, including calling Javier in Costa Rica to ask him. I figured he&#8217;d gone through this with the three gorgeous dogs that he has. Turns out, I was right, but he did it differently, where he shipped the dog in. And the above applies. He had a friend, however, who flew back with a puppy.<br />
Turns out that if you fly with your pet, all you should really need is the documentation from your vet, and signed by the appropriate animal control authority (the Ministry of Agriculture, in my case). Within 10 days of travelling, of course.<br />
All I have to do now is figure out if I can actually get down there with Asia on-board. I suppose in the worst-case scenario, she ends up in a quarantine for a little while. I would really hope to avoid that, though.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/bringing-my-cat-into-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">982</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
