<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>rainforests &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/rainforests/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 18:01:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>14 things I love about Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 18:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainforests]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1103</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Well, I&#8217;ve been in Costa for nearly two straight months now &#8212; this is the longest continuous time I&#8217;ve ever spent outside of Canada &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s high time to answer the two most often-asked questions that I get: What do I like about Costa Rica, and what do I hate? I&#8217;ll answer &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "14 things I love about Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&#8217;ve been in Costa for nearly two straight months now &#8212; this is the longest continuous time I&#8217;ve ever spent outside of Canada &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s high time to answer the two most often-asked questions that I get: What do I like about Costa Rica, and what do I hate?<br />
I&#8217;ll answer the latter in <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/17-things-i-hate-about-costa-rica/">a separate post</a>, but like all reviews, there&#8217;s reason to start with the positive stuff. Of course, these are not in any order whatsoever &#8212; they&#8217;re just as they come to mind.</p>
<h3><span id="more-1103"></span>The Food</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to go to any country and not enjoy eating differently than you do where you came from. Much of the food here is Spanish-influenced (kind of obvious), but draws heavily on Peruvian, Mexican, American (you wouldn&#8217;t believe the number of KFC outlets here), Italian, and then a hodge-podge of other cuisines. There&#8217;s a lot more seafood, especially when you&#8217;re on the coasts, and healthy portions of chicken and beef. And fresh fruit.<br />
It&#8217;s not spicy, but there is a fair bit of fat as a result of oils, which is sometimes a bit hard to get by. But it&#8217;s fairly easy to avoid the deep-fried stuff.</p>
<h3>Fresh Fruit</h3>
<p>The biggest problem in Calgary when it comes to fruit is getting it fresh. And I mean <em>fresh</em>, as in the originating farm is less than 100 kms away. And here, it&#8217;s probably less than 10 kms. I&#8217;ve never had pineapple this fresh, papaya that is outstanding, and absolutely wonderful strawberries. And unlike back in Canada, there is no &#8220;season&#8221; &#8212; you get this fruit year-round.</p>
<h3>The Beer&#8230;</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s no Big Rock, no Sleemans, and certainly no Guinness. But in this heat, lighter beers are much more appreciated, anyway. Especially when they&#8217;re cheap. Your average bottle of Imperial (the most popular beer in Costa Rica) is 4.8% alcohol (by volume) and costs less than a dollar at the store. How can you go wrong with that?!</p>
<h3>&#8230; And Getting It Anywhere</h3>
<p>And wine, and liquor. No stupid rules like back in Canada &#8212; the grocery stores sell beer right next to the legs of lamb. Like it should be. The only place in Canada you can do that is in Quebec, which is a real shame as the heavy restructions on alcohol are likely part of the reason why people drink &#8212; it&#8217;s a taboo, rather than a normal part of life.<br />
The only place you can&#8217;t get any alcohol is at the football games. It&#8217;s an absolute no-no, and searches for booze are pretty strict on entrance. But then, we North Americans aren&#8217;t used to seeing riot police in regular attendance, either.</p>
<h3>Year-Round Green</h3>
<p>A note on the weather: to a Canuck, the seasons don&#8217;t change much in Costa Rica. It goes from warm and dry to warm and wet. (Or hot and wet to hot and dry, or just plain hot and wet, depending on where you are in the country.) People here start to haul out jackets when the sun goes down, but I wear shorts as much as I can (only the air conditioning at the office makes me think otherwise) and I almost always wear sandals.<br />
The heat, combined with the plentiful rain, means the leaves never fall from the trees, so the trees stay green year-round. (There is one tree I&#8217;ve seen that is losing its leaves, but there seem to be new green ones sprouting already.)</p>
<h3>Costa Rican Coffee</h3>
<p>Okay, I don&#8217;t drink coffee &#8212; yet (I&#8217;m determined to try, soon), but all I have to do is smell it to know the coffee here is outstanding. But this is also a coffee-growing country, so you have to expect it. All I do know is that Alex, Mark, and Jason have all raved about the coffee.<br />
And yes, when I do get around to having my first cup of joe, I&#8217;ll be documenting it. You folks don&#8217;t wanna miss that&#8230;</p>
<h3>The Beaches and the Ocean</h3>
<p>We are about 90-100 kms from a the beach. Not just any beach &#8212; a <em>good </em>beach. Given, that 100 kms takes about 2.5 hours to drive, thanks to the rather poor road situation here (see <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/09/17-things-i-hate-about-costa-rica/">the  Hate list</a> for more info). The ocean is also warm, like a nice warm bath. Not like the oceans on either side of Canada, which will deliver a pretty decent chill up your spine, no matter what time of year it is.</p>
<h3>Rainforests</h3>
<p>There is nothing like walking under the thick canopies, listening to countless birds, monkeys, insects, and who-knows-what-else while rain trickles down from above. That is, if you can get past the creepy-crawly things that live there. Not everyone can hack the spiders, snakes, huge beetles, millipedes, and mosquitoes. Personally, I love it. The closest I&#8217;ve come are the coastal forests in British Columbia. But these are, well, foreign to me, and offer such a different experience.</p>
<h3>The Birds</h3>
<p>I&#8217;m used to magpies (which I hate), robins, sparrows, crows, hawks, and if I&#8217;m really lucky, we might get some finches. All fairly typical of western Canada.<br />
Down here? Buzzards, toucans, birds of nearly every colour, and songs that we&#8217;ve never heard and that seem to change nearly every day. This is something I never tire of.</p>
<h3>Crickets</h3>
<p>I grew up with crickets chirping out my window at night. Alberta is devoid of crickets. Or at least where I am, there aren&#8217;t any to be heard. Once again, when the screen door is open (which is most nights), I can hear not only the chirping, but also the croaking of frogs out in the lago.</p>
<h3>Monkeys!!!</h3>
<p>I love monkeys. (Yeah, probably because I&#8217;m related to them. I&#8217;ve heard the joke. Next&#8230;) It is very easy to find wild monkeys in Costa Rica. Howlers are easy to hear at a distance, and if you&#8217;re lucky <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/2774164871/">you&#8217;ll be chased by capuchins looking for a banana</a>.</p>
<h3>Relaxed Environment</h3>
<p>No-one really rushes here. The insane drive that most North Americans are attuned to doesn&#8217;t exist down here. There is no urgency (which is also not a good thing), no heavy pressure, and a much more laid-back attitude. While you might hate it at first, you slowly get sucked into it. It&#8217;s actually nice, once you get used to it.</p>
<h3>Storms</h3>
<p>It rains here nearly every day (we&#8217;re in the rainy season at the moment), sometimes for a few minutes, sometimes for hours. But at least once a week, we get a good thunderstorm. A rip-snorting one that rattles windows and knocks out power. I grew up to those kinds of storms, too, and Calgary just doesn&#8217;t get good thunderstorms.</p>
<h3>Extreme Friendliness</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to find someone who&#8217;s a real jerk. (And you know it when you do!) Most people here smile on mere gaze, and if you&#8217;re carrying a cute baby (like we regularly do), you&#8217;ll have people walk right up to you and chat you right up as if you&#8217;re a local. They&#8217;ll even ask to pick your child up and show it off to whomever&#8217;s around. It&#8217;s a little odd, but it&#8217;s still a wonderful thing.</p>
<h3>Things You Won&#8217;t See On The Hate List</h3>
<p>These are things I don&#8217;t hate, but perhaps not necessarily love. Still, they&#8217;re worth calling out because &#8212; believe it or not &#8212; I&#8217;ve been asked about all of them.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rain. Believe it or not, I actually don&#8217;t mind it here. It&#8217;s not cold, and even in the heaviest part of the year (which we&#8217;re in), it&#8217;s not really terrible as one might think.</li>
<li>Heat. I don&#8217;t dig heat, I admit that. But I&#8217;m acclimatising. I don&#8217;t sweat (as much) and I don&#8217;t complain about the heat (as much).</li>
<li>Lack of skilled help. This should drive me crazy, given that I need to find skilled help, but in the end I&#8217;m actually looking forward to the training aspect</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/14-things-i-love-about-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1103</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekend in Punta Leona</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=weekend-in-punta-leona</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 23:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puntarenas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainforests]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1026</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I had promised Alex that the second weekend we were in Costa Rica would be spent away from our apartment. I just had to find the right place to go. So I spent a fair bit of time working out the location, time to get to the location (because any estimates of travel time here &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Weekend in Punta Leona"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had promised Alex that the second weekend we were in Costa Rica would be spent away from our apartment. I just had to find the right place to go. So I spent a fair bit of time working out the location, time to get to the location (because any estimates of travel time here are usually way off once you leave the #1), cost, and whether or not they had massages.<br />
Yes, that is a consideration in her (and hence my) world.<br />
In the end, I decided on Punta Leona. This would be our first surprise weekend in Costa Rica, and it would seem the first surprise weekend in &#8212; we fear &#8212; two years! Turned out to be not too bad.<br />
<span id="more-1026"></span>I ducked out of work a couple of hours early on Friday. I knew the trip was going to be about two hours, and I also knew the traffic going through Lindora (where our current office is) tends to be pretty evil towards the end of the day. I zipped home, packed up the remaining parts that weren&#8217;t already packed, and the three of us took to the road.<br />
Getting to the highway &#8212; the Panamerican highway #1 &#8212; takes about 30 minutes from where we are in traffic. It&#8217;s far from a straight route. Once we got to the highway, we still had to contend with a bit of traffic between where we got on (near CervecerÃƒ ­a Costa Rica S.A. &#8212; CCR, which makes Imperial beer) and the airport (there&#8217;s a traffic light) and a couple of areas where the highway narrows to a single lane as you head west.<br />
By this point, Alex was already well into the game of rhyming off places that we could go. Normally, when we did this back in Canada, she was much better at it. But Alex isn&#8217;t attuned to Costa Rican geography yet (nor am I, for the record), so the game wasn&#8217;t as lively as usual.<br />
We drove until we got to Highway 3, which heads to Atenas. This is the &#8220;fastest&#8221; route to Jaco, which is the destination often used to help guide people.<br />
If you look on the map, <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=+Costa+Rica&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=9.841686,-84.460831&amp;spn=0.372773,0.478592&amp;z=11">the road from the junction of the #1 and the #3 all the way down to Punta Leona</a> looks reasonably nice. A little curvy in a few places, but overall nice. It&#8217;s about as misleading as a cigarette salesman. The road is 74 kilometres, packed into a straight-line distance of about 50 kilometres. That&#8217;s how much it weaves. The curves are tight, the valleys are deep, having a manual transmission is a God-send, and all the little one-lane bridges slow you down.<br />
The information to find Punta Leona suggested (look for the sign, you can&#8217;t miss it). Well, folks, at dusk it&#8217;s pretty darn easy to miss the sign. It was almost dark by the time we got there (in just over two hours, I should add), and the massive PUNTA LEONA sign isn&#8217;t lit at that point. It&#8217;s not a town &#8212; it&#8217;s a resort.<br />
This threw me a little. I thought Punta Leona was a town, and the hotel was a resort in the town. Nope. It&#8217;s its own little world. Security is high (you need to have a reservation or invitation to come in after 5pm), and it&#8217;s isolated. The drive from the front gate on the highway all the way down to the hotel area is 15 minutes through bamboo forests and the jungle.<br />
Yes, jungle.<br />
Punta Leona is built into a rainforest. It&#8217;s one of the neatest things I&#8217;ve yet seen for a hotel. It&#8217;s a resort &#8212; a timeshare, so far as I can tell &#8212; and the construction puts it very close to two beaches: Playa Mantas and Playa Blanca. Technically, you can&#8217;t own a beach in Costa Rica (that&#8217;s what I understand), so Punta Leona still has to provide access to the beaches &#8212; they&#8217;re public property.<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña was beyond hungry. Over two hours in a car was more than enough for her, and she wanted out. Alex had to get into the back seat for the last 1/3 of the trip to try and keep the wee one happy. By the time we&#8217;d turned off the highway and were driving down the 15 minutes of road, it was just &#8220;GET ME OUTTA HERE&#8221;.<br />
Jungle everywhere, but almost impossible to see. It was dark, and in the jungle, it gets dark quickly. We checked in, got our key and tried to go directly to dinner. But the restaurant doesn&#8217;t open until 19:00, so we opted to put everything in the room first. By the time we were done, the restaurant was open. I think we were the first to arrive.<br />
The next morning, we finally got a good look at our little slice of heaven. We stayed in the Selvamor suites, which are little huts amidst the giant rainforest trees. After a bite of breakfast and a nap (for the baby, not us), we wandered down to the pool area for a morning of splashing around.<br />
I should note that this is the baby splashing around, not us. She doesn&#8217;t know how to swim yet, and isn&#8217;t in water wings just yet. So she needs us to keep her head above water.<br />
We returned to the buffet for lunch, as we didn&#8217;t really have anything for Mi Pequeña Niña to eat. The afternoon was much slower, with another nap, and some wandering around for Alex and I. (Yes, we leave our child in the room to sleep alone. The door is locked, and we&#8217;re very confident in the way she sleeps.) We ended up being caught in a tropical downpour.<br />
Before dinner, we drove out to Playa Blanca (walking there would have taken well over an hour) to watch the sunset. Sadly, the weather was against us and there was no sun to be seen. It would appear we have to wait a while longer before we can see another fantastic Costa Rican sunset again. It won&#8217;t be long, I&#8217;m sure.<br />
At dinner, we met a rather interesting couple from &#8212; of all places &#8212; Calgary, who were on their 12th time visiting Costa Rica. Mi Pequeña Niña, as with every meal it seems, attracted attention from virtually every restaurant staff and from most of the nearby tables. There&#8217;s something about a blonde-haired, blue-eyed baby that doesn&#8217;t stop smiling that seems to get people happy.<br />
Punta Leona, as I&#8217;ve already said, is surrounded by jungle. This includes all the jungle creatures that live there, including leaf-cutter ants, a couple kinds of raccoons (one of which looks like a slightly longer version of the one we&#8217;re most familiar with back in Canada), all sorts of birds, squirrels, and supposedly monkeys (but we didn&#8217;t see or hear any).<br />
It&#8217;s also filled with stupid tourists who feed those animals human food. That bothered me a lot. I hate it when it happens in Canada, and there&#8217;s stiff penalties for doing it. Here? Well, it&#8217;s a blind-eye situation.<br />
Following breakfast the next morning, I zipped back out to Playa Blanca to get some pictures in the daylight, while Alex and the Wee One went to the playground. Then the three of us began a much slower drive home.<br />
The route back was oddly harder than the route out. Some of the road signs aren&#8217;t particularly clear, and twice I had to turn around to re-join the right road. Alex caught me the first and third times, I caught myself the second. I&#8217;m sure with more practise at driving here, I&#8217;ll be able to read the signs a little more easily.<br />
We stopped twice. Once at this place called Mirador Something-Or-Other, which is almost at the border of Atenas and San Mateo along a windy strip of road that makes the Trans Canada between Field and Golden look like a straight, flat line. The view was spectacular &#8230; and the service exactly the opposite. We had something to drink and left.<br />
The second place was in an area with a number of small restaurants in Atenas. Alex chose one place that was as typÃƒ ­co as food gets in Costa Rica, but with a menu that featured English so we knew what we were eating. Mi Pequeña Niña ate a significant portion of my arroz con pollo (rice with chicken) and most of my steamed vegetables. She rather liked the rice, and couldn&#8217;t get enough. Noted, for future meals!<br />
Arriving at home, I started to feel that it was &#8230; home. I&#8217;m almost living here (the work visa is the only thing preventing me from saying that I am living here), and our apartment is starting to feel like home. This is good. &#8216;Cuz it&#8217;s gonna be a long couple years if I don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;ve got a home to go to.<br />
[flickr]tag:puntaleona+august+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr] [flickr]tag:atenas+august+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/08/weekend-in-punta-leona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1026</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
