<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>education &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/education/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 15:43:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>How to fix the Calgary Board of Education</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 15:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been wrestling with the Calgary Board of Education for a couple of years, now. And it&#8217;s not for anything complicated. To be honest, all I have is a simple hope: to have my children go to a school where they don&#8217;t have to worry about if they&#8217;re staying in the school, or if there &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to fix the Calgary Board of Education"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I&#8217;ve been wrestling with the Calgary Board of Education</strong> for a couple of years, now. And it&#8217;s not for anything complicated. To be honest, all I have is a simple hope: to have my children go to a school where they don&#8217;t have to worry about if they&#8217;re staying in the school, or if there will be a school at all. Note that this is a &#8220;hope&#8221;, not anything more concrete&#8230;<br />
Over the last couple of years, I&#8217;ve come to realize a few nasty things about <strong>how the public education system works in this city</strong>. The internals of the <strong>CBE are highly secretive</strong> (finding out who is actually in charge of certain things is about as easy as learning the inner workings of CSIS), and so intensely political that decisions appear to be made utterly at random, against student interests. None of this seems to go through check-and-balance because &#8230; well, <strong>there&#8217;s no accountability to anyone</strong>, nor does anyone take responsibility.<br />
As a result <strong>the CBE, as a whole, is failing</strong>. And that needs to change.<br />
<span id="more-3432"></span>The system is split into <strong>three basic parts</strong>: <strong>the teachers</strong> (who generally do an exemplary job, given limited resources), the <strong>board administration</strong> (at this point, pretty much the polar opposite of the teachers), and the <strong>Board of Trustees</strong> (elected, but ineffectual).<br />
The teachers are, at the heart of the CBE, the gears that allow the machine to move forward. (I&#8217;m sure the board administration would say it&#8217;s them. It&#8217;s not.) So <strong>we&#8217;re not going to worry too much about the teachers</strong>. Yes, we can delve into the problems of tenure and people past their prime, but those folks have a limited impact.<br />
And while I would love to (figuratively and literally)<strong> throw the administration under a bus</strong>, that&#8217;s a tough challenge. While I see <strong>utterly inept planning</strong> (bordering on outright lying, which I&#8217;ve had happen to my face), <strong>impenetrable organization</strong>, <strong>unavailable communication</strong>, and <strong>top-down decision-making</strong> that gets dictated without input from the bottom, these are not things that we cannot change without pressure from someone else with authority.<br />
And authority, at least with the CBE, seems to necessarily involve the one holding the purse strings.<br />
Every year, the <strong><a href="http://www.cbe.ab.ca/about-us/budget-and-finance/Documents/Budget-Briefing-April-6-2015.pdf" target="_blank">CBE receives about $1.25 <em>billion</em> a year</a></strong> for operating the schools in Calgary. That translates into over $9,000 per student (CBE&#8217;s own numbers). Obviously, each student doesn&#8217;t see that funding, that&#8217;s just an average. Those dollars are broken down into how the CBE operates.<br />
However, <strong>there is considerable concern</strong> (largely from parents) that the Resource Allocation Method (an algorithm that apparently is subject to privacy laws, so parents can&#8217;t actually see it) is funnelling away funds from schools back into the CBE &#8230; for <em>something</em>.<br />
It&#8217;s the vagueness that&#8217;s driving a lot of concerned parents (and yes, I am one) a bit off the edge. <strong>The CBE is protecting their own information for unknown purposes.</strong> They won&#8217;t even disclose the reasons why. It&#8217;s like asking your child why they broke your favourite lamp, and with pieces of said broken lamp in their hands, they respond: &#8220;I didn&#8217;t do it&#8221;.<br />
<strong>The CBE is not transparent</strong> when it comes to funding. Not even close. They&#8217;re quick to pull the &#8220;privacy&#8221; card and not discuss the details. Details that, ultimately, concern the very they&#8217;re supposedly protecting. (I do have to ask exactly <em>how</em> my child&#8217;s name has been directly attached to operating budgets. That seems a bit <em>wrong</em> to me.)<br />
This all happens for one simple reason: <strong>no-one is telling the CBE they&#8217;re doing it wrong</strong>. Or to be more specific, no-one with <em>authority</em>.<br />
Supposedly, that&#8217;s what the <a href="http://globalnews.ca/news/872020/what-does-a-school-board-trustee-actually-do/" target="_blank">CBE&#8217;s Board of Trustees</a> is supposed to do. That&#8217;s why we elect them. Except that over many years,<strong> it&#8217;s become exceptionally hard to actually <em>trust</em> our trustees</strong>. There&#8217;s issues of transparency, <a href="http://metronews.ca/news/calgary/963030/accusations-fly-during-impromptu-calgary-board-of-education-trustee-call-to-metro-reporter/" target="_blank">being belligerent to the media</a>, ignoring parents (this one I&#8217;ve experienced myself), and <a href="https://www.google.ca/webhp?q=cbe+board+trustees+%22closed+door%22+-cbe.ab.ca" target="_blank">controversial &#8220;closed door&#8221; matters</a>. It also doesn&#8217;t help that the Board of Trustees apparently voted out their own authority, putting into the hands of the CBE&#8217;s Chief Superintendent. You know, the head of the very group the Board of Trustees is supposed to monitor?<br />
I think there&#8217;s a better approach: put the very people who have the most vested interest in the CBE&#8217;s operations as oversight. <strong>We, the parents.</strong><br />
Every year, in every single CBE school across the city, we elect a Parent Council. Every Parent Council follows a set of operating rules, which includes the election of a <strong>Chair of the Parent Council</strong>.<br />
<strong>I propose that these Chairs then form a CBE Parent Chair Council</strong>, a group that meets month (or as needed, if matters dictate) to deal with larger issues. They are the ones tasked with broadcasting information from the CBE operations down to the parents of their respective schools. They also help communicate the specific issues from their schools back to the Council.<br />
The Parent Chair Council, in turn, elects from themselves a Board of Governors. The Board of Governors are the replacement for the current Board of Trustees. But this is not a one-for-one swap, as that achieves only a little. In addition to the <strong>establishment of a parent-run Board of Governors</strong>, we bestow upon them the <em>authority</em> to demand information from the CBE, to which the CBE must comply. (This is something the province needs to enact, as the CBE itself will not change without outside influence.)<br />
Already I can hear the complaints: <strong>How is this any different than the mess we currently have?</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Parents with children <em>currently </em>in the CBE are in control.</strong> Once children have left the CBE, parents become (necessarily) disengaged.</li>
<li>The election of the Board of Governors is an extension of the election of the Chair of a given school&#8217;s Parent Council: <strong>parents putting trust in one of <em>their own</em></strong> to represent them.</li>
<li><strong>Any member of the Board of Governors can be ousted at any time</strong> by the <em>current</em> rules that elect a Chair of Parent Council: someone who loses the trust in their school&#8217;s parents would be voted out at the school level, thereby removing that Chair from both the Parent Chair Council and the Board of Governors.</li>
<li><strong>Real authority would be given</strong> (again, requiring provincial mandate) that would allow the Board of Governors to truly <em>govern</em> the CBE (see, there&#8217;s a reason for the name!). I know this is a sticky part, but I do not see it as unrealistic.</li>
</ol>
<p>Okay, one major point I know some will raise: <strong>where would people find the time to do all of this?</strong> I mean, being on the Board of Governors is a lot of work, right?<br />
Yes, it is. Two counters to that point, however:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Board of Trustees already invest a fair bit of time</strong> with the existing situation. So it&#8217;s not unrealistic.</li>
<li><strong>There are parents in this city who are more than willing to invest that time</strong> because they <em>believe</em>. Every school has a few of these people, and interestingly, they&#8217;re often ones who put themselves up for election as the Chair of their Parent Council.</li>
</ul>
<p>The other obvious elephant is <strong>the teeth the province needs to bestow upon the Board of Governors</strong>. This is not a trivial aspect, but it is something that can be readily defined. It&#8217;s not like we don&#8217;t see similar constructs for other &#8220;watchdog&#8221; agencies who ultimately can deliver painful judgements against governments and/or industries.<br />
It is time for the <strong>parents to take back their schools</strong>, and require more of an organization that demands more and more, while delivering less and less. Parents get engaged very quickly, and can do a far better job as a collective interest than <strong>long-standing obstacles who march only to their political aspirations</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/04/how-to-fix-the-calgary-board-of-education/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3432</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling the awful to the angry</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=selling-the-awful-to-the-angry</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 05:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Selling the awful to the angry"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE Area IV director, as well as the Planning &amp; Transportation folks.<br />
I emphasize the word &#8220;supposed&#8221; &#8212; that was the CBE&#8217;s perspective. They thought they would get a lot of interest, and a lot of people who were genuinely happy that a solution had been found for the accommodation woes at Westgate School, which is at over 90% of its rated capacity.<br />
But, funny thing, there weren&#8217;t many happy people.<br />
<span id="more-3405"></span><br />
When we received the official notice that Eugene Coste was the &#8220;solution&#8221; to the problem, there&#8217;s been almost the equivalent of an angry mob. (I know &#8212; I&#8217;m one of them.) And that angry mob has been inundating the CBE with emails, phone calls, petitions, and even an appeal rally in the lobby of their headquarters last Friday. It would be awfully hard for anyone at the CBE to be able to not notice that there are a lot of unhappy people.<br />
Yet, despite all the warning, the CBE continued with its open house at Eugene Coste. I would like to refer to it as &#8220;Eugene Coste School&#8221; at this point, but in truth, it&#8217;s only a building with some rooms &#8212; everything that could make it a school, like desks, chairs, art on the walls, books in the library, and so forth, are utterly <em>absent</em>. The building was little more than a shell.<br />
When we entered the building, we were effectively directed to what I think was previously the library, to see some information, and talk to the directors. Except there wasn&#8217;t much talking &#8212; it was largely listening to the angry parents question the directors, and listen to the directors attempt to explain their position. Amongst all of this were kids running about, having to be corralled by parents who were trying to speak their minds. There were a lot of angry parents. Amazingly, so I heard later, the CBE was surprised that so many people were unhappy about the affair.<br />
Now this, dear reader, is where I give myself the facepalm. You know this expression, yes?<br />
<img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://forums.riftgame.com/attachments/general-discussion/9358-open-challenge-daglar-picard-facepalm.jpg" width="750" height="600" /><br />
I say this because I&#8217;m utterly unable to see how the CBE thought that asking a large number of unhappy parents to drive through rush hour traffic to a school to which they&#8217;re largely opposed with their tired and hungry kids in tow (without a single distraction available to occupy them), not run a single tour of the facility to sell its virtues, and corral everyone in one room to &#8220;talk&#8221; with the people most of the angry parents are blaming in the first place, was <em>ever</em> a good idea.<br />
Exactly <em>how</em> was this supposed to be successful?<br />
I work in marketing. You know, the industry that exists to sell you the things you don&#8217;t really want to buy? (Okay, slightly cynical. I admit that perhaps I&#8217;ve been doing this job too long&#8230;) You can look at <em>Mad Men</em> and snicker, but the basis of the show isn&#8217;t far from reality: we make you want something.<br />
The CBE didn&#8217;t even <em>try</em> to make us want to send our kids to Eugene Coste. Let&#8217;s ignore the hour-long bus rides and massive disruption to families&#8217; lives &#8212; the school building was devoid of any life whatsoever, and we didn&#8217;t even really get a chance to see much of it. And having our fears glossed over by &#8220;best case&#8221; scenarios of bus routes and timing? A little more than moderately insulting. Basically, they failed at selling the idea.<br />
This is the point at which an agency is asked to leave the pitch process and not return. Or, worse, the agency&#8217;s account is brought up for review and they have to validate their existence against dozens of competitors who want the account.<br />
This is something the CBE needs to figure out: how to sell awful situations to angry people. The entire city is under school space crunches, and there aren&#8217;t a lot of options for anyone. The releases we receive are emotionless, lacking sufficient information, and unable to address the fears that arise &#8212; the very things that any good marketing job should address.<br />
No competition for the CBE, you say? You&#8217;d be surprised how many people are readily willing to consider the separate school system, or even the extra cost of charter schools. And we&#8217;ve got a lot of charter schools in Calgary, so this is definitely not a hypothetical scenario. The CBE just ends up with more angry customers, who won&#8217;t be willing to put up with the problem much longer.<br />
So a suggestion to the CBE: you want people to like you? Get someone else to tell your story, &#8216;cuz you&#8217;re doing a lousy job of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trying to save Westgate Spanish</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/trying-to-save-westgate-spanish/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=trying-to-save-westgate-spanish</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/trying-to-save-westgate-spanish/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 23:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Way back in 2012, the Calgary Board of Education asked the parents of Westgate School what they thought of the CBE&#8217;s plan to try and alleviate the overpopulation problem. We were engaged, we went to many meetings, and then we waited. A lot. And, heaven help us, we told them to make up their minds. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/trying-to-save-westgate-spanish/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Trying to save Westgate Spanish"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Way back in 2012, the Calgary Board of Education asked the parents of Westgate School what they thought of the CBE&#8217;s plan to try and alleviate the overpopulation problem. We were engaged, we went to many meetings, and then we waited. A lot. And, heaven help us, we told them to make up their minds.<br />
A week ago today, they told us. And we didn&#8217;t like the answer. Not remotely. It wasn&#8217;t worst-case &#8212; it was worse than that: it was an option never previously hinted at, and while it did address some of the things that the parents had been asked for, it was wrapped up in a big ribbon of stink. In short, the <a href="http://www.westgatespanish.ca/">Westgate Spanish</a> program was going to be taken away.<br />
I suppose this is a lesson in &#8220;be careful what you wish for&#8221;.<br />
<span id="more-3402"></span><br />
Short version: The CBE decided that all four (remaining) Spanish grades would be pulled from the school and bussed 14 kilometres away to another, currently empty, school. Across the Glenmore Trail causeway. During rush hour(s).<br />
Once the &#8220;WTF&#8221; moment had passed, anger started to set in. Not so much because of the distance, but because of the betrayal. Never had the CBE even mentioned the existence of the new school (Eugene Coste Elementary), or hinting that students could be bussed such a distance away from where most students lived.<br />
Right now, most students at Westgate School are bussed in, from west of the school. &#8220;Well, what&#8217;s the problem, if they&#8217;re already being bussed?&#8221; you ask. And it&#8217;s a good question. The point isn&#8217;t so much that they&#8217;re being bussed, it&#8217;s the <em>distance</em>. Some kids would be spending over two hours on the bus every day, the equivalent of over 60 instructional days. There&#8217;s no world where that makes sense, in an <em>urban centre</em>, where there are other schools that should be available.<br />
Oh, and then there&#8217;s the other question that I&#8217;ve heard some of you say: &#8220;Why Spanish? They should take French, which is our other official language!&#8221; Sure, it&#8217;s an optional program, no-one&#8217;s making them take it. The same goes with the French program. Oh, and that French program? That&#8217;s <em>Parisian</em> French. You just try using that in Quebec and see how far you get. In Canada, we do not teach <em>Quebecois</em> as a language outside of Quebec.<br />
So now I&#8217;m spending far too much time trying to help a group get the CBE back into a conversation. Short version: we don&#8217;t like the presented &#8220;solution&#8221;, because it affects the students and their families far too much. It violates several of the CBE policies and principles, and even from a <em>moral</em> standpoint: who thought with honest truth that putting a kid on a bus that long <i>inside city limits</i> was the right solution?<br />
I have no idea where this is going to end, yet. Right now, we&#8217;re amassing parents into a group. We&#8217;re hearing rumours from many angles, and all of them have grains of truth, and equally need grains of salt. It&#8217;s hard to tell who&#8217;s friend, and who&#8217;s just a &#8220;silent observer&#8221; (dear elected school trustees, we&#8217;re looking in your direction). The only ones truly helping us are those with the passion to not take this lying down.<br />
So, yeah, loss of sleep, more stress (nosebleeds, to boot!), and I&#8217;ve had to apologise to my boss for not doing enough work, lately.<br />
What do we want? A reasonable option that doesn&#8217;t involve long-distance bussing. I think it&#8217;s possible. The question is if everyone else does, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/trying-to-save-westgate-spanish/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3402</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary Board of Education: we need a decision on Westgate Elementary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi, CBE? I&#8217;m a concerned parent. Yeah, I know you&#8217;ve heard from a lot of us in the last year regarding what you want to do with Westgate Elementary. You&#8217;ve heard so much, you&#8217;re not listening to us anymore, which I can understand &#8212; there&#8217;s only so much you can hear before you&#8217;ve heard enough. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary Board of Education: we need a decision on Westgate Elementary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, CBE? I&#8217;m a concerned parent. Yeah, I know you&#8217;ve heard from a lot of us in the last year regarding what you want to do with <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b140/">Westgate Elementary</a>. You&#8217;ve heard so much, you&#8217;re not listening to us anymore, which I can understand &#8212; there&#8217;s only so much you can hear before you&#8217;ve heard enough.<br />
But we &#8212; that&#8217;s you as the Board, and us as parents &#8212; have a problem: there&#8217;s no decision. The school is still over-populated, and despite having pulled another grade out, there&#8217;s going to be too many students for next year.<br />
So &#8230; what&#8217;s going on? We need an answer. And preferably now, and not at the end of this school year.<br />
<span id="more-3392"></span><br />
You&#8217;ve pulled Grade 5 and sent them abroad. (Those students, by the way, are having trouble trying to function in a much bigger school. Big trouble. Ask their parents.) But that&#8217;s not enough. You need to decide the future of French and Spanish at the school. We&#8217;ve already heard that Spanish is likely to be the one to depart. It&#8217;s the youngest of the two programs, after all. (It&#8217;s terrible reasoning, incidentally &#8212; both programs are equally used, according to the Principal.) It needs to live, separately, at a different school.<br />
My problem is that my child is enrolled in Grade 1 Spanish. She quite likes it. I quite like that the school is less than five minutes <em>by foot</em> from our home in Westgate. It&#8217;s effectively our community school, even though it&#8217;s really not, since it&#8217;s a language school first. So if Spanish leaves &#8230; where does my child go?<br />
Did I mention she&#8217;s in Grade 1? I&#8217;m not a big fan of bussing her somewhere, even less considering driving her. Yes, I know <em>kindergarten</em> students are currently bussed &#8212; I don&#8217;t agree with that, either. Maybe I&#8217;m old school (pardon the pun), but I believe schools should be walked to, not driven.<br />
Okay, rant aside, we still have to contend with <em>where</em>. In all the discussions that have been had to date, the schools mentioned are quite a way beyond Westgate. One of them, <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b103/">Jennie Elliott Elementary School</a>, is in Lakeview, a minimum 7.7 kilometre drive. I know that doesn&#8217;t sound like much to you, but for someone who has been a mere 350 <em>metres</em> away, it&#8217;s a significant change.<br />
Admittedly, that&#8217;s just us. We know that we&#8217;re in the minority &#8212; most kids are shipped into Westgate everyday, and in the end, the percentage of bussed/driven students vs. walking distance would probably remain somewhat similar.<br />
What won&#8217;t remain the same is the effort and time taken to get students somewhere. Let&#8217;s go back to that change in distance: about 8 kilometres between the two schools. Why is this significant? Because bus routes will have to change, and parents driving their kids will have to change. Going in and out of Lakeview isn&#8217;t particularly easy during rush hour (Westgate, we know, is bad enough). You&#8217;re diverting people even further (we know a large proportion comes from &#8220;up the hill&#8221; to the west of Sarcee), and incurring more time.<br />
How about we suggest something different? There&#8217;s a highly unused school barely a kilometre away that could easily accommodate the change: <a href="http://schools.cbe.ab.ca/b133/">Rosscarrock Elementary</a>. It&#8217;s very underpopulated. So much so that a large portion of that school is used by Chinook Learning Services, presumably to fill the otherwise unused space. (We know this because our youngest child attends a preschool there, presumably also in unused space.) And at barely a kilometre difference from Westgate Elementary, you&#8217;re not asking for huge changes in how people move around &#8212; it&#8217;s only an extra couple of minutes to drive there, and access to Rosscarrock is marginally better.<br />
So, can I suggest you consider Rosscarrock for the new home for Spanish? For the parents at large, and for the kids who have to travel by bus, this is a far more sane option than asking them to trek further into Lakeview. And if, as your plans last year suggested, that Spanish kids would eventually flow to A.E. Cross, Rosscarrock is a closer school, again reducing the distance delta.<br />
No matter what your final decision, we would like to know <em>soon</em>. We&#8217;ve been waiting a long time for a decision, because &#8212; believe it or not &#8212; it does affect how we plan our lives. We know planning things like this is hard, and that no matter what you do, you&#8217;ll be heavily criticized for it. That&#8217;s just the nature of providing a service like this. But make the decision, and allow us to start adapting soon. Because if it doesn&#8217;t go in our favour, adapting could take quite a long time.<br />
Thank you for your consideration,<br />
A loving and concerned parent</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2013/10/calgary-board-of-education-we-need-a-decision-on-westgate-elementary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3392</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009, A Year in Review</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2009-a-year-in-review</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving the hangar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunsets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "2009, A Year in Review"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year past was one of the toughest ones I can remember. It&#8217;s been a year of extreme highs, some pretty darks depths; my share of awesome joys, mixed with an unhealthy dose of stress. And that&#8217;s not when you consider the economy, I might add &#8212; things are even worse when you roll all that in.<br />
The year closed out on a more sombre note for me, in many ways. Much quieter, and I got to spend a lot of time with my family (which I cherish now, and cannot regret in anyway), but the future is a little less certain. I&#8217;m less concerned about that fact than I thought I would be, however.<br />
On with the year that just was&#8230;<span id="more-2500"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Rang in the new year watching fireworks go off all over the Central Valley in Costa Rica (a spectacular sight, if you ever happen to be in Costa Rica at New Year&#8217;s)</li>
<li>Had numerous run-ins with illness between The Monkey, myself, and Alex (and some far less pretty than others, lemme tell ya!)</li>
<li>Experienced my first, bonafide, scare-the-crap-outta-me earthquake, measuring in at 6.2 at its epicentre</li>
<li>In Costa Rica, travelled to:
<ul>
<li>Villa Blanca (Los Angeles Cloud Forest), three times</li>
<li>Arenal (for my very wet birthday)</li>
<li>Parque de Diversiones</li>
<li>Playa del Coco</li>
<li>Playa Hermosa</li>
<li>Playa Chiquita</li>
<li>Puerto Viejo</li>
<li>La Paz Waterfalls</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Had a few troubles with our trusty Suzuki, Dave, and spent more than a few bucks getting &#8217;em all fixed</li>
<li>Managed to avoid becoming totally addicted to coffee, but still drank a lot of it</li>
<li>Took pride in The Monkey starting school (yes, even though she wasn&#8217;t even 2 years old yet)</li>
<li>Worked through the challenges of getting a startup business up and running; the stress took its toll on me and my family, and likely all lead to where I am at this very moment</li>
<li>Travelled to Canada for a visa run, though it was originally planned as a family visit:
<ul>
<li>Barrie</li>
<li>Bolton</li>
<li>Oakville</li>
<li>And wee bit of Toronto (I had to go into the Toronto office) just for flavour</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Saw far too few sunsets on beaches</li>
<li>Discovered great Indian food in Costa Rica</li>
<li>Moved from our first apartment to a new apartment, after our condo management company couldn&#8217;t come to an agreement on a contract extension</li>
<li>Got utterly screwed by the aforementioned condo management company, to the tune of about USD$1,500</li>
<li>Celebrated 20 years of journalling/blogging with post #1,000 (total coincidence, I swear!)</li>
<li>Did a Stampede-style breakfast for my co-workers</li>
<li>Finally acquired my Temporary Residency visa &#8230; after realising that staying in Costa Rica long-term wasn&#8217;t an option for my family, and we&#8217;d decided to go home</li>
<li>Waxed poetic on management and management style (perhaps too much so?)</li>
<li>Cringed as The Monkey crossed into &#8220;The Terrible Twos&#8221; (which, thankfully, haven&#8217;t really been that bad)</li>
<li>Finally snapped after running into a &#8220;Perfect Storm&#8221; of difficult project, dealing with the relocation company, organising the family, trying to sell the car, cancelling services, and making sure that what little money we had saved was properly moved out of the country before we left &#8212; I was an utter wreck at the end</li>
<li>Ate far too many of our last meals in Costa Rica in a Denny&#8217;s</li>
<li>Managed to survive the 19-hour ordeal of moving from Costa Rica; flying through Houston with a few bags, an irate cat in a bag, and a toddler hell-bent on doing her own thing; finally arriving in -18 degree weather in Calgary after 22:30 at night</li>
<li>Moved back into a house we hadn&#8217;t seen in a year and a half, finding things we hadn&#8217;t seen in probably over three years</li>
<li>Bought a 2006 Jetta TDI</li>
<li>Critical Mass and I parted ways after about 9.75 years</li>
<li>Landed a wonderful case of Benign Positional Vertigo on Boxing Day</li>
<li>Realised that, yes, there are many things that Costa Rica has better than Canada &#8230; beyond the weather</li>
<li>Rang in the new year year to come with a visit to the Calgary Zoo&#8217;s &#8220;Zoo Year&#8217;s Eve&#8221;, at -22 degrees Celsius</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m missing easily a couple of months&#8217; of detail in there, but the simple fact is that most of Q1 and Q2 last year were chaotic, busy, and stressful. I&#8217;m proud of what we all achieved, and I miss the people I left behind in Costa Rica. Time changes, and people have to change with them. As such, 2010 will be a year of change for me. I don&#8217;t see that as a bad thing, just that as with any human, change ain&#8217;t easy.<br />
But change <em>is</em> exciting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/01/2009-a-year-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2500</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On your first days of school</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/on-your-first-days-of-school/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=on-your-first-days-of-school</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/on-your-first-days-of-school/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 19:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey kiddo! I know I haven&#8217;t written to you since your first birthday. That&#8217;s not good for me to do, but sadly your father has been a very busy person in the last few months. That&#8217;s not an excuse &#8212; there is no excuse for not communicating with you &#8212; it&#8217;s just a very sad &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/on-your-first-days-of-school/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "On your first days of school"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey kiddo! I know I haven&#8217;t written to you since <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/happy-first-birthday-my-daughter/">your first birthday</a>. That&#8217;s not good for me to do, but sadly your father has been a very busy person in the last few months. That&#8217;s not an excuse &#8212; there is no excuse for not communicating with you &#8212; it&#8217;s just a very sad reality.<br />
Today you&#8217;re on your second day of school &#8212; your first was just yesterday. Your Mom and I were a little worried how you&#8217;d handle school. For the last near-18 months, the only people you&#8217;ve really known are us, and you&#8217;ve seen us nearly every day of your life. And certainly, you&#8217;ve seen your mother far more than I.<br />
And that&#8217;s what I want to talk about, actually.<br />
<span id="more-1254"></span>Lately, you haven&#8217;t seen a lot of me. It&#8217;s been hard for you, I know, wondering where your father is all the time. I leave early in the morning, usually just after you finish breakfast, and I&#8217;m usually not home until after you&#8217;ve had dinner and are watching &#8220;Backyardigans&#8221;. If we&#8217;re lucky, we get 90 minutes of time together before you go to bed, though it&#8217;s usually an hour. Sometimes, it&#8217;s not at all.<br />
I hope you can forgive me for this one day. I never intended to be away from you so long every day. Had I known that 90 minute commutes and a longer-than-expected work day would be a part of life here in Costa Rica, perhaps things would have been different. Naturally, that&#8217;s all 20-20 hindsight talking, and I can&#8217;t change the past.<br />
But I can try change the future. I can try as hard as I can to spend what time I do have with you doing things that bring us close together: getting you out of bed in the morning, feeding you breakfast, giving you your baths (and letting you soak me through splashing and squirting me with your bath toys), reading you stories, and putting you to bed. On weekends, I can add walks, going to the pool (and hopefully helping you learn to swim), and playing with you. And of course, I love making you laugh.<br />
Please know that I love you very much, and being away from you every day for so long is very hard for me. I do it only because I love you, because this allows us to live here in Costa Rica, and allows Mom to be around you all the time. It&#8217;s a sacrifice, one that I hope does not hurt you too much.<br />
I feel in a way that I&#8217;m missing your first days at school. I don&#8217;t know how it would be any different had we not left Calgary, but I still feel that I&#8217;m falling short. But it&#8217;s important for you to go to school, to be with other children, and learn things that I cannot teach you (like learning how to speak Spanish properly). It&#8217;s important that you learn the things that will take you through life.<br />
And I will be there for you, as will Mom. I might not always be there to be with you, holding your hand, reading with you, sitting in my lap when you watch TV, or pick you up if you fall down. But know that you&#8217;re always in my thoughts, my head and my heart, and I always look forward to seeing your smile and hear your chatter.<br />
With love,<br />
Dad</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/02/on-your-first-days-of-school/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1254</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Misconceptions on learning Spanish</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/misconceptions-on-learning-spanish/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=misconceptions-on-learning-spanish</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/misconceptions-on-learning-spanish/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 19:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[know-it-all]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[languages]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I remember when I was back in university. As part of my English degree, I was told that I had to take two languages. Literally, different languages, not just something that was culturally different (a couple of friends not in English got away with courses about the French language&#8217;s cultural impact, rather than having to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/misconceptions-on-learning-spanish/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Misconceptions on learning Spanish"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember when I was back in university. As part of my English degree, I was told that I had to take two languages. Literally, different languages, not just something that was culturally different (a couple of friends not in English got away with courses about the French language&#8217;s cultural impact, rather than having to learn French, for example).<br />
At the time, I signed up for French. I figured I already knew enough that I could ace the course and not worry about it. The other language was harder. My advisor suggested Latin, mostly because the one instructor he said I should have had a simple rule: ace all the weekly tests, you get 100% and you don&#8217;t have to take the final. I liked that plan.<br />
Sadly, the plan didn&#8217;t work exactly as planned. The French teacher was an absolute bitch.<br />
<span id="more-1013"></span>I don&#8217;t use that word often &#8212; bitch. It represents a very specific type of attitude in my mind, and using it means I really don&#8217;t like someone. And in this case, she was a bitch. Sadly, this seems to be a very common stereotype of French teachers. I don&#8217;t know why. I&#8217;ve had several over the years of forced French language education. I bailed after the first day &#8212; degree or not, I wasn&#8217;t putting up with that crap.<br />
My advisor then suggested Spanish. &#8220;It&#8217;s simple,&#8221; he said, &#8220;no silent letters, no irregular verbs, you always know what&#8217;s masculine and feminine, and you always know where the accent goes.&#8221;<br />
I took Spanish for four months. Had probably the best teacher for a language I&#8217;ll ever have. Sadly, I no longer remember her name, only that she made us do skits in Spanish without notes. Marshall and I talked a lot about chickens and bananas (we loved the alliteration &#8212; &#8220;platanos&#8221; and &#8220;pollos&#8221;). For the most part, I felt that the advisor wasn&#8217;t far off.<br />
But now that I&#8217;m trying to speak Spanish properly, I&#8217;m finding that what my advisor told me was a crock of shit.<br />
Sadly, this mistaken perspective has now earned me the title &#8220;Mr. Spanish&#8221; from Mark and Jason. Far too often I&#8217;ve opened my big yap, only to find out later that I wasn&#8217;t actually right. (Remember, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/?s=&quot;know-it-all&quot;">I&#8217;m a know-it-all</a>, which causes its own problems.) Despite lessons in Rosetta Stone (an outstanding language product &#8212; my extremely high praise to the software&#8217;s designers), it hasn&#8217;t hit some of the points I&#8217;ve been getting wrong.<br />
My Spanish/English practical conversation guide, however, is showing me that I know sqwat. For example, my impression was that any (singular form) word ending in &#8220;a&#8221; was feminine, and pretty much anything a consonant was masculine. Way wrong. It&#8217;s generalisation, and it&#8217;s far from exact.<br />
Silent letters? Try the &#8220;h&#8221;. It has no sound whatsoever. It&#8217;s there to distinguish between other words, but it&#8217;s not pronounced at all. (The &#8220;h&#8221; sound is pronounced by the &#8220;j&#8221;.) Otherwise, the letters are pronounced.<br />
Irregular verbs? I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s one there somewhere. I just haven&#8217;t found it yet.<br />
About the only thing that still holds up is accents. It&#8217;s pretty simple: with certain letters (all vowels and the letter &#8220;n&#8221;) it&#8217;s on the second last syllable. Everything else is the last syllable. All exceptions are marked with an accent. So in that sense, it&#8217;s obvious.<br />
I&#8217;m learning. I&#8217;m far from perfect, and I&#8217;ve resolved to keep my big trap shut until I know I can speak reasonably well. The key thing will be to take additional lessons, so we can correct all my bad habits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/07/misconceptions-on-learning-spanish/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1013</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canada&#039;s history is wasted on its youth</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 19:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/19/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The CBC published a news article about how Canada&#8217;s youth scores a measly 18% on a Canadian history quiz. Everyone is aghast at the marks &#8212; are we truly that bad at our own history? Of course we are. Because we haven&#8217;t the ability to appreciate it. This was a conversation point I had with &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Canada&#039;s history is wasted on its youth"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CBC published a news article about how <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2007/11/09/canadians-quiz.html">Canada&#8217;s youth scores a measly 18% on a Canadian history quiz</a>. Everyone is aghast at the marks &#8212; are we truly that bad at our own history?<br />
Of course we are. Because we haven&#8217;t the ability to appreciate it.<br />
<span id="more-858"></span>This was a conversation point I had with my mother- and uncle-in-law the other night over dinner. My uncle was recounting a cruise he had taken from New York City that wound up the coast to Boston, Halifax, Cornerbrook, Quebec City, and a couple of other places that I now forget. Along the way, the cruise was replete with history, with guides not only present on the ship, but also on the tours at the various ports of call.<br />
His point was that the trip really put together all the things he&#8217;d previously learned in his history classes as a youth. Back then, it was mere words on a page, dates he had to memorise, without the context needed to put everything together.<br />
And that&#8217;s the catch: context.<br />
I remember from my own history classes having to memorise large chunks of useless information. I state &#8220;useless&#8221; because as a teenager, none of it had any bearing on my current state of life. I no longer remember when the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decline_of_the_Byzantine_Empire">Byzantine Empire collapsed</a> or when the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_River_Rebellion">Rouge River (Metis) Rebellion</a> took place. Those dates are lost among the other detritus that regularly floats around in my noggin. What matters is the &#8220;why&#8221;, the &#8220;how&#8221;, the &#8220;what&#8221;. Not so much the &#8220;when&#8221;. Well, specific &#8220;when&#8221; &#8212; approximate &#8220;when&#8221; does help.<br />
For example: Kids are taught (in Canada) that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_Confederation">Confederation took place on 1 July 1867</a> in Charlottetown, Prince Edward Island. This brought about the creation of Canada as a nation. But that&#8217;s not the whole truth, and really glosses over a whole whack of things, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>We were still a colony of Britain <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statute_of_Westminster_1931">until much later</a>, when <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada_Act_1982">other documents were signed</a></li>
<li>We didn&#8217;t have a <a href="http://www.pch.gc.ca/progs/cpsc-ccsp/sc-cs/df3_e.cfm">Canadian national flag</a> until the 1960s</li>
<li>Confederation was mostly to handle issues with business and trade, and not for the idealistic creation of a nation</li>
<li>Natives got screwed over badly, along with the entire Maritime region</li>
<li>Upper Canada was given the upper hand</li>
<li>The West was largely a footnote</li>
</ul>
<p>The problem is that a lot of history comes down to one thing: politics. (Mind you, that gets sub-categorised into greed, sex, religion, and a healthy dose of insanity.) This is something teenagers don&#8217;t understand. Politics is one of those things you truly can&#8217;t appreciate until you&#8217;ve personally participated in a few elections (as a voter, anyway) to see what crap goes on.<br />
&#8216;Cuz the same crap has gone on for millennia. People always want what they can&#8217;t have, want to establish complete control, or simply get the girl and wreak havoc in the process. Politics have created and ended civilizations (witness the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carthage#The_fall_of_Carthage">Fall of Carthage</a> &#8212; mostly due to politics.) It takes years of reading books, watching documentaries, and attending in-depth classes to start understanding why the world works the way it does.<br />
It&#8217;s only once you get the bigger picture that the finer details are appreciated. Suddenly, you can see more significance in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spanish_Civil_War">Spanish Civil War</a>. You understand how <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_War_I">World War I</a> was almost unavoidable. Why the discovery of Canada and its deep exploration was so important to world development. How Canada steered the development of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Nations_Emergency_Force">United Nations peacekeeping</a>. Why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Vimy_Ridge">Vimy</a> does (and should) matter to Canadian. You see why oil is possibly the worst thing humanity has ever found. And you see the patterns that have governed human civilization for thousands of years.<br />
The saying goes that &#8220;those who do not learn from history are doomed to repeat it&#8221;. History merely validates that we do not learn from it. (A rather interesting cycle, when you think about it.) I think it&#8217;s less about those who learn from history, but those who actually understand it. And not just individual parts &#8212; that only really gives you an edge on Jeopardy. You need to understand the big pictures, and be able to dive into the details to understand the motivating factors.<br />
A really neat show from the BBC that used to be shown on TLC (when it was still known as The Learning Channel) was <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connections_(TV_series)">Connections</a></em>. While a distorted view of history (the connections were sometimes a bit tenuous), it did a great job of demonstrating why the end result often comes from things seemingly unrelated. History is about that very thing, and memorising dates won&#8217;t give you the high view.<br />
Should Canada&#8217;s youth still be taught history? Yes. But not in terms of dates. Learn big picture stuff first. Formative years should cover world history: civilizations, developments, world religions, political systems. In the years that come, teach the deeper concepts through specific examples (e.g. the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Hong_Kong#Colonial_Hong_Kong_Era_.281800s_-_1930s.29">rise of Hong Kong through Britain&#8217;s colonial development</a>, or why many of the towns and cities in western Canada come from Scotland).<br />
Give our youth context. I didn&#8217;t understand history until I was in my 20s, well after leaving high school. Give them the pieces to start assembling the bigger picture. You can&#8217;t teach all of the World history to anyone &#8230; but you can give them the tools to understand it themselves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/canadas-history-is-wasted-on-its-youth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">858</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
