<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>google &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/google/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 05:37:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Why you should use Google Analytics</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/why-you-should-use-google-analytics/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-you-should-use-google-analytics</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/why-you-should-use-google-analytics/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 05:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2933</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[For anyone out there trying to do any form of semi-serious work on the internet (notably with websites), you often end up asking yourself: is what I&#8217;m doing having any effect whatsoever? It&#8217;s an important question &#8212; especially if there are monetary values attached to the work you&#8217;re doing &#8212; and it&#8217;s not always the &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/why-you-should-use-google-analytics/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why you should use Google Analytics"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For anyone out there trying to do any form of semi-serious work on the internet (notably with websites), you often end up asking yourself: is what I&#8217;m doing having any effect whatsoever? It&#8217;s an important question &#8212; especially if there are monetary values attached to the work you&#8217;re doing &#8212; and it&#8217;s not always the easiest one to answer.<br />
That&#8217;s where analytics packages come in handy. They can tell you who is visiting your site, where they&#8217;re from, what browser they&#8217;re using, their navigation path, search terms, etc. From a metrics perspective, it&#8217;s  indispensable  information. And there&#8217;s a lot of packages that&#8217;ll help you get all that.<br />
But only one of them will get you into Google&#8217;s search index almost instantly.<br />
<span id="more-2933"></span>Okay, let&#8217;s back up a sec. Going back a few years, one of the things I did frequently was work on search engine optimisation. I&#8217;d spend hours &#8212; days, even &#8212; writing code in specific ways so that it would be equally accessible to a search engine&#8217;s spider (such as Google) as it would to any normal human. But, most importantly, when the search engine read it, that without having human knowledge, it could categorise that information accordingly.<br />
We regularly had to tell clients that significant changes to their sites (especially site redesigns) could take weeks, even more than a month, to show up in search engine indices. This was always a troubling point, as clients were often worried about making sure important information was indexed as soon as possible.<br />
Today, my team launched a new website for our client, <a href="http://www.bigrockbeer.com">Big Rock Brewery</a>. It was one we&#8217;d planned for a while, making sure the site was carefully built, and all the appropriate 301 redirects were in place to assist with the inevitable ranking shift due to URL changes.<br />
Now, knowing how Google et al behaved in the past, one would think that I wouldn&#8217;t spend any time peering at Google&#8217;s results to see what had already changed, wouldn&#8217;t you? Well, maybe my old self would. My current self, however, is just too darned curious.<br />
Imagine my shock when I saw, <strong>within less than two hours</strong> from seeing the first hits to the new site (which was on a completely different server), I saw the new URLs and even whole new pages showing up in Google&#8217;s index. Complete index, too, I might add &#8212; copy and description already in place.<br />
&#8220;Stunned&#8221; doesn&#8217;t quite cut it. It&#8217;s almost as if the world had changed.<br />
Naturally, being curious, I wanted to know <em>why</em>. So I pestered some colleagues of mine who deal with the search aspect a lot more than I do. Their thought? It&#8217;s Google Analytics.<br />
Now, without actually peering under the hood (&#8216;cuz even long-time Googlers don&#8217;t get that kind of privilege), I can only surmise that each hit from Google Analytics is being translated into an index request at Google&#8217;s end, which is then verified by a separate spider request (which obtains the copy and meta tags). I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s more to it than that, but that seems pretty reasonable at a basic level.<br />
I&#8217;d read somewhere a while back that <a href="http://www.niallkennedy.com/blog/2008/01/google-mapreduce-stats.html">Google chewed through something like 20 petabytes of data per day</a>. (After some poking around, it looks like that was circa 2008, by the way.) During that time, it took a while for a simple change to appear. Now? It might as well be 20 petabytes an <em>hour</em>, or Google&#8217;s gone through some really significant changes in the indexing algorithms.<br />
Frankly, I think it&#8217;s a double-edged situation. It&#8217;s a boon to those of us who plan releases, because we know it&#8217;ll get indexed pretty quickly. But it&#8217;s also a danger &#8212; one wrong move, and Google will have your mistake indexed before you know it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/why-you-should-use-google-analytics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2933</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Make April 1 &#034;IE6 Dies&#034; Day</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=make-april-1-ie6-dies-day</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 18:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2574</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[At the moment, IE6 still holds about 20% of the market (according to today&#8217;s metrics from NetMarketShare). That&#8217;s far too large a share for a 8.5 year old browser, especially one that has been  superseded  by successive releases of its own code by two versions. It&#8217;s far too much for a browser that costs too &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Make April 1 &#34;IE6 Dies&#34; Day"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the moment, <strong>IE6 still holds about 20% of the market</strong> (<a href="http://www.netmarketshare.com/browser-market-share.aspx?qprid=2">according to today&#8217;s metrics from NetMarketShare</a>). That&#8217;s far too large a share for a 8.5 year old browser, especially one that has been  superseded  by successive releases of its own code by two versions. It&#8217;s far too much for a browser that costs too much to support, and despite several service packs still bears significant security issues. It continues to haunt the internet, acting like a lazy bouncer allowing the seediest of activities to go on unchecked.<br />
I propose <strong>April 1st be &#8220;IE6 Dies&#8221; Day</strong>.  It&#8217;s time that IE6 be shown the door. But we&#8217;ll need help.<br />
<span id="more-2574"></span>This isn&#8217;t the first time people have called for IE6 to go away. But previously, these were developer-led challenges, all of which met the same problem: <strong>we&#8217;re not the ones who get to make that decision</strong>. All a client needs to do is pull out a report from their stats engine to prove why they need it. (Or simply open their company-issued laptop to show the IT-mandated browser.) Going against this kind of weight, we&#8217;re lost.<br />
<strong>We need to go the other way.</strong> Not to the browser makers (they&#8217;re on our side), but to the people offering services that people want to see. Want to punish a child? Take away its access to its toys.<br />
We need to call out to the Big 3 search engines. <strong>Google, Bing, and Yahoo: Block access to IE6.</strong> And I don&#8217;t mean provide a subtle hint page, I mean block it entirely. With a big, bold page that says:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;font-size: 1.5em">We&#8217;re sorry, but your browser is no longer supported. Please upgrade to one of the following [insert browser list here]. If necessary, please contact your IT department.</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s already on this path. Microsoft has encouraged upgrades to IE8. Yahoo hasn&#8217;t really said anything yet, but I imagine they&#8217;ve thought something similar. Take these three pages away, and you <strong>cut off a primary tool</strong> that millions of IE6 users go to daily. With these unavailable for no reason other than a browser update, it should help drive that final spike into the heart.<br />
So why April 1? Well, there&#8217;s the obvious reason: IE6 has been &#8220;fooling&#8221; us for far too long, and it&#8217;s time that we prove that we&#8217;re not fooled any longer. But a bigger reason is time: Namely, <strong>give companies some warning</strong>. The upgrade cost can be  significant, and companies need time to get things in place. Frankly, they&#8217;ve had enough, but a sudden stop without warning can cause some pretty major headaches. (I may be a jerk, but I&#8217;m not without sympathy for IT teams, having some good friends who do IT, and having enough IT to respect the problems they solve.)<br />
I can&#8217;t do this alone. For this to work, <strong>we need as many people as possible</strong> to spread the message. Tweet/retweet this message as much as you can (please use the hashtag #ie6diesday, if possible). Send them this message:</p>
<blockquote><p>Dear Search Provider,<br />
Due to the on-going security and support problems with Internet Explorer 6, I would like to suggest that you consider April 1 &#8220;IE6 Dies Day&#8221;, and block IE6 from accessing your search engine. There are many other options and alternatives. http://bit.ly/bZTUej<br />
Sincerely,<br />
[Your name here]</p></blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s some quick links to get you started!</p>
<ul>
<li>Yahoo: <a href="http://help.yahoo.com/l/us/yahoo/search/indexing/webmaster-01.html">http://help.yahoo.com/l/us/yahoo/search/indexing/webmaster-01.html</a> and <a href="http://www.ysearchblog.com/">http://www.ysearchblog.com/</a></li>
<li>Google: <a href="http://www.google.com/support/contact/bin/request.py?bdpg=1&amp;hl=en">http://www.google.com/support/contact/bin/request.py?bdpg=1&amp;hl=en</a> and <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/">http://googleblog.blogspot.com/</a></li>
<li>Bing: <a href="https://feedback.discoverbing.com/default.aspx?productkey=bing">https://feedback.discoverbing.com/default.aspx?productkey=bing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Spread the news. Let&#8217;s convince the search engines that <strong>it&#8217;s time for IE6 to die</strong>, once and for all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/02/make-april-1-ie6-dies-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2574</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I (heart) Google Chrome</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/i-heart-google-chrome/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=i-heart-google-chrome</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/i-heart-google-chrome/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 20:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1079</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Not 45 minutes ago, Google released their latest contribution to the internet: Chrome. This effectively ended years of speculation that Google was writing a browser, that it would throw its hat into the ring and kick off another heated browser war.   Figures that Google wouldn&#8217;t just drop a bomb, it would lay waste to &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/i-heart-google-chrome/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "I (heart) Google Chrome"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not 45 minutes ago, Google released their latest contribution to the internet: <a href="http://www.google.com/chrome">Chrome</a>. This effectively ended years of speculation that Google was writing a browser, that it would throw its hat into the ring and kick off another heated browser war.  <br />
Figures that Google wouldn&#8217;t just drop a bomb, it would lay waste to the expectations of a browser. My hat is off to the <a href="http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/">Chrome development team</a> &#8212; you guys pulled off a doozy.  <br />
<span id="more-1079"></span>Google (correctly) identified that there is a significant problem with browsers today: They&#8217;re too slow. That generalisation is borne of the increasingly complicated apps that are being developed each and every day on the web. There&#8217;s so many websites out there that require extensive scripting and content richness that even the most advanced browsers sometimes chug away.  <br />
So for only-Google-knows-how-long, the Chrome team slugged away with the fundamental problems of a browser: How to deliver something quickly. Browsers were all based on the same core model of sequential loading (there have been countless presentations to that effect) and this still causes a lot of optimisation headaches for complex web apps.  <br />
Google did what most mature applications do, and turned everything into multiple processes, running them independently so they&#8217;ll execute (overall) more quickly. Add onto that the complete rewrite and virtualisation of the JavaScript engine (courtesy of V8). Finally, take some of the caching/processing out of the browser and lob it over the fence to <a href="http://gears.google.com/">Google Gears</a> (another one of Google&#8217;s underrated little gems), and you don&#8217;t have a browser anymore. You have something worthy of using the internet.  <br />
Yes, all this high praise comes with a major caveat &#8212; I&#8217;ve only used it for about 45 minutes now. But that&#8217;s 45 minutes of trying to break it with everything that bothered me in other websites.  <br />
My personal favourite? <a href="http://www.flickr.com/">Flickr</a>. I love Flickr, don&#8217;t get me wrong, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey">I&#8217;ve got (currently) 6,515 items</a> and I will continue to use Flickr until either it disappears from the web, or I die. (Hopefully the latter will be the case &#8212; I don&#8217;t wanna move that many pictures and metadata.) My biggest gripe with Flickr isn&#8217;t even really with Flickr itself &#8212; it&#8217;s with how browsers handle the map.  <br />
I love to <a href="http://www.flickr.com/map">place images on maps</a> so I know where I&#8217;ve been. But the processing needed to do all that (without a plugin like Flash) ain&#8217;t light. And 30 minutes of placing images on the map in <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/">Firefox 2</a> would grind it to a halt, sucking up over 1 GB of memory. Although IE was better, its JavaScript engine was never very good. Firefox 3 was a huge step over Firefox 2 (it corrected the memory leak). None of them compare to Chrome. It&#8217;s ability to literally fly over the map astounds me. Thirty minutes of hardcore panning, placement, jumping, and moving (with the hybrid map turned on) did nothing to kill performance.  <br />
With 1.3 GB of RAM already in use by other applications, I should add.  <br />
And I need to figure out how on the internet (as opposed to &#8220;how on Earth&#8221;) Chrome managed to slice 75% off the loading time for <a href="http://www.rolex.com/">Rolex.com</a> down here. In Costa Rica (at least on the lousy connection I have right now), it takes forever to load my favourite website. But with Chrome, it was zip-BANG-done. I am stunned. <em>Stunned</em>, I tell you!<br />
(I should note that down here, the lags in response time are much more exaggerated. So when something like Chrome suddenly yanks those delays out, you notice it.)<br />
Okay, okay, so not everything is all sunshine and lollipops. I have noticed a few things:  </p>
<ul>
<li>Chrome ain&#8217;t perfectly handling <a href="http://www.wordpress.org/">WordPress</a>&#8216;s scripting. I have to remind Chrome where the cursor is supposed to be. (Noticed this as I write this entry.)</li>
<li>It&#8217;s lauded memory management seems a bit weird. Although performance wasn&#8217;t affected, Chrome seems to cache a lot of material in memory. Over 100 MB of data while I was in Flickr (and I&#8217;m sure I haven&#8217;t downloaded 100 MB of map data). Given, it cleaned it all up when I closed the tab, but it still seems odd.  </li>
<li>Chrome kicks up a minimum of two processes in memory. It seems to be one for the browser itself, and one per tab. This is inline with Google&#8217;s &#8220;multi-process&#8221; design &#8230; but do we really need to see each process?</li>
<li>Plugins. We need plugins. Someone build <a href="http://getfirebug.com/">Firebug</a> for Chrome, please!!</li>
</ul>
<p>Pros vs. cons aside, the biggest problem Chrome has is market presence. The average public doesn&#8217;t know about Chrome, and they&#8217;re not going to go out of their way to get Chrome (though they should). Despite a press conference that was held just before launch today, the average person will take much longer to even hear of Chrome, let alone use it.  <br />
But Firefox, my old friend, you&#8217;ve been supplanted. Chrome wins this round. I still like you, though &#8212; you&#8217;ve been a trusted friend and assistant for years. And you&#8217;ll remain in my development toolset until further notice. Do yourself a favour &#8212; learn from Google. They&#8217;ve got a few tricks that you haven&#8217;t picked up on yet.  <br />
And <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/ie">Microsoft</a>? [Picks up Ballmer&#8217;s head and slams it repeatedly into a concrete wall.] PAY ATTENTION. <strong>GET IT THROUGH YOUR THICK FUCKING SKULL</strong>. This is how development should be done. See how a real browser works.<br />
I suddenly feel a need to kneel at the Altar of Google and make a sacrifical offering. I hope a bottle of Coke will suffice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/09/i-heart-google-chrome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1079</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web Analytics Porn</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-analytics-porn</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=994</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[So this morning, I&#8217;m scanning through my Twitter feeds on Twhirl, and I came across a rather interesting note by Dave Fleet, which said: @cspenn planning to install it tonight. Waiting for the confirmation email. Long-winded installation process! Things like that tend to pique my curiousity. I&#8217;m a curious person. So I decided to see &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web Analytics Porn"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So this morning, I&#8217;m scanning through my <a href="http://twitter.com/">Twitter</a> feeds on <a href="http://www.twhirl.org/">Twhirl</a>, and I came across a rather interesting note by Dave Fleet, which said:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://twitter.com/davefleet/statuses/826847428">@cspenn planning to install it tonight. Waiting for the confirmation email. Long-winded installation process!</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Things like that tend to pique my curiousity. I&#8217;m a curious person. So I decided to see what Christopher Penn had wrote about it. I quote:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://twitter.com/cspenn/statuses/826843267">OMFG. Just installed Woopra and it really is web analytics porn.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>That just sooooo necessitated a look-see.<br />
<span id="more-994"></span><a href="http://www.woopra.com/">Woopra</a>, as it turns out, is free. I like free. Free is always good for evaluation, and if the evaluation goes well, I&#8217;m rarely objected to purchase. But that&#8217;s just me. The sign up process was a little slow, as I had to wait for an approval code first (it&#8217;s still in beta), but once it was set up, away I went.<br />
I&#8217;ve been using <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> for a long time (though I only realised this morning that I&#8217;d accidentally forgotten to put my new code in with the <a href="http://www.onehertz.com/portfolio/wordpress/mandigo/">Mandigo theme</a>, so I&#8217;m out of stats for the last month or two), and I&#8217;ve also relied heavily on <a href="http://www.feedburner.com/">Feedburner</a>&#8216;s stats to get an idea of how my site&#8217;s been performing. Overall, I&#8217;ve had little to complain about, but I missed having something real-time.<br />
A few years ago, <a href="http://www.schillmania.com/">Scott Schiller</a> turned me onto a tool that provided real-time stats. It was pretty cool to see the numbers come by, see where people were visiting from, and so forth. Compiled stats aren&#8217;t as interesting &#8212; it&#8217;s like reading the newspaper. It&#8217;s yesterday&#8217;s news. I want something that can tell me what&#8217;s happening right now. Not because I have a business need, but because I&#8217;m a nosey little bastard.<br />
Woopra is stats porn. Wow.<br />
Installation is simple: a snippet of JavaScript code not unlike putting in Google Analytics. You can then use Woopra&#8217;s site to see what&#8217;s going on, or you can download the (also in beta) desktop app. This is where you go hardcore.<br />
[flickr]photo:2550756431(medium)[/flickr]<br />
Not only is there a crawl at the bottom of the window (think stock ticker), you can see real-time where people are coming from and what they&#8217;re doing. The tools allow some pretty deep-diving for information, too.<br />
Does this hold up against other tools like Google Analytics? Yep. Some features aren&#8217;t the same, but it&#8217;s still in beta so there&#8217;s a lot of things they can yet change. Does it stand up to things like Omniture? Hell, no. Not yet, anyway, but taking on the 8,000 lb gorilla of web analytics is just not a wise idea, anyway.<br />
Woopra, if you&#8217;re listening, can I suggest a couple of changes?</p>
<ol>
<li>Allow me to exclude my own IP from the stats. I can&#8217;t see anything in the interface for this.</li>
<li>Let me set how long items stay in the live feed. I don&#8217;t have the most active site, and I&#8217;m a curious S.O.B.</li>
<li>Let me copy and paste items, like referrers. Just &#8216;cuz.</li>
<li>Put a sort into the search results &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of neat stuff that can be seen merely by sorting, before filtering.</li>
</ol>
<p>For an average schmuck like me, this is just plain fun. Now if you&#8217;ll excuse me, I&#8217;ve got website stats to watch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/06/web-analytics-porn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">994</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There&#039;s nothing quite like a good ego boost</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/theres-nothing-quite-like-a-good-ego-boost/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=theres-nothing-quite-like-a-good-ego-boost</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/theres-nothing-quite-like-a-good-ego-boost/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=973</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Over the last couple of years, I&#8217;ve been approached by a number of organisations looking for &#8220;talent&#8221;. (I use the term loosely, mostly because I don&#8217;t really see myself as &#8220;talented&#8221;. I like to keep that word for the artistically-minded. I prefer &#8220;skilled&#8221;, since it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve learned, and something anyone else following in my &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/theres-nothing-quite-like-a-good-ego-boost/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "There&#039;s nothing quite like a good ego boost"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last couple of years, I&#8217;ve been approached by a number of organisations looking for &#8220;talent&#8221;. (I use the term loosely, mostly because I don&#8217;t really see myself as &#8220;talented&#8221;. I like to keep that word for the artistically-minded. I prefer &#8220;skilled&#8221;, since it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve learned, and something anyone else following in my steps can learn. But I digress.)<br />
It doesn&#8217;t really matter how they found me, only that they approached me. Hey, I&#8217;m talking my ego here &#8212; believe me, it needs all the help it can get. Working at an agency with extremely skilled and talented people on demanding accounts will often leave you wondering: Am I really any good at my job?<br />
Then opportunity knocks. It&#8217;s really quite validating.<br />
<span id="more-973"></span>Over the last year or so, I&#8217;ve been approached by a number of companies, local and international, regarding some fairly high-level positions. Among them:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.avenuea-razorfish.com/">AvenueA/Razorfish</a> (twice &#8212; I just got a call from another recruiter for a different office)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.google.com/">Google</a> (yeah, totally honoured to get this request)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.replicon.com/">Replicon</a> (a local company that makes the time tracking software we use &#8212; I was very tempted)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.iqinteractive.com/">IQ Interactive</a> (also very cool, as they do some really neat work)</li>
</ul>
<p>And most recently, this morning as a matter of fact, <a href="http://www.yahoo.com/">Yahoo!</a> That&#8217;s also a very cool one, since I admire what Yahoo! does. It also doesn&#8217;t hurt that I know three people who currently work there (Jude, Scott, and Jim), and a couple who used to work there (Scott and Dr. Yes).<br />
If you at least feel wanted, then you don&#8217;t feel rejected. And that&#8217;s a good thing in my books.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/theres-nothing-quite-like-a-good-ego-boost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">973</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web 2.0 Expo: Even Faster Web Sites</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-even-faster-web-sites/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-20-expo-even-faster-web-sites</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-even-faster-web-sites/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 13:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=945</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Hanging out with Schill today, and he&#8217;s giving me some really great suggestions on what to see. Although the CM team did suggest something different, he&#8217;s saying we should see this one. Naturally, Schill knows the guy, but from his POV, this is a cannot-miss session. Presenter: Steve Souders, Google Used to be Chief of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-even-faster-web-sites/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web 2.0 Expo: Even Faster Web Sites"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hanging out with Schill today, and he&#8217;s giving me some really great suggestions on what to see. Although the CM team did suggest something different, he&#8217;s saying we should see this one. Naturally, Schill knows the guy, but from his POV, this is a cannot-miss session.<br />
<span id="more-945"></span>Presenter: Steve Souders, Google</p>
<ul>
<li>Used to be Chief of Performance at Yahoo, doing the same thing at Google now</li>
<li>Backend performance fairly trivial to handle</li>
<li>Backend time produces up to HTML; frontend is parsing HTML and loading other assets</li>
<li>80-90% of end-user response time spend on frontend; start there to optimise</li>
<li>Need to try follow the 14 rules (similar to the notes that appear in YSlow!)</li>
<li>Why focus on JavaScript?
<ul>
<li>Has a painful impact on loading pages</li>
<li>Scripts block parallel downloads and execution</li>
<li>Cuzillion is an automated script performance testing app</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Split the load
<ul>
<li>Only 9% of JS is needed on a Facebook page, but have to wait for 550k to load before any of it is used</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Split into at least two parts: What&#8217;s needed to render the page, and everything else</li>
<li>Separate manually (Firebug can help); Doloto from Microsoft can help automate this</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Parallel scripts
<ul>
<li>Write out the DOM elements to load the JS using JS (obj.createElement(&#8220;script&#8221;)), which allows parallel execution</li>
<li>Set up XHR eval to execute without blocking (some refactoring needed)</li>
<li>XHR injection, which allows XHR to attach the code (no refactoring needed)</li>
<li>Can insert code into iFrames as they run as parallel (note: must be on the same domain; some refactoring might be necessary for object reference)</li>
<li>&amp;lt;script defer src=&#8221;&#8221;&amp;gt; works only in IE</li>
<li>XHR techniques don&#8217;t trigger the browser busy indicators (e.g. spinning logo, mouse cursor); script in iFrame</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Long executing inline scripts block rendering of the entire page
<ul>
<li>workarounds: execute using setTimeout</li>
<li>move inline to external (see above)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Firefox blocks parallel downloads when downloading stylesheets
<ul>
<li>load inline scripts before stylesheets</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>[flickr]tag:web20expo+evenfasterwebsites@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-even-faster-web-sites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">945</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web 2.0 Expo: Friday Keynote</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-friday-keynote/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=web-20-expo-friday-keynote</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-friday-keynote/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[california]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conferences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=943</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Maybe it&#8217;s just me, but running keynotes every single day of a conference seems really silly, and waters down the value of the concept of a keynote. But I digress. Either way, this morning features Tim O&#8217;Reilly (again), Jonathan Schwartz (Sun Microsystems), Fake Steve Jobs (aka Daniel Lyons), Matt Cutts (Google), and Matt Mullinweg (WordPress). &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-friday-keynote/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Web 2.0 Expo: Friday Keynote"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maybe it&#8217;s just me, but running keynotes every single day of a conference seems really silly, and waters down the value of the concept of a keynote. But I digress. Either way, this morning features Tim O&#8217;Reilly (again), Jonathan Schwartz (Sun Microsystems), Fake Steve Jobs (aka Daniel Lyons), Matt Cutts (Google), and Matt Mullinweg (WordPress).<br />
<span id="more-943"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Another day, another video. This is the sort of stuff that should be delivered to clients, not to people who understand.</li>
<li>Co-chairs return the stage. Much clapping.</li>
<li>Housekeeping items.</li>
</ul>
<p>Tim O&#8217;Reilly + Jonathan Schwartz</p>
<ul>
<li>Looks back at the past and how things have gone.</li>
<li>Introduces Jonathan Schwartz, CEO Sun Microsystems</li>
<li>Schwartz sees blogs being one day achronistic</li>
<li>Sees one part of his job as communicating, which the internet serves well
<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s harder to do it inside the company; so answer both at once</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Most terrifying day when the General Counsel descided to write a blog (turned out to be really good)</li>
<li>Doesn&#8217;t think he&#8217;s terrified anyone but the securities group (SEC compliance, apparently)</li>
<li>Discussion about MySQL &#8212; what&#8217;s the strategy?
<ul>
<li>Deal is closed and integration is going well</li>
<li>Sun acquired a financial asset that is growing like a week</li>
<li>MySQL was actually working towards going public</li>
<li>Sun sees this as a way of expanding the market as a result of all the downloads</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Open source strategy connecting with the cloud strategy
<ul>
<li>The goal is about delivering value, not *how* that value is delivered</li>
<li>You have to reach out to the market with an asset, which will draw them into the network (cloud)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sun distributes 50MM Java runtimes a month</li>
<li>Cloud distribution of databases, not so much to worry about the database and more about making sure you can get the data</li>
<li>Moore&#8217;s Law supporting social networking &#8212; the cost to have thousands of cores is trivial
<ul>
<li>Scientific computing, which was traditionally the largest benefitter, is &#8220;collapsing&#8221; as they don&#8217;t get the same benefit</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Working to everything being virtualised</li>
<li>Efficiency doesn&#8217;t lead to less purchase &#8212; it usually leads to much more</li>
<li>Green computing
<ul>
<li>We&#8217;ve already hit problems</li>
<li>Costs more to run your server in Japan than the cost of the server itself</li>
<li>Not many of the CIOs are responsible for their own power bills</li>
<li>Sun wants to green their infrastructure to stay competitive</li>
<li>A fifth of all energy is just to move air around; very inefficient for cooling</li>
<li>Sun now builds data centres in shipping containers for fast deployment anywhere</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li> 1/3 more efficient than an equivalent data centre</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>ZFS to be GPL&#8217;d</li>
</ul>
<p>Fake Steve Jobs (Daniel Lyons)</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;It&#8217;s great to be here at the peak of the second dotcom bubble&#8221;</li>
<li>This guy is pretty funny in person</li>
<li>Long intro, but totally worth the time to hear it</li>
<li>Paranoid about being Twittered like Zuckerberg + Lacy</li>
<li>Why?
<ul>
<li>It was mostly a stupid prank, but was really boredom</li>
<li>Can&#8217;t believe he&#8217;s doing speeches about it now</li>
<li>Was also a part of fear &#8212; saw his business being distrupted by the web, so he decided to learn how to do it (hard partly been crucified by an articled &#8220;Attack of the Blogs&#8221;)</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>What if a transparent CEO went &#8220;nuts&#8221; and was insane on this blog?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Why Steve Jobs?
<ul>
<li>Seemed perfect &#8212; takes himself too seriously, no sense of humour</li>
<li>&#8220;Dude, it&#8217;s a fucking cell phone! Get a grip!&#8221;</li>
<li>Started as a sort of comic strip, then started adding news</li>
<li>Had 90,000 readers in six months; sparked the manhunt</li>
<li>The person who offered the reward to find FSJ was the publisher of Forbes (Lyons&#8217; boss)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Why does it work?
<ul>
<li>It works because the audience feeds him ideas</li>
<li>Has a Fake Noam Chomsky and Fake Vladimir Putin sending him ideas</li>
<li>It&#8217;s almost a social platform onto its own</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The big discovery is not taking content from another channel and putting it online, it&#8217;s about feeding back into the online media and watching it evolve</li>
<li>Thinks it&#8217;s not long before the big media companies figure out how to exploit this</li>
</ul>
<p>Rob Curry, Dash</p>
<ul>
<li>Connected GPS for cars</li>
<li>Crowdsourced traffic &#8212; other drivers provide info back into the system to provide real-time traffic updates</li>
<li>Can do Yahoo searches based on location</li>
<li>Can provide (anonymous) data about where people conduct searches (e.g. knowing where to build a new Starbucks based on requests)</li>
<li>Can subscribe to data sets for search</li>
<li>Has an interesting long tail</li>
</ul>
<p>Matt Cutts, Google</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;What Google knows about Spam&#8221;</li>
<li>People spam mostly for money, but also for recognition (e.g. church trying to get more people)</li>
<li>Build trust and reputation into your system</li>
<li>Make spams frustated, and they&#8217;ll usually stop</li>
<li>We know most of this stuff, nothing new</li>
<li>Can register the site on google.com/webmasters/ to be alerted to hacks or issues</li>
</ul>
<p>Matt Mullinway, WordPress / Automattic</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;AH-kiz-mit&#8221;</li>
<li>This guy doesn&#8217;t really seem comfortable on the stage</li>
<li>1/4 of traffic comes from the US</li>
<li>99.999% of blogs get under 10,000 pageviews a day</li>
<li>WordPress.com gets 10+ million pageviews to permalink pages</li>
<li>New feature: (Possibly) Related Posts
<ul>
<li>Introduces a form of personalisation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A Wikipedia and a half of new content is being generated each month on WordPress.com</li>
<li>http://ma.tt</li>
<li>Monotone (theme) will adjust the colour based on the picture in it.</li>
</ul>
<p>[flickr]tag:web20expo+keynote+friday@Geoff S.(thumb)[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/web-20-expo-friday-keynote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">943</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I pick on Microsoft</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/why-i-pick-on-microsoft/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-i-pick-on-microsoft</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/why-i-pick-on-microsoft/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 15:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yahoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/28/why-i-pick-on-microsoft/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;ve probably noticed a few posts about Microsoft on this site. Most of them are rants. And, indeed, there are those who&#8217;ve noticed me picking on Microsoft on Experience Matters as well. (Certainly, Neil&#8216;s noticed it and taken me to task on that.) But I don&#8217;t do it for the sake of doing it. Ranting &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/why-i-pick-on-microsoft/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Why I pick on Microsoft"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve probably noticed a <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/tag/microsoft/">few posts about Microsoft on this site</a>. Most of them are rants. And, indeed, there are those who&#8217;ve noticed <a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/2007/10/20/is-microsofts-popfly-an-easy-out/">me picking on Microsoft on Experience Matters</a> as well. (Certainly, <a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/contributors/neil-clemmons/">Neil</a>&#8216;s noticed it and taken me to task on that.)<br />
But I don&#8217;t do it for the sake of doing it. Ranting (bitching, complaining, whatever you want to call it) is pointless without reason. And it&#8217;s only with a bit of retrospect that I&#8217;ve come to the root of my problem with Microsoft.<br />
In short, Microsoft doesn&#8217;t suck. But it could be a whole lot better.<br />
<span id="more-914"></span><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft">Microsoft has been around for 33 years</a>, and has been a mainstay in the computer industry since the early 80s with the release of MS-DOS. They went from a small company of a couple of people to the largest software company on the planet, capable of wiping out smaller companies (witness the <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=microsoft+antitrust">countless issues with Microsoft antitrust</a>) in the act of solidifying their majority market share.<br />
Despite the &#8220;Evil Empire moniker&#8221;, Microsoft is a business that operates much as many businesses before it (such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Oil">Standard Oil</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Telephone_%26_Telegraph">AT&amp;T</a>, and &#8212; it could be argued &#8212; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Union_Pacific">Union Pacific</a>), which is to make money and ensure that your position in the market is solid. Yes, I chose those companies specifically (broken up by antitrust lawsuits, or accused of monopolistic habits), because Microsoft emulates many of the behaviours.<br />
(For the record, so do Google and Yahoo!, but no-one has gone after them. Yet.)<br />
Anyway, back to Microsoft. They&#8217;ve been around a very, very long time. Longer than 95% of other software companies (rough estimate, could be even higher). That longevity has brought them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wild success (Windows 3.x)</li>
<li>Significant failure (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_bob">Microsoft Bob</a>)</li>
<li>Tough competition (Google, Linux, Adobe, Sony, Apple)</li>
<li>Governments forcing Microsoft to recognise boundaries (namely, the antitrust suits in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_v._Microsoft">the US</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_Union_Microsoft_antitrust_case">in Europe</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>But something that I see more frequently from Microsoft is their inability to adapt to customer demands. In the earlier days, there wasn&#8217;t much of a need to do so &#8212; people were very quick to adopt new products and concepts, and upgrade constantly to get better, faster features.<br />
Incidentally, that kept in pace with hardware development, as well. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore's_law">Moore&#8217;s Law</a> meant that every 18 months, there were computers that could process your work faster (and hence more efficiently) than before. Moore&#8217;s Law is finally slowing down (we&#8217;re finally running up against the physical restrictions of the silicon medium), which means that most of the non-gamers out there (which is the majority) don&#8217;t really have a pressing need to upgrade frequently anymore. Computers more than two years old are still operating perfectly for the need.<br />
I think Microsoft&#8217;s last major push without significant objection was Windows 2000. The Windows NT platform had served Microsoft well in terms of building a solid operating system that could handle a variety of needs &#8212; and visual graphics weren&#8217;t too heavy a need (Windows was still largely a business-oriented environment). I also think the first major &#8220;why&#8221; started with Windows XP.<br />
Admittedly, my memory is a little fuzzy these days on specifics on this (nor can I find articles on this), but I do remember that there was a question &#8212; why should we move away from Windows 2000? Given, there was the end-of-life for Windows 2000 to consider, but from an end-user&#8217;s perspective, what was fundamentally wrong?<br />
Since that day, the &#8220;why&#8221; question has come up more often. <a href="http://apcmag.com/microsoft_humble_pie_over_office_bloat.htm">Microsoft Office continues to bloat</a> with features most people don&#8217;t need. I&#8217;m a proficient Word user, and have been so since about 1990, yet I use at most 50% of the functions in the system. (And yes, I used to be a Technical Writer, so I do know what Word has to offer.) The memory footprint of these software packages is also quite large &#8212; almost obscenely so when one considers the type of document these packages handle.<br />
And yes, I&#8217;m making comparisons to packages like WordPerfect, OpenOffice, and even some web-based items like Google Docs. I&#8217;m talking the ability to create productivity information and share it appropriately.<br />
More importantly is an issue I&#8217;ve had with large software companies for a long time: setting a   schedule and sticking to it come hell or high water.<br />
Yeah, I know, that sounds really silly &#8212; why is that a bad thing? For one reason, which I know very, very well in my own industry. If you set a hard deadline, you will (almost invariably) get to a point where shortcuts are necessary to launch the product on time. In the world of marketing, it&#8217;s often unavoidable to handle all the various moving parts of a campaign. But in the world of software, your restrictions are more under your own control.<br />
Microsoft has this problem. They release products before they&#8217;re ready. And problems occur. Vista is the single best (and most recent) example of this. So many shortcuts were made that <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/blog/main/archives/2008/03/why_did_vista_s.html">drivers were left uncompleted</a> (many vendors wouldn&#8217;t recommend them), the <a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20060518-6863.html">hardware requirements</a> put most people in the position of needing a new computer (Mac OS X &#8220;Leopard&#8221; runs on 3+ year old G4s without a significant problem), and everyone asked &#8220;why&#8221;?<br />
Why do I pick on Microsoft? Because after all this &#8212; 33 years in the biz and more collective experience than   most of the rest of the industry, combined &#8212; they should know better.<br />
Yes, I have high expectations for Microsoft. Experience demands it. They should know that rushing out a product is asking for trouble. They should know that making enemies of your customers will drive them elsewhere, and they should know that there are equivalent alternatives that people are more than willing to use.<br />
They should know. But I&#8217;m not seeing enough of the proof.<br />
What should Microsoft do? I&#8217;ve got a few thoughts on that:</p>
<ul>
<li>Replace <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Ballmer">Steve Ballmer</a>. He&#8217;s just not appropriate for that company. He doesn&#8217;t understand the industry and his ego writes cheques that Microsoft can&#8217;t cash. Ray Ozzie gets it, and he&#8217;s the kind of solid ego you can rely on.</li>
<li>Embrace your customer&#8217;s input on your software. Right now, if I have a problem, I have to call someone. Think forums or blogs. Allow people to bring the issues up, even let them rant. But let the community know that you&#8217;ve identified the issue and are working on it. (I still see certain issues &#8212; namely paragraph numbering &#8212; in Word that have dogged me for years that I&#8217;ve logged several calls on. Likely all long-forgotten.)</li>
<li>Make Windows free. Compete directly with Linux. You don&#8217;t have to go to the point of open source, but remove the barrier to entry.</li>
<li>Allow the community to write drivers. Why do you think Linux took off so quickly? All you needed was one person to write a driver to use Linux on a different piece of hardware.</li>
<li>Extend your evangelism program beyond developers to your business products. I still deal with sales people who want all-Microsoft implementations. The developer evangelists know that it&#8217;s not achievable, and it&#8217;s a great way to kill a sale. Understand what your potential customers have, and determine how you can help with what they&#8217;ve got. You&#8217;ll find the softer approach works much better.</li>
</ul>
<p>Okay. There&#8217;s my reason. I think Microsoft has potential. They just need to recognise it more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/why-i-pick-on-microsoft/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">914</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How much of the internet is a waste of time?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/03/20/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[So the other day, one of my coworkers starts laughing about how there&#8217;s this video out there, two somewhat-scantily clad women with tinfoil-wrapped boxes on their heads, doing a choreographed &#8220;dance&#8221; to Daft Punk&#8217;s Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger. Then it hit me. Someone &#8212; namely these two people &#8212; had to spend a considerable amount &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How much of the internet is a waste of time?"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So the other day, one of my coworkers starts laughing about how there&#8217;s this video out there, two somewhat-scantily clad women with tinfoil-wrapped boxes on their heads, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cva_sGN_0VA">doing a choreographed &#8220;dance&#8221;</a> to Daft Punk&#8217;s <em>Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger</em>.<br />
Then it hit me.<br />
Someone &#8212; namely these two people &#8212; had to spend a considerable amount of time creating this. Thinking up the idea, practising it, filming it (with however many takes to get through the mistakes and undoubted laughter), and editing it.<br />
Then it really hit me.<br />
How much of the stuff out there is a complete waste of time?<br />
<span id="more-912"></span>Maybe this is just me. Lately, I feel as if I&#8217;ve got almost no time at all. I get up, I go to work, run myself ragged all day, sprint home to spend (maybe) 90 minutes with my child before bedtime (including feeding the Wee One while eating myself, and sometimes making dinner), then make up the last couple of hours trying to tie of other things that need doing. And back to bed. Rinse. Repeat.<br />
No video. No fancy dance routines. No costumes. I&#8217;m lucky to listen to music in the spare minutes at work. Where the heck do people get time for this stuff?<br />
Examples that come to mind:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hKoB0MHVBvM">Diet Coke and Mentos</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.icanhascheezburger.com/">LOLCats</a></li>
<li>Let&#8217;s give a conservative estimate of 80% of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/">Youtube</a>, to name but one of many such sites<a href="http://www.youtube.com/"><br />
</a></li>
<li>People who write <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/category/rants/">really long blogs that really mean nothing</a></li>
</ul>
<p>By &#8220;useless&#8221;, I mean &#8220;adding no significant difference to the advancement of human knowledge&#8221;. Given, my definition. But the point&#8217;s the same: how much of the stuff out there on the &#8216;net is actually useful?<br />
For the record, I count myself in the list of useless &#8212; most of this website (with a few <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2006/08/15/calgary-transit-sucks/">notable</a> <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2004/04/27/how-to-throw-a-surprise-party-and-not-get-caught/">exceptions</a>, which seem to regularly show up on the popular posts lists) is useless. (It could even be argued that most of my job is useless by the same token, but I&#8217;m not going to go there right now, since that will get me very depressed.)<br />
So, the question is asked, and I&#8217;m curious to know what others think: How much is useless?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/03/how-much-of-the-internet-is-a-waste-of-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">912</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Maps in (a) Flash!</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/google-maps-in-a-flash/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=google-maps-in-a-flash</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/google-maps-in-a-flash/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 21:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critical mass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience matters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rich media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rolex]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/12/14/google-maps-in-a-flash/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, we posted a new part to Rolex.com: the ability to find a local Authorised Rolex Dealer. This on its own is hardly breaking any new ground &#8212; it&#8217;s a fairly routine piece of functionality. To help you find your local dealer, we provided a map &#8212; a Google Map. Those of you who know &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/google-maps-in-a-flash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Google Maps in (a) Flash!"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, we posted a new part to <a href="http://www.rolex.com/">Rolex.com</a>: the ability to <a href="http://www.rolex.com/en/inside-rolex/sales-service/find-a-rolex-dealer/index.jsp">find a local Authorised Rolex Dealer</a>. This on its own is hardly breaking any new ground &#8212; it&#8217;s a fairly routine piece of functionality. To help you find your local dealer, we provided a map &#8212; a <a href="http://maps.google.com/">Google Map</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img src="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/google-maps-flash-rolexcom.jpg" alt="Google Maps Flash Interface" /></p>
<p>Those of you who know the two technologies are probably now scratching your heads. Google Maps. Flash. Aren&#8217;t they incompatible?<br />
Not any more.<br />
<a href="http://experiencematters.criticalmass.com/2007/12/14/google-maps-in-a-flash/#more-142" class="more-link">Continue reading &#8220;Google Maps in (a) Flash!&#8217;</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/12/google-maps-in-a-flash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">876</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
