<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ruskin &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/ruskin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 03:06:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving in Ruskin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-in-ruskin</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2006 03:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abbotsford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maple ridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2006/10/09/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had a quick jaunt out to Ruskin (a section of Maple Ridge, BC) for the Thanksgiving weekend. It was a trip I wasn&#8217;t sure I was going to be able to take at first. Reason: Too much work, and too tight deadlines to allow it. Deadlines changed. Whether they changed for the better remains &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thanksgiving in Ruskin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a quick jaunt out to Ruskin (a section of Maple Ridge, BC) for the Thanksgiving weekend. It was a trip I wasn&#8217;t sure I was going to be able to take at first. Reason: Too much work, and too tight deadlines to allow it.<br />
Deadlines changed. Whether they changed for the better remains to be seen&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-476"></span>The flight to Abbotsford was easy. That&#8217;s why I like flying there instead of Vancouver. Alex was already on the coast, having spent a week visiting friends in Victoria and Vancouver. Borrowing a car, she was picking me up at the airport before heading over to Ruskin. It had been only a week, but I was so happy to see her again.<br />
Jean had dropped her car off at the airport, which we were to pick up. As Alex was driving a borrowed car to another location, we were a mini-caravan for a little while. Sandra&#8217;s car (which Alex was driving) was going to her parents&#8217; place, also in Abbotsford, so the trip was quick and easy.<br />
After dropping off the car, we stopped briefly at the farm to drop off our things before going to Maple Ridge to get the turkey. I honestly can&#8217;t remember what the heck we did for dinner, though.<br />
The next day, we visited with Joel and Michelle. For all the times we&#8217;ve been to Ruskin already, I felt bad for never dropping by. So we planned it this time. It wasn&#8217;t anything grand or whiz-bang, but it was a great chance for them to meet Alex, and a chance for us to catch up &#8230; in their hot tub. (It reminded me to get ours cleaned and running again.)<br />
We picked up dinner at Bruce&#8217;s Market, which really amounted to lentil soup with cubed ham. Dirt simple, but surprisingly tasty. We picked up Allen and Jean from the airport, returning to sample our home-cooked meal. There were no leftovers.<br />
We had Thanksgiving dinner on the Monday. Alex was on pie detail. I made cranberry sauce and worked on some of the vegetables. Meanwhile, the household was invaded by various family members all ready for dinner. We even got Audrey to come over (Frank was a given &#8212; he loves turkey). Dinner was at 15:00.<br />
Dropping Nichole off at the bus stop, Allen took Alex and I back to the airport for our short flight back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/10/thanksgiving-in-ruskin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">476</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Ruskin to Three Valley Gap</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2004 04:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kamloops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three valley gap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/07/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We awoke about an hour earlier than we have in mornings past, but for no real reason. We didn&#8217;t even hear the rooster! The porridge was followed, almost as soon as we could get ready, by a cat hunt. Allen has plans for his farm, which includes a new barn (of some kind). The problem, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Ruskin to Three Valley Gap"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We awoke about an hour earlier than we have in mornings past, but for no real reason. We didn&#8217;t even hear the rooster!<br />
The porridge was followed, almost as soon as we could get ready, by a cat hunt. Allen has plans for his farm, which includes a new barn (of some kind). The problem, of course, is that you can&#8217;t have a barn without having mice and rats &#8212; that&#8217;s just a side effect. They can be controlled, however, with cats.<br />
<span id="more-385"></span>Understand, Allen does not want cats for companionship. He doesn&#8217;t even want them in the house. Ever. He wants outdoor cats that will keep the rodents under control. They&#8217;ll have to contend with the wolves, coyotes, and bears &#8230; oh my.<br />
The trick will be creating a barn cat. A stray isn&#8217;t an automatic barn cat &#8212; it could just as easily be a wanderer and just leave the barn. To be honest, I have no idea how you&#8217;d do it. In my opinion, the only way to solve the problem is to create an &#8220;outdoor cat&#8221;, that roosts inside at night. That&#8217;s what both Sylvester (my first cat) and Spaz did. Both outdoor cats, but they knew where home was.<br />
The Maple Ridge SPCA had quite a few cats, most strays, almost all adults. Ideally, Allen would want to start with kittens, or at least non-adult cats, as they&#8217;d stand the best chance of getting familiar with the barn and consider it home. There were only two kittens there, so we headed out in search of more at a veterinary hospital at the opposite side of Maple Ridge.<br />
Striking out there, Allen headed off in search of something different &#8212; a haircut. Alex and I ended up on a quest of our own &#8212; the search for her grandfather&#8217;s grave. It had been 18 years and two days since he died, which was probably the last time Alex actually saw the grave. As you can expect, that meant it was exceedingly difficult to find. Despite a 40-minute search, the site remains unknown.<br />
We were back at the bagel shop again for lunch, where we met Allen with his fresh new &#8216;do. A bite to eat, and we were off back to the SPCA again (adoptions weren&#8217;t until noon, and the kittens seemed like a good idea). As we found out upon return, there were actually two sets of kittens. Two that were 12 weeks old, and two that were five months old. The interest was primarily in the older kittens (brothers named Tom and Jerry), since they were old enough to find for themselves, and young enough to not have any previous need to go anywhere.<br />
The kittens would not find a home today, however. Both sets required neutering first, and I think Allen was a little hesitant to move forward right away. This didn&#8217;t stop Alex from taking a moment to play with the two kittens, and an older cat named Hillary.<br />
(Alex would later tell me that Human Societies often give cats names to make them more appealing, even if they already have a name of some kind. So the names we saw were likely not their &#8220;real&#8221; names, if they had any to begin with.)<br />
As soon as we got back to the house, Alex and I packed our things up. The tent and fly had been moved to the front porch that morning to dry in the sun, the sleeping bags put through the washing machine and dryer. It was barely 30 minutes before we were all ready to go.<br />
We weren&#8217;t leaving the Lower Mainland just yet &#8212; we had one more stop to make: the family of Nicole&#8217;s adopted child. She had given birth three months ago, and given the baby up for adoption. Due to new adoption laws in British Columbia, you can now keep in contact with the adopting family, and even the child. Nicole actually has visitation rights.<br />
Why we were going was beyond me, and I didn&#8217;t want to question it. I think it was mostly to support Nicole. I have no connection to this child, emotionally or even through family. Even when Alex and I get married (no, we&#8217;re not engaged &#8212; calm down!), I still will have no connection. Alex&#8217;s connection is tenuous at best, as Nicole isn&#8217;t a blood relative. Then there is the question of how much contact there will be as the years go by &#8212; will the family, or Nicole, want to continue the visitations? It&#8217;s all very curious.<br />
We never met the father, but the mother (whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten) was extremely nice. They were certainly be outstanding parents for the young one, who will no doubt grow up in a loving, caring environment.<br />
Alex and I took our leave after a little while, deciding that we really didn&#8217;t need to be there. We had to be at Three Valley Gap before midnight, and had a long drive ahead of us. After a brief stop at the 7-11 on the Haney By-pass (for a Slurpee, of course), we headed to Hope.<br />
We stayed on Highway 7 for the trip out of the Lower Mainland, enjoying the quieter ride away from the Trans Canada. Passing through Hope, we switched to the Trans Canada (as it then turns north up the Fraser valley, with the bulk of northbound traffic going to the Coquihalla).<br />
The drive from Hope to Cache Creek is beautiful, but not fast. (The trip from Hope to Kamloops along the Trans Canada is over an hour longer than taking the Coquihalla.) The valley is narrow and deep, offering a wide variety of views as the road snakes its way along the canyon walls. Right along side the road are the two major railways: CN and CP, who use the Fraser canyon as their entry into the Lower Mainland.<br />
(CN and CP have an agreement that sends trains from both companies down one side, and up the other, effectively double-tracking the canyon. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd arrangement, considering how they compete with each other, but the predicent isn&#8217;t unheard of.)<br />
We stopped in and around Alexandra, which was once a station along CN&#8217;s line. Today, it is a name used only on a bridge, tunnel, and on a lodge that is now for sale. Alex wanted a photo with her name on it &#8230; literally.<br />
Kamloops appeared just before 19:00 (we&#8217;d left at 14:30). Instead of the other restaurants we&#8217;d eaten at over the last week, I wanted something a little nicer. So we stopped at Milestone&#8217;s. It was a chance to relax a bit before resuming our trip out to Three Valley Gap.<br />
Alex took over driving at this point, having to do the remainder in the dark. I felt bad about this &#8212; driving in the dark is difficult at the best of times. But we were driving through the mountains, which is not always fun. Fortunately (oddly enough), there were a lot of trucks on the same route, which makes driving a little easier.<br />
Unable to read any books, I read Alex my journals, which she cringed and corrected as I read. (Hopefully, all of the mistakes I made have been corrected.) Finishing that, we chatted for the remaining time.<br />
The lights of the Three Valley Gap Chateau blinked across the surface of Three Valley Lake. Suddenly, the anxious tension we were feeling (we really wanted to stop driving) melted away as we arrived at our destination for the day. We checked in, found the room, and took a necessary step towards restful bliss.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-ruskin-three-valley-gap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">385</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fort Langley</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fort-langley</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 04:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/06/bc-vacation-fort-langley/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[That stupid rooster woke us up again. We&#8217;ve taken to mocking it. If it crowed normally, we probably wouldn&#8217;t mind so much. I fell back asleep, though, and Alex went into the house. She came back to wake me up for breakfast. Fog was hugging the ground all down the river valley. (Not exactly unheard &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fort Langley"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That stupid rooster woke us up again. We&#8217;ve taken to mocking it. If it crowed normally, we probably wouldn&#8217;t mind so much. I fell back asleep, though, and Alex went into the house. She came back to wake me up for breakfast.<br />
Fog was hugging the ground all down the river valley. (Not exactly unheard of in the Lower Mainland.) Naturally, this set me off on a photography expedition. You have to move quickly with fog &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t last long once the sun starts coming up. I got some wonderful pictures, especially of a space amongst the trees near the tent.<br />
<span id="more-384"></span>Friends of Jean&#8217;s, visiting from Rocky Mountain House, arrived while I was traipsing around the yard. They were to be breakfast guests. Sadly, this would mean I couldn&#8217;t shower before eating. They had to meet me in all my &#8220;morning glory&#8221;. Thankfully, they seemed to not notice over the porridge, peaches, apricots, and toast.<br />
After breakfast (and a needed shower), Alex and I took Erika back to the ferry. But it was far from a direct trip. Although we crossed on the Albion Ferry again, we didn&#8217;t go straight through Fort Langley. Instead, we decided to hang around a while.<br />
Fort Langley holds an interesting place in British Columbia history. It was the first settlement in the Lower Mainland, and was the main outpost for the Hudson Bay Company. First founded in 1827, the original fort was abandoned due to small size and relocated upriver in 1838. A fire destroyed the fort, and it was rebuilt at the site of the current National Historic Park two years later. Twenty years later, for about one month, Fort Langley was the capital of the Crown Colony of British Columbia. (It was moved to Queensborough, now New Westminster, just after Christmas of 1858.)<br />
Although changed repeatedly over the last 150 years, Fort Langley tries to hold to a time long since past. This is evidenced by the well-maintained CN Fort Langley railway station (obviously no longer in use), the stores and shops down the main street (the IGA is almost unnoticable, until you see the sign), the Community Hall could be brand new &#8230; as of 1922. Not to mention the plethora of vintage cars that seem to frequent the area. (Along with, oddly enough, a near-endless string of dump trucks.)<br />
We zipped in and out of various stores (curious, antiques, hand crafts) until hunger got the better of us, and we stopped for lunch. Ham and cheese sandwich. (Thankfully, no diamonds.) With that, it was time to get Erika to Tsawwassen for her ferry to Sidney.<br />
After that, Alex and I were to go to Haney to go swimming. We were going to go to the water park near the ferry terminal, but at $20 each for a couple of hours, it seemed a bit pricey.<br />
We detoured through Delta, Surrey, and Langley in desperate search of a 7-11. (We did find a Canadian Tire, where we got rope for the hammock, and a set of knives for Allen and Jean as a &#8220;thanks for putting us up&#8221; gift.) You&#8217;d think that at least one of the main roads in those three cities would have a 7-11, right? Just one?<br />
Of course not &#8212; that would actually MAKE SENSE. What the heck is wrong with the world when you can&#8217;t find a 7-11?! Okay, yes, there were Macs stores, but we needed a 7-11 specifically, because we had a 7-11 Slurpee container that needed filling (and then emptying). I think we successfully killed over an hour searching for those illusive 7-11s. It was just wrong. The only ones we ever found were on the north shore of the Fraser River. It&#8217;s like the south shore is afraid of them, or something.<br />
The lineup at the Fort Langley ferry was long. But even with the length, it only took about three or four sailings before we got on. (About 40 minutes or so.) I was dying for something to drink. When we finally got across, we headed to Haney, and stopped at the 7-11/ESSO at the Haney By-pass. This solved two problems: Slurpee cravings, and a lack of fuel in the car. Our next stop was at the London Drugs, to drop off a roll of Alex&#8217;s film.<br />
This was where we were going to go swimming. As it was now so late in the date (the Slurpee search had killed a lot more time than we&#8217;d thought), swimming was dropped as an activity. (Turned out to be a good thing, since the Leisure Centre ended up being closed for annual maintenance.) Having to kill a little time before the pictures were ready, we looked at houses on the window of a local realtor. All I can say is, we won&#8217;t be moving to the Lower Mainland any time soon with those prices.<br />
Returning to the London Drugs, we first searched for a pair of sunglasses for Alex. She was having issues with the ones she had, and something new was in order. (When you&#8217;re missing an arm off the pair you have, a new pair is allowed.)<br />
The hammock was hung within 10 minutes of arriving back at the farm. It took a bit of effort, since the trees where we hung the hammock were rather smooth, having no small branches or knots to hold the rope high enough to use the hammock. Alex took to it almost immediately, while I went to help Allen with dinner.<br />
Roasted red peppers were my duty. Everything else was left over from the night before. This was when I finally met Nicole, Alex&#8217;s adopted sister. Nicole is one-quarter Cree. She had just returned from a summer in Toronto, working so she could go back to school this fall. We didn&#8217;t get a chance to talk much.<br />
Almost immediately after dinner, Alex, Nicole, and I headed over to Frank and Audrey&#8217;s house. Frank is Allen&#8217;s father&#8217;s brother, Audrey is his mother&#8217;s sister. Convenient family merger, ain&#8217;t it? Frank had just turned 90 &#8212; it was his birthday.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long, due to the late hour for them, and because Nicole was quite tired (her clock was two hours ahead of ours).<br />
[flickr]tag:fortlangley+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fort-langley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">384</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2004 04:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[british columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairmont hot springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruskin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/09/04/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "BC Vacation: Fairmont Hot Springs to Ruskin"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cory had called me yesterday. I didn&#8217;t know until this morning because I hadn&#8217;t checked my cell phone. I&#8217;d had a dream that things had gone horribly awry at the office, and for some reason, that had made me want to check my cell phone. Good or bad, something was up. Sure enough, our newest star hire had backed out &#8212; an extremely disappointing turn of events. I wouldn&#8217;t talk to Cory about it until late in the afternoon.<br />
We were gone before 8:00. (We were to have left at 6:00, then 7:00, but last night&#8217;s arrival in Fairmont pushed us even later.) Allen was in Jean&#8217;s Honda Civic, Alex and I in Alex&#8217;s car. I drove while Alex read &#8220;Why I Hate Canadians&#8221;. Today&#8217;s lesson? Canada&#8217;s cast system, more formally known as how poorly we treat Indians. It&#8217;s a hard thing for a Canadian to admit that we don&#8217;t treat everyone fairly and equally. For a country known as being &#8220;nice&#8221;, we treat our aboriginal peoples very poorly. We&#8217;ve marginalized, forcibly contained, abducted and tried to convert them, even poisoned them with disease. And yet after 400 years, they&#8217;re still who they are.<br />
<span id="more-382"></span>A lot of people think Indians have it easy here in Canada &#8212; pay no taxes, live on welfare, do what they please when they want. Lest we forget that we made them wards of the state &#8212; they *have* to live this way, because there is no other way for them to live. We never gave them a chance.<br />
(Incidentally, this is a view I&#8217;ve long held, and the book has since backed up. Ferguson is definitely a socialist who supports equal rights, nationalism (he rather dislikes the ill-guided attempts of Quebec separatists), and believes the monarchy should take a hike.)<br />
When we arrived in Golden, right behind Allen&#8217;s car, we headed to the Humpty&#8217;s on the Trans-Canada Highway for breakfast. I&#8217;d never been to Humpty&#8217;s before, having always viewed it as a lower-end sort of place to obtain a meal. My opinion of that hasn&#8217;t changed (the state of the bacon alone held me to that perspective).<br />
The weather yo-yo&#8217;d constantly from the time we left Fairmont until we arrived in the Lower Mainland. It was cloudy, rainy, spittling, sunny, warm, foggy, and windy all at various times (and varying combinations) throughout the trip. Alex seemed to get the bulk of the bad weather from Golden to Revelstoke.<br />
I read &#8220;Mythic Journeys&#8221; aloud. I disagreed with some of the interpretation, and wasn&#8217;t too thrilled with the depth &#8212; quite often, there was more commentary than story. It doesn&#8217;t make for great reading.<br />
We stopped in Revelstoke for drinks and snacks, and once again changed drivers. We stopped barely five kilometres past Revelstoke to make reservations at the Three Valley Gap hotel, which is a bit of a landmark in the area, and one of Alex&#8217;s favourite locations to be. (It&#8217;s a long story, which I&#8217;m going to forego with repeating here.) We&#8217;ll be stopping there on our way back.<br />
Off to Kamloops we went. We would have driven straight through, had we not also come across Craigellachie (&#8220;cray-GAL-ah-kee&#8221;), which was where the last spike was driven on the Canadian Pacific Railway in 1886. There&#8217;s not much there other than a cairn, bearing stones from every province and territory, and a stone from Craigellachie, Scotland, where most of the original directors of the CPR hailed from.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stay long. Just enough for a couple of photos, and a chance to mock some idiotic 20-something tourists from Ontario. They were being typical of that age: stupid. Though I never remember being quite so dumb that I would have inspired someone else to think of me: &#8220;Look at me, I&#8217;m an idiot!&#8221;<br />
Pulling into Kamloops about an hour later, running almost on fumes, we headed for the ABC Country restaurant on the junction of the Trans-Canada and Highway 5A. When we went inside, I realized that it was the same restaurant where Greg and I had eaten breakfast four and a half years before, when he helped me move from Vancouver to Calgary (see [[Left Vancouver, Job, and Girlfriend for New Start in Calgary]]). This time, thankfully, I wasn&#8217;t doing anything even remotely traumatic.<br />
Alex took over for the last stint of driving to Ruskin (a hamlet next to Maple Ridge, BC), where her father lives. The trip was much shorter than I had expected &#8212; for some reason, I thought the distance from Kamloops to Hope was much longer than we experienced. Mind you, the distance from Hope to Highway 11 seemed almost as long. (It didn&#8217;t help that we got stuck in traffic.)<br />
Dairy Queen made a call to us as we pulled off the highway. We&#8217;d been dying for a Blizzard since half-way down the Coquihalla Highway, but had missed the turn-off in Hope. Fortunately, the one on Highway 11 would suffice &#8230; even if some of the patrons were a little strange.<br />
Continuing up Highway 11, across the Fraser River (and getting a dirty look from a police officer at a radar trap for going a little too quickly), we turned west on Highway 7. Another 15 minutes, and we arrived at the farm &#8212; Allen and Jean&#8217;s new home, built on the former location of Alex&#8217;s grandparent&#8217;s home.<br />
We got a tour almost as soon as we were in the house. It&#8217;s an impressive structure. It looks unassuming from the outside, but there is much hidden under the covers. First and foremost, it&#8217;s a green building. It&#8217;s made with the most energy-efficient materials available, has radiant heating in the floors, recycling wood for the flooring upstairs, low-wattage lights, and nice, large windows to allow sunlight to come in during the winter.<br />
But the best feature was found tucked away, behind the garage: geothermic heating. This is the créme de la créme of cool (or heat, depending on what season you&#8217;re in). Because the house is built on an acreage, there is sufficient space to build this. (I could probably do this in Calgary, but I shudder to think at what cost.) A space about 25 feet wide, 80 feet long, and about seven feet deep was dug out behind the house and filled with long spiral tubes, and partially filled with clay. The tubes are then filled with a vicous liquid which tranfers heat in and out of the house. The system also hooks into the hot water tank to cut down on the energy needed to keep the water hot.<br />
The end result? Theoretically, a lower energy bill. If Allen has his way, he&#8217;ll also build a windmill to generate some additional electricity, and maybe even cut his BC Hydro bill to zero.<br />
A dream worth shooting for, indeed.<br />
Alex and I ducked out for a quick tour of the yard. The acreage isn&#8217;t huge (about 6.2 acres), with the main property lot about 200 feet on both sides, and then extending about 30-50 feet into the woods and down to the creek. The landscaping potential of this place is amazing &#8212; I have great dreams of a staircase and deck space down at the creek level. Now I just need to convince Allen that it&#8217;s a good idea.<br />
I pitched the tent (Alex and I are sleeping outdoors) under four great cedar trees on the east side of the house. The ground underneath is spongy from decades of cedar leaves and soil growth. Tonight, we will sleep well.<br />
I certainly hope so, because although today&#8217;s trip was outstanding, it really wore me down.<br />
[flickr]tag:craigellachie+2004@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/09/bc-vacation-fairmont-hot-springs-ruskin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">382</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
