<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CP 2816 &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/cp-2816/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 06:16:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>The Super Secret Monkey Surprise</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-super-secret-monkey-surprise</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 06:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For at least the last couple of years, Heritage Park finds a way to bring in Thomas the Tank Engine for the kids. (It&#8217;s a fake engine, but the kids don&#8217;t care.) The big thing is to ride the train behind Thomas, and tickets for the chance on the Day Out With Thomas sell out &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Super Secret Monkey Surprise"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For at least the last couple of years, Heritage Park finds a way to bring in Thomas the Tank Engine for the kids. (It&#8217;s a fake engine, but the kids don&#8217;t care.) The big thing is to ride the train behind Thomas, and tickets for the chance on the <em>Day Out With Thomas</em> sell out well before the day even arrives.<br />
This year, we&#8217;d resolved to get you on that train, Monkey. And &#8230; well, we did try. But apparently we&#8217;d waited too long (trying to coordinate with other parents) and &#8230; well, we blew it. This year, like last, probably all you&#8217;d have done is stood and watched as other kids got to ride the train.<br />
But, thanks to a fluke chance, you got to ride something those other kids didn&#8217;t even know about&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2935"></span>There are things you&#8217;re just starting to understand about your Old Man (that would be me), Monkey. One of them is that Daddy loves trains. And that Daddy will &#8212; if given the chance &#8212; go to long lengths to do train-related things. Like <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/">last year&#8217;s little chase of CP 2816 through the mountains</a>, or the model train show (although we couldn&#8217;t go this year, as it was the same weekend that I was recovering from surgery).<br />
Virtually the day after we realised that there was no way we were going to get tickets to ride Thomas, my friend Graham sent me a message that CP 2816 was exiting it&#8217;s winter maintenance for a shakedown run out to Carseland and back (about 80 kilometres, there and back). It was supposed to be a Canadian Pacific Railways employee-only event, but Graham has a little sway with a few people and very graciously secured two tickets for us.<br />
And thus was born the Super Secret Monkey Surprise.<br />
It was thus created for two reasons. First, I didn&#8217;t want to tell you in case some plan changed. It&#8217;s a weird situation when it actually makes more sense to surprise you rather than to let you know about something fun that might not happen. Second, you were coming down with something nasty (and particularly on Thursday night and Friday morning, you were really, really, really sick) and taking you out on Saturday might not have been the wisest of moves.  But, once Dr. Mom had given her approval, you and I set out for our little adventure.<br />
You kept calling it the &#8220;Super Duper Monkey Surprise&#8221;, which you were keen to recount to anyone who&#8217;d listen. You rambled on and on until we got to the Royal Canadian Pacific offices on 9th Ave. downtown, where we entered and went through a side door into the Pavilion, which is a mostly glass-enclosed space that houses Canadian Pacific Railways&#8217; fleet of vintage parlour cars used on the RCP train.<br />
No sooner had we entered the Pavilion itself than you asked if we could ride the train &#8212; you&#8217;d figured that part out. As if on cue, that&#8217;s when CP 2816 pulled into the siding outside, steaming away as its bell clanged.<br />
You were anxious, amidst a bit of coughing. You wanted to go on the ride, even though I&#8217;m sure you weren&#8217;t really sure what to expect. It&#8217;d been a long time since you&#8217;d been on a train (I&#8217;m pretty sure it was when we were in Scotland two years ago), and aside from Heritage Park, you&#8217;d never been on a big train pulled by a steam locomotive.<br />
We hopped on, and immediately went forward, finding seats as close to the steam locomotive as we could. (There was a baggage car, generator car, tool car, the 1900 and 1400 F-unit diesel assists between us and CP 2816, so it wasn&#8217;t like we could hear it really clearly.) The passenger cars are all vintage, with giant comfy seats and enough legroom to host a concert. It&#8217;s what rail travel used to be, and I (for one) greatly lament its loss in favour of cramped automobiles.<br />
Soon, the train slowly began to back up, and you got very excited to be moving. We had to back up quite a ways down the line (the siding is in part of the staging yard that allows the huge freight trains to line up to arrive and exit from Calgary westwards) before we could join up with the main line. Then, we started moving forwards.<br />
I can&#8217;t really remember the last time I rode behind a steam locomotive on main line rail. I was probably around 5 or 6, and it was most likely behind CN 6060 when it still ran steam excursions out to Niagara Falls. (I suppose you could consider CP 2860 when it was running North Vancouver to Squamish as well, but BC Rail was only a Class II railway at the time.) Only CP 2816 and the odd run of CP 2860 ever go on main line rail these days.<br />
It took a while for us to wind our way through the rail yards that stretch from downtown Calgary out to just past Ogden in the east. From there, the train picked up a bit of speed before passing through CP&#8217;s intermodal yard. After that, we were off!<br />
And so were you. You didn&#8217;t want to sit anymore. You wanted to get up and walk around. This is another reason I love trains &#8212; you can do that. Just try wandering on an airplane. You get weird looks. And Monkey, you don&#8217;t sit still, so really, a train is the best thing for you. And you saw just about every window and vestibule on the the train. Several times.<br />
We arrived at Carseland in about 45 minutes. In fact, it wasn&#8217;t even Carseland proper &#8212; it was a wye just to the west of Carseland that also services the Agrium fertilizer plant. It was more than long enough to &#8220;turn&#8221; the entire train. And, thankfully, it was also dry enough for us to get off and look around a bit &#8230; which, of course, means running up to the head end to get pictures with the steam locomotive.<br />
Take that, Thomas!<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/the-wye-at-carseland/' title='The wye at Carseland'><img width="300" height="225" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/The-wye-at-Carseland-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3275" alt="The wye at Carseland" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5726672548/">Geoff S.</a><br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/cp-2816-at-carseland/' title='CP 2816 at Carseland'><img width="300" height="165" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/CP-2816-at-Carseland-300x165.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3276" alt="CP 2816 at Carseland" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5726679944/">Geoff S.</a><br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/the-crowd-at-carseland/' title='The crowd at Carseland'><img width="300" height="179" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/The-crowd-at-Carseland-300x179.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3277" alt="The crowd at Carseland" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5726686720/">Geoff S.</a><br />
It was quite windy that day (it&#8217;s been quite windy for a few days, actually), and you wanted to get back on the train before too long. That gave you time to have more of your snacks and drink some more water, before resuming your incessant pacing up and down the train. I had to get you to stop for a while until the train moved again, so everyone could get on without running into you.<br />
On the way back, you made friends with another little girl, and the two of you (and the girl&#8217;s little sister, I believe) hung out in the vestibules, going from one stool to another to peer over the high doors. You never really seemed to mind your hair blowing in the wind, or the periodic shifting of the cars as the train rolled down the tracks.<br />
Although I don&#8217;t think you were quite as bummed as I was when the trip was all over. But you definitely said that it was fun, and how you wanted to do it again.<br />
I&#8217;m pretty sure we will.<br />
<a href='http://www.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/returning-to-town/' title='Returning to town'><img width="225" height="300" src="https://new.sowrey.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2013/04/Returning-to-town-225x300.jpg" class="attachment-medium alignnone wp-image-3278" alt="Returning to town" /></a>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sowrey/5726140553/">Geoff S.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2011/05/the-super-secret-monkey-surprise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2935</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four fun-filled days</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=four-fun-filled-days</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 03:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dim sum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Four fun-filled days"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I sit here at my kitchen table, rubbing the weariness from my eyes. Not the things you&#8217;d normally hear from me, mind you &#8212; I haven&#8217;t been working too hard as of late (as you know, my big project is done). No, this is from something much better &#8212; spending time with my family, and notably you, Monkey.<br />
The last four days have been a lot of fun. Maybe even too much fun. Both of us are pretty pooped. You went to bed and for the first time in a long while, there wasn&#8217;t hours of chatter from your room. I think you pretty much passed out. I won&#8217;t be too far behind you, I think, but I do wish to describe the fun that we&#8217;ve shared.<br />
&#8216;Cuz, frankly, I&#8217;m not sure how the heck I survived it all&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-2688"></span>First off was Canada Day. This year, Mommy and I decided to try a visit at Heritage Park. If you got there early enough, you got a free pancake breakfast. It seemed like a fun thing to do. And it probably would have been more fun if it had been a few degrees warmer &#8212; it was rather chilly for the first day of July.<br />
Still, you had a lot of fun. Once we&#8217;d gobbled down the pancakes, we went and got ride tickets. You swung on a vintage ship-styled swing, rode the big steam train around the park, went on the paddlewheeler out in Glenmore Reservoir (although you barely stopped moving the entire time, necessitating me following you around the entire time), and went on the merry-go-round (you demanded to ride the white horse).<br />
You ate a pretzel, and drank some frozen lemonade with me. We saw the farm animals (you mooed at the cows, and nearly had your bright red Crocs eaten by a misguided horse). Then we went through Gasoline Alley. By this point, you were tired and got fairly cranky, so we all opted to go home.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762441701(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762451847(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762453683(square)[/flickr]<br />
Mommy wanted to go visit with Grandpa for a week, and had to take Choo Choo with her. (Choo Choo&#8217;s still nursing, so she goes wherever Mommy goes.) But &#8230; well, Monkey, all me to be rather honest for a moment &#8212; travelling with you lately requires a lot of high-test drugs to keep people calm. Either you or us, it doesn&#8217;t matter. But Mommy travelling with you and Choo Choo wasn&#8217;t even discussed as an option, and Mommy really wanted to go without all of us in tow. (You&#8217;ll understand this years from now, when you have a near-3 year old.)<br />
Of course, what all that means is, it was just you and me, kid. And we got off to it before Mommy and Choo Choo&#8217;s plane had taken off.<br />
Our first stop was the Galaxie Diner on 11th St., not far from Grandma&#8217;s house. There we enjoyed a filling breakfast, because we had a long day of chasing trains ahead of you. I hadn&#8217;t chased a train since before you were born, and I was itching to go out and take pictures. I figured you might like to see a big train in motion, and when my friend Graham told me CP 2816 was going out to Banff on 2 July, I couldn&#8217;t resist.<br />
After breakfast, we went home just long enough to get a few things together (like my camera), and then we went searching for our first place to wait. I originally thought of a place known as Keith, which is roughly where Stoney Trail crosses the Bow River. But as we came down Sarcee Trail towards the highway, I spied an even better location: where the train tracks cross 32nd Ave NW. It would give me an easy access for photography, a decent backdrop, and not far from the highway to get back out again.<br />
We ended up having to wait longer than I would have liked. One thing you&#8217;ll learn, kiddo, is that when you chase trains, you have to be patient and wait. A lot. Even though Graham was sending me text messages on the train&#8217;s status, it didn&#8217;t come quickly. We saw a freight train have to wait for CP 2816, too. But eventually, we got the note that she was heading west. Before long, we could hear its whistle echo through the valley. It came towards us, barrelling along as fast as it could, belching out black smoke.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762469809(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763109230(square)[/flickr]<br />
For a moment, I saw myself in you. When I was your age (maybe a little older), your granddad (my daddy) used to take my family (Nana, Auntie Cathy, and me) to the train tracks near our house, to watch another steam locomotive &#8212; CN 6060 &#8212; come racing by, huge clouds of black smoke filling up the sky. It used to scare the hell out of me. Of course, I look back at that now and I feel really glad that I did see that &#8212; it&#8217;s a fond memory. I hope maybe one day, it is for you, too.<br />
We hit the road and headed out to a place out towards the mountains called Ozada. You were asleep before we were outside city limits, and slept all the way there. Ozada is on the Stoney Indian reserve, and is one of Canadian Pacific&#8217;s old stations for servicing steam locomotives. (The concrete pylons for the coaling and water towers are still visible.) Today, it&#8217;s little more than a siding in the middle of nowhere, just off the highway. And we waited there because Graham had told me CP 2816 would be stopping there for servicing as well.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762477071(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762477937(square)[/flickr]<br />
We were not disappointed. We saw the train come in slowly, pass by, and stop in the siding. After it had passed, we drove to the other end of the siding, and watched it race westward. (The train was about two hours late, so they had a reason to move quickly.) We drove out to the highway, and saw the train&#8217;s smoke as we drove by it on the highway. We saw some other people we&#8217;d seen back in Calgary stop at the side of the highway to take more pictures.<br />
Finally, we stopped in Banff, and waited about halfway between the station and Bankhead. We had to wait a long, long time before we saw CP 2816&#8217;s lights. As CP 2816 was going on show at the station, the train stopped again not far from us for one last servicing before going in. This gave us a fantastic view, although the whistles did give you a bit of a scare &#8212; they were quite loud.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762480609(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4763119200(square)[/flickr]<br />
After meeting up with Graham at the station (it seemed only fair to thank him in person for the information), we had lunch at Bruno&#8217;s, and then headed back to Calgary. You slept from Canmore all the way home.<br />
On Saturday, you and I went to the Calgary Farmer&#8217;s Market, mostly so you could go to the jumping castle &#8212; probably your most favourite thing in town (after me, of course). You ate your mixed berry crepe almost as fast as I could eat my ham and cheese crepe. I swear it&#8217;s the only thing you eat quickly &#8212; everything else requires a pry bar and a shovel&#8230;<br />
When I asked what you wanted to do next, you said: &#8220;I want [to see the] giraffes!&#8221; So off we went to the zoo. We went though the dinosaurs, then over to the giraffes, zipped by the gorillas, and spent a lot of time at the playground (you love the playground, there). Then it was into the Australian  pavilion  (I was devastated to find that the nocturnal animal area is permanently closed), through the monkey house, and then over to the elephants (where we had hot dogs), zipped over to the carousel (just opened), before going through the Canadian Wilds (where you were completely obsessed with the prairie dogs).<br />
[flickr]photo:4763125998(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762491661(square)[/flickr] [flickr]photo:4762511327(square)[/flickr]<br />
For dinner, I took you to a Japanese restaurant. I found that your chopstick skills had degraded quite a lot &#8212; we&#8217;ll have to work on that. But you ate half of the edamame, a couple of avocado rolls, and even a piece of hamachi sashimi (well, it was nigiri sushi, but it was just plain easier to give you just the fish). You wouldn&#8217;t touch the miso soup (I&#8217;ll work on that, too). For your first shot, I was very proud of you.<br />
The next morning, we walked over to the #2 bus stop. You were ecstatic about riding the bus. I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s from singing <em>The Wheels On The Bus</em> so much.   We went to the Silver Dragon restaurant, where we met up with my friend Tamara and her husband, Dan. There we ate dim sum (Mommy was rather annoyed that we went without her). It was so good. You ate buns, and pork dumplings, and quite a lot of deep fried squid. Yes, you ate squid. I kid you not. Mind you, as I&#8217;ve said to others, the squid tastes a lot like scrambled eggs. So I told you it was scrambled eggs. You couldn&#8217;t get enough.<br />
Following dim sum, you and I walked along the river over to Eau Claire Market (which really isn&#8217;t a market anymore &#8212; it&#8217;s mostly businesses and empty store space &#8212; nothing like it used to be), where you and I saw Toy Story 3. I cried a bit. You seemed to like it a lot, though. Especially anything with Woody.<br />
[flickr]photo:4762516489(square)[/flickr]<br />
In fact, you like Woody and Jesse (the Yodelling Cowgirl) so much, and because the Calgary Stampede is just around the corner, we walked over to Stephen Avenue afterwards to try and get you a cowgirl outfit. You&#8217;ve got the boots and jeans, but you need a hat and a shirt. Sadly, we were less than successful &#8212; no-one seemed to have a cowgirl shirt in your size.<br />
On the way home, much to our luck, we ran into Grandma on the bus (she was coming to our house, anyway &#8212; we just had really good timing). You had some fun with Grandma while I went off to get something for us to eat for dinner.<br />
In fact, I&#8217;m so tired from all of this excitement that it&#8217;s taken me a while to write all of this. But I hope you had fun, Monkey. I know I did.<br />
And now, I need to go to bed. &#8216;Cuz I&#8217;m really, really, <em>really</em> tired.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/07/four-fun-filled-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2688</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chasing CPR Empress 2816 from Calgary to Canmore</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 04:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/07/02/chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every time that I&#8217;ve chased CP 2816, it&#8217;s been eastbound. Never before have I had the chance to actually do a westbound chase. Today, I finally got that chance. I almost didn&#8217;t. A small crisis at work broke out, and I kept my cell phone at close range. I honestly thought I might get lucky, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chasing CPR Empress 2816 from Calgary to Canmore"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every time that I&#8217;ve chased CP 2816, it&#8217;s been eastbound. Never before have I had the chance to actually do a westbound chase.<br />
Today, I finally got that chance.<br />
<span id="more-761"></span>I almost didn&#8217;t. A small crisis at work broke out, and I kept my cell phone at close range. I honestly thought I might get lucky, get off one shot, and then head into the office. But my team is very dedicated and pretty much did everything without any additional input from me. I&#8217;m not sure whether to be proud that I don&#8217;t have to say anything, or be depressed that I&#8217;m simply not needed.<br />
Either way, I got to chase 2816 again. The last time I tried (see [[Surprise birthday weekend in Revelstoke]]), the timetables were so messed up that we didn&#8217;t get to actually chase her &#8212; she ended up chasing me, and I didn&#8217;t get any pictures. Alex was very patient then, but I opted not to drag her out with me on this run.<br />
I started off near Bowness Park, sitting on the edge of Bearspaw Dam Rd., a vantage that I thought might work okay. I probably should have gone further east to the bridge to get a better angle, but hey &#8212; it&#8217;s a first time, and I gotta try something different. I had a lot of time to doubt myself &#8212; the scheduled 9:00 departure should have put 2816 next to me by about 9:10. Assumedly, a late freight train held up the run, and I ended up waiting about a half hour until I could hear the whistle blowing east down the valley. It wasn&#8217;t long before I could see smoke, and then the headlights.<br />
Aim, click, run.<br />
The chase was on! After Bearspaw, my next thought for a location was quite a ways out of town. The tricky part is staying ahead of 2816. Bill knows how to run that engine, and Canadian Pacific tends to let her run open rather than put her in sidings. I drove pretty much flat out to Morley Road. There I had to wait about another half hour, along with a few others who got in my frame of view. I hate it when people do that.<br />
Once 2816 had passed, I was off like a shot to Highway 1X, and the overpass at Seebe. I made it with only a minute to spare.<br />
Aim, click click click click (I used the rapid shoot feature), run.<br />
I&#8217;d heard that instead of going right to Lake Louise (her end for the day), there would be a three-hour delay in Banff (Bamf!). Not wanting to spend that much time in Banff (Bamf!), I opted for a final picture just east of Canmore, along the 1A. The hard part of that wasn&#8217;t so much getting there, but getting there before the train. And to make things more nerve-wracking, I actually had to get far ahead and then run straight at the oncoming train.<br />
One minute to spare, again. Click click click done.<br />
Phone calls to wrap up the problem at the office came up during my return trip. It felt good to get out and chase again. It might be a while before I can do this again.<br />
[photopress:_MG_6449.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6455.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6459.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6461.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6463.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6471.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6475.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6481.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6482.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6486.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:_MG_6490.jpg,thumb,pp_image]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/07/chasing-cpr-empress-2816-from-calgary-to-canmore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">761</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chasing CPR Empress 2816 from Golden to Calgary</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/2816-chasing-golden-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2816-chasing-golden-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/2816-chasing-golden-calgary/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2004 23:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/26/2816-chasing-golden-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometimes, I think I&#8217;m part dog. They chase cars. Me? I chase trains. I don&#8217;t know why. Canadian Pacific is sending 2816 across Canada from Vancouver to Montreal in May this year, bringing along a load of very high-paying customers. The tour, arranged by a company in England, charged USD$25,000 per person for the experience. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/2816-chasing-golden-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chasing CPR Empress 2816 from Golden to Calgary"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes, I think I&#8217;m part dog. They chase cars. Me? I chase trains. I don&#8217;t know why.<br />
Canadian Pacific is sending 2816 across Canada from Vancouver to Montreal in May this year, bringing along a load of very high-paying customers. The tour, arranged by a company in England, charged USD$25,000 per person for the experience. Supposedly, the trip sold out almost immediately. I can certainly understand why.<br />
To prepare for this rather large excursion, 2816 has spent the large portion of the last six months undergoing a rather significant overhaul in Vancouver at the soon-to-be-demolished BC Rail Steam Shops. (Demolished because BC Rail is now under the control of the corporation formerly known as Canadian National Railways, and they have no need for steam shops in valuable rail yard property.) After a few tests, someone (not sure who, nor am I going to complain) felt a good shakedown run was needed.<br />
A run out to Calgary.<br />
As soon as the rail community catches wind of something like this, plans start swinging into shape. Although not publicized like the Inaugural Run (see [[The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816]]), there was still a fair bit of information being distributed. It is safe to say that there will likely be more publicity behind the Trans-Canada Steam Express when it runs 10 May to 30 May. (With ticket prices like that, and the train itself as the showpiece, you can expect to hear about it.)<br />
On Saturday, I decided I would chase from Golden to Calgary &#8212; a distance of about 260 km. I wouldn&#8217;t go all the way to Golden, since the canyon from just east of Golden for about 25 km is more-or-less useless for shooting. Instead, I started at the roadway that we used to go down for the Kootenay River Runners for whitewater rafting. We were just east of the area Canadian Pacific calls Palliser.<br />
Now I know what you&#8217;re thinking. You&#8217;re thinking: &#8220;Geez, Geoff, you&#8217;ve already chased that thing twice before! (See [[The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816]] and [[Chasing CPR Empress 2816 to Brooks]].) Why do you want to do it again?&#8221; Simple: No two chases are the same. There&#8217;s always something different, and you always meet new people. Besides, it&#8217;s as good a reason as any to get out of the city for a few hours.<br />
I was originally not going to travel alone &#8212; I had hoped Graham might come along. Unfortunately, Graham and his wife are preparing to move out of their condo, so he didn&#8217;t have time. He did offer me one bit of advice: get a shot at Ottertail. I knew of the place called Ottertail, but admittedly had no idea where it was. By description, I had thought I&#8217;d have seen at least a sign for Ottertail Creek. As it stands, I ended up in Palliser, giving up on finding Ottertail to the west.<br />
A good 40 minutes early before 2816 would even depart from Golden, I took the opportunity to take in the majesty of the Rocky Mountains in spring. It was about two degrees, but the chill was stayed by a bright sun. When the nearby Trans-Canada Highway wasn&#8217;t carrying vehicles past, you could hear the wind whistling through the conifer needs, a small babbling brook, birds of several varieties, and the distant rumble of east-bound freight trains.<br />
Unlike the last time, CP wasn&#8217;t about to shut down the Mountain and Laggan subdivisions just so The Empress would have an easy go of its route. The freight still had to go through. A lumbering eastbound popped into view about 20 minutes after I first heard it, blatting its horn as it approached the crossing. This gave me a chance to take a test photo of the angle I had wanted. Assuming 2816 arrived before it was too late, the sunlight would be good.<br />
Not long afterwards, a CP Police truck rolled down the logging road from the highway. This was my first sign that I had for certain not missed 2816. The officer told me that there was a video crew shooting HDTV for the History Channel, or some such thing, and that they&#8217;d probably want to set up around where I was standing at the time. I thanked the officer for the information and let him know that I&#8217;d keep it in mind. With that, he bade me a good day, and rolled off to wherever he needed to be next.<br />
A lot of people give railway police a lot of grief. They think of them as &#8220;near cops&#8221; rather than the full thing. Most people don&#8217;t realize that railway police have the same authority as regular police within 500 metres of railway property. That means for (at minimum) a kilometre-wide swath of land running across several parts of the country, a railway police officer can arrest and charge you with a criminal offense, the same as the RCMP.<br />
Most of them, for the record, are nice people. A few throw the odd &#8216;tude, and a couple are a tad on the racist side (particularly east of Calgary, near the Native reservations). But treat the police with respect and don&#8217;t try to be an idiot, and generally they&#8217;ll treat you the same. I haven&#8217;t had any negative experiences with railway cops &#8212; just tell them what you&#8217;re doing, and they&#8217;ll let you keep doing it. (Unless it&#8217;s illegal, of course.)<br />
Before long, I was no longer the only person at the crossing. An elderly gentleman, who knew some of the Rocky Mountain Rail Society members (he had received news of the schedule from them), and his wife took up station by the crossing. The man set up his camera a bit down the track, and the woman stayed in the truck to relay information from the radio chatter. (I need to get myself a scanner one of these days.)<br />
By the time 2816 could be heard chugging up the hill, I had joined the older man on the south side of the tracks &#8212; the sun had risen far enough that my north vantage was decidedly poorer than it had been earlier. Over the loaded chuffing was the distinctive whine of an SD40-2, #6067 (in desperate need of a new paint job, I might add) following right behind the two tenders. CPR 2816 is a powerful locomotive, but doesn&#8217;t have the oomph needed to pull the train it carried over the Mountain and Laggan subdivisions, facilitating the need for the diesel. (The Empress now has MU controls, so it can operate the diesels directly, rather than having to have additional crew.)<br />
On the train were CP 2816, its two tender cars, diesel locomotive SD40-2 6067, three tuscan red boxcars (including the much-needed tool car), the &#8220;Dominion&#8221; (buffet car), the &#8220;Smokie Smith&#8221; (recently renamed after a war hero), the &#8220;H.B. Bowen&#8221; (functioning as the CP crew car), and two California Zephyr Budd-built cars, the &#8220;Silver Lariat&#8221; and the bullet-nosed &#8220;Silver Solarium&#8221;. (The Zephyr cars are apparently for a hoity-toity excursion from Calgary to Vancouver, and were deadheaded with 2816 &#8212; though there were passengers on the cars from Golden to Calgary.)<br />
As we were at a crossing, we got to hear the new whistle on 2816 as it approached. For some reason I have yet to learn, CP went out and acquired the whistle from 2-10-4 #5935, currently resting at the Canadian Railway Museum in St. Constant, Quebec (see <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/journals/20020928.shtml">28 September 2002</a>). How they got it, I can&#8217;t even begin to imagine (aside from a large cash infusion into the non-profit&#8217;s coffers, anyway). Why they got it, I&#8217;m not sure. But I do have to say, it sounds nice. Different, though. I&#8217;m not yet decided if I like it or 2816&#8217;s previous whistle.<br />
Leaving Palliser, I headed down the road to try and find my next spot. Finding 2816 having stopped not far away (the switches were full with two trains, and one had to move before 2816 could proceed), I blasted ahead to an overpass near the east end of Leanchoil. It would have been an ideal photo, the sunlight on a perfect angle, were it not for a westbound intermodal on the east track, blocking the view of the west track. Dejected, I continued east.<br />
I spotted a crossing not far from the stop, spied easily by all the cars parked at the side of the road, and people milling around. I quickly pulled in and tried to find a good spot to take the photo. Although the track itself bended nicely, there wasn&#8217;t any suitable high ground from which to get a good shot. I had to settle for something mildly interesting. As 2816 rolled past, I waved at the passengers in the cars, as I had done at Palliser. And then I spotted her &#8212; my friend Terri was on board, about halfway down Dominion, waving back. She knew I was big on the chase.<br />
At an unnamed bend a few miles away, I found several people camped out at the side of the highway. It looked like a decent area, and thought this might be the infamous Ottertail. It wasn&#8217;t. Still, I stuck around for a photo, and chatted with the other chasers while waiting for the train. It soon whistled its way around a bend, and shutters flew open and shut. Then it was back in the car and off to the next point.<br />
On the way west, I&#8217;d seen a small bridge that I thought might be Ottertail. The only person there was having difficulty setting up his shot. He didn&#8217;t know what the area was called, but it wasn&#8217;t Ottertail. It was also a lousy shot due to so many trees between the ridge and the bridge. Five minutes and a few sticks of dynamite would have done wonders for photography&#8230;<br />
Driving further east, I came across a large number of cars parked at the sides of the highway. Simple rule when you&#8217;re chasing trains: if there are a lot of cars parked at the side of the road, chances are there are a lot of people who know what the angle there is like. I scampered out of my car, scooted across the highway and hopped the concrete barrier. I hiked over to a creek valley where the people were standing, to find that I had arrived at the mythical Ottertail. It&#8217;s a beautiful area to shoot, despite a couple of poorly-placed trees.<br />
As I took up my position, I glanced around to see who else I recognized from the previous stops. One of them I did a double-take on, because suddenly, I realized that I knew the person.<br />
&#8220;Geoff?&#8221;<br />
It was Mel, the photographer from McKinley Masters. He and I have been working on the McKinley Masters website, improving the content with more pictures. I hadn&#8217;t realized that Mel chased trains, too. It was something else we had in common. We didn&#8217;t get a chance to talk, though &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t long before 2816 came barrelling through.<br />
Focus. Click. Snap. Run. Drive.<br />
A few of us staged ourselves at the bridge over the CPR at the west end of the Field yard. One even got up the gumption to go down to the ground level and shoot from there (the elderly man I had met at Palliser, who was still with the rest of us, had suggested the same).<br />
The train needed to stop at Field to get batteries for the passenger cars. (Apparently one of them had died.) This gave the photographers a chance to get some up-close shots of the train, and the video crew to readjust their camera on the front of the locomotive.<br />
I left long before the train did and headed up to Cathedral, where a short tunnel covers the eastward rise up the Kicking Horse Pass. It&#8217;s a great place to get a few shots. I wasn&#8217;t the first to arrive, and I wasn&#8217;t the last. We probably had about 25 people up there at the high point, including a few CP employees (notably The Empress&#8217; runahead crew, and the manager for the Royal Canadian Pacific passenger train), and the video crew. We had a while to wait.<br />
It was cold. Barely above zero, and really windy. There&#8217;s not a lot of cover up there, either. The videographer stood out in a button-up shirt for the better part of 30 minutes before sending his partner back for his jacket. It even snowed a bit while we waited. It wasn&#8217;t as cold as when I chased 6060 back in 2001, but it was still uncomfortable.<br />
Originally, 2816 was to meet the Royal Canadian Pacific (heading out to Vancouver for some big-name excursion) at Cathedral, where a siding allows two trains to pass on the mountain. Owing to a bit of a delay in Field, we were treated to a runby of the RCP on it&#8217;s way west. Led by 1401 (1400 apparently is in the shop), we found the errant 3084, which normally rides behind the Empress. We photographers would have far preferred 3084 to 6067, but then we weren&#8217;t the ones forking out for paying customers.<br />
The Empress soon chugged up the mountain, belching huge clouds of smoke as it struggled with the weight behind it. You could hear the whine of 6067 kicking in when it was needed, and dying down when the grade eased up a bit. The hoggers on 2816 like to make her work whenever possible &#8212; most hoggers do in general &#8212; so killed the diesel as much as they could get away with.<br />
I stopped at the Spiral Tunnel lookout, despite the parking area being closed, and snapped off a couple of photos before continuing to the summit. There, I found a pair of CP employees (both chasing the train) who had climbed up the side of a fair steep hill to get a good vantage. The light was lousy, but I tried it anyway.<br />
On the east side of the pass, west of Lake Louise, I found my little bridge again to take some more pictures. It was only myself and a pair of men with their children. We almost didn&#8217;t hear 2816 coming &#8212; it&#8217;s all downhill to Lake Louise, and neither locomotives were under any load at all. They sailed right through, the linkages clanking on 2816, followed by the hum of the diesel.<br />
I bypassed Lake Louise completely, opting for Morant&#8217;s Curve instead. The last time I was at Morant&#8217;s Curve was for 2816&#8217;s inaugural run (see [[The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816]]), it was about one degree and early in the morning. This time, it was a bit warmer (about six degrees) and well into afternoon. The light wasn&#8217;t going to be great, but unless 2816 ran from the first thing in the morning, the light would never be ideal.<br />
The video crew arrived just as 2816 made its approach to the curve. I have no idea if they even got anything useable on film. After that, it was a harrowing race east along Highway 1A (average speed: 90 km/h, including all the hairpins; average speed limit: 60 km/h) just to keep up. I caught shots at mile 100, shot through Banff to just east of Canmore (I was the only one there), the Highway 1X bridge east of Exshaw, and finally back to Calgary.<br />
I laid in wait at Edworthy Park, where the CP line runs through into town. I had hoped for a better setting, but the leaves aren&#8217;t out fully, so I had a bit of a more dismal backdrop. My camera battery also decided to give me trouble, and I missed the nose shot, and had to settle for a departing view.<br />
Didn&#8217;t matter, though. I had what I wanted: a full day of running through the mountains, following a hot hunk of iron on wheels. I still think I&#8217;m quite insane for this bizarre little hobby of mine, and I certainly can&#8217;t explain why I do it, but I love it all the same.<br />
[photopress:193-9322_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9324_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9330_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9332_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9333_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9334_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9335_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9336_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9338_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9339_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9343_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9344_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9345_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9346_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9347_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9348_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9349_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9350_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9351_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9352_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9353_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9355_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9356_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9357_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9360_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9362_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9363_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9364_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9365_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image][photopress:193-9366_crw.jpg,thumb,pp_image]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/2816-chasing-golden-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">352</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chasing CPR Empress 2816 to Brooks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/2816-chasing-brooks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2816-chasing-brooks</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/2816-chasing-brooks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2003 18:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2003/05/25/2816-chasing-brooks/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While this weekend was absolutely amazing, too many of these and I&#8217;ll die from exhaustion. I started early Saturday morning. Those of you who are chiming in with &#8220;must be train stuff&#8221; can smile smugly &#8212; &#8216;cuz you&#8217;re right. But it wasn&#8217;t with 6060. This was my first chase since 6060 last year (see [[Chasing &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/2816-chasing-brooks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Chasing CPR Empress 2816 to Brooks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While this weekend was absolutely amazing, too many of these and I&#8217;ll die from exhaustion.<br />
I started early Saturday morning. Those of you who are chiming in with &#8220;must be train stuff&#8221; can smile smugly &#8212; &#8216;cuz you&#8217;re right. But it wasn&#8217;t with 6060. This was my first chase since 6060 last year (see [[Chasing CN 6060 Stettler to Big Valley]]), and this was a lot more challenging. 6060 doesn&#8217;t move very fast &#8212; it can&#8217;t because of the track it runs on. This chase, however, as significantly faster.<br />
The Canadian Pacific Railway is taking their steam locomotive, 2816, out east on the &#8220;Breakfast for Learning&#8221; tour. It&#8217;s the biggest run they&#8217;ve done since the engine was overhauled. From here to Toronto and back, in about 45 days, making a lot of stops between here and Toronto. Saturday was their first leg, from Calgary to Medicine Hat. And I wanted to follow it across the prairies.<br />
I decided I would pick up the train at the old CP Ogden shops (now owned and operated by Alstom). Although the east end of Alyth had a great place to take a picture with a bridge, the light wasn&#8217;t cooperative, and there was no place to park my car. I was the first to show up at my location, but I was soon joined by a few others: the director who was responsible for the locomotive and the train, one of the other members of the Rocky Mountain Rail Society, the parents of one of the train&#8217;s crew, and a guy who had been born and raised in the Ogden area and who&#8217;s father had opened the nearby Ogden Garage in the 1920s.<br />
The train was to leave at 7:00, but started off the day running late, for some reason. When it finally reached us, around 7:20 or so, it looked gorgeous, and running beautifully. It passed by at about 30 km/h &#8212; not very fast. Not yet, anyway. Piling into my car, I gave chase.<br />
I was hoping to catch the train at the east end of the intermodal yard on the east side of the city. But due to a wad of people getting in my way, the train ended up alluding me. Because of the much warmer weather than the last time I chased 2816 (see [[The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816]]), there was no steam cloud to see at a distance. All I had to rely on was the fireman every so often putting too much oil in the burner and creating a bit of smoke. I still don&#8217;t have a scanner, which makes following the train&#8217;s progress very difficult.<br />
Passing the intermodal yard, I started onto a gravel road, with two other cars in front of me. I couldn&#8217;t see anything but the dust cloud they kicked up. Finally, we reached a paved road, and I turned south to try and catch up. I reached 22X, and headed east again. I had no idea where the train was, other than it was ahead of me.<br />
The new map I had purchased at the ESSO station actually showed where the railway went, and I still had to go a fair bit south to find the line again. That&#8217;s the problem with chasing trains on the prairies &#8212; the highways rarely follow the tracks. At least on the Laggan sub, I can keep up because there ain&#8217;t a lot of room &#8212; and there the highway *does* follow the railway.<br />
I raced down Highway 24, hoping I&#8217;d be able to catch the train down there. Just as I came over a hill near to where the 24 turns east, I saw the train coming to the crossing. I arrived mere seconds before the train crossed it, but I didn&#8217;t have time to get a picture. The chase was on again!<br />
Further down the road, I stopped in a farmer&#8217;s field east of Carseland to take a picture. As the railway was curving away again, I had to race down more highways to hook back up again. I turned out on to Highway 817 and then onto 901 to continue following. At this point, the train wasn&#8217;t too hard to follow &#8212; the tracks weren&#8217;t too far from the road. The train got held up in Strangmuir for 15 minutes to undergo some greasing, which allowed me to find a comfy little field that sported a small bridge that the train was going to go over. There I found one of CP&#8217;s rail traffic controllers (RTCs), who dispatched the Brooks sub (the line we were both chasing down). He didn&#8217;t go on shift until noon, so had some time to chase.<br />
I caught the train again where the tracks cross the 901, along with a few others including an A-Channel truck. Then to Gleichen, where I met a rather racist CP police officer, snapped a photo, and ran off to Cluny. There, I met up with the RTC again. He suggested Bassano as the next decent stop, so off we went. This time, I followed him, and it was good that I did. He led me right to the best spot to get a picture. Pretty much where everyone else chasing the train was: an old CP railway station and a rather large yard.<br />
There I met a couple of far more professional photographers who suggested my next venue: the Brooks Aqueduct. Once the train had left, we were off. Brooks is about 180 kilometres southeast of Calgary, heading towards Medicine Hat. Brooks is pretty much the last stop before you enter the vast, barren plains of the southern prairies. There ain&#8217;t much in Brooks, which really surprised me when I saw on my map a marker for &#8220;Brooks Aqueduct National Historic Site&#8221;. It wasn&#8217;t too hard to find. All you have to do is find the sign on the highway, and drive south until you see a huge concrete aqueduct, like a modern version of a Roman aqueduct.<br />
But modern it isn&#8217;t. I parked in the interpretive centre&#8217;s lot, and was immediately met by Lee, one of the two interpreters at the site. She was a little puzzled by why I was there &#8212; though most of their visitors come from Calgary. I explained that I was chasing a train. Yes, I did get a rather strange look. She recommended that I walk down the aqueduct canal to the siphon, which was apparently the best place to see trains in the area. Thanking her for the advice, and promising to come back, I went off in search of my quarry.<br />
The canal is a huge earthen trench built up on the floor of the shallow valley that Brooks sits in. Barely 100 metres to the north of the canal is the old aqueduct, no longer in service. (More on it in a moment.) I walked until the canal &#8220;ended&#8221; at the railway &#8212; where an inverse siphon runs under the railroad and re-enters the canal on the other side. The siphon works on the venturi principle &#8212; basically, what goes in has gotta come out.<br />
I was well ahead of the train, which gave me a lot of time to wander around and find the best place to take a picture. By the time I&#8217;d found the ideal place, three more photographers showed up, including the guys who&#8217;d told me about the place. We took our positions and waited.<br />
Soon, the light appeared in the distance, and the train raced towards us. Though not going at full speed, it didn&#8217;t take long to pass. I have to completely agree with Lee and the photographers &#8212; the aqueduct was the best place to see this train.<br />
I returned to the interpretive centre, where Lee came out to meet me. I asked her for her perspective on the aqueduct. (I told you I was getting back to this.) Back in the early 1900s, CP was in the colonizing business. There was a lot of money to be made in bringing people to the west. Especially if you&#8217;d bought all the land around the railway tracks when you built them, and sold it off to the immigrants who paid you to come west. However, not all parts of the west were ideal for farming &#8212; some are quite dry.<br />
Such is the case with the area east of Brooks. No significant rivers, no lakes, and little rainfall poses a lot of problems. To make the area saleable, CP had to provide water for irrigation. This lead to the need to dam the Bow River at Bassano, then move the water through canals to the east. At Brooks, the land forms into a shallow valley that created a problem &#8212; without massive (and expensive) pumps, there was no way to get the water to the east. CP&#8217;s engineering department came up with the solution: the Brooks Aqueduct.<br />
At 3.2 kilometres long, and upwards of 90 feet tall, it was the largest aqueduct in the world at the time. It pushed all the boundaries of construction knowledge, which also led to problems. Most revolutions don&#8217;t go off very well the first time. The alkaline water dissolved the concrete, the lead expansion joints leaked constantly, the spars across the top of the sluice caused backflow, and the 0.01% grade kept the water moving so slowly that silt, plants, and even fish slowed the water flow. The aqueduct only ever reached 2/3 of its planned capacity. After an extensive and expensive overhaul in the 1930s, the aqueduct was turned over to the local farming collective.<br />
By the 1970s, the aqueduct was costing too much to repair. The local governments decided to replace it with an earthen canal that provided more water than the aqueduct ever could have (even if it had reached full capacity), and doesn&#8217;t leak. The old aqueduct was made a National Historic Site in the 1980s.<br />
I drove down the length of the aqueduct to get a good look at it. Well, as much as I could. Once decommissioned, the aqueduct no longer received maintenance. To prevent injury, a fence runs around the perimeter. A gap in the fence did allow me to sneak in for a couple of pictures from underneath. The western end, completely cut off from the original water supply, is now home to the local party hangout, identified from the graffiti, countless broken beer bottles, and the still-smouldering remnants of a fire. The view down the aqueduct is something else.<br />
It was about then that I noticed the time: 12:45. I needed to be back in Calgary for a party at 14:00. I was going to be late.<br />
I pulled into the car wash at 16th Ave. and Edmonton Trail just before 15:00. The car had turned a brownish green (from all the dust), with multicoloured speckling (from all the bugs). It was shiny in only a few minutes. Then it was my turn to get clean.<br />
I arrived at Shantie&#8217;s house just before 16:00. This was a soccer party, and as near as I could figure, I was one of the only non-soccer people invited. Needless to say, I wasn&#8217;t too keen to leap right into the game. Mostly because I haven&#8217;t played since high school, and even then I was terrible. I resolved to sit in the weak shade of a tree (not all the trees here have sprouted leaves yet) and take pictures. The six-year old daughter of one of the guests noticed it right away and asked if she could use it. It&#8217;s a durable little thing, and I figured &#8212; could get some interesting pictures.<br />
The girl, Shayla, took almost 150 pictures over the next few hours.<br />
The game ended around 17:00 and we retreated to Shantie&#8217;s house (across the street from the soccer field) to engage in conversation and food. John (one of the other guests) tried to engage in a battle of wits with Shayla. The six year old won, hands down. It was just the beginning.<br />
Shantie has some really great friends. They&#8217;re hilarious to hang around with, and are in no way exclusionary. They even knew when to pick on me because I brought veggie burgers. (Relax, I haven&#8217;t gone vegan &#8212; but I&#8217;ve had these sitting in my freezer for a year, and I gotta eat &#8217;em.)<br />
I ended up talking with Lindsay for over an hour about Japan. (She&#8217;d been there in high school.) We talked until it was just too cool to be away from the fire pit everyone else had gathered around. (I should note that it was gorgeously warm, and it was just a slightly cool breeze that was making it uncomfortable. Besides, we were feeling left out.)<br />
By midnight, everyone had left, including myself. I&#8217;d been up for 18 hours, was harbouring a half-dozen sunburns, and needed some serious sleep.<br />
Today was the Lilac Festival in Calgary. I didn&#8217;t go to it this year, as I felt I had more pressing things to take care of: namely the small army of dandelions that were laying siege to my front lawn. Screwdriver in hand, I went to eradicate the little buggers from my grass.<br />
Most people use chemicals when they get rid of weeds. I&#8217;m not a big fan of chemicals in the yard, not even fertilizers. I prefer the natural, brute force methods. I even use an unpowered push mower to cut my grass. Yeah, it&#8217;s hard work, but you feel better for it. Especially when total strangers thank you for not using chemicals.<br />
While there was still a lot of afternoon left, I went for a walk along the river, taking in the sights and sounds of the World Walk, or something like that, taking place at Prince&#8217;s Island Park. I didn&#8217;t spend long, so I don&#8217;t really know what it was all about. I had a mission: I needed to get my bike.<br />
People were everywhere. Calgary becomes very active when it gets warm. When there&#8217;s a festival on, you almost have problems moving at times. Along all the major strips, the patios are open and full. Everyone is enjoying the outdoors again. Summer is definitely here.<br />
Now if it would just rain so we could all cool off&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2003/05/2816-chasing-brooks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">281</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fixing super heater tubes on CP 2816</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/2816-super-heater-tubes/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=2816-super-heater-tubes</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/2816-super-heater-tubes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 06:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2002/10/21/2816-super-heater-tubes/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It doesn&#8217;t take long for me to get back into the swing of (some) things. I&#8217;m already working on trains again. This time, it&#8217;s the locomotive from which I caught the train chasing bug. I got a call from Don on Saturday, wanting the tapes I shot for 6060&#8217;s trip out to Jasper last year &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/2816-super-heater-tubes/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Fixing super heater tubes on CP 2816"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It doesn&#8217;t take long for me to get back into the swing of (some) things. I&#8217;m already working on trains again. This time, it&#8217;s the locomotive from which I caught the train chasing bug.<br />
I got a call from Don on Saturday, wanting the tapes I shot for 6060&#8217;s trip out to Jasper last year (see [[The Great Jasper Run, CN 6060 Stettler, Red Deer, Edmonton, Hinton, Jasper]]). We chatted briefly, then mentioned that I should drop by the roundhouse at CP&#8217;s Alyth Yard to see 2816 all steamed up. Asking if the engine were heading back to Vancouver for a six-month inspection or more work, Don replied that 2816 was making a run from Calgary to Banff and back with some of CP&#8217;s executives. I was to drop by around 11:00am on Sunday.<br />
When I arrived, Don&#8217;s truck was nowhere in sight. Having never been here before, and coming at Don&#8217;s invitation &#8212; not CP&#8217;s &#8212; I was careful to wait for my escort. Don arrived shortly afterwards, and I followed him in.<br />
2816 was not out in the yard, or even on the turntable (as I&#8217;d hoped). It was tucked inside, the smokebox cover completely removed, the superheater covers removed, and four men milling around inside. Present were Bill (2816&#8217;s lead engineer), Jim (CP employee, RMRS member, and steam locomotive engineer &#8212; Jim had run 6060 to Jasper with us last year), Al Broadfoot (who supervised 2816&#8217;s overhaul), and another man who I&#8217;d never met before.<br />
It seemed that the night before, after Don had left, Bill noticed an odd noise in the smokebox. Upon investigation, he found steam eminating from one of the flue tubes. That could mean only one thing &#8212; a superheater had burst.<br />
We had arrived to find them in the midst of removing superheater tubes. Luckily, they knew exactly which one was giving them trouble, but it was tucked behind a couple of other tubes that needed to be removed first. This involved using an overhead crane for support, and a forklift for leverage. Superheater tubes, especially in larger locomotives, are extremely heavy. Removing them by hand is torture (or so I&#8217;m told by the 6060 crew, who had to do just that).<br />
I didn&#8217;t directly participate. Partly because Bill and Al don&#8217;t know me, but also because I have no idea what I&#8217;m doing. I&#8217;ve never seen this done before, let alone participated. I fell into my role of gopher. (Which I&#8217;m quite comfortable at, especially with people who know a lot more than I do.) That basically meant a coffee run.)<br />
While all this was happening, I had long chats with Al. It would appear that my education of Al has been woefully one-sided. I&#8217;ve heard lots of stories and some generally not nice things about him. I&#8217;d always been a little skeptical &#8230; but not enough. Al seems to be a genuinely honest man, trying to keep locomotives in good running shape. This is what I gathered talking to him directly. He actually mourned the RMRS&#8217; lack of a proper shop to maintain 6060. (This is something everyone agrees with.) Needless to say, if for nothing else, I&#8217;m glad I went just so I could talk with Al.<br />
The troubled superheater soon slid out of the boiler. As it popped out and was slowly lowered to the ground, water seeped from the bend. Etched in the forged piece was a tiny hole, about 1/16th of an inch across. Possibly a thin-walled area, aggravated by a grape (a weld that has pooled into a sphere on the inside) causing an eddy, bored right through the side.<br />
Normally, this would sideline a locomotive. But with CP&#8217;s resources, it&#8217;s a matter of cutting off the offending piece and getting in a welder to attach a new bend. Jim knew a good one in town who could come the following day to fix it.<br />
We left 2816 in the roundhouse, covers off, superheaters laid out, awaiting repairs. It almost looked like a patient anxiously awaiting a dentist to fill a cavity. It&#8217;s due to run to Banff (Bamf!) on Friday. I&#8217;m pretty sure it will.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2002/10/2816-super-heater-tubes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">251</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/09/inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/09/inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2001 17:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CP 2816]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2001/09/24/inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Most of you know how hard it is sometimes to catch a train. Sometimes you&#8217;re running late, or the train&#8217;s early, or your watch stopped and you&#8217;re not really sure what time it is &#8212; any number of a dozen reasons why you&#8217;d be running your heart out trying to get there before you hear: &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/09/inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Inaugural Run of the Steam Locomotive CPR Empress, CP 2816"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most of you know how hard it is sometimes to catch a train. Sometimes you&#8217;re running late, or the train&#8217;s early, or your watch stopped and you&#8217;re not really sure what time it is &#8212; any number of a dozen reasons why you&#8217;d be running your heart out trying to get there before you hear: &#8220;Stand clear of the doors, please.&#8221;<br />
Imagine trying to catch a train for two days. That&#8217;s what I did this weekend&#8230;<br />
Okay, so I wasn&#8217;t trying to ride it, but keeping pace with it was something else, I&#8217;ll tell you.<br />
<span id="more-164"></span>I was following the CPR Empress, a Hudson H1b steam locomotive, number 2816, that was making its inaugural run from Vancouver to Calgary, it&#8217;s new home. CP had just spent two years and a rumoured CDN$2 million rebuilding the locomotive to be its corporate show piece. And its journey from the West Coast was to be every bit as much a publicity stunt as it was the real test of its abilities.<br />
CP 2816 was originally built in 1930 by the Montreal Locomotive Works (at an original cost of $116,555). She ran regular service between Calgary and Thunder Bay (then Fort William) until the late 1930&#8217;s, when she was transferred to the Quebec City-Windsor corridor. There she enjoyed another 20 years of regular service until her last run on 26 May 1960. In December, 1963 she was sold to American interests, where she sat idle and neglected for 35 years.<br />
2816 is a cousin to 2860, the Royal Hudson locomotive that runs out of North Vancouver. A predecessor, 2816 predates the streamlining efforts that began in the mid-to-late 1930&#8217;s. 2860, an H1e class engine, fell into the streamlining era, and lacks all the bumps, rivets and exposed tanks that 2816 bears.<br />
It&#8217;s a big engine, too: 91 feet and 2 inches in length, 15 feet and 3 inches tall. That&#8217;s roughly the size of 6060 (a little shorter, but a little taller). 2816 weighs in 10,000 pounds more than 6060, and her driving wheels are 2&#8243; taller. 6060 has more tractive effort than 2816, so technically she&#8217;s more powerful. But put them side-by-side, and you wouldn&#8217;t notice much difference in size&#8230;<br />
In 1998, CP started to feel the pressure from a resurgence in steam power. They started to look for an ex-CP engine (as CP had none left in their fleet) to parade around the continent. They likely talked with BC Rail about acquiring the Royal Hudson, to which they were likely laughed away. The finally approached Steamtown National Historic Site in Scranton, Pennsylvania, the then-owners of CP 2816.<br />
Having sat out in the elements for more years than she was active, 2816 was not in the best of shape. It took much time and effort to effect repairs where she could be run on a rail line at track speed, and another 19 days just to get the engine to North Vancouver. After a lengthy and detailed inspection, the boiler (the most important part of the locomotive) was deemed salvageable, and the arduous two-year restoration began.<br />
2816 was almost entirely taken apart, piece by piece. The boiler was shipped down to Portland for rebuilding, the frame repaired, the pins and bearings replaced, the tenders rebuilt, new cover sheets were made, lines installed, and it was topped off with a new cab (the old one was apparently in terrible shape). By the time it was finished, the engine was, for all intents and purposes, new.<br />
CP dubbed the locomotive &#8220;CPR Empress&#8221; and planned its triumphant return to operation on its main lines. It was mostly word-of-mouth &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear about it until I started working on 6060. But with a little bit of digging, I got a hold of the rough schedule, and made sure that I&#8217;d be around when the train started coming through Alberta.<br />
For me, that was Saturday afternoon. (I spent the morning running errands.) My start for the day was going to be in Field, British Columbia, about 20 kilometres inside the Alberta/BC border. This was one of the designated stops for the Empress, and the last stop before the Spiral Tunnels.<br />
I arrived around 2:50pm MDT, about 40 minutes before 2816 was due to arrive. A few people already milled around, many of them CP employees, wearing orange safety vests. What I didn&#8217;t know (but soon learned) was that CP was expecting a lot of crowds, and had recruited people (mostly CP employees) to help out with safety along the tracks. There were, of course, the obligatory CP police, but they were grossly outnumbered by the amateurs.<br />
Slowly, but surely, people began to show. By the time 3:30 rolled around, there had to be at least 100 people waiting for the train to arrive. But like with most modern railways, the Empress wasn&#8217;t holding to schedule, and didn&#8217;t arrive until nearly 4:00. Aside from the scorching sun, I didn&#8217;t mind too much.<br />
I stood in one spot, where I could get a decent shot of the train as it appeared from behind the Trans Canada sweeping away to the west. When we finally heard the distant whistle and chugging (which carried very well through the valley), people started getting excited. A moment later, it burst from its hiding place, and raced along the riverbed.<br />
Hopping over to the rails, I kneeled down next to the line to take a shot as it rounded the corner. One of the hired help asked me to move back from the rails for my own safety (a wise precaution) &#8212; I quickly explained I only wanted to get a distance shot down the rail as the train rounded the corner. Left to my own for a moment, I lined up my camera and prepared to shoot. Then a CP cop asked me to move back from the rails for my own safety. The urge to be terse was pushed aside by the urgency to get the picture. I quickly explained myself, and bent down to take the picture before there was any comment. A second later, shot in camera, I backed away from the rails for my own safety.<br />
I&#8217;ve seen quite a few steam trains in the last few years. Some in decent condition, and some not. But I had never seen a locomotive in as good shape as 2816. The dull grey sheeting on the boiler glistened in the sunlight, the handrails glistened, the lights twinkled, and the running gear gleamed. There was no question about the quality of workmanship &#8212; every detail had been covered, every possible mentionable was mentioned. Even the slops of grease on the drawbars looked clean.<br />
People crowded around almost as soon as the train came to a halt. At first, it was hard to tell who were the true fans, and who were the ones who happened to see a steam train from the highway and came out to take a look. Though after a short while, you could start to guess the avid people &#8212; they were the ones lining up for camera shots and positioning themselves away from the crowd.<br />
The train stayed at Field for about 40 minutes, departing at 4:30pm MDT. The time to leave was signified by a blast from its powerful whistle. Having recently heard 6060&#8217;s whistle, I had the unique perspective of comparison. 6060&#8217;s whistle is more powerful &#8212; I not only had to plug my ears when next to it, but I could feel the vibration in my chest. 2816&#8217;s whistle is a more &#8230; melodic, even though there is but one tone. And in that valley, did that whistle ever echo &#8230; such a glorious sound has not been heard there for decades.<br />
As the train began to pull away, many of us ran for our cars, and promptly began the race up the hill. My destination was a small tunnel about halfway up the side &#8212; a place I would later learn is called Cathedral (I have no idea why). Arriving, I found that I was not the only one. Luckily, it wasn&#8217;t crowded, and I managed to get a place where I could take a good picture. We could hear the train coming the whole way &#8212; both CP and CN engines bark loudly when on grades, even with the diesel engine assisting 2816. A moment later, we were rewarded with the engine powering through the 10-metre long tunnel.<br />
No sooner had the engine gone through that I raced down the side of the hill, climbed into my car, and sped up the hill. My goal was to reach the view of the Spiral Tunnels before the train arrived. My poor car had to endure the strain of sudden stops, starts, quick acceleration, and speeding for two days. Darn good thing I got the oil changed that morning&#8230;<br />
I parked on the shoulder of the highway, and sprinted across to the observation area. I could hear 2816 pounding away. I arrived not even a minute before she entered the Lower Tunnel. It was then I realized just how fast the train was running, and how hard it was to keep up. A moment later, she poked back out of the tunnel. A quick snap, and I was off like a shot to the overpass on the highway. I hoped to get a video shot of the train as it travelled up the grade. I passed a man who asked if the train was at the tunnel yet. He looked quite disappointed when I told him that it was already through the Lower Tunnel.<br />
Fortunately, the distance from the Lower Tunnel to the bridge was far enough for me to run down, find a spot, and set up. Again, we were rewarded with a tremendous sight, as the engine continued it&#8217;s climb. The sound it produced was enough to produce a great rumble in my chest. It was wonderful.<br />
Having passed, I again charged up the hill, crossed the highway, and got into my car. I sped off for my next stop, a small lake at the continental divide. There, too, I found a host of people waiting to get a view of the train, including a tour bus, which I can only assume was hired to chase the train.<br />
Pulling off to the site, I raced down the side of the lake where I could get a shot across, without the sun&#8217;s glare interfering with the picture. As I waited for the train to catch up, I entered into a conversation with another fan, whom I learned was also a card-carrying member of the Rocky Mountain Rail Society. I had to wonder just how many of us there were roaming about.<br />
Another run by, another picture, and I ran back to my car. Traffic was becoming a nightmare. The Trans Canada is only two lanes at that point, one in either direction. This makes for a bad traffic jam when 100 or so cars try to merge back on at the same time. Fortunately, many pulled off as they got just ahead of the train, so eventually I was able to get ahead of the train again.<br />
I pulled off to the side, and jogged up a small dirt road to a place where I had seen a small iron bridge on my west earlier that afternoon. At the time, I had hoped it would be an ideal location for me to get a shot without dozens of people. Instead I got a few select diehards (which was fine with me) and CP&#8217;s film crew. It seemed I&#8217;d walked right into a staged event.<br />
CP was going to make as big a hullabaloo about this as they could &#8212; including going so far as to hold up freight trains for most of the weekend. This was a staged event &#8212; CP was going to &#8220;meet&#8221; trains. At this particular point, there are two separate lines, one for the train exiting the Spiral Tunnels, and one for the train waiting to go in. (This is also why Field still has its rail yard.)<br />
CP had a freight staged to run west while the Empress ran east. This was carefully staged &#8212; you could hear the whistles from either train as they prepared to cross paths. Several of the diehard fans couldn&#8217;t care less about the &#8220;weasel&#8221; (as they called it), and concentrated on the passing of 2816.<br />
None of us, film crew included, were disappointed. (Well, at least by the run; several of the diehards were rather irritated at the film crew&#8217;s placement, which made taking pictures and video a little more difficult.) The trains passed, whistles and horns blowing, and continued on their merry way. With that, I brushed off the rest of the ticks that were trying to make a new home, and headed back to my car.<br />
Chasing was now getting very difficult &#8212; traffic was murder. The train kept pulling ahead as others in front of me tried to pace the train and others were driving poorly. By the time I caught up, the train had already pulled into the Lake Louise station.<br />
As this was the final stop for the day, the passengers (VIPs invited from the run from Revelstoke that morning) disembarked for the bus ride back home, but not before another look at the train. They even dragged out a set of steps so people could get a look into the engine&#8217;s cab.<br />
As I stood off to the side, watching the throng of people mill around 2816 like a colony of enraged ants, I listened to conversations. One of them, occurring behind me, was about the engine&#8217;s conversion from coal to liquid fossil fuels. One of the people there was a local, who said the engine was converted to diesel. Not knowing any better, I poked my nose in to &#8220;correct&#8221; him, saying it wasn&#8217;t diesel, but Bunker C fuel oil.<br />
I should note, for the record, that I was apparently wrong. Although the literature says otherwise, apparently CP did manage to convert the engine to burn diesel fuel. Anyone who knows steam engines knows that burning diesel fuel is great because it&#8217;s really hot. Unfortunately, that&#8217;s also the problem &#8212; it&#8217;s too hot. BC Rail used diesel on 3716, their spare locomotive for the Royal Hudson run. They managed to get it so hot that the firebox warped under the heat. It&#8217;s now in indefinite storage, as the cost to repair it is probably too prohibitive.<br />
Interestingly enough, the man often credited with making the decision to burn diesel in 3716 was also the man responsible for restoring 2816, and was the man running the engine &#8212; Al Broadfoot. Among the RMRS folk, Broadfoot&#8217;s name is mentioned only with insults &#8212; he&#8217;s not a popular guy. I met the man, not knowing who he was, when I ascended the stairs. I suppose the smug indignation of mentioning the RMRS to him should have been a clue. He merely said: &#8220;Ah, Harry Home.&#8221;<br />
Mind you, I suppose he as reason to be smug &#8212; he restored 2816 to perfect running condition, which can (apparently) safely burn diesel. But if the RMRS had the budget, facilities and people that Broadfoot had, I can only imagine what condition 6060 could be raised to.<br />
Anyway, back to the guy I corrected. He was talking to a tourist from Australia. We had a short chat (about 10 minutes) about steam power, and how Australia has quite a bit of it still in operation. (Something I didn&#8217;t know.) He was amazed to find that we didn&#8217;t have a lot left &#8212; I explained why, and even provided a bit of commentary for the video he was shooting.<br />
I also managed to run into someone from work &#8212; Kelly, who is our Operations Manager for Creative Services. He was in Lake Louise with his wife and child. He introduced me to his wife as &#8220;the story teller&#8221;.<br />
Me tell stories? Never&#8230;<br />
I started to leave Lake Louise, aiming to head home. But for some reason, I couldn&#8217;t help but turn into a short drive barely 500 metres from where I&#8217;d first parked. There, I found more rail fans, just waiting for the train to leave. There I met Graham and his girlfriend, Carrie. Graham was one of those rail fans that most people would refer as a &#8220;freak&#8221;. For him, this was his life.<br />
Ever since he was a child, his parents took him train chasing. It got to the point where the engineers along the line knew Graham&#8217;s family. Graham&#8217;s mother wrote a book called &#8220;CP and the Selkirks&#8221;. It ran in the family, and Graham showed no signs of slowing down. In fact, he&#8217;s in the process of converting Carrie to the life &#8212; and she&#8217;s not resisting too hard. She even showed me their little secret weapon &#8212; something called the &#8220;Canadian Trackside Guide&#8221;.<br />
Yeah, doesn&#8217;t sound like much, but to the diehard train chaser, it&#8217;s practically a bible. It lists the number of every locomotive owned by every railway in Canada, the mile markers of every railway sub in Canada, the locations of all the hotboxes, and all the radio frequencies you can listen to when chasing a train. Needless to say, Graham also has a scanner for listening to the radio chatter and hotbox reports.<br />
(A &#8220;hotbox&#8221;, for those of you who&#8217;ve never heard of one, is a sensor that alerts engineers of overheated axles. Hotboxes date back to when trains used solid bearings instead of roller bearings. The solid bearings relied solely on lubrication to keep the axle turning. If there wasn&#8217;t enough oil and grease, the axle would get too hot and could catch what little lubricant there was on fire. Before the demise of the caboose, conductors and linesmen would look for smoking hotboxes as a sign that something was wrong.)<br />
I chatted with Graham and Carrie for about a half hour, before 2816 finally headed out for the night. It was going to rest in a siding about 10 miles away, called Eldon. As we turned to leave, Graham asked if I was going to come out early the next morning to see 2816 run Morant&#8217;s Curve. I did my best not to give him a blank stare.<br />
My education continued as I was told about CP&#8217;s most famous photographer, Nicholas Morant. For over half a century, Morant was responsible for taking pictures of CP&#8217;s trains. Over the course of years, he found a location in Banff National Park that was ideal &#8212; a nice &#8216;S&#8217; curve, mountains in the background, and the river flowing along side. He shot so many pictures there that it became known as &#8220;Morant&#8217;s Curve&#8221;.<br />
Graham was courteous enough to drive me out (I followed) to the location. He told me that he&#8217;d meet me the next morning there. But for all three of us, it was time to go home and get some sleep.<br />
When the alarm went off the next morning at 5:00, I wasn&#8217;t sure if I was awake or dead. I managed to pull myself out of bed, dress, and leave without waking Chris from his place on the couch, Dreamcast controller still barely in his hand. A quick stop at the Esso / Tim Horton&#8217;s at the edge of town for a bit of gas and TimBits, and I was on my way west again.<br />
The dawn was breaking as I entered the Rockies. The sky went from black to a deep navy blue, breaking into a dark pastel blue by the time I reached Lake Louise. A bare five minutes later, I was joining the crowd already forming at Morant&#8217;s Curve.<br />
Graham never showed &#8212; in fact, I didn&#8217;t see him all day. However, I met still more people who had come from all over western North America to witness this trip. A few had been following 2816 since she left Vancouver on Wednesday. Many knew each other from previous encounters. I was part fly on the wall, part student, and all listener.<br />
CP had a film crew there, too. In fact, CP was the one who had organized this run. According to the &#8220;official&#8221; schedule, the Empress was supposed to be in Banff by 9:00am. But CP wanted stills and video of the train at Morant&#8217;s curve. We were more than happy to tag along, even despite the near-freezing temperatures.<br />
My poor TimBits froze. Although, admittedly, the chocolate ones are really tasty like that.<br />
The run was supposed to take place at 8:00, but the train didn&#8217;t show up until nearly 8:45, and then promptly sat for another 25 minutes before moving behind trees so it could get enough speed to get a good run &#8212; we were only going to get one shot at this, so we had to make it good.<br />
A few blasts of the whistle, and she began to charge forward to run the curve at about 25 mph. The plume of steam was like a massive cloud erupting from 2816&#8217;s stack as she rounded the corner. All you could hear were camera clicks as a hundred or so photographers did their best to get some kind of an award-winning picture. A couple minutes later, 2816 was racing towards Banff. We packed up our things, and continued the chase.<br />
The Bow Valley Parkway between Lake Louise and Banff is a fun drive, but is no good when you&#8217;re trying to chase a train, especially if you&#8217;re trying to get in front of it. I took the Trans Canada, and easily cleared it by about 20 minutes. My goal was to perch myself on the bridge that overlooked the railway and shoot from there. But as I neared my destination, I noticed a lot of cars parked down under the bridge &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t the only one looking for this area. I found the road and joined others waiting for 2816 to come along.One such person was Jim, a Seattle rail fan who had picked up 2816 just east of Golden and had been chasing since Saturday. He had missed Morant&#8217;s Curve &#8212; he really didn&#8217;t want to know what he&#8217;d missed. He was getting increasingly annoyed with the position of the light. An hour earlier, the light had been fantastic, which seemed to be how long most of these people had been waiting. Now, the light was &#8220;fading&#8221;.<br />
By fading, Jim meant that the side of the rail cars would not be lit by the sun, and would not glow the way they should. But given the location, a wonderful bend in the rail, mountain behind, and not a could to be seen, it was still going to be a great run. Along with an older couple, we chatted about our experiences on rail when out of the corner of my ear, I heard a chug. All conversation fell dead as several people called out &#8220;she&#8217;s here!&#8221;.<br />
Not wasting any time, 2816 tore around the corner and towards Banff. We packed up, returned to our cars, and raced after the train. I arrived just in time to see the train roll over the crossing and into the station. After the traffic cleared, I parked and wandered around to take yet more pictures. (I took over 120 images in all, including video.)<br />
The crowds were getting bigger. I could only imagine what Calgary would be like. I took a few pictures, and then decided I needed to get further down the line. I found a crossing on the eastern edge of town, where many of the rail fans I kept running into were waiting, including Jim. We both agreed that the picture of the day (to that point) was the one of the two Mounties at the front of the locomotive.<br />
I had barely been there five minutes when the whistle started blowing &#8212; 2816 was coming. We stood ready, everyone silent (there were a number of video cameras), waiting for our quarry to pass. Then it was back to our cars, and off in hot pursuit.<br />
I&#8217;m amazed that I didn&#8217;t see more radar traps on the Trans Canada &#8212; there had to have been at least a hundred of us, racing around the highways trying to keep pace with the engine. At some point, we all managed to pace 2816 &#8212; and I wasn&#8217;t even trying.<br />
Although the next stop was in Canmore, I figured I&#8217;d get a better shot further down the line. I filed onto Highway 1A and raced towards Exshaw, where I hoped there would be a great picture across the water. But along the way, I found a pack of cars at the side of the road. By that time, I&#8217;d learned that it was always someone chasing the train. A few fans had found a small, isolated place to take pictures and record audio of the train. Jim appeared a few moments later, and we figured we&#8217;d get a better shot at this place than at Exshaw. (As it stands, we were right.)<br />
Wait. Train. Click. Pack. Run. Drive.<br />
Exshaw was packed with people, but none of the vantage points were any good. We raced through the town (at nearly double the speed limit) to the east, and Highway 1X (after I made a short, unfruitful stop at what I thought might be a good place) where the bridge overlooked the rail line.<br />
Shortly after a freight train sneaked by, 2816 raced by on it&#8217;s way to Cochrane, it&#8217;s last stop before Calgary. It was quite the site to see all the people lined up on one side of the bridge suddenly race across to the other side to take a picture as the Empress disappeared off into the distance.<br />
It was time to go back to Calgary. Cochrane wasn&#8217;t a great place to take pictures, and the CPR was almost inaccessible by road from Exshaw until Calgary. Besides, I was getting tired from all the chasing.<br />
I arrived back home at about 2:00. 2816 wasn&#8217;t due to arrive in Calgary until 3:30, but already CP was setting the stage &#8212; their equipment was already out, including an SD40 Mac diesel locomotive to meet 2816. I rested for an hour before heading down.<br />
The crowd built fast &#8212; by 3:30 there were a couple hundred onlookers. A short tweet in the distance let us know that 2816 was in the final stretch &#8212; the end was finally in sight. As she rolled into the west industrial yard, her chugging seemed almost laboured &#8212; like a long-distance runner who just finally crossed the finish line. But it was a happy labour &#8212; the job finally done.<br />
Speeches. CP spokesman. Blah. CP CEO Robbie Robertson. Blah blah. Alberta Premier Ralph Klein. Blah blah blah, you stinkin&#8217; jerk! Yeah, I&#8217;m a bit ticked. The speech was so unbelievably sanctimonious that it made me ill &#8212; he said how great it was to have an engine like this running the lines and I just about screamed at him how the Alberta government had let 6060 go because they thought steam was a white elephant. Well, I was ticked for a while, but maybe this was a sign that the government was willing to look at possibilities again &#8212; there could yet be hope, I guess.<br />
It also didn&#8217;t hurt that I talked with another RMRS member, who proudly displayed his custom-made 6060 hat for all to see. He had been waiting for someone to mention it. He had been hoping it would be Al Broadfoot, but anyone would do.<br />
Now we have a little support and competition, all rolled into one. Just so long as interest in steam stays strong, we should hopefully be able to hang onto our heritage, and teach the future how to chase its past.<br />
[flickr]set:72157603479888481[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2001/09/inaugural-run-steam-locomotive-cpr-empress-cp-2816/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">164</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
