<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>calgary transit &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/calgary-transit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 22:49:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Privatize Calgary Transit</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/privatize-calgary-transit/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=privatize-calgary-transit</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/privatize-calgary-transit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 22:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[york]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was recently out in the United Kingdom on vacation. If you know my travel habits, you know I rarely stay in one place for long &#8212; I like to move around. (Yes, this often fuels or is fueled by my mild obsession with trains.) It means that I often pay close attention to public &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/privatize-calgary-transit/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Privatize Calgary Transit"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was recently out in the United Kingdom on vacation. If you know <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/category/travel/">my travel habits</a>, you know I rarely stay in one place for long &#8212; I like to move around. (Yes, this often fuels or is fueled by <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/category/trains/">my mild obsession with trains</a>.) It means that I often pay close attention to public transit, and how it operates.<br />
While we were in York, a thought suddenly hit me. I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;d seen this elsewhere, but it hadn&#8217;t really registered. The buses weren&#8217;t run by York Transit, or Transit Yorkshire, or anything directly related to the city/region government. The buses were privatized through <a href="http://www.firstgroup.com/">FirstGroup PLC</a>.<br />
And suddenly I thought: Why couldn&#8217;t Calgary do the same?<br />
<span id="more-962"></span>Let&#8217;s do a quick comparison, though. (To be fair.)</p>
<table border="1">
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calgary">Calgary</a></th>
<th><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/York">York</a></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Population</td>
<td>1,019,942 (2007)</td>
<td>191,800 (2005 est/2006 Urban)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Area</td>
<td>726.5 sq km</td>
<td>271.94 sq km</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Routes</td>
<td>160 bus routes<br />
2 C-Train lines</td>
<td>19 bus routes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Schools</td>
<td>400+ public/Catholic<br />
5+ colleges<br />
1 university</td>
<td>55+ public schools<br />
2 colleges<br />
2 universities (one is medical)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Avg. Age</td>
<td>35.7 (2006)</td>
<td>39+ (2006, w/ info from York&#8217;s website)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tourists/year</td>
<td>~5 million</td>
<td>~4 million</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>One way fare*</td>
<td>2.50</td>
<td>1.10 &#8211; 2.80 (depends on distance)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Day pass</td>
<td>6.75</td>
<td>3.50</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Weekly pass</td>
<td>N/A</td>
<td>14.00 (price effective June)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Monthly pass</td>
<td>75.00</td>
<td>47.00 (price effective June)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Student pass</td>
<td>50.50 (ages 6-14)<br />
Post-secondary part of tuition, cost unknown</td>
<td>99.00 /term<br />
269.00 /academic year</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Senior fare</td>
<td>35.00 /year</td>
<td>Free (after 9am)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>* I&#8217;m not taking exchange rates into account, since CDN$1 in Canada has about the same buying power of  £1 in the UK.<br />
Now, to prevent myself getting into a really deep hole, let me preface the next part of my argument with the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>I do not know what subsidies, if any, <a href="http://www.firstgroup.com/ukbus/yorkhumber/york/home/">First York</a> (the division of FirstGroup PLC that runs the bus system in York) receives</li>
<li>Differences between Calgary and York do not scale consistently (e.g. ~5 times for population, ~3 times for area, ~8 times for bus routes)</li>
<li>York thrives off of tourism, whereas oil rules here in Calgary, which places public transit as a bigger priority in York</li>
<li>York has a large and busy train station; Calgary has long since forgotten what a train is</li>
<li>Privatized public transit is virtually unknown in North America (most are government-owned, or heavily government-subsidized)</li>
</ul>
<p>It should be also pointed out that while York is a much smaller city with smaller problems, Hong Kong has multiple competing privatized systems. Those tend to work very well.<br />
Alright, all that said&#8230;<br />
The cost of running a transportation system &#8212; including public transit &#8212; is rarely straight-forward. Equipment (airplanes, trains, buses, ferries, taxis, support vehicles ad nauseum) and its upkeep, facilities (stations, maintenance buildings), ticketing and billing, training, administrative support, and so forth adds up. It ain&#8217;t cheap. And in most cases, run by the wrong institutions &#8212; governments.<br />
Everyone likes to point out that governments are wasteful. They&#8217;re bureaucratic, slow to adapt (and often do not receive pressure to adapt), and as a result become very insulative such that those who can make the decisions never really get feedback from the users (e.g. passengers) to make a significant difference.<br />
Don&#8217;t believe me? Allow me to quote some particularly stellar examples:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swissair">Swissair</a></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alitalia#Financial_situation">Alitalia</a> (not gone yet, but just wait&#8230;)</li>
<li>Air Canada (multiple <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/story/2003/03/31/aircanaid030331.html">bailouts</a>)</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amtrak#Controversy">Amtrak</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Given, these are mostly airlines, and the ones that have tended to make headlines in one way or another. All of them suffer from the same problem &#8212; governments can&#8217;t run businesses. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_National_Railway#Privatization">CN Rail</a>, as a near-perfect example, has been a very profitable company since it went private. (Given, it&#8217;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canadian_National_Railway#Recent_controversies">safety record has been abysmal</a> in the last few years. That&#8217;s another post.)<br />
Calgary Transit is on a much smaller scale &#8212; it has but one city to contend with. But the administration of Calgary Transit bubbles up to the same person responsible for roads. That, my friends, is a conflict of interest. (Or at least, conflicting priorities.) You can imagine that he gets more people yelling at him about the state of the roads than he does about bus schedules.<br />
So move Calgary Transit away from the <a href="http://www.calgary.ca/">City</a>. Tender out the operation to another company. Sell off the assets (think of the taxes the city might earn from this), and let them negotiate with the city for things like bus lanes, dedicated spaces, etc. Remove the employment from the City and put it under private ownership, where it would hopefully be dealt with in a more business-like manner than the current &#8220;whenever&#8221; approach that there seems to be now.<br />
Yes, there are a thousand reasons this might not work. There are also a thousand reasons that it might. And frankly, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2006/08/15/calgary-transit-sucks/">I&#8217;m not convinced</a> that the City of Calgary is putting in the effort to run a public transportation network properly or efficiently &#8212; and <a href="http://www.screwcalgarytransit.com/index.php?option=com_fireboard&amp;Itemid=27&amp;func=view&amp;id=41&amp;catid=4">I&#8217;m not the only one who thinks that</a>, either.<br />
So who could run this? How about <a href="http://www.firstgroupamerica.com/">FirstGroup America</a>? Yep, they&#8217;re already here. Laidlaw buses? That&#8217;s them. They also own one of the largest bus lines in North America &#8212; <a href="http://www.greyhound.com/">Greyhound</a>. So it&#8217;s not like they don&#8217;t have any knowledge and/or experience. But wait, it gets better! Under their <a href="http://www.firsttransit.com/">FirstTransit</a> moniker, they run <a href="http://www.firsttransit.com/services_fixedTMC.php">routes all over the 50 States</a>. That&#8217;s street cred, in my book.<br />
With the constant rise (and likely to keep rising) of oil prices, it will become more prohibitive to drive personal automobiles. We need effective public transit in Calgary now, and we need it effective before we have a meltdown (and I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re far off).<br />
Privatize. Before it&#8217;s too late.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/04/privatize-calgary-transit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A bullet train in Calgary?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-bullet-train-in-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 22:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/09/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train from here to Fort McMurray. Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks. Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A bullet train in Calgary?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/calgary/story/2008/01/09/10year-plan.html">Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train</a> from here to Fort McMurray.<br />
Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks.<br />
<span id="more-887"></span>Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train in Alberta is insane. Completely. Why, you ask?</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is going to pay the $3-4 billion to build a dedicated grade-separated, high-speed rail network? Don&#8217;t look to either <a href="http://www.cp.ca/">CP</a> or <a href="http://www.cn.ca">CN</a>.</li>
<li>Similarly, who runs it? If it&#8217;s VIA, expect the service to have constant problems, since budgets to run high-speed are much higher than regular trains, and <a href="http://www.viarail.ca">VIA</a>&#8216;s got enough budgetary problems as it is.</li>
<li>Do we honestly think there would be enough use of the trains to make them even remotely cost-effective? <a href="http://www.westjet.com">WestJet</a> is pretty darn cheap, y&#8217;know&#8230;</li>
<li>The provincial government was looking to shore up the existing lines up north to help move heavy equipment by train. CN passed on the work (they own the lines) after realising the cost to build up the service wasn&#8217;t worth the revenue. Take that as a subtle hint for new lines.</li>
<li>It hits -40 in many places, with a lot of snow. I don&#8217;t know of many (read: any) high-speed lines that regularly go through such conditions. Hokkaido in Japan is the nearest, and even that&#8217;s not as severe.</li>
</ul>
<p>Politically, it strikes me as odd that anyone would stand up behind this as a good idea, since it&#8217;ll likely be a government that owns it, and it would probably become a white elephant. Very cool, and I&#8217;d ride it just for the sake of riding it &#8212; but governments have been voted out of office for stuff like this.<br />
All of that said, it&#8217;s totally the green option. Run the train often enough, and you have less cars (less automobile pollution) and less planes (less aviation pollution). It&#8217;s also a nicer way to travel long distances. And Canada&#8217;s full of that distance thing.<br />
Mind you, the bullet train wasn&#8217;t the only &#8220;odd&#8221; thing in that report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Building a ring road in Calgary. Um&#8230; <a href="http://content.calgary.ca/CCA/City+Hall/Office+of+the+Mayor/Press+Room/Archive/2006/February+2006/NE+Ring+Road.htm">aren&#8217;t we doing that already</a>?</li>
<li>Where is the mention of expanding Calgary Transit? For the love of Pete, people &#8212; why are you trying to link together cities when [[Calgary Transit Sucks|we can&#8217;t even sort ourselves out]]?</li>
<li>A covered skywalk or monorail between the Telus Convention Centre and the Stampede facilities. What, the C-Train isn&#8217;t good enough for you already? (See previous note about public transit.)</li>
<li>An international aerospace hub. If there was a way to eloquently describe my blank stare at this one, I would. But I&#8217;m simply not that good a writer.</li>
</ul>
<p>I offer one thought to the people who came up with this: Let&#8217;s blueprint something for success, please? Around my office, we ask people to set SMART goals. It&#8217;s an acronym, with the &#8220;R&#8221; standing for &#8220;realistic&#8221;. Which these blueprints really seem to be missing.<br />
If you want success, you needn&#8217;t look further than our own front door. We have three overloaded hospitals, our transit system is not keeping pace with the need, ambulances are running short on availability regularly, and if you haven&#8217;t thought about our water supply availability, you might want to consider that soon, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>West LRT Line in Calgary approved</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 22:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/21/west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s official &#8212; I&#8217;m going to be able to ride the C-Train to work in four years. Sounds like a long time away, but the reality is that this is going to make my life a lot better. Back when I used to live in Sunnyside, I periodically took the C-Train to work &#8212; though &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "West LRT Line in Calgary approved"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s official &#8212; <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/calgary/story/2007/11/20/west-lrt.html">I&#8217;m going to be able to ride the C-Train to work in four years</a>. Sounds like a long time away, but the reality is that this is going to make my life a lot better. Back when I used to live in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunnyside,_Calgary">Sunnyside</a>, I periodically took the C-Train to work &#8212; though it was really more like cheating given the short distance.<br />
But I&#8217;m almost back to driving to try and make up 30 minutes a day from travelling on buses and waiting for them to show up (basically, a 1.5 hour round-trip commute). This would help since the trains run near-constantly during rush hour, and cut down on the amount of walking I have to do!<br />
<span id="more-862"></span>So far, based on the <a href="http://www.calgary.ca/portal/server.pt/gateway/PTARGS_0_0_395_203_0_47/http%3B/content.calgary.ca/CCA/City+Hall/Business+Units/Development+and+Building+Approvals+and+Land+Use+Planning+and+Policy/Land+Use+Planning/Current+Studies+and+Ongoing+Activities/Transit+Oriented+Development+TOD/West+LRT+Land+Use+Study/West+LRT+Land+Use+Study.htm">information</a> <a href="http://www.calgary.ca/docgallery/BU/planning/pdf/west_lrt_study/2007/west_lrt_visioning_workshop_one.pdf">that I can</a> <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/lrtincalgary/FutureW.html">freely find</a> (the only think I can&#8217;t seem to find on the net are the conceptual drawings &#8212; those apparently come out on the 21st), the <a href="http://www.calgarytransit.com/w_lrt_base_map_c.pdf">West LRT</a> (as it&#8217;s being called) will run <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/lrtincalgary/WLRT1.jpg">from the existing 7th Avenue line</a> downtown (I also assume this will effectively become an extension of the <a href="http://www.calgarytransit.com/Routes/html/rte202.html">existing 202 line</a>) <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/lrtincalgary/WLRT2.jpg">above ground out to</a> <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/lrtincalgary/WLRT3A.jpg">roughly 33rd St. West, where</a> it&#8217;ll go <a href="http://www.canada.com/calgaryherald/story.html?id=91b129bc-9c22-464d-a605-fa31ef5c9a1b&amp;k=35044">underground for a portion</a> before <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;time=&amp;date=&amp;ttype=&amp;q=calgary&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=51.038085,-114.147896&amp;spn=0.001744,0.003471&amp;t=k&amp;z=18&amp;om=1">reappearing around 41st St.</a>, <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/lrtincalgary/WLRT4.jpg">continuing until it&#8217;s end at 45th St</a>. (the current location of the Alberta Motor Association&#8217;s headquarters in Calgary).<br />
Based on that, they&#8217;re going to need to expropriate some land &#8212; houses along 17th Ave. between 41st and 42nd streets, and <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;time=&amp;date=&amp;ttype=&amp;q=calgary&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=51.038416,-114.154108&amp;spn=0.001744,0.003471&amp;t=k&amp;z=18&amp;om=1">the existing AMA building</a>.<br />
Frankly, I think this is a great time for Calgary to [[Improving Calgary Transit in the city core|make the investment and start burying the C-Train]], especially downtown. The line should also run underground once it crosses into the west, staying under Bow Trail rather than beside it &#8212; or worse, in the middle of it (this is going to cause traffic nightmares the likes of which we can only begin to have night sweats over). And leave it underground.<br />
Based on the maps (see the links in the previous couple of paragraphs), this is planned to run down the middle of Bow Trail and 17th Avenue. I shudder to think of the traffic nightmare that is going to ensue as both of those roads are torn up for widening. It&#8217;s going to make for a very rough couple of years of commuting, I tell you.<br />
And please, can we put the 45th St. station as one set of platforms instead of staggering it? Those are annoying enough downtown without having to subject poor schmucks (like me) to different loading and unloading areas. (Ironically, the future station at Sirocco will actually be closer for me. Go figure.)<br />
Yes, it costs more. But you gain so much more by not having it visible: less interruptions, less noise, less room being taken up, and less chance of some idiot hitting the train (or being hit by the train because of doing something stupid). You also get better security, because underground stations won&#8217;t be open like the the current above-ground stations &#8212; you have to buy a ticket in order to get in.<br />
Either way, this is great news, since it means I won&#8217;t have to worry about driving ever again downtown. When the light permits, I&#8217;ll bike. When the light (and/or weather) sucks, I&#8217;ll train.  And if we happen to have a good party at Critical Mass (<a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/critical-mass/">like that never happens</a>), I&#8217;ll have an alternative to the taxi.<br />
One major drawback that I can think of: parking in my area is gonna suck. Lots of people are going to want to take that C-Train rather than drive downtown. Which means lots of people parking on roads that &#8212; at least for now &#8212; have no restrictions on parking. I&#8217;m outside the 600m radius from the proposed station, but it&#8217;s still only a five-ish minute walk. Ain&#8217;t a stretch by any means.<br />
Bring it on, Calgary! This is a step in the right direction. [[Calgary Transit sucks|Just please keep stepping!]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/west-lrt-line-in-calgary-approved/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">862</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary is big enough for better transit</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 14:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hong kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/11/16/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I&#8217;ve said before, I&#8217;m no expert. I haven&#8217;t been everywhere or done everything. But one thing I have done is paid attention to public transit systems, especially the ones I&#8217;ve had to deal with on a daily basis. Such as the one in Calgary. You already know [[Calgary Transit Sucks&#124;how I feel about our &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary is big enough for better transit"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I&#8217;ve said before, I&#8217;m no expert. I haven&#8217;t been everywhere or done everything. But one thing I have done is paid attention to public transit systems, especially the ones I&#8217;ve had to deal with on a daily basis.<br />
Such as the one in Calgary. You already know [[Calgary Transit Sucks|how I feel about our beloved transit system]]. And we&#8217;re long overdue to consider how much bigger it should be.<br />
<span id="more-861"></span>In fact, some replies to posts I did on [[Calgary Transit Sucks]] and [[Improving Calgary Transit in the city core]], and a half-argument I got into with someone waiting for the 301 led me to think: How does Calgary compare to other cities in terms of transit, anyway?<br />
Some cities I do have direct experience with:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Toronto, Canada</strong><br />
Canada&#8217;s largest city. Hundreds of thousands of people need to enter and leave the city daily. It&#8217;s messy. <a href="http://www.gotransit.com">GO Transit</a> funnels people into the downtown core. <a href="http://www.toronto.ca/ttc/">TTC</a> (subway, buses, streetcars) whisk people about town. The subway is nowhere near as extensive as it needs to be, having only started in the early 1950s  (when the city was less than a million people) and never having received the attention it needs. If it weren&#8217;t for a well-planned surface system, the city would be screwed.</li>
<li><strong>Montreal, Canada</strong><br />
Once Canada&#8217;s largest city (now #2), Montreal has perhaps one of Canada&#8217;s <a href="http://www.stm.info/">best public transportation systems</a>. This all stems from a signficant investment made in the mid-1960s in preparation for for <a href="http://expo67.ncf.ca/">Expo 67</a> &#8212; a large-scale subway system was installed. Combined with ages-old railway (Montreal was the headquarters of both <a href="http://www.cpr.ca">Canadian Pacific</a> and <a href="http://www.cn.ca">Canadian National Railways</a>, so was strewn with large train stations), and well-planned bus routes, Montreal is a public transit dream. Sadly, not one that seems to show up in a lot of case studies.</li>
<li><strong>Ottawa, Canada</strong><br />
Despite a reputation for the surliest bus drivers in Canada (my friend Chris took serious issue with a few of them during his habitation in our Nation&#8217;s Capital for not listening to passengers, yelling at passengers, driving like a maniacs, etc.), Ottawa has a pretty decent system. Notably because someone saw fit to have <a href="http://www.octranspo.com/">OC Transpo</a> buy roads and make them dedicated transit ways. It&#8217;s helped keep the million-plus area flowing well. And the addition of the O-Train should help keep major corridors flowing even better. Problem: I&#8217;m sure this plan never accounted for the Ottawa area extending over the border into Hull.</li>
<li><strong>Vancouver, Canada</strong><br />
Vancouver has a lot of trouble due to its physical and geopolitical limitations (mountains to the north, ocean to the west, USA to the south), which add up to some interesting problems for the population. Namely, they tend to live in a 20-kilometre wide swath from the Georgia Strait out to Hope. To get people around is <a href="http://www.translink.bc.ca/">an excellent bus system</a> (including rapid service buses on major routes), an ever-expanding light rail system (despite the NIMBYism in Point Grey), and the <a href="http://www.westcoastexpress.com/">West Coast Express</a> along the CP line (although the trains need to run all day, instead of just a few in the morning and a few in the evening &#8230; and run them until 23:00, would ya?).</li>
<li><strong>Kitchener/Waterloo/Cambridge, Canada</strong><br />
The tri-city area was once just Kitchener Transit. KW (as it was known when I went to university) were two cities that functioned as one. The <a href="http://www.grt.ca">Grand River Transit</a> system (as it&#8217;s now known) grew from a single small city system to cover three cities. And a lot more effectively than Calgary Transit seems to cover its measly self.</li>
<li><strong>New York City, USA</strong><br />
New York City is a true prototype of how to build a city: vertically. People live in skyscrapers, and travel quickly underground. The Big Apple&#8217;s first subway rolled along in the mid 1860s &#8212; a full century before Montreal got its Metro. <a href="http://www.mta.info/">New York&#8217;s system</a> covers five cities (now boroughs) and started when the population meter was barely at 830,000! And NYC is wholly dependent on the system &#8212; if the subways stop, the city goes into traffic gridlock. You can get anywhere in NYC by subway, and it&#8217;s simple for any visitor to pick up the system quickly. Trains and buses bring people in and out of the city, but inside, it&#8217;s the subway bringing the city to life.</li>
<li><strong>San Francisco, USA</strong><br />
Although San Francisco was late in getting its light rail (BART), San Francisco had already mastered ferries, trains, streetcars (the famous cable cars). Buses came later. And with San Francisco being on a peninsula, there was a lot of need to make it work well. Yes, SF was big when light rail finally came in (the SF area was huge) but this was to augment <a href="http://transit.511.org/">the transit system</a> already in place.</li>
<li><strong>London, England</strong><br />
London was the first to get an Underground in the mid-1860s. The city was already 1.6 million, though, and the Underground was to alleviate the trouble of travelling on the surface. All the trains, all the horse-drawn vehicles (and automobiles were fast-coming), and all the people were making movement nearly impossible. (Calgary &#8212; does this at all sound familiar? Well, maybe on with the horses during Stampede.) <a href="http://www.tfl.gov.uk/">London now is a paradise for public transit</a>, with outstanding subway systems, excellent rail services (for those of you who would beg to differ, I offer Canada as an example of how bad it can get), and well-marked bus services (you don&#8217;t need a map to know where you&#8217;re going).</li>
<li><strong>Paris, France</strong><br />
Given, Paris was about two million when the Metro arrived. Paris had similar problems to London &#8230; just with more people in a smaller space. The Metro saved Paris&#8217; population from having to survive travelling on roads and quickly get around. Today, <a href="http://www.ratp.fr/">Paris&#8217; Metro is fast, cheap, and effective</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Moscow, Russia</strong><br />
One of the largest in the world in terms of volume, the <a href="http://www.metro.ru/">Moscow Metro</a> has only been around since the 1930s. A bit more on the state-enforced development end, the Metro is something most Moscovites depend on, much in the way New Yorkers depend on the subway. No Metro, no Moscow.</li>
<li><strong>Shanghai, China</strong><br />
In addition to a great subway system (connected with China&#8217;s extensive rail system), Shanghai also has the world&#8217;s <a href="http://www.smtdc.com/en">first commercial magnetic levitation train</a>. It runs at high speed (over 400 km/h) to the airport. Sadly, it doesn&#8217;t do this from downtown Shanghai (which would make it truly exceptional), so it&#8217;s almost more kvitchy. I doubt Calgary would benefit from maglev, but such a train from Calgary to Edmonton would cover the distance in less than an hour.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong SAR, China</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.hkpt.com/">Buses</a>: super-comfortable and air-conditioned. <a href="http://www.mtr.com.hk/prehome/index.html">Subway</a>: not very extensive, but at least runs out to the airport. Trains: not many, but they do run into China. <a href="http://www.hktramways.com/">Tramways</a>: Handy and cheap, when you&#8217;re in the Central/Admiralty areas of Hong Kong. Mind you, much of that area is small enough that you can walk on foot.</li>
<li><strong>Tokyo, Japan</strong><br />
Tokyo and trains go hand-in-hand. <a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp/e/">No trains, no Tokyo.</a> Japan it heavily dependent on public transit because its made owning a car prohibitive. This is a lesson most of the rest of the world should learn: cars shouldn&#8217;t be considered necessities, except in some circumstances (e.g. ambulances). There is little that can&#8217;t be accomplished on your own two feet, with buses, trains, and subways covering the rest.</li>
</ul>
<p>Calgary should be learning from cities such as these &#8212; especially its cousins in Canada &#8212; and learning what could be done to make things better. It should also look at its own history. Calgary used to have an interurban system that covered a lot of the city. Gone, and pretty much forgotten. But more extensive (by a wide margin) than the current C-Train.<br />
It&#8217;s not about planning for more roads. It&#8217;s not about ensuring there&#8217;s parking downtown. It&#8217;s about making better (that includes regularly-staffed, regularly-timed, and appropriately-equipped) bus routes, dedicated lanes during rush hours to funnel people in and out of downtown, [[Improving Calgary Transit in the city core|buried transit lines downtown]], more C-Train lines, and maybe (just maybe) trains to/from <a href="http://http://www.banffrailco.com/commuter.htm">High River, Canmore, Strathmore, and Airdrie</a>.<br />
It&#8217;s not like it hasn&#8217;t been done before.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/11/calgary-is-big-enough-for-better-transit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">861</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Improving Calgary Transit in the city core</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 15:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2007/10/24/improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve gone back to taking the bus. While biking to work is (believe it or not) faster than taking the bus, I&#8217;m not too fond of the idea of biking down the side of the hill (switchback or not) in the dark, where I know coyotes tend to lurk. I&#8217;ve seen them in my neighbourhood &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Improving Calgary Transit in the city core"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve gone back to taking the bus. While biking to work is (believe it or not) faster than taking the bus, I&#8217;m not too fond of the idea of biking down the side of the hill (switchback or not) in the dark, where I know coyotes tend to lurk. I&#8217;ve seen them in my neighbourhood &#8212; some distance from the river &#8212; so I know they hang out in the bushes.<br />
Besides, I&#8217;m a lazy bastard and right now I&#8217;m having a hard enough time getting out of bed let alone biking 11.4 kilometres first thing in the morning.<br />
<span id="more-845"></span>One observation that I&#8217;ve made as I take the bus (which, I should point out, isn&#8217;t going too badly, <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2006/08/15/calgary-transit-sucks/">compared to previous situations</a>) is that the traffic downtown is a bit nightmarish at times. Especially because of all the buses that flow in and out during rush hours.<br />
Add to that the complexity of having one avenue completely closed to anything but public transit, and another one that&#8217;s half-closed to nothing but pedestrian traffic. And a whack of one-way roads. And a rail line that runs along the bottom of the core, a river across the top, and only eight entry/exit points.<br />
Yeah, it gets messy. And Calgary&#8217;s core isn&#8217;t that big. (Yet &#8212; it&#8217;s growing. Last I counted, I could see 13 cranes from my desk, and I&#8217;m not even next to a window.)<br />
So how do we solve what will become a real mess in later years?<br />
I&#8217;m gonna go out on a limb here and suggest something really crazy: <strong>bury Calgary Transit</strong>. Literally.<br />
For Calgary Transit to be really effective, it needs to run where there are no other vehicles to slow it down. The C-Train needs to run without having to cross all the roads (especially in the North East quadrant &#8230; but that&#8217;s another topic). The idea of burying the C-Train isn&#8217;t new (there&#8217;s even a roughed-in C-Train station under City Hall), but I think it should go one step further, and bury the bus lines, too.<br />
Buses would still enter the downtown area above ground, like everything else. But as it gets closer to the core, the bus shifts to dedicated lanes, and eventually goes right underground. Entering the underground, the bus enters a racetrack-like loop that runs across most of the width and part of the height for the downtown, hitting the major areas, and then exits at the appropriate location.<br />
Calgary&#8217;s core is ideally suited to this for two reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>It&#8217;s small. The core is only about 14 blocks wide and not even 10 blocks high at it&#8217;s tallest point. Most of the main buildings are in an 6&#215;10 area.</li>
<li>The downtown already concentrates much of the radiating transit services.</li>
</ol>
<p>So here&#8217;s what I propose:<br />
[flickr]photo:3871045003[/flickr]<br />
Allow me to describe the above diagram in more detail.</p>
<ul>
<li>The existing C-Train line is buried under its current route &#8212; 7th Avenue &#8212; and rerouted to start using the City Hall station. New underground stations are built at:
<ul>
<li>Centre St.</li>
<li>Between 2nd and 3rd St. SW</li>
<li>Between 5th and 6th St. SW</li>
<li>At 8th St. SW</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> C-Trains enter the downtown from the North East along the same route as present, but go underground before they cross 4th St. SE.</li>
<li>C-Trains exit the downtown to the North West along the same route, but remain underground until they pass under 5th Ave. At that point, they could turn into an overpass over 4th Ave. Or go under 4th Ave and have a steeper approach to the bridge over the Bow River.</li>
<li>The new West Extension would remain underground until passing under 14th St. SW, coming out next to the car dealerships.</li>
<li>Buses entering downtown along Bow Trail/9th Ave would enter the underground system just west of 11th St. (before all the traffic lights).</li>
<li>Buses exiting downtown towards Bow Trail would exit just west of 11th St.  along 6th Ave., thus bypassing all the traffic lights.</li>
<li>Buses entering/exiting downtown from the south enter through the underpass at the railway tracks along 2nd St. SE (aka MacLeod North), and exit via the underpass at the railway tracks along 1st St. SE (aka MacLeod South)</li>
<li>Buses entering/exiting downtown via Centre St from the north will enter and exit through ramps starting around 4th Ave, so the curve into the racetrack isn&#8217;t too blinding (e.g. tight corners).</li>
<li>Buses entering/exiting downtown from the east via Memorial Drive will enter from the 4th Ave flyover into a tunnel leading into the racetrack, and exit onto the 5th Ave flyover via a similar tunnel.</li>
<li>Buses travelling down 10th Ave. into Kensington will enter the racetrack (southbound) via 9th St. once they cross over the river into the core.</li>
<li>Buses travelling out of the core to go up 10th Ave. into Kensington will use a tunnel that exits out onto 4th Ave., where they can turn onto the bridge without a light. (This assumes the C-Train has also been suitably diverted.)</li>
</ul>
<p>The &#8220;racetrack&#8221; is effectively a rectangular course that runs in one direction (counter-clockwise) under the existing streets, bordered by 9th St. SW in the west, 9th Ave. S in the south, 2nd St. SE in the east, and 6th Ave. S in the north. Buses would stop at designated areas along the 9th Ave. section (between 8th St. and Centre St.), 2nd St. SE, and along 6th Ave. SE (between 1st St. SW and 7th St. SW).<br />
The stops would be shared across several routes (as there are probably over 50 that come into downtown during rush hours), taking advantage of schedules that don&#8217;t have buses all arriving at the same time. Buses would stop at 2-3 different points in the racetrack before exiting (possibly looping once before leaving).<br />
In theory (I stress that I am neither a city planner or a transit expert), this would reduce surface traffic (less buses stopping and changing lanes, and freeing up 7th Ave. back to vehicular traffic), and improve bus performance (fewer lights, easier movement underground, less traffic).<br />
Furthermore, having all the transit underground means people could avoid the nasty, cold weather during the winter months. The space could be easily ventilated for fumes, and the underground situation balances heat and cold seasonally.<br />
Any thoughts? I&#8217;m curious to know if I&#8217;m just on crack, here&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2007/10/improving-calgary-transit-in-the-city-core/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">845</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calgary Transit Sucks</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=calgary-transit-sucks</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 01:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[c-train]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ottawa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toronto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vancouver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was having a discussion with Doug down in the Bistro this morning, and I came to a rather interesting realization: Calgary Transit sucks. Let&#8217;s have a realistic view, here. Calgary is the third or fourth largest city in Canada. We&#8217;re over a million people (we recently had our one millionth baby, but I suspect &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Calgary Transit Sucks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was having a discussion with Doug down in the Bistro this morning, and I came to a rather interesting realization: Calgary Transit sucks.<br />
Let&#8217;s have a realistic view, here. Calgary is the third or fourth largest city in Canada. We&#8217;re over a million people (we recently had our one millionth baby, but I suspect we&#8217;re actually well over that number in population). We have a massive city by area because Calgary hasn&#8217;t quite figured out that we should be building up, not out.<br />
<span id="more-3535"></span>Calgary is attempting to address this fact by improving roads. Roads. As in expecting people to drive. Wow. There&#8217;s incentive to take public transit. Okay, in their defense, the C-Train will be up in the Northwest at Crowfoot Crossing in the next year or two. But not in the Northeast or in the effective places in the south, where the city is growing the fastest.<br />
The bus system is a joke. Some parts of the city are well-served. But overall, it&#8217;s far from what this city needs. Ottawa at least had the smarts to put in bus routes that use their own roads, where cars cannot go. Calgary can&#8217;t do that because the roads are already filled with cars carrying a single person. I know &#8212; I used to be one of them.<br />
A few months ago, I used to drive to work. Seven-odd kilometres one way. Fifteen minutes if I hit every light and got stuck behind slow people. I had a prime parking spot. It was everything I shouldn&#8217;t be doing. I live <strong>SEVEN</strong> kilometres from work. Why on earth would I drive? I decided in the spring to bike and bus. So far, the biking is going very well &#8212; I can get to work almost as fast as it took me to drive. Getting home takes a bit longer, but it&#8217;s mostly uphill.<br />
The bus is a different story. Although the #7 is actually pretty convenient in the morning, the afternoon is another issue. I&#8217;ve been passed by at the stop near my office several times because the bus was full. (There were a couple of cases where the bus simply didn&#8217;t show up.) The telephone schedule is wildly inaccurate because the bus never actually follows that schedule.<br />
The bus where I am is good compared to those poor folks who end up living on the outskirts of town. Bus service exists out there too, but the timing sucks. Somewhere, the person at Calgary Transit who sets the schedules needs to spend some time with the people who ride the bus and ask how it works for them. Based on all the people I&#8217;ve talked to, it&#8217;s not working.<br />
There are a series of express buses designed to help funnel people in from the outer ring. For these people, it can cut as much as 50% off their commute time. But it doesn&#8217;t come without a price. People have to start earlier and have to leave early or face a long ride to and from work. One of my co-workers, Colin, has to run out at 16:55 sharp every day or face the prospect of a long ride home because he&#8217;ll miss the last express. The last one. Not the last for an hour &#8230; the last of the day.<br />
<em>What Einstein doesn&#8217;t know that most offices actually close at 17:00?</em><br />
This baffles me beyond belief. Yes, some places in Calgary close earlier in the day, but not all of them. Many places are open until 17:00 or later. But too bad if you&#8217;re not one of the lucky few who actually close when Calgary Transit says you should. This insular ignorance of reality amazes me to no end. (The same problem exists with the West Coast Express in Vancouver. Vancouver runs more on the 9-5 workday than Calgary does!)<br />
And lest you think that I&#8217;m just some rambling idiot (which I very well may be), my friend Tom has piped in with his own thoughts:</p>
<blockquote><p>I figured moving to a company right downtown where the C-Train is close would be great. Not so. In order for me to catch the C-Train at the Dalhousie station, I have to be there before 06:40 just to get a parking spot. The Citadel bus (199) goes right past the Dalhousie station and feeds the Brentwood station. Where&#8217;s the logic in that? When the weather is nice, I get to ride my Hog-2-be to work (I double park in the bosses spot). Riding the bike takes 25 minutes from Citadel to downtown. Driving to Dalhousie and taking the train usually takes about 40 to 50 minutes. It costs in fuel for the bike $1.00 each way, transit &#8211; $2.25. Just to recap, when I can ride my bike, it takes half the time for less than half the price and I don&#8217;t need to squeeze myself on the homebound train, which of course is the last stop out of downtown going North West. Why in the world would I ever want to take Calgary Transit??? I am so looking forward to our company moving out of downtown and up on Centre street and 11th ave North in October where I will have my own parking spot and never have to rely on Calgary Transit again!</p></blockquote>
<p>Calgary has a 15 year plan to expand all the C-Train stations to add a fourth car to the trains. And eventually they&#8217;ll get enough cars to handle the load. Already the trains are packed tight. We&#8217;ll need to hire some Japanese pushers to get everyone in before too long. We don&#8217;t need longer trains in 15 years &#8212; we need more trains <strong>now</strong>. We need to double the number of trains, and then use those cars to expand the three-car trains to four-car trains in the future. We need to expand the C-Train route to the southwest to Westhills, the southeast to Mackenzie Town, the north west to Tuscany, the northeast (admittedly, I don&#8217;t know the area up there that well), and for God&#8217;s sake, can we please run the C-Train to the airport? Would it really kill someone to think that Calgary should have a <strong>single</strong> route from the airport to downtown? Or am I being grossly naive here?<br />
The bus routes, as Chris recently pointed out, are all undocumented. If you don&#8217;t live here, you have no idea where the bus is going or when it should come. It doesn&#8217;t take a lot of effort to put up schedules on the bus stops and put maps so people know where they&#8217;re going. Really smart bus companies show major routes so people know where to change to other routes. London has this figured out. Tokyo has it down to a science. Paris has it made. Honk Kong is a breeze. Calgary&#8217;s a frickin&#8217; disaster.<br />
And it costs a lot for the privilege, too. $2.25 by current prices. That doesn&#8217;t get you much. And Calgary Transit wonders why they&#8217;re losing money.<br />
Someone please wake up and check out the reality of the city&#8217;s transportation needs? We&#8217;re grossly behind compared to other cities, and if we have any hope at all of stemming the tide of cars driving in and out of downtown, we need some common sense helping set the direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2006/08/calgary-transit-sucks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>256</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3535</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
