<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>toyohashi &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/toyohashi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 22:58:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 22:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiroshima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miyajima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/29/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.) It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.)<br />
It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. Twenty-four degrees is just uncomfortable. We rose, repacked our bags, and prepared for the trip to Hiroshima. Neither of us were particularly hungry, so would skip breakfast. Chris called to inform us of the paper shinkansen schedule, which we&#8217;d found out about the night before.<br />
<span id="more-336"></span>One thing the schedule had shown was the difference in shinkansen trains.There are three different types running between Tokyo and Hakata: Kodama, Hikaru, and Nozomi. Kodama shinkansen are local trains, hitting every station on their runs. Hikaru shinkansen are limited, hitting only some of the stations. Nozomi shinkansen are express, and run between only a few stations. Nozomi trains are the only ones that will run all the way from Tokyo to Hakata. The others terminate roughly half-way.<br />
We came to Toyohashi on a Kodama, but we left on a Hikaru. (We can&#8217;t take a Nozomi, as the rail pass doesn&#8217;t cover those trains.) It took us to Shin-Osaka, where we switched to another Hikaru that took us to Hiroshima.<br />
Getting a seat on the shinkansen wasn&#8217;t as easy as I&#8217;d hoped. I figured that when we got to Shin-Osaka, getting prime seats on the next Hiraku would be as simple as being the first in line. Except that when we got to Track 20 (no, there aren&#8217;t 20 shinkansen tracks &#8212; the track we were on just happened to be the last in the series of all tracks at the station), the lines were already quite full. Luckily, we still got good seats, although we were quite crammed in with our backpacks and day bags.<br />
It&#8217;s odd. On weekends, getting a seat is surprisingly easy on long-distance trains, when you&#8217;d figure most people would be travelling. But during the week, the seats are packed to the point of standing-room only, when people would normally not be travelling. This is an odd country&#8230;<br />
Jen slept most of the way between Toyohashi and Shin-Osaka, and between Shin-Osaka and Hiroshima. I did, too, opting for some much-needed rest. The last couple of days had taken their toll on me, and a short nap was much welcomed. Although I haven&#8217;t been here long, I&#8217;m already adapting to the Japanese way of riding the trains &#8212; fall asleep just enough to rest, but not enough that you don&#8217;t hear the call for the next station.<br />
Disembarking at Hiroshima, we went in search of lockers. The idea was to ditch our bags and lug around only our day bags. Sadly, the only lockers we could find weren&#8217;t large enough to store the big bags, so we were forced to continue with those. Instead, we put away some of the stuff we didn&#8217;t want to carry.<br />
Once outside, we found streetcars that would take us to the Atomic Bomb Dome. This is one of the major tourist spots of Japan, and is so well-featured that many signs bear the name. Even signs at the streetcar made it clear that you could take the streetcar to the Hiroshima Bomb Dome for 150 yen. It was almost too easy.<br />
Easy enough for us to realize that either we left our bags at the station, went to the dome, and then came back before going to Miyajima, or we took our bags with us, and then continued on the streetcar to the Miyajima ferry. We oped for the latter.<br />
The streetcar ride down was easy, requiring little more than to obtain a ticket, and wait for the station to appear. Once I realized that there was a digtal sign that read off station names in English, it was impossible to miss the dome. That, and the station stop is barely 100 metres from it. Very hard to miss.<br />
The Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome is the former Hiroshima Prefecture Industry Promotion Hall, barely 100 metres from the hypocentre of the blast. It has come to symbolize the destructive power of the atomic bomb, and is a constant reminder of what happened at 8:15, 6 August 1945.<br />
It was a strange moment for me. I&#8217;ve read all about the atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima. I&#8217;ve read about the reasons for and against it. I&#8217;ve heard the debates and listened to the stories. It&#8217;s something to have a perspective on the event, but it&#8217;s entirely another to witness the actual building &#8212; or what&#8217;s left of it. Aside from excavations following its destruction, and some preservation work to keep it intact, the dome remains untouched from when it was destroyed nearly 60 years ago.<br />
As Jen and I walked taking photos, a little elderly woman came up to her and flashed a small sign that read: &#8220;Would you like to receive prayers for happiness?&#8221; I didn&#8217;t know this at first, because all I found was this tiny woman holding her hand up towards Jen&#8217;s bowed head. A little confused for a moment, another elderly woman came up to me and flashed a similar sign. Jen and I were blessed, in a way, to allow us to have a much happier day.<br />
Taking a photo of the two women, they directed us to the Peace Memorial Park, surrounded by the Ota-gawa River, the shores lined with sakura &#8212; cherry trees just entering full bloom. We could hardly pass that up.<br />
On the other side, we found more monuments to the tragedy of the a-bomb attack. One was a peace bell, the supports built of concrete, from which was suspended a traditional shinto bell. The chain used for the bell&#8217;s clapper had a metal origami crane. This is significant because next to the bell are several transparent plastic observation booths filled with hundreds of thousands of paper cranes, offered in peaceful remembrance of 6 August.<br />
Further into the park is the eternal flame, near the Peach Arch. Looking through the Peace Arch towards the flame, you can see directly to the dome. The Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum is past the Peace Arch, but we didn&#8217;t go there. Instead, I followed Jen over to something she saw off to one side. It was a concrete wall, inside of which looked like a clock surrounded by a bed of broken bricks.<br />
It was the top of the Hiroshima National Peace Memorial Hall for the Atomic Bomb Victims. The clock is a skylight into the middle of musem, and is fixed at the time of detonation, 8:15. The bricks were excavated from the Atomic Bomb Dome.<br />
Deciding that it might be an interesting thing to see (and because it was free), we headed down into the entrance. (The museum is underground.) Inside, we were handed English pamphlets, and directed down the walkway, which spirals further down into the earth. Every 20 feet or so, there is a glass panel with text about World War II and the atomic bomb and its affects on Hiroshima.<br />
The perspective is interesting. This should be the Japanese perspective. This is their view of (what is basically) an attack of unwarranted scale. But they&#8217;re not accusatory, not disdainful. The presentation is factual, and appeals to visitors to campaign against the use of nuclear weapons.<br />
At the bottom, you enter a huge round room. At the top is the skylight you see at ground level. Directly under the skylight is a fountain, also in the shape of the 8:15 clock. The water is offered as a consolation to all those who died begging for a drink. On the walls are the names of the neighbourhoods destroyed by the bomb, their proximity to the floor indicating how close they were to the hypocentre. Around the upper third of the room is a 360 panoramic view of the destroyed Hiroshima, as seen from the hypocentre, recreated with 140,000 hand-carved tiles. One tile for each person who died.<br />
Leaving the room, you come to a display of some of the victims. Each of the pamphlets accesses one of 9,606 photographs of a victim through a computer. Mine accessed the record of a 48 year-old woman by the name of Masayo Kubota. Suddenly, it wasn&#8217;t just a piece of paper. This was a real person.<br />
Sobered quite a lot by the museum, it was quite strange to come to the surface to be confronted by the sounds of a bustling metropolis (Hiroshima is quite large), the laughs of playing children, and the chatter of a people who most likely don&#8217;t think about the events of 6 August on a regular basis.<br />
Stopping briefly at the Tourist Information Office for a map and a drink (green tea slushie, anyone?), we continued back to the streetcar station to head down to Miyajimaguchi station, to catch the ferry to Miyajima.<br />
A note for anyone going from Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome to Miyajima. As soon as you can switch to the JR Sanyo line, do so. The trip by streetcar, although nice, is very long.<br />
At Miyajimaguchi station, I called the ryokan in Miyajima to let them know we were catching the next ferry to the island. (They offered a pickup service, and we were to call ahead.) The conversation was a bit difficult due to the language barrier, but the person I was speaking with had obviously taken the trouble to learn enough English to make herself understood.<br />
The ferry trip over was short, only about 10 minutes, and we were soon waiting out in front of the ferry station for our ride to the ryokan. A small white bus appeared in view, and an enthusiastic employee beckoned us to join him for a drive.<br />
The speed limit in Miyajima seems to be about 20 km/h. This guy was doing at least 60 in most places, narrowly missing people and other cars in his mad dash to get to the ryokan to drop us off. The ride, though confusing, was enough to make Jen and I suddenly wish that we didn&#8217;t have to go to Kyoto tomorrow (we have reservations, so don&#8217;t have much of a choice) and stay here a while longer.<br />
Hold on, you&#8217;re probably looking at that &#8220;ryokan&#8221; word and are wondering what that is. We&#8217;re staying at what&#8217;s called a ryokan &#8212; it&#8217;s a type of Japanese hotel. We&#8217;re at the Momijiso ryokan, which sits in the middle of Momijitani Park, up the hill from the town/village of Miyajima. In fact, the ryokan is on the way to the ropeway to the top of the mountain.<br />
Mimijiso is the only building in sight. (Mind you, with the forest, it&#8217;s hard to see the next ryokan down the side.) It&#8217;s also a cafe for travellers going up and down Mt. Meisen, a focus of religion in the area &#8212; there are many shrines at the top of the mountain. The isolation is glorious.<br />
We were greeted at the door by what I can only describe as the house matron, a wonderful elderly woman whom I can only assume was the one I had talked to earlier. She guided us to our room, ushered us in, and immediately served us maple leaf-shaped cakes (filled with red bean paste) and two cups of very strong green tea. She told us that dinner was at 18:30, and that breakfast was at 8:00 tomorrow morning.<br />
We had time to kill, so leaving most of our bags behind, Jen and I went to explore the town of Miyajima. The town centres on the shrine, which sits in a tidal area at the shoreline. Just offshore is a torii, a huge red gate that is the symbol for Miyajima. There are shrines all over this part of the island.<br />
One of the other symbols of Miyajima is the maple leaf. Not the same as the Canadian maple leaf, but a Japanese maple. (Jen described it as looking like a marijuana plant.) During the fall, apparently the entire area turns a bright red from the changing leaves. The symbol is found in everything from the cakes, cell phone (kaitei) baubles, markers on the roads and sewer grates, signs, and various tourist trinkets.<br />
As Jen and I walked around, we came realize that we really liked Miyajima. I might have trouble tomorrow when it comes time to leave. Jen and I might not want to get on the boat. I really wish I could change the reservation in Kyoto so we could stay another day. The architecture here is quaint and simple, the people nice, and the lifestyle laid back. And walking around in the park is a joy.<br />
Deer are everywhere. Miyajima has countless deer. They&#8217;re small, about the side of a large dog. And completely unafraid of humans. They probably eat a little too much from humans, so have no qualms about coming up to you for food. Jen refused one, and it whined.<br />
We wandered down to the shrine and torii, up to the pagoda, around the town and through the countless gift shops (my only complaint of Miyajima &#8212; it&#8217;s almost like an amusement park at times, though at least some of the stores aren&#8217;t too tacky), before arriving back just in time for dinner.<br />
The cooking was &#8230; exquisite. We were told it was mostly fish. The &#8220;appetizers&#8221; were sashimi (locally-caught whitefish, sea breem, and the most succulent tuna I&#8217;ve ever had), traditional sunomuno, and some egg thing that I can&#8217;t even begin to describe. Then it was a cooked piece of sea breem (that blew me away), rice, miso soup, pickled roots, and finally fresh strawberries and melon.<br />
Following dinner, Jen and I went exploring again. With all the tourists gone, it was easier to move around, and much quieter. The deer had gone to sleep. We took pictures of the torii (now lit up for night), walked around the town, and explored a few roads we hadn&#8217;t been down.<br />
I need a tranquilizer for Jen, though. She gets quite hyper.<br />
We returned for about 21:00, since the ryokan closes down around 21:30 for the night. Which was fine with us, since both of us were quite tired. It&#8217;s been a long day, but a very good one.<br />
I think those prayers worked, because tonight, Jen and I are very happy.<br />
[flickr]tag:toyohashi+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr] [flickr]tag:hiroshima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:miyajima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#039;s Wedding</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2004 22:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irako]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/28/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I woke just before sunrise. I probably should have gotten up to look around, but decided that I&#8217;d rather sleep a bit more. I had a sneaky suspicion that it was going to be a long day. I woke again around 7:00, when my alarm went off. Jen sounded like she was still asleep (though &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Chris and Kaz&#039;s Wedding"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke just before sunrise. I probably should have gotten up to look around, but decided that I&#8217;d rather sleep a bit more. I had a sneaky suspicion that it was going to be a long day.<br />
I woke again around 7:00, when my alarm went off. Jen sounded like she was still asleep (though she claims she wasn&#8217;t), so I opted not to disturb her and went to go see what the area looked like with the rising sun.<br />
<span id="more-335"></span>Back up to the roof and the observation deck, I took in the morning glory of Irako, and the mouth of the bay beyond the tip of the peninsula. Smog lined the shores on the other side, it&#8217;s thick, brown haze unmistakable. (By noon, the brown would be replaced by a thick, white haze, obscuring the other shore.)<br />
We headed down for breakfast around 8:00. The buffet was a little different than the night before. Still offering miso soup and soba noodles, the selection also offered fruit, eggs, and a variety of Japanese and western choices. Chris convinced Garth, Jen, and I to try a Japanese plum, which is sour and salty. Garth liked it, but Jen and I found it less palatable.<br />
Mind you, the same division in tastes exists among the Japanese. Like with several things (like natto), they either love it or hate it. Few just accept or tolerate.<br />
Shinichiro and Riko appeared soon after Mr. and Mrs. May appeared. Tony would straggle down a little later, not looking much different than he had the night before. (As Tony put several times, life on Saipan is slow, so as a result, he&#8217;s slow. Take that for what it&#8217;s worth&#8230;)<br />
Jen and I had come prepared for a little excursion down to the beach following breakfast, and took our leave of the others before they had finished. We took a steep set of stairs from an exit on the west side of the hotel down to a service road of some kind, which took us to the hotel&#8217;s driveway, and down to the main road that runs along the coast. Along one side is a cycling path, which guided us down and around the windy coastline.<br />
It took a while to find a break in the dense tropical vegetation that would show us a path down to the beach. The time wasn&#8217;t poorly spent, however, since the walk was warm, and the sounds of songbirds were an absolute delight. But as we came closer to the surf, the rushing of the waves would become the dominant music.<br />
The trail down to the beach was not maintained, formed over years of people trying to get down to the beach from the road. It&#8217;s about 100 feet in elevation, and you need to be a bit of a mountain goat to do it easily. Fortunately, both Jen and I do a lot of hiking, so the trail wasn&#8217;t an issue.<br />
The beach is long &#8212; a couple of kilometres in total length, following the curve from the point to the bulge that the hotel sits on. The beach mostly disappears there, before reforming on the eastern side of the bulge. The section we were on is littered with tetrapods &#8212; concrete forms with four &#8220;legs&#8221; sticking out at 120 angles to each other. They form an interlocking pattern that creates a barrier against beach erosion.<br />
We wandered the beach a little while, taking pictures and enjoying the sound of the waves on the shore. Jen played chicken with the incoming surf, looking for unique shells, while I walked around taking pictures. But we couldn&#8217;t stay long, and soon had to head back to get ready for the wedding.<br />
I ironed out the wrinkles formed from packing my suit (thankfully minimized), showered, and shaved. Jen showered and dressed, then packed up our collective collection o&#8217; crap and headed back down to the lobby. We had to check out prior to the wedding, and put our bags in a holding room for the day.<br />
Tony and I had been drafted to greet incoming guests, having them sign their names, presenting them with drink tickets, and showing them to a waiting area until they were ready for us at the chapel.<br />
Tony and I had a good laugh at this. Here were two gaijin white guys (one of whom knows enough Japanese to be dangerous, the other can say &#8220;hello&#8221;, &#8220;please&#8221;, and &#8220;sushi&#8221;) greeting people who know a couple words of English and telling them what to do. As Tony said several times: &#8220;Better to laugh, &#8216;cuz crying ain&#8217;t gonna do anything for you.&#8221;<br />
At a little after noon, we were directed towards the second floor (one floor below the lobby), and out to the chapel. The chapel is a small building with a tall spire, just slightly separated from the hotel building. (The Irako View Hotel must do a lot of weddings.) The inside was nice, if perhaps a little austere. But it was small, so it didn&#8217;t seem too awkward.<br />
We entered through a door on the north side of the building, and entered the octagonal chapel room. The western three sides had massive windows that overlooked the water and across the bay. (It would make taking pictures a little difficult.) Chris&#8217; family and friends (totalling eight, including Shinichiro, who was doubling as photographer) sat on the left side of the room, while Kaz&#8217;s family and friends (totalling about 30) sat on the right side of the room.<br />
The emcee was one of the hotel&#8217;s employees, who regularly performs this duty (it&#8217;s not hard to tell). She&#8217;s quite good, although her English is a little forced. While a very nice service overall, I was a little perturbed by the woman&#8217;s need to inject a bit of a sales pitch for wedding services at the hotel. Probably normal, though I couldn&#8217;t imagine anyone of us single, English-speaking folk really interested in getting married there.<br />
With Enya playing over the speakers, the doors to the chapel on the east wall opened, and Mrs. May walked in her son to be married. They bowed at the door and entered. It&#8217;s not easy to take pictures when you can&#8217;t see for the tears in your eyes. They walked to the west side of the room, where they faced the audience over a white-draped table. A moment later, Kazumi and her father followed, bowing, and taking their positions next to Chris and his mom. The two parents then left the soon-to-be-newlyweds behind. The last ones through the doors were Kaz&#8217;s nephews (both about three years old), who brought in a small teddy bear with their rings. (As far as I know, the same rings they bought two years ago &#8212; see [[A Surprise Engagement]].)<br />
No-one stood for Chris and Kaz. This is a bit of an odd service, at least by western standards. The emcee guided the audience through the ritual, which went as follows. First, the register was signed by Chris, Kaz, their parents, and then everyone in attendance. This is, I assume, to prove that the civil service was approved by everyone in attendance. Jen was a little confused at first, not sure what she was supposed to do. I just told her to follow what everyone else was doing.<br />
It was a little odd signing the register. I&#8217;ve never signed one before. At the time I was signing it, it was just me putting my name down. But as I rose to leave, Chris said: &#8220;Thanks, Geoff&#8221; That&#8217;s when it hit me. This wasn&#8217;t just a signature. This was an affirmation of the marriage, of Chris&#8217; love for Kaz, and my love for him.<br />
Following the registry signing, they exchanged rings, and exchanged vows, Chris reading in Japanese and Kaz reading in English. The ceremony was short, but simple. The married couple then walked down the aisle. I took pictures that I could not see.<br />
I always seem to cry at weddings.<br />
Once outside, we all engaged in attempts to take pictures of Chris and Kaz, before being directed to a pair of benches so we could take a large group photo. This was nigh-excrutiating, as we were not only looking directly into the sun, but were also subjected with a bright flash. My eyes felt like they were burning out of my head. I hope that my eyes don&#8217;t look too screwed up from trying to keep them open.<br />
After all this, Chris can actually say that I&#8217;ve gone to the ends of the Earth for him.<br />
After the group shots were more photos, done with Shinichiro. We took a barrage of rather confusing instructions and eventually figured out where we were supposed to stand. Finally, we followed Chris and Kaz back into the hotel, and over to the wedding reception room for the family meal (Jen, Tony, Shinichiro, Riko, and I were considered extended family).<br />
The reception was a little odd, being a little more dramatic than I thought it would be. Once we were all seated around the long table, the drapes were drawn over the windows looking out onto the bay, the lights dimmed, and a spotlight put on Chris and Kaz as they entered the room to their place at the head of the table. Then champagne was poured for everyone, and the two fathers read out speeches (Chris translated his father&#8217;s speech for Kaz&#8217;s family).<br />
The drapes were reopened, and the meal began. And what a meal it was! Three dishes awaited us right away: a salad of seaweed and fish egg sacks, a lettuce-based salad, and one other thing I can&#8217;t remember now. Why can&#8217;t I remember? Because that was the first of about 10 rounds of food,including smoked salmon, lobster mousse, lobster with a chili sauce served in a lobster shell cut in half length-wise, sushi, clear soup, noodles, and two or three desserts, including the wedding cake. Garth, Jen, and I couldn&#8217;t believe that the food just kept coming.<br />
Mind you, there really wasn&#8217;t a lot of food, all told. In total, it would have amounted to maybe four large courses at a regular wedding. Still, it was a lot more food than any of us were expecting.<br />
And of course, there was drink. In addition to the champagne, there was beer. Tradition holds that everyone offers to fill the groom&#8217;s glass at least once. After a while, people start going around, filling other&#8217;s glasses. It&#8217;s impossible to tell how much beer one consumes over the course of the meal, but I think it safe to assume that Garth<!--, Jen,--> and I consumed far too much, mostly thanks to Shinichiro.<br />
During a break between rounds, Mrs. May and I talked a bit about the wedding, and she suddenly announced that I was next. Stuart and Therese got married in 2002, and now Chris. That means I&#8217;m the last one. Maybe in 2006&#8230;<br />
After the meal finally ended around 16:00, we headed out to collect our bags (some changed into more comfortable clothes), gathered our bags, and boarded the bus for Toyohashi. We were changing to the Associa Hotel, and then going to a reception party in the city.<br />
The bus ride back took a different route than the one going out, and though a little more direct, seemed to take longer. Tony and Shinichiro slept, and I swear Jen dozed once or twice. But it was a lot quieter on the way back than it had been on the way out.<br />
Back at the hotel, we checked in, hauled our stuff up to our rooms, and then prepared to head out. Jen and I were down first, followed shortly by Garth. Tony was a few minutes behind, wearing the infamous monkey suit.<br />
Yes, Tony has a monkey suit. It&#8217;s a costume he picked up a couple of years ago for a party. He has no qualms about wearing it, even to a large dinner party. He&#8217;s worn it on the plane from Saipan to Narita, and almost wore it on the shinkansen to Toyohashi. Garth convinced him to wear it for the dinner.<br />
A little late leaving (Kaz wanted to hear her wedding dress), we arrived a little late at the Bali-Hai restaurant. Inside waited about 80 or 90 people, only one of whom I knew &#8212; Alex, a friend of ours from Calgary, who&#8217;s teaching English in Nagoya (about 20 minutes by shinkansen).<br />
The dinner was a strange one, featuring several asian dishes I&#8217;d never had before. All quite tasty. We all played bingo, for some reason, which offered prizes to anyone who managed to get five in a row. The closest I got was four. Jen won a shampoo/body wash set, for which she was extremely happy.<br />
And yes, there was drink. Quite a bit of it. Beer, mostly, though Shinichiro had me try so-ju, which Tony described as &#8220;watered-down vodka&#8221;. It tastes a little like mildly alcoholic oolong tea. And of course, there was beer. Lots of beer. Jen couldn&#8217;t stop laughing or giggling.<br />
We had to leave before 21:00, as there was another reservation coming in. We all headed back to the hotel to dump off a few things, dress down a bit, and head out for an izakaya to have a little more fun. We had to wait a while, unfortunately, as Chris and Kaz lost track of time for a while.<br />
This gave Tony and I a bit of time to try to sort out tomorrow&#8217;s shinkansen schedule. Jen and I are heading to Hiroshima, and we need to be in the city by noon. Shinkansen run fairly often, but the trick is to catch the right ones so we don&#8217;t waste too much time. Luckily, the hotel provided paper schedules that we&#8217;ll take with us.<br />
Finally, around 23:00, Tony, Jen, Garth, Chris, Kaz, Shinichiro, Riko, and I gathered to go to the izakaya. An izakaya is a Japanese public house, where people get together for a lot of loud talking, heavy drinking, and a little bit of food. The place, called Fuku, was already full when we arrived, but they managed to clear some space for us.<br />
And yes, more drinking. Garth and I split warm sake, but the real surprise was Jen. Cold sake. A full bottle, all to herself. And about half of the second warm bottle, too. Her parents are gonna kill me. Surprisingly enough, she wasn&#8217;t too bad off, something I&#8217;ll attribute to body mass and metabolism.<br />
Although we were not privy to most conversations (Chris is quite capable of holding his own when talking with others; Garth, Jen, and I talked amongst ourselves or with Shinichiro and Riku), we were periodically brought in by Chris when something interesting was raised. Such was the case when he suddenly told Jen and I to stand up. We did. (We assumed, correctly, that this was to compare heights.) Chris then asked those sitting near him how old they thought Jen was.<br />
One said 28, another 27, and another would only go so far as &#8220;late-20s&#8221;. Chris then asked Jen to tell them how old she really is. She privately asked Chris first how to say her age in Japanese, which she then repeated to the three men. Their jaws dropped when they found out she&#8217;s only 15.<br />
Last call came, and we all headed out into the cool night air to return to the hotel. Jen had a new souvenir, a &#8220;gift&#8221; from Shinichiro &#8212; one of the two warm sake serving bottles. Doesn&#8217;t matter what country you&#8217;re in, people like to take stuff from restaurants.<br />
Jen and I need sleep. Tomorrow is going to be another longish day.<br />
[flickr]tag:irako+march+2004+&#8221;28&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]<br />
(Also see <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/photos/wedding/chris-and-kazumi/">photos from Chris and Kazumi&#8217;s wedding</a>.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-chris-kaz-wedding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">335</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2004 22:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irako]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/27/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone. Jen and I proceeded to get &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone.<br />
Jen and I proceeded to get on with our morning. For me, showering and shaving (showering when it&#8217;s eight degrees in the shower room is a bit of an odd experience), gathering our things from the previous night, laying out Chris and Kaz&#8217;s wedding gifts (that they don&#8217;t yet know about), and getting breakfast.<br />
<span id="more-334"></span>This meant a trip to the 7-11. I knew what I wanted, but Jen really didn&#8217;t know. She was about to find out that her typical breakfast foods either don&#8217;t exist here, or are different enough to cause problems. This was most notable when she bought what she thought was normal milk (which bore the slogan: &#8220;Milk as milked&#8221;). Apparently, the Japanese like their milk sweetened, which Jen found thoroughly repulsive.<br />
About 9:45, we headed out to the train station to meet up with Tony, one of Chris&#8217; friends. Tony used to be a teacher with the same company Chris now works for. He&#8217;s since moved to Saipan (an American protectorate) where he works as a &#8220;beach boy&#8221; at a resort. Tony is trouble incarnate, at least as far as Chris has described him.<br />
After grabbing a bite to eat at the bakery (Tony hadn&#8217;t had breakfast yet), the three of us boarded the train for Tokyo. It was already standing room only when we boarded, and was crammed full until about two stops before Tokyo station. We stood the whole way.<br />
Once in Tokyo, we found our way up to the main level, where Tony bought something to eat for lunch, and then headed out to the Shinkansen area. Took a bit to find the right train (none of the signs were in English), and waited for our 12:23 departure. We took one row of two seats, flipped it 180 degrees so they faced the two seats behind them, and the three of us sat down to enjoy our 2.5 hour trip to Toyohashi.<br />
Tony and I talked almost the whole way. Jen slipped in and out of consciousness while listening to her music. The scenery zipped by at a leisurely 250 km/h. We even got a good look at Mount Fuji (it had decided not to hide itself from us). Shinichiro (another of Chris&#8217; friends) found us, and gabbed a bit with Tony. We would meet up with him and his girlfriend Riko again when we got to Toyohashi.<br />
Chris and Kaz were waiting for us when we arrived at the station. It was good to see them again, though it was a short-lived reunion with Kaz. Chris led us to the shuttle bus, where we found Chris&#8217; parents Tony and Carole, and Chris&#8217; uncle, Garth (Carole&#8217;s brother).<br />
I had thought that the hotel we were staying at was close to the train station. I was so wrong. The Iraku View Hotel isn&#8217;t even in Toyohashi &#8212; that&#8217;s just the nearest train station. We had another hour on a shuttle bus to the hotel. A long, albeit nice ride through and around the Aichi Prefecture&#8217;s countryside, which appears to be primarily agricultural.<br />
The hotel sits on top of a small mountain, overlooking a large bay. The view here is &#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say there&#8217;s a reason why &#8220;View&#8221; is in the hotel&#8217;s name. It&#8217;s amazing. Chris picked a heck of a location.<br />
The hotel room arrangements had changed from the last time I&#8217;d talked with Chris. Originally, Chris, Tony (friend, not father), and I were going to share a room, and Jen and Kaz would share another. Now it was Chris, Tony, and Garth, with Jen and I sharing a room. (We don&#8217;t see Kaz again until tomorrow.)<br />
Admittedly, I was a little disappointed. But I&#8217;m certainly not in a position to complain in any way. These are the way things have to be. It&#8217;s called &#8220;life&#8221; &#8212; you get used to it after a while. (Actually, I almost prefer it this way. At least Jen won&#8217;t be with a stranger. Admittedly, though, I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen if there is a desire to go out drinking.)<br />
The room is pretty nice. More western in style, there are twin beds, a desk, TV, small table, two chairs, Japanese-style bathrobes, a Japanese-style western toilet (complete with electronic bidet controls and seat warmer), and a complementary water heater and green tea bags.<br />
But I need an iron. My suit is a little wrinkled.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Jen and I went exploring, to see what this hotel has to offer. It&#8217;s quite interesting. There&#8217;s a great view of the area from the hotel&#8217;s roof (you&#8217;re actually allowed up there), an arcade, a couple of restaurants, a kareoke bar, a bowling alley, and birds in the lobby. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd hotel.<br />
Following our exploration, Jen and I watched a bit of the local Japanese TV. Very odd things to watch, such as a commercial for what we think was a car, but featured two kids in cat costumes who steal fish from the back of a fish truck.<br />
We all met up and went for dinner just after 19:00, at the Sunset Restaurant, which features a buffet. It&#8217;s quite good (for a buffet), including such favourites as sashimi, seafood-flavoured miso, gyoza, and a few things I&#8217;d never even heard of before.<br />
Chris and his family sat at one table, while Shinichiro, Riko, Tony, Jen, and I sat at another. We talked, joked, learned a little more about each other, and drank. (Well, we did &#8230; Jen didn&#8217;t, for obvious reasons.)<br />
Following our dinner (we finished just after 21:00), the six of us (the rest of Chris&#8217; family headed to bed) went in search of the bowling alley. Chris&#8217; last night as a single man would be demonstrated on the lanes.<br />
Unfortunately, Chris didn&#8217;t do all that well &#8212; mind you, neither did I &#8212; as he was distracted by conversations with Kaz. I&#8217;m going to have to make sure that his cell phone is either left behind, or confiscated by either Tony or myself so he can actually enjoy tomorrow, and not spend it talking to others.<br />
The game finished (Shinichiro came first, Jen a close second), we adjourned to Shinichiro and Riko&#8217;s room for a bottle of melon wine. An odd flavour, to say the least, but still pleasant. Shinichiro and Chris took it upon themselves to try and teach Jen some new Japanese words. Tony tried to figure out how to use some of the features on his new phone.<br />
But it&#8217;s late, and we all need sleep. Tomorrow&#8217;s going to be a long day.<br />
[flickr]tag:tokyo+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:irako+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">334</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planning for a Return Trip to Japan</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2004 22:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/11/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fourteen days, and counting. Two weeks from today, I&#8217;m off to Japan. Again. Relax, this isn&#8217;t going to turn into a yearly thing. If I&#8217;d had a choice, I&#8217;d probably be going to Australia this year, maybe New Zealand. But I&#8217;ve got a good reason for going back to Japan. Chris is getting married. Of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Planning for a Return Trip to Japan"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fourteen days, and counting.<br />
Two weeks from today, I&#8217;m off to Japan. Again. Relax, this isn&#8217;t going to turn into a yearly thing. If I&#8217;d had a choice, I&#8217;d probably be going to Australia this year, maybe New Zealand. But I&#8217;ve got a good reason for going back to Japan.<br />
<span id="more-332"></span>Chris is getting married. Of course, you already knew that (see [[A Surprise Engagement]]). It was just a question of when and where. I&#8217;d been suggesting Hawaii, partly because it was (roughly) half-way between Japan and North America, but also because I&#8217;d never been there.<br />
But it ain&#8217;t my wedding. It&#8217;s going to be held in Toyohashi (about two hours south-west of Tokyo by shinkansen). So Down Under will have to wait for another time. For my closest friends, I&#8217;ll gladly travel halfway around the world.<br />
Last time I was in Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]), I spent most of my time in the Tokyo area. This time, I want to see more of the country. The furthest away I got was Shizoika, which was in an effort to see Mount Fuji (see [[My Trip to Japan, Shinkansen to Mount Fuji]]). This time, I&#8217;m going all the way down to Hiroshima, then working my way back up to Tokyo, and even north to Nikko.<br />
But I won&#8217;t be travelling alone. Back in October, I gained a travel partner. This came about from a discussion we were having over dinner at my Aunt and Uncle&#8217;s, celebrating Nana&#8217;s six-month anniversary at being in Calgary. Most of my family knows Chris quite well, and were asking about Chris&#8217; then-recently-announced wedding. What was the date? What were the plans? Was I going?<br />
When I replied that I was going back (wouldn&#8217;t pass it up for anything), a voice suddenly chirped up: &#8220;Can I come?&#8221; It was Jen, my cousin (Uncle Mike and Aunt Brenda&#8217;s sole child). She had a giant, hopeful smile. For a brief moment, I thought against her coming along &#8212; I kind of wanted to travel solo. But then I realized that having a person to travel with would be a lot more fun.<br />
&#8220;Sure! Why not?&#8221;<br />
The look on Mike and Brenda&#8217;s faces was priceless.<br />
Needless to say, there were monetary issues to resolve before Jen could actually be allowed to go. My family is, if nothing else, very supportive. Nana chipped in for a sizable portion of Jen&#8217;s costs, her parents covering the rest. But by the time Jen&#8217;s 15th birthday rolled around in November, it was a done deal. Jen was going to Japan.<br />
We leave 25 March, going through Vancouver. Jen and I will be seated side-by-side the whole way out and back. (Heck, for over two weeks, we&#8217;ll be tied at the hip.) We arrive 26 March (owing to the International Date Line) and begin our little adventure.<br />
This adventure, unlike my previous one, needs a little planning. For example, we had to get Jen familiar with Japanese food. She&#8217;s going to be eating nothing but for two weeks. Then there&#8217;s the need for footwear. My shoes would not survive two weeks&#8217; of walking about.<br />
This is what I did last Saturday. I hadn&#8217;t really even thought about until I almost absent-mindedly walked into the R &#8216;n R store next to Sumo Sushi in Eau Claire Market. The odd little squeak emanating from my old shoes was enough to irk me into new shoes. The need for walking shoes, combined with a desire for something I can hike in, led me to a long afternoon of shoe shopping.<br />
Hey, when you&#8217;re going to spend $120 on a pair of shoes, you make sure you&#8217;re buying something that meets your needs.<br />
The next step of planning is the list of destinations and activities. I tasked Jen to pick out all the places she wanted to see in Japan, with the caveat that we wouldn&#8217;t likely be able to see it all. Far easier to whittle things down than it is to find more things to see and do. Her list was lengthy, but well thought out.<br />
I started looking at the lists on Sunday night. The list was long and organized by prefecture (the Japanese equivalent of a province or state), so while it wasn&#8217;t too hard to figure out where approximately Jen wanted to go, it wasn&#8217;t particularly obvious how easy it would be.<br />
Using a rather nice map from japanrailpass.net, I plotted out the key areas in the list on Monday night. Much to my delight, about 80% of them were on the shinkansen lines. This made them easy to get to. (There were a few that were quite some distance away, on what I can only assume are the much slower local lines.)<br />
Tuesday ended up being a complete waste of a day at the office. There was no work to be had at all. Luckily, this gave me a chance to sit down with the lists and the map, and try to figure out how the heck we were going to spending all of our time in Japan.<br />
I was delighted yet again to find that a first run-through of an itinerary produced something that not only covered a lot of ground but allowed us to attend the major events without difficulty. It&#8217;s a little tight in a couple of places (we&#8217;re spending only one day in Kyoto, for example), but has some flexibility if we want to play with things a bit.<br />
Well, at least that&#8217;s what I want myself to believe. This morning, Chris called me on the draft itinerary, saying: &#8220;You are out of your fucking tree.&#8221; While I had been fairly proud of the itinerary, there was a reason I&#8217;d CC&#8217;d Chris when I sent it out to Jen and Aunt Brenda. I needed a sanity check.<br />
Reality: Two weeks to experience a slice of Japan. Now, it&#8217;s possible to do the itinerary in two weeks. That doesn&#8217;t make it a good idea. We&#8217;d literally be spending hours in some places before going onto the next. As Chris so wisely pointed out, there&#8217;s no time to experience anything. Jen and I will be in parts of Japan even Chris hasn&#8217;t been to (some he hasn&#8217;t even heard of). If we&#8217;re going to actually *experience* something, then perhaps we need to slow down.<br />
Two weeks. I haven&#8217;t been looking this forward to a trip in a long time. It&#8217;s going to be an interesting one, to be sure. I just hope there&#8217;s enough time to finish planning before we leave.<br />
&#8216;Cuz there won&#8217;t be any time once we get there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">332</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
