<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>santa ana &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/santa-ana/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 03:28:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Happy 2nd birthday, Monkey</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/happy-2nd-birthday-monkey/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=happy-2nd-birthday-monkey</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/happy-2nd-birthday-monkey/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 03:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avalon country club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DearMonkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, you turned 2, Monkey. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe that it&#8217;s been two years, and yet those two years seem to have disappeared in a blink. You&#8217;ve spent just over half of your life (to date) here in Costa Rica, and I wonder if you even remember Canada. One day, I suppose, we&#8217;ll be &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/happy-2nd-birthday-monkey/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Happy 2nd birthday, Monkey"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, you turned 2, Monkey. It&#8217;s almost hard to believe that it&#8217;s been two years, and yet those two years seem to have disappeared in a blink. You&#8217;ve spent just over half of your life (to date) here in Costa Rica, and I wonder if you even remember Canada. One day, I suppose, we&#8217;ll be wondering if you remember Costa Rica.<br />
Your day started off with all of us getting up early &#8230; well, early for a weekend, anyway. We had to make breakfast, cut up fruit, make hibiscus tea, make salsas, and decorate the louge area up by the pool for your birthday party!  I wonder if you&#8217;ll remember this, too?<br />
Well, even if you don&#8217;t, we took lots of pictures and movies.<br />
<span id="more-1920"></span>This time last year, your party was small &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/08/happy-first-birthday-my-daughter/">just you, Mommy, and me</a>. This time, we invited all of our friends and (if they had any) their children. Your friends Marissa and Luba came. I wonder if you&#8217;ll remember them?<br />
Sadly, before we could go up for your party, we had a small accident. Well, <em>you </em>had a small accident. You were climbing up on the toilet in your bathroom, and presumably slipped. You fell down and bit your lip. You might have even have bitten it all the way through, but we&#8217;re not really sure as it&#8217;s hard for us to look at it without you crying. Maybe this will teach you not to climb on the toilet?<br />
Slowly everyone arrived, and you played at the table Mommy borrowed from your school. You ate a lot of corn chips with the avocado salsa (you love avocados) and the mango salsa, too. You ate the yummy cookies that Mommy baked, as well as ones that Julia baked. You ate some of the fruit skewers, too.<br />
It wasn&#8217;t long before you wanted to go in the pool, though. Marissa was in the pool mere minutes after getting to the party, and you didn&#8217;t want to miss out. I took you to the wading pool, which was absolutely perfect for once, and we all played in there. Eventually Luba came, too, and the three of you splashed each other, as well as Marissa and Luba&#8217;s mommies, and me.<br />
But it wasn&#8217;t long before noon came, and it was time for everyone to go home. You were pretty tired by then, too, and you had a really good nap. So did I, actually. I was soooo tired.<br />
We played for a bit when you got up, and then I went and got us dinner from Tandoori Palace again. You&#8217;re really liking Indian food, and I can&#8217;t wait to introduce you to other kinds, like Chinese, Japanese, Ethopian, Greek, Eastern European, and so forth. There&#8217;s so much to experience, kiddo!<br />
Anyway, while I was out, you talked with Grandpa and Granny (though Grandma was here for the last two weeks), but we couldn&#8217;t get a hold of Nana, unfortunately.<br />
After dinner, we had cake and ice cream. You ate the ice cream happily (and much less messy than last year), but didn&#8217;t eat much of the cake. You opened presents, one of which was Tyrone &#8212; the last &#8220;Ya Ya&#8221; (your word for &#8220;Backyardigans&#8221;), so now you have all five. You still can&#8217;t say &#8220;Tyrone&#8221;, of course, but you&#8217;re trying.<br />
Speaking of speaking, your word count increases daily, although your pronounciation has led to some rather funny moments. Like when you talk about the shirt you got from Marissa. Sadly, her name comes out sounding like &#8220;pizza&#8221;, and you can&#8217;t really say your R&#8217;s right now, so &#8220;shirt&#8221; is &#8230; well, it&#8217;s a word you shouldn&#8217;t be saying right now. The two words together are inappropriately hilarious.<br />
Now you&#8217;re two years old. And if it&#8217;s even remotely possible, you not only get cuter each and every day, but I&#8217;m finding more things to love about you every day, too. It makes it all the more hard when I have to hug you and Mommy every morning before I go to work, because I just count the minutes before I can see you again.<br />
Sleep well tonight, Monkey, and dream of Ya Yas, and baby frogs, and planes. Tomorrow&#8217;s going to be another great day!<br />
Well, except for the fact that Grandma&#8217;s going home tomorrow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2009/08/happy-2nd-birthday-monkey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1920</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thanksgiving in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 19:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canadian club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=1134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen. Thanksgiving &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Thanksgiving in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was always a foregone conclusion that we&#8217;d end up spending various holidays and celebrations doing things differently here. The ubiquitous summer long weekends (every month except June) are one thing, but when it comes down to the core family staples such as Thanksgiving and Christmas, we had no idea what would ultimately happen.<br />
Thanksgiving &#8212; for Canadians, anyway &#8212; comes on the second Monday of October. Officially, that&#8217;s today, but many Canadians tend to have the feast on the Sunday owing to a need to travel. And since Thanksgiving isn&#8217;t observed in Costa Rica (in fact, it&#8217;s barely known outside the expat community), it&#8217;s not even a blip on the radar.<br />
Which begs, of course, the question: How does one get their turkey fix?<br />
<span id="more-1134"></span>Well, luckily for us, there&#8217;s a whack of people who have that exact same problem, and are significantly better organised than we are at this point. They&#8217;re the <a href="http://www.canadianclubcr.com/">Canadian Club of Costa Rica</a>, a collection of former Canucks who want to preserve some of the feelings of home down here in the tropics. We&#8217;d first heard about them not long after first arriving, but hadn&#8217;t moved on anything due to the other aspects of trying to live here &#8230; like getting internet and a phone.<br />
I digress&#8230;<br />
Alex, though one of the other mothers in her playgroup, found out that the Canadian Club (why does this always <a href="http://www.canadianclubwhisky.com/">make me think of whisky</a>?) was holding a Thanksgiving &#8220;dinner&#8221; (more like a lunch) at &#8212; of all places &#8212; <a href="http://www.sowrey.org/2008/06/second-weekend-in-costa-rica/">Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo</a>, our (well, my) favourite bar in Santa Ana.<br />
The opportunity to sit down with other expats, chat, and have some turkey was rather appealing. So we signed up for a pair of seats. On Sunday, just after Mi Pequeña Niña woke up from her morning nap, we headed out to quell our turkey fix.<br />
A large Canadian flag was draped over one of the bushes out in front of the restaurant. Many of the people attending had to drive from much further distances, so it was helpful as a landmark. The restaurant was chosen (I think) mostly because the owner (I believe his name is &#8220;Paul&#8221;) is an expat from Vancouver.<br />
Upon entry, I quickly realised that the Canadian Club&#8217;s primary membership seems to be retirees. I hadn&#8217;t even considered that fact (rather stupidly!). Alex and I were among the youngest there &#8212; our daughter, included. Only two other children (no older than 10), and one couple that I could see that could have been in their late 20s.<br />
[flickr]tag:thanksgiving+2008@Geoff S.(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
We were at Table 13. Not the last table in the arrangement, but apparently the unluckiest &#8212; we were served last. We were seated with a man who&#8217;s been in Costa Rica about as long as I have (Steve) and his American friend, Jo. Jo has been here 17 years so seems more Costa Rican than she is American.<br />
It took a while for the MC to get everyone&#8217;s attention as the conversation just kept going. Ten minutes later, they were going over the details of the afternoon&#8217;s events (a funny hat contest, a raffle for a round-trip ticket on Continental, our meals, etc.), and that the Ambassador would be dropping by. It hadn&#8217;t even occurred to me that Canada&#8217;s ambassador to Costa Rica (whose name I&#8217;ve forgotten, and even Google can&#8217;t easily find it &#8212; bad architecture, Canada!) would come to such an affair. Nice guy, though. Flatlander from Saskatchewan.<br />
While we were waiting for things to get moving, we ordered up some beverages. I went with my usual Imperial (kind of hard to pass up on), Alex went with a white wine, Jo went with a Bavaria, and I think Steve only had club soda (Canada Dry Club Soda, to be precise). But we had to get ice &#8212; Alex&#8217;s wine came unchilled, and Jo seemed to like ice in her beer (a common practice here for some). The ice came in a large, red bucket with a pair of toothed metal tongs.<br />
MPN had fun for a while, laughing and giggling, but she didn&#8217;t take too well to being stuck in one place and not being able to walk around on her own. This happens frequently (usually after she&#8217;s finished eating, and especially on airplanes), and can sometimes lead to &#8230; incidents. Such as the one we had yesterday.<br />
Remember the ice bucket? What happens if you leave an uninsulated plastic bucket of ice out in a tropical climate? Right &#8212; you get water. Cold water.<br />
Ice cold water.<br />
Mi Pequeña Niña decided that the bucket would be fun to play with. (She does this with most things put in front of her, including (but not limited to) cutlery, glass bottles, plates, sunglasses, keys, paper, books, tablecloths, flowers &#8230; basically anything she can reach.) Sometimes she plays with those objects with other things in her hand, such as her small plastic feeding spoon. And sometimes, she gets just the right grip&#8230;<br />
Suddenly, I felt a wash of extreme cold in my lap. I thought she&#8217;d spilled her juice. Then I saw the bucket, heard MPN starting to scream (the shock got to her, too), and noticed that my lap was very wet. Ice cold, as it were.<br />
Lunch/dinner was actually pretty good, considering Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Pollo isn&#8217;t exactly known for its Canuck cuisine. (It&#8217;s not known at all, to be frank.) But it was real turkey, with potatoes, stuffing (decent stuffing, at that), creamed beans, and cranberry jelly (which I fed to MPN). Dessert? Alex&#8217;s favourite &#8212; pumpkin pie.<br />
We didn&#8217;t stick around long after the meal was over. MPN was rapidly heading towards naptime, and the wetness of my shorts was finally getting to me.<br />
Sadly, not enough to induce turkey coma, but certainly better than if we&#8217;d gone with no turkey at all. I think we&#8217;re going to have to figure out how to get a turkey for Christmas, though &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to go another holiday without turkey. I honestly miss it too much, and there&#8217;s just such potential down here. With luck, we&#8217;ll be able to invite a few people over to make it worthwhile.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/10/thanksgiving-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1134</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding a Costa Rican Casa, Day 2</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-2/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-2</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 04:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avalon country club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[condo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I knew today was going to be awkward when I woke up. Based on the conversation I&#8217;d had with Alex last night, none of the houses we&#8217;d seen on Day 1 were at all suitable. Either way too large, in not-so-nice areas (e.g. you&#8217;d feel like you couldn&#8217;t go anywhere), or had stairs (which we&#8217;re &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finding a Costa Rican Casa, Day 2"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I knew today was going to be awkward when I woke up. Based on the conversation I&#8217;d had with Alex last night, none of the houses we&#8217;d seen on Day 1 were at all suitable. Either way too large, in not-so-nice areas (e.g. you&#8217;d feel like you couldn&#8217;t go anywhere), or had stairs (which we&#8217;re trying to avoid with our almost-walking infant).<br />
When Luz Elena and Lina Maria arrived this morning, I took their carefully crafted plan, opened the window, and tossed it out. (Figuratively speaking, of course.)<br />
It was time to get a little more serious.<br />
<span id="more-977"></span>Although we headed off almost right away, there were a lot of rapid phone calls as Luz Elena tried to pin down some different places to see. Still, we went to some they&#8217;d had planned because they weren&#8217;t really that far off the mark.<br />
The first one really didn&#8217;t sit well with me. Although cheap, it felt like I was living in a prison. And by &#8220;cheap&#8221;, that&#8217;s in gringo prices. Down here, you can get cheap. And it&#8217;s CHEAP, with all the connotations that come along with it. We gringos are accustomed to certain things, for which we are required to pay through the nose. We bring in the money, and we have to pay it out. Fair trade, all things considered.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530543979(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530575589(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
On the way to the next place, a series of phone calls suggested that both Mark and Jason were interested in it as well, an apartment in Santa Ana. I immediately thought that I should throw my hat into the ring as well &#8212; for no other reason than just to be a pest.<br />
When we got there, Mark was just leaving to see another unit in the same complex. It was a very modern apartment, but it felt closed in, to me. Maybe it was the curtains, or the fact that when you looked out the window, all you saw was the other row of buildings. After a few minutes, Mark and his realtor came back in, followed by Jason and his realtor a few minutes later.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530577161(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530578567(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
We scooted back through Lindora, hanging a right about a click past the strip malls (yes, there are strip malls in Costa Rica now &#8212; civilisation is officially over), into a place called Rincon del Sol. A very nice two-level unit (yes, stairs, which are bad) that really stood out for appeal. But the neighbourhood felt cold &#8212; I didn&#8217;t see anyone on the streets, and all the driveways had barricades (common in Costa Rica).<br />
[flickr]photo:2530580203(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530582093(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Scooting back into Escazu for the last place, we came to an apartment block. By this time, I was fairly disheartened about the whole affair. I wasn&#8217;t going to find the &#8220;perfect&#8221; place. They don&#8217;t exist here. Not with the requirements I have. This place was nice, including a very modern-looking apartment and a pretty killer view over Escazu and the mountains.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530584657(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2531401628(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530587053(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Lunch was at a place in Lindora called &#8220;La Mar&#8221;. Seafood. Damn good seafood. Octopus should never be cooked that well &#8212; it&#8217;ll make me not want to eat anything else. I actually didn&#8217;t taste last night&#8217;s dinner any longer (thankfully). But make no mistake, I was depressed. What was I going to do?<br />
Luz Elena and Lina Maria dropped me back at the hotel afterwards &#8220;to rest&#8221; (read email, catch up with people, make phone calls), while they arranged more showings for the afternoon. They know the pressure I&#8217;m under.<br />
At 15:15, I jumped back in their car, and we went off to the Avalon Country Club, which I&#8217;d heard of from Mark. It&#8217;s not a &#8220;country club&#8221; in the way that most North Americans know them. This is a walled garden, with condo units inside. There&#8217;s a &#8220;lago&#8221; (pond, really), 25m olympic-style pool, gym, tennis courts, football (soccer) field, lounge pool with a SWIM UP BAR (*cough*), and over four kilometres of trails to walk around.<br />
Colour me stunned. And the unit comes furnished.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530588761(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2531410350(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
It&#8217;s not cheap. But the unit costs less than our mortgage back in Calgary. That&#8217;s not too shabby, really.<br />
The last place I saw was the closest one to the office, not far from the Marriott. It&#8217;s nice, but isolated, without really anything near it at all. You have to drive just to see another house outside the complex. That pretty much discounted it.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530590195(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530592211(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
I talked with Alex tonight, and I&#8217;m going back to Avalon tomorrow. I&#8217;ve got some questions that need to be answered, and with any luck we can get all this squared away tomorrow. It&#8217;ll be nice to go back to Calgary knowing that I don&#8217;t have to worry about a place to live when I get back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">977</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding a Costa Rican Casa, Day 1</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-1/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-1</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 04:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[condo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heredia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oy. It&#8217;s been a really long day. Didn&#8217;t sleep great last night (long travels tend to do that to me if I&#8217;m not traversing a dozen or so timezones, in which case passing out is a snap). Got up early thanks to the engine retarders on passing trucks (there is no bylaw against them here, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Finding a Costa Rican Casa, Day 1"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oy.<br />
It&#8217;s been a really long day. Didn&#8217;t sleep great last night (long travels tend to do that to me if I&#8217;m not traversing a dozen or so timezones, in which case passing out is a snap). Got up early thanks to the engine retarders on passing trucks (there is no bylaw against them here, and truckers seem to use them to slow down, say &#8220;hello&#8221;, accelerate, turn right or left, order coffee, etc.) and a bit of excitement.<br />
Did a couple of Spanish lessons on Rosetta Stone before and after breakfast, when we met with our Crown Relocations team. One for each of Mark and Jason, but I scored a mother/daughter team (Luz Elena and Lina Maria) to help me find a house for my family.<br />
<span id="more-975"></span>The goal isn&#8217;t just to find a place to live. It was also to show us around so we know where things are. As it turns out, I was fully able to get my bearings, to the point where I could successfully navigate through a number of places without too much difficulty. I think. It helps to have an idea of where you are. I could even plot them in Google Earth, which I&#8217;m using to communicate locations with Alex.<br />
&#8216;Bout near died and went to heaven with the first place &#8212; a 450 sq. metre (4,800+ sq. ft) pad that happened to be right next door to the brother of Costa Rica&#8217;s President. Wild. It was getting some touch-ups, but was generally gorgeous.<br />
[flickr]photo:2531350168(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2530535331(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Second place was nice, too. The communal pool might as well been from a tropical resort. Oh, wait. We are in a tropical resort. I keep forgetting that. You&#8217;d think all these palm trees would clue me in.<br />
[flickr]photo:2530535471(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2531352916(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Broke for lunch in Escazu. I find it no end of ironic that I had to go to Costa Rica to find an excellent Italian pannini. There&#8217;s just something wrong with that.<br />
Third place was a bit of a hole, sadly. Not at all what I wanted, and was pretty sure Alex wouldn&#8217;t want it either.<br />
[flickr]photo:2531355516(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2531354170(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
Fourth place was better, but it felt like I was in Tuscany. The bad part about being in Tuscany &#8212; too many people you don&#8217;t know/never see, and nothing else around you. I&#8217;m at work all day, so we have to make sure this works for Alex.<br />
[flickr]photo:2531357444(thumbnail)[/flickr][flickr]photo:2531358752(thumbnail)[/flickr]<br />
At dinner Jason, Mark, and I all talked about our experiences of the day. It seems the realtors for Mark and Jason are more experienced. Could also be that my requirements are just that much more difficult to find. Jason&#8217;s almost pinned down a place. After talking with Alex, we&#8217;re not even close.<br />
Ate way too much for dinner. Absolutely great food (Azteca soup and a &#8220;platter of meat&#8221;, which was pork, black beans, guacamole, and tortillas). Beer went down way too easily (I&#8217;m going to like Imperial).<br />
Maybe with luck, we&#8217;ll find a place tomorrow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/finding-a-costa-rican-casa-day-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">975</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back in Costa Rica</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=back-in-costa-rica</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 05:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airlines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san jose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santa ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Years ago, I used to think business travel was glamourous. You got to go to far-flung places, see different things, and engage in activities you just don&#8217;t do at home. Then I started going on business trips. I learned fast that the enjoyment is only so deep. Worst experience was [[Live from Cincinnati&#124;Cincinnati in 2000]]. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Back in Costa Rica"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Years ago, I used to think business travel was glamourous. You got to go to far-flung places, see different things, and engage in activities you just don&#8217;t do at home. Then I started going on business trips. I learned fast that the enjoyment is only so deep.<br />
Worst experience was [[Live from Cincinnati|Cincinnati in 2000]]. Second, and only because I was utterly exhausted by the end (the trip itself was very helpful) was [[Je suis en Paris!|Paris in 2006]]. (As I learned, when you travel to Europe, you end up with 18-20 hour days, because you&#8217;re trying to stay sync&#8217;d with the home office.)<br />
But today hasn&#8217;t exactly been a slice, either. And just because I&#8217;m currently in Costa Rica <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=Santa+Ana,+San+Jos%C3%A9,+Costa+Rica&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;cd=2&amp;geocode=0,9.933607,-84.184196&amp;t=h&amp;ll=9.945418,-84.189987&amp;spn=0.002859,0.003659&amp;z=18&amp;iwloc=addr">doesn&#8217;t mean I&#8217;m sitting on a beach</a>.<br />
<span id="more-974"></span>I woke up at 3:50. That&#8217;s AM, as in &#8220;before most sane people wake up&#8221;. I was at Jason&#8217;s house by 4:30. We were at the airport by 5:00. Along with &#8212; it seemed &#8212; all the Japanese tourists in Canada. Very strange. Check in, customs, security, and wait for the flight.<br />
Roughly four hours to Houston. And then a six hour wait. There are no direct flights from Calgary to San Jose, Costa Rica. You have to fly through somewhere. And with costs being what they are, that means Houston. There are worse places to be stuck for six hours, but frankly, any six-hour stint in an airport is enough to drive you batty.<br />
About 45 minutes before our flight boarded, we met up with Mark. Mark&#8217;s day has been considerably easier, as he didn&#8217;t have to wait nearly as long. Flights from Chicago are much more reasonable. The three of us boarded our flight to San Jose &#8212; another 3.25 hour journey.<br />
I should point out by this point that it was 18:15, and I&#8217;d been up quite a lot longer than I&#8217;d like, and wasn&#8217;t feeling particularly happy about the next leg of the trip. I wanted a nap. Badly.<br />
The flight, like the one before it, had a few bumpy parts (especially the landing &#8212; I was certain the pilot had blown out one of the tires), iffy food (we were actually fed, though), and not-so-great movies (or more importantly, they weren&#8217;t ones I wanted to watch).<br />
But it was on that flight that it hit me. The announcements were no longer in just English. Now I heard Español, too. I need to learn Spanish. It sounds weird, but this all sounded fine on paper sitting comfortably 5,000 kilometres to the north. But here, now, sitting in my hotel room, this is something different.<br />
Tengo que hablar Español. Especially if I have any hope of survival.<br />
Anyway&#8230;<br />
Arrival (bumps aside) was easy. Going to the States on business merits proctological examination. Here, we could have brought in an entire company and no-one would have been the wiser. In typical Tican form, we were immediately hit upon by a guy willing to take us to his hotel. Disappointed that we already had reservations elsewhere, he still drove us. For $6 each. Probably a bit on the expensive side, but we&#8217;re here, and that&#8217;s all that matters.<br />
Tomorrow, we house-hunt. This should be interesting&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/05/back-in-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">974</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
