<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>marketing &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 22:58:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>Marketing is common sense</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/marketing-is-common-sense/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=marketing-is-common-sense</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/marketing-is-common-sense/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 22:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoff.sowrey.org/?p=3605</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve worked in the marketing industry, in one form or another, since the mid-1990s (save for a couple-year break when I did technical writing, but we&#8217;ll ignore that for now). I&#8217;ve seen a lot in those many (many) years, but one thing has really stuck through all of that: what marketing does. That&#8217;s not a &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/marketing-is-common-sense/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Marketing is common sense"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve worked in the marketing industry, in one form or another, since the mid-1990s (save for a couple-year break when I did technical writing, but we&#8217;ll ignore that for now). I&#8217;ve seen a lot in those many (<em>many</em>) years, but one thing has really stuck through all of that: what marketing does.<br />
That&#8217;s not a question, it&#8217;s a realization. Truth is, most people don&#8217;t know what marketing is, or what it&#8217;s supposed to do. Most people think marketing is advertising: making TV commercials, radio blurbs, internet banners, print flyers, and so forth. To a degree, marketing is absolutely <em>involved</em> in that process, but the act of doing advertising is tactical, whereas marketing is strategic. And the end of the day, marketing does something that most people don&#8217;t realize:<br />
Marketing is about creating common sense.<br />
<span id="more-3605"></span><br />
Everyone thinks they know what &#8220;common sense&#8221; is. After all, that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s <em>common</em>, right? It&#8217;s a <em>shared</em> idea, concept, or message. It&#8217;s not about the fancy visuals per se (although that&#8217;s certainly a component), it&#8217;s about making you believe the change.<br />
And it is about change. If at some point we didn&#8217;t need to change your opinion on something, we wouldn&#8217;t need marketing. Did you need that new car? Probably not, but we&#8217;re going to give you a lot of reasons why it&#8217;s a good idea. How about looking at green technologies? It used to feel vague and untouchable, but odds are you&#8217;ve got some of it in your home right now. <span style="font-size: 1rem;">Marketing is about </span><em style="font-size: 1rem;">creating</em><span style="font-size: 1rem;"> </span><span style="font-size: 1rem;">common sense. It&#8217;s about something new, be it information, or a product or service that didn&#8217;t exist before; something so different from current common sense that we need a change in thought.</span><br />
Let&#8217;s take Apple Inc. as an example. A couple of decades ago, it was a fledgling company, far back in the ranks of technology firms that was trying to show people a new way. They had a good idea, but they were terrible about how to communicate it to the world. Despite the campaigns to &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Think_different" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Think Different</a>&#8220;, and their shattering &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R706isyDrqI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1984</a>&#8221; ad, the messages didn&#8217;t resonate with the general public. They struggled to develop the <em>common sense</em> to buy Apple, instead of Apple&#8217;s competitors.<br />
Then came the excitement. In 1998, in what would become a pattern for the next decade, Steve Jobs announced something truly different: the original <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IMac_G3" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;Bondi Blue&#8221; iMac</a>. In that announcement, Apple grabbed two things: the world&#8217;s attention at the first computer that wasn&#8217;t boring to look at, and how it would change the experience for those who used them. They capitalized on an industry that was filled with beige boxes that did typically dull things, and wanted to do something more exciting. They would not change the industry overnight: the core audience was still fringe, from an industry perspective. But the common eye was now opened. The release of the equally interesting clamshell iBook the following year continued the trend. In 2000, Apple went announced Mac OS X, a radical departure from macOS, which captured the technical attention.<br />
And attention was all they needed to release the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iPod</a>, five years &#8220;too late&#8221; into a saturated MP3 player market. Though the first version wasn&#8217;t the &#8220;boom&#8221; moment that later versions would become, common sense won out over price alone (the iPod was more expensive), and Apple started it&#8217;s meteoric rise.<br />
Yes, marketing is manipulative, and that&#8217;s the point, really: we have to change the way you think to see something new. It&#8217;s not about fear (though that is an oft-used tactic), it&#8217;s not about beating you over the heads with facts (people tend to tune out). It&#8217;s about coercing you to seeing something differently. To co-opt Apple&#8217;s one-time slogan: Think Different[ly].<br />
That&#8217;s what we do. We change your mind (hopefully for the right way). We do this to sell cars, watches, newspapers, movies, television shows, crackers, ground beef, gasoline, dishwashers, tables, toilet paper, cameras, computers, email services, music streaming, cellular service, education, mutual funds, pets, pretty much anything you&#8217;d ever spend a dime on. That includes things you don&#8217;t actually acquire: because we also help you support your local food banks, international relief agencies, scientific organizations, museums, your church, municipal services, environmental groups, and political parties (elections, in particular).<br />
We are convincing you to think of a future. Unless you&#8217;ve already accepted our common sense, we&#8217;re trying to change yours for a point ahead of you. Because common sense doesn&#8217;t appear instantly. You might be able to change one or two minds instantly, but it takes time to change <em>many</em> minds. That&#8217;s why we call them &#8220;campaigns&#8221;. That&#8217;s why we have to think of different ways to create a common way of thinking, so that decision-making is made simpler for the intended audience.<br />
Audience is a significant factor. If you go truly &#8220;common&#8221;, and cast a wide net to encompass everyone, you&#8217;ll likely miss a lot of people. The greatest myth of &#8220;common sense&#8221; is that there is really is no &#8220;common&#8221;. The term &#8220;common&#8221; means &#8220;belonging equally to, or shared alike by, two or more or all in question<sup>[<a href="http://www.dictionary.com/browse/common" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1</a>]</sup>&#8220;. It takes only a quick glance through the daily events to know that our civilization is far from &#8220;belonging equally&#8221;.<br />
That reality drives the massaging of message. The core concept of the message might be the same (ie. buy an iPhone), but how you sell it will vary across age groups (Millennials have much different economics than Baby Boomers), income brackets (lower-cost iPhones are sold to low-income earners), location (city dwellers live by their devices, whereas famers look more for utility), even by political leaning (left-leaning audiences receive more social branding, where right-leaning audiences are about self worth). The same approach is used for every product, service, and support organization, to ensure that &#8220;common&#8221; comes into existence, even if you see it a little differently than your neighbour.<br />
This happens all day, every day, everywhere you look. You see this information in newspapers, on websites, in Twitter and Facebook, on the sides of buses, over the radio. It&#8217;s done to sell, and to inform you to act. Because at the end of every penny spent on marketing, our goal is to get you to do something. Not just change your mind, but to follow through with some kind of a transaction. It&#8217;s not always financial: we also need your time, your effort, even your donated blood.<br />
I suppose we should apologize for having to manipulate you. But humans are pretty terrible at change; we don&#8217;t like change because it causes us to have to do something potentially uncomfortable. It means giving up a tightly-held idea, sacrificing loyalty to a person or company, or accepting a difficult concept that requires us all to accept fault.<br />
These changes are needed, because this is what drives us forward. The irony is that the notion of &#8220;forward&#8221; isn&#8217;t common, nor ever will be. There are some aspects that are more uniformly directional than others, and there are others (like with politics) that can be horrifically divisional. Because people are different, and despite all efforts to the contrary, we think differently, too. And we always will.<br />
Hopefully this diatribe gives you little insight into marketing and why it exists. With luck, you&#8217;ll see things in a different light &#8212; and see some marketing for what it really is. And if you&#8217;ve got a new opinion about marketing, even better: because that&#8217;s what marketing does.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2017/08/marketing-is-common-sense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3605</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>20 Years a Web Developer</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=20-years-a-web-developer</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 22:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3426</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Twenty years ago this month &#8212; and very possibly this week, though I&#8217;m not 100% certain of that &#8212; I entered into the very nascent industry of digital marketing. At the time, the project had been little more than a simple idea, something to possibly prove my own abilities, a problem that sort of needed &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "20 Years a Web Developer"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twenty years ago this month &#8212; and very possibly this week, though I&#8217;m not 100% certain of that &#8212; I entered into the very nascent industry of digital marketing. At the time, the project had been little more than a simple idea, something to possibly prove my own abilities, a problem that sort of needed solving. And yet, little did I know at the time, it would send me down a long and sometimes disturbingly windy path.<br />
It&#8217;s also a milestone where one does need to consider &#8230; well, everything. Honestly, a bit of reflection and introspection is needed from time to time, but the decade markers seem to have a certain extra amount of importance. Though to be honest, that&#8217;s just a perceived thing; there&#8217;s no legal or social reason that I&#8217;m aware of. It&#8217;s more about having a well-defined chunk of time to really take that step back and say:<br />
&#8220;Ye gods I&#8217;m getting old&#8230;&#8221;<br />
<span id="more-3426"></span><br />
Twenty years seems like such a long time. Indeed, it&#8217;s just less than half of my life at this point. A lot has happened in those twenty years, not just in my own personal life (which is considerable), but also in my industry, which as I noted earlier, barely existed when I started.<br />
I learned HTML in my ENGL 209 course at the University of Waterloo, taught by <a href="https://uwaterloo.ca/english/people-profiles/neil-randall" target="_blank">Professor Neil Randall</a>. Why an English professor was teaching markup was a bit baffling at the time. I learned later that he wrote frequently for <em>PC Magazine</em>, and was a hardened geek. (He still is.) When he gave us the option of filing &#8220;webpages&#8221; instead of papers, I leapt at the change. (Yes, <em>change</em>, not <em>chance</em>.)<br />
Not long afterwards, I took at a job at a company near Don Mills and the 401 in Toronto, writing manuals for a financial software company. Nearby was a small store called &#8220;Movie Poster Warehouse&#8221;. One day, at lunch, I strolled over to peer in and see what it was all about.<br />
Shelley, the owner, told me a bit of their history, most of which went clear through my head at the time: I was absolutely enthralled with the (literal) <em>warehouse</em> of movie posters. Not the junky Imaginus stuff that does the campus circuit. I mean <em>real</em> movie posters. Some of them decades old, and many in pristine original condition. As a rather hard-core movie addict (at the time, anyway), I couldn&#8217;t resist buying one before my lunchtime ran out.<br />
But as I left, I asked if they had a website. &#8220;What&#8217;s a website?&#8221; she asked. And so it began&#8230;<br />
Their <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19961222132316/http://www.movieposter.com/" target="_blank">first website went up in March 1995</a>. My friend Scott did the design, I did the build. I look back on it and cringe a bit, but it was my first professional foray, and my first real beginning to understand how marketing and commerce would work online. (They&#8217;re still online, <a href="https://ca.movieposter.com/" target="_blank">though under a different domain</a>.)<br />
Since then, I&#8217;ve done websites for so many companies that I&#8217;m not even sure I can remember them all. I&#8217;ve done nearly every kind of website at some point, for companies and organizations of nearly every size, in a dozen different languages, in at least a dozen different countries. I&#8217;ve lived the Agency Life<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />, and lived to tell about it. Well, tell about some of it. I can&#8217;t tell you all of it, either due to having forgotten, or &#8230; well, some things do need to remain a secret.<br />
So, twenty years down the road, I&#8217;m still at it. I&#8217;m still a developer at heart, looking at the technology and technical needs of a solution. Not necessarily &#8220;site&#8221;, I should add &#8212; not all problems lead to a website, and the internet is so much more than HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. You need to know a lot more to make a solution work: you need to know what works, how it works, and when best to use it. And all of that has changed from those first few HTML tags I learned so many years ago.<br />
I look back and I can say there&#8217;s been really only one constant in all of this: change. I know that&#8217;s something you&#8217;ll hear a lot in nearly every industry, but the truth is that digital marketing changes constantly. Daily, even. There hasn&#8217;t been a single week in those twenty years when I&#8217;ve not had to look into something different or new. Because that&#8217;s the nature of the internet, which is the real basis for digital marketing: it allows that kind of change.<br />
And if you don&#8217;t keep up with that change? You die. Or worse, you become irrelevant. Not changing, not keeping up with change, is a death sentence. Others will eclipse you in short order, and no matter how loud your thunder may have been, someone else&#8217;s lightning will be crisper, brighter, and faster.<br />
In a way, web developers become slaves to change: we&#8217;re always on the watch for new things, new ideas. We&#8217;re simultaneously excited by them, and terribly burdened by them. The vast majority of us are self-taught, having learned by trial and error, and often trial by fire. We&#8217;ve all been burned, overloaded, unappreciated, misunderstood, belittled, and regularly forgotten.<br />
It&#8217;s an ugly reality, but it&#8217;s a painful truth of where web developer lie in the digital marketing world: we&#8217;re the nameless few. We don&#8217;t win awards for amazing code; we get praised for being on budget (which is difficult), and chastised when things don&#8217;t work perfectly (it&#8217;s exceptionally difficult &#8212; and expensive &#8212; to be perfect).<br />
&#8220;Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic,&#8221; wrote Arthur C. Clarke. I offer a corollary: &#8220;Any sufficiently skilled developer can make the impossible seem magical.&#8221; When we do our jobs well, no-one notices. How&#8217;s that for irony?<br />
Actually, that&#8217;s not entirely true. When you do your job better than someone else, then you&#8217;re noticed &#8230; and not in a good way. Hence, the first rule of the internet: There will always be someone better than you. That means you need to be ready to adapt at a moment&#8217;s notice. And the day I can no longer adapt is the day I forever leave this industry, because I won&#8217;t be able to keep up.<br />
Today is not that day. Tired, I may be. Exhausted even. That&#8217;s a result of age (I&#8217;m no spring chicken, anymore), home life (my kids are awesome, but they have boundless energy), and evolution (the act of changing is draining). But I&#8217;m not done.<br />
I won&#8217;t be done until I say I&#8217;m done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2015/03/20-years-a-web-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3426</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Selling the awful to the angry</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=selling-the-awful-to-the-angry</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 05:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3405</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Selling the awful to the angry"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening, my family trucked down to 96th Ave SW, invited by the Calgary Board of Education (along with the other families in the Westgate School Bilingual Spanish program) to view the &#8220;new&#8221; school, Eugene Coste Elementary. It was supposed to be a chance to see the new location, and ask questions of the CBE Area IV director, as well as the Planning &amp; Transportation folks.<br />
I emphasize the word &#8220;supposed&#8221; &#8212; that was the CBE&#8217;s perspective. They thought they would get a lot of interest, and a lot of people who were genuinely happy that a solution had been found for the accommodation woes at Westgate School, which is at over 90% of its rated capacity.<br />
But, funny thing, there weren&#8217;t many happy people.<br />
<span id="more-3405"></span><br />
When we received the official notice that Eugene Coste was the &#8220;solution&#8221; to the problem, there&#8217;s been almost the equivalent of an angry mob. (I know &#8212; I&#8217;m one of them.) And that angry mob has been inundating the CBE with emails, phone calls, petitions, and even an appeal rally in the lobby of their headquarters last Friday. It would be awfully hard for anyone at the CBE to be able to not notice that there are a lot of unhappy people.<br />
Yet, despite all the warning, the CBE continued with its open house at Eugene Coste. I would like to refer to it as &#8220;Eugene Coste School&#8221; at this point, but in truth, it&#8217;s only a building with some rooms &#8212; everything that could make it a school, like desks, chairs, art on the walls, books in the library, and so forth, are utterly <em>absent</em>. The building was little more than a shell.<br />
When we entered the building, we were effectively directed to what I think was previously the library, to see some information, and talk to the directors. Except there wasn&#8217;t much talking &#8212; it was largely listening to the angry parents question the directors, and listen to the directors attempt to explain their position. Amongst all of this were kids running about, having to be corralled by parents who were trying to speak their minds. There were a lot of angry parents. Amazingly, so I heard later, the CBE was surprised that so many people were unhappy about the affair.<br />
Now this, dear reader, is where I give myself the facepalm. You know this expression, yes?<br />
<img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://forums.riftgame.com/attachments/general-discussion/9358-open-challenge-daglar-picard-facepalm.jpg" width="750" height="600" /><br />
I say this because I&#8217;m utterly unable to see how the CBE thought that asking a large number of unhappy parents to drive through rush hour traffic to a school to which they&#8217;re largely opposed with their tired and hungry kids in tow (without a single distraction available to occupy them), not run a single tour of the facility to sell its virtues, and corral everyone in one room to &#8220;talk&#8221; with the people most of the angry parents are blaming in the first place, was <em>ever</em> a good idea.<br />
Exactly <em>how</em> was this supposed to be successful?<br />
I work in marketing. You know, the industry that exists to sell you the things you don&#8217;t really want to buy? (Okay, slightly cynical. I admit that perhaps I&#8217;ve been doing this job too long&#8230;) You can look at <em>Mad Men</em> and snicker, but the basis of the show isn&#8217;t far from reality: we make you want something.<br />
The CBE didn&#8217;t even <em>try</em> to make us want to send our kids to Eugene Coste. Let&#8217;s ignore the hour-long bus rides and massive disruption to families&#8217; lives &#8212; the school building was devoid of any life whatsoever, and we didn&#8217;t even really get a chance to see much of it. And having our fears glossed over by &#8220;best case&#8221; scenarios of bus routes and timing? A little more than moderately insulting. Basically, they failed at selling the idea.<br />
This is the point at which an agency is asked to leave the pitch process and not return. Or, worse, the agency&#8217;s account is brought up for review and they have to validate their existence against dozens of competitors who want the account.<br />
This is something the CBE needs to figure out: how to sell awful situations to angry people. The entire city is under school space crunches, and there aren&#8217;t a lot of options for anyone. The releases we receive are emotionless, lacking sufficient information, and unable to address the fears that arise &#8212; the very things that any good marketing job should address.<br />
No competition for the CBE, you say? You&#8217;d be surprised how many people are readily willing to consider the separate school system, or even the extra cost of charter schools. And we&#8217;ve got a lot of charter schools in Calgary, so this is definitely not a hypothetical scenario. The CBE just ends up with more angry customers, who won&#8217;t be willing to put up with the problem much longer.<br />
So a suggestion to the CBE: you want people to like you? Get someone else to tell your story, &#8216;cuz you&#8217;re doing a lousy job of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2014/01/selling-the-awful-to-the-angry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3405</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Red Herring: QR Codes</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/marketing-red-herring-qr-codes/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=marketing-red-herring-qr-codes</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/marketing-red-herring-qr-codes/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 21:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3124</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m in digital marketing. I spend a lot of time dealing with ways of people visit websites to get them to spend money. (That&#8217;s the short version. The really short, and moderately soul-suckingly depressing version. The long version is &#8230; an entire career.) So I deal with a lot of different ideas, tools, methodologies, and &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/marketing-red-herring-qr-codes/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Marketing Red Herring: QR Codes"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in digital marketing. I spend a lot of time dealing with ways of people visit websites to get them to spend money. (That&#8217;s the short version. The really short, and moderately soul-suckingly depressing version. The long version is &#8230; an entire career.) So I deal with a lot of different ideas, tools, methodologies, and directions that &#8212; in theory &#8212; make everyone&#8217;s lives easier.<br />
Every so often, we get hit with buzzwords. Sometimes, they&#8217;re tech-related, like DHTML, AJAX, and HTML5 (remember, I deal with these things <em>every day</em> &#8212; I know what they really mean). Sometimes, they&#8217;re things like &#8220;progressive enhancement&#8221; or &#8220;responsive design&#8221; (yes, buzzwords &#8212; they can <em>grossly</em><em> </em>over-simplify reality). And then there&#8217;s the Big Shiny<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> stuff that distracts from simplicity.<br />
Let me tell you a few things about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code">QR Codes</a>&#8230;<br />
<span id="more-3124"></span>If you haven&#8217;t already heard of the term, you&#8217;ve <em>definitely</em> seen them by now. They&#8217;re almost impossible to miss. <a href="http://robinsfox.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/banana-qr-72.jpg">They&#8217;re on <em>bananas</em> for pete&#8217;s sake!</a> What are they? Simple version: bar codes, an improvement on the decades-old UPC barcodes we normally see on our cereal boxes.<br />
But.<br />
They&#8217;re not doing the same thing that UPC codes do. UPC codes provide a number &#8212; JUST A NUMBER &#8212; to a computer for the purposes of recording something. We see them most in grocery stores (leading to the ubiquitous &#8220;bleep&#8221; sound as the number is acknowledged by the till), but they&#8217;re also used by companies like FedEx for tracking, and by companies doing equipment inventories, and so forth.<br />
QR Codes were invented by a Japanese automaker to do basically the same thing, but provide more information than UPC codes, and allow the code to be effectively read even if the code was upside-down or on an angle. QR Codes can contain quite a lot of information, and textual information &#8212; not just numbers &#8212; including the ability to use different alphabets.<br />
So what the heck is it doing on your banana?<br />
Well, that&#8217;s the problem, actually. <em>It shouldn&#8217;t be there</em>.<br />
Here&#8217;s what happened. The Japanese realised the (notable) intelligence of the QR barcode format, and started to use it in <em>intelligent</em> places, such as passport documentation, train tickets, and places where things needed to be scanned, quickly, and information needed to be encoded for computers. They were <em>never</em> meant to be used by humans directly.<br />
Well, some <em>intelligent</em> marketing shmuck (&#8216;cuz it weren&#8217;t no engineer, I&#8217;ll tell ya that) saw these things in use, did a little research, and suddenly realised: HEY! This would make a GREAT way of providing a short cut for people to get URLs, or text information, or [insert not-thought-through idea here].<br />
Sounds good, though, doesn&#8217;t it? But here&#8217;s the problem. Someone jumped from Step 1 to Step 4, without considering the full experience. Let me try this one on for you (which I&#8217;ve actually seen, and attempted, myself).<br />
You&#8217;re at a bar. The waitress (honestly, are men allowed to work at bars, anymore?) places down a coaster for the soon-to-arrive beer. On the coaster is an eye-catching graphic title of a brewery, along with a big ol&#8217; QR code.<br />
Okayyyy&#8230; now what? Do you know what to do with it? Take a picture, maybe? Okay, but there isn&#8217;t a SINGLE mobile phone on the market (that I know of, anyway) that &#8212; when you use the <em>default</em> picture-taking functionality &#8212; do anything but take a picture. You now have a picture of that coaster. Whoop-dee-do.<br />
The problem is you need a QR decoder &#8212; something that&#8217;ll look at that picture, analyze the alignment, and figure out what those dots are supposed to mean. Every phone requires you to fire up an app to do that. On Blackberry, you need to open App World. On Android, you need to at least fire up Google Goggles (assuming it&#8217;s even installed). On iOS, you need to <em>download</em> an app that you don&#8217;t already have &#8212; there is no native ability <em>whatsoever</em>.<br />
Oh, and you have to take the picture again with that app, &#8216;cuz they don&#8217;t usually go to the picture you just took.<br />
Depending on the app, they&#8217;ll display a message (let&#8217;s assume it&#8217;s a URL, just for fun), or (if you&#8217;re lucky) prompt you to open the webpage directly. Basically, you have to open an app, just to open the <em>real</em> app (the browser).<br />
And all of that assumes you actually know what the hell to do with QR codes. I would argue a large number of people don&#8217;t know <em>or care</em>. They remember the brand name that&#8217;s there, and check it out later. Assuming, that is, that some moron didn&#8217;t make <a href="http://www.blackberryqr.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/1303435833-42.jpg">the entire ad a QR code</a>.<br />
Let&#8217;s be honest, marketers, you&#8217;re trying to drive mobile traffic. We get that, it&#8217;s totally cool, really. But, for the love of pete, put some thought into it? You&#8217;re spending way too much time addressing the barrier to entry, than about the actual <em>content</em> you&#8217;re using to actually sell something. You&#8217;d be smarter getting yourself a nice, short (and preferably memorable) URL.<br />
&#8216;Cuz I&#8217;ll wager in the time it takes someone to fire up their QR code app, I can already have typed in the URL into my browser.<br />
Two more things to consider:</p>
<ol>
<li>Don&#8217;t forget the mobile market&#8217;s biggest segment &#8212; youth &#8212; can type <em>way</em> faster than you can. Making them work for a website is going to turn them off whatever it is you&#8217;re trying to sell them.</li>
<li>When was the last time you tried to remember a QR code to share with someone else?</li>
</ol>
<div>Put a pretty picture on my coaster, please. I&#8217;d prefer to look at that more.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/07/marketing-red-herring-qr-codes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3124</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to really succeed in (any) business</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/how-to-really-succeed-in-any-business/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-really-succeed-in-any-business</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/how-to-really-succeed-in-any-business/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 19:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Renovations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=3046</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Recently, if you&#8217;ve been following this blog, you know my family has been going through a kitchen renovation. It&#8217;s not quite done, but it&#8217;s turning out very nicely, and we really, really, really cannot wait for it to be all over and done. It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s been particularly frustrating &#8212; inconvenient for day-to-day life, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/how-to-really-succeed-in-any-business/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "How to really succeed in (any) business"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, if you&#8217;ve been following this blog, you know my family has been going through a kitchen renovation. It&#8217;s not quite done, but it&#8217;s turning out very nicely, and we really, really, really cannot wait for it to be all over and done. It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s been particularly frustrating &#8212; inconvenient for day-to-day life, maybe &#8212; it&#8217;s just that it&#8217;s extra stress that I really do not want.<br />
The entire process has really reinforced my belief that if you want to succeed in business, you need to do two things <em>well</em>: Communicate, and set expectations. If you do nothing else right, these two will save your ass, not to mention help you get out of the mess you got yourself into.<br />
<span id="more-3046"></span>Now lest ye believe that I&#8217;m merely standing on a soapbox (which I regularly do, anyway), please remember that I&#8217;m a 17-year veteran of internet marketing. I work in advertising, one of the more notorious industries for screwing things up and having to make sure you say the right things or lose your client. (If you&#8217;re not in the ad industry, watch &#8220;Mad Men&#8221;. You&#8217;ll get it.)<br />
In my world, everything starts with communication. You need to make sure everyone understands what&#8217;s been requested, what&#8217;s being done (and how it&#8217;s being done), when it&#8217;s due, and how much it&#8217;ll cost. Those are key points to getting what you asked for, and it doesn&#8217;t matter if you&#8217;re the client, or the vendor. (Or the person working on the project, for that matter&#8230;)<br />
Clear communications leds to the second important thing (they&#8217;re related, if you haven&#8217;t picked up on that yet): setting expectations. Here&#8217;s the single biggest problem with dealing with humans: we leap to conclusions, especially when we&#8217;re not presented with enough information. (This is why action movies thrill us, horror movies terrify us, and jokes are funny.) These expectations prepare us for what will come, and these expectations are created through communication.<br />
The key thing is whether or not you <em>deliberately</em>  set expectations. Like it or not, expectations will come, so it behooves you to be the one in control of those expectations, and make sure they&#8217;re set properly so there as few surprises as possible (and, hence, fewer people pissed off).<br />
Let me give you a very recent example of why this is important&#8230;<br />
Our kitchen renovation also includes upgrades to the two bathrooms upstairs, part of which is two new toilets. Our contractor had convinced us to go with Toto toilets, which we already knew and liked, and he said he could get us a decent price. We&#8217;d pushed (a bit) for cheaper American Standard toilets, which we felt would be more cost effective, but in the end bought into the higher-end Totos.<br />
Today, not 30 minutes ago, the plumber hauled in a pair of Kohler Sterling Karsten models. Imagine our &#8230; puzzlement. This, naturally, precipitated a conversation with the poor plumber, who had apparently been instructed in such a way as to decide that the Kohler was more cost-effective, and the colour would more closely match the pedestal sink in the one bathroom.<br />
In the Grand Scheme of Things, does a different toilet really matter? Not if it flushes properly, in my view. We weren&#8217;t about to balk at a change of manufacturer if the overall  aesthetic is maintained or improved (and money saved is also a benefit). The balking came in not knowing there was going to be a change. It was a complete surprise, because our expectation was for something else.<br />
I see this all the time, too, in my industry. Someone makes an &#8220;executive&#8221; decision that affects a delivery, be it time, scope, appearance, or functionality. In the Grand Scheme of Things, said decision is usually for the best. But, ultimately, someone else needs to know of this decision so they don&#8217;t &#8230; well, balk at the surprise. We engage in that discussion to mitigate the shock, and ensure things continue moving forward as they need to.<br />
So consider this, dear readers, as you engage in your daily  hullabaloo. Make sure you&#8217;re clear about what you&#8217;re doing, and make sure you stay on top of that message &#8212; especially if it needs to change &#8212; so your partner/client/spouse/teacher/etc. know what&#8217;s coming. It just saves grief, and keeps things calm.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2012/04/how-to-really-succeed-in-any-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3046</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing is from Mars, IT is from Venus</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/04/marketing-is-from-mars-it-is-from-venus/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=marketing-is-from-mars-it-is-from-venus</link>
				<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/04/marketing-is-from-mars-it-is-from-venus/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 15:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/?p=2622</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent over a decade in the Big Leagues of interactive marketing. I started in the low rungs as a web developer, and slowly worked my past the coding to see the bigger pictures: what made marketing work, why certain campaigns were better than others, how to think like a client, and so forth. These &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/04/marketing-is-from-mars-it-is-from-venus/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Marketing is from Mars, IT is from Venus"</span></a>]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve spent over a decade in the Big Leagues of interactive marketing. I started in the low rungs as a web developer, and slowly worked my past the coding to see the bigger pictures: what made marketing work, why certain campaigns were better than others, how to think like a client, and so forth. These are all truly interesting skills, and helped a lot with the projects I worked on.<br />
One thing that regularly amazed me, however, was how often a client&#8217;s internal IT group seemed to have non-trivial input on almost every aspect of an initiative, from the way it was hosted right down to the specific use of a given image. I often found myself watching our best-laid plans being eaten away to the point of delivering something I was less than happy with. The repeat experience led me to focus on one inexorable fact:<br />
IT departments should never have any input on the marketing website. <em>Ever</em>.<br />
<span id="more-2622"></span>Before the IT folks all try to kill me, please understand something &#8212; I&#8217;m on <em>your</em> side. My background is technical &#8212; I have done corporate IT in my previous lives, and am well aware of the implications and consequences of a haphazard platform rollout or a half-baked application install. I know why Sarbanes-Oxley creates havoc every quarter. And yes, I too have denied people hardware upgrades merely for the reason that I didn&#8217;t see the need. I know where you&#8217;re coming from.<br />
To over-simplify things, it&#8217;s the men and women problem: they&#8217;re both human, but communication and understanding sometimes comes in very short supply. Hence the book, and the numerous parodies thereof. (Though why women got stuck with the toxic atmosphere planet remains a mystery to me.) In my view, IT and marketing are on equally distant worlds, with the same challenges to understand given needs.<br />
This is not about just mere communication. This goes past communication to perceptions, politics, policies, and also budgets. The resulting confounding confusion ends with uncertainties, namely: who actually is responsible for the website, who owns the website and its operation, and who pays for it. (Yes, IT and marketing work for the same company, but each has their own budgets.) This is where the tug-of-wars start, and why IT tends to get sucked (or shoved) into the website space.<br />
Like I said, IT, I&#8217;m on your side. And believe me when I say this: <strong>You do not want to handle the trouble of the marketing website.</strong><br />
Simply put, a marketing department&#8217;s purpose is to sell a company&#8217;s products or services. As the adage goes, you have to spend money to make money. In the world of profit/loss, a marketing department is almost entirely loss &#8212; they spend the money to raise awareness and encourage sales of their organisation&#8217;s wares.<br />
An IT department&#8217;s purpose is to support the organisation&#8217;s internal operations through implementing technology standards, ensuring stability and control over technology infrastructure, and assisting when things go awry. Like marketing, internal IT is entirely loss as well &#8212; it is the traditional form of a &#8220;cost center&#8221;, meaning it doesn&#8217;t even feed directly into a revenue chain. That also means that it&#8217;s a constant focus of cost control.<br />
The two departments also (typically) report up through different executives as well, with marketing going to a marketing-oriented office (such as a Chief Marketing Officer) and IT going through the financial/administrative office (such as a Chief Financial Officer). This means that messages provided to each of them are different, the directions given to them are different, and their are told to focus on different things.<br />
Which means, of course, that when the marketing department asks for something, the IT department will think it means something else.<br />
In my experience, this usually arises when a company&#8217;s web presence is the point of discussion. This is the ultimate tug-of-war: marketing needs the freedom to do what they need to do to their job, and IT sees this as something they need to own and support. Almost invariably, it ends up getting messy, and the marketing department ends up subservient to the IT department.<br />
Now, before all you geeks out there cheer for this apparent victory, this is a bad thing. As alluded to above, IT departments do not understand marketing needs. What IT departments see is a need to keep things in line with supported standards, and keep costs to a minimum. <a href="http://www.projectcartoon.com/cartoon/2648">This misunderstanding has been lampooned many times in cartoon</a>, often sending those in the industry to nod their heads sadly at the truth.<br />
Consider the following scenario: Marketing has a project that will raise awareness for a new product. Their budget allows for about two weeks of work, and will have a one year lifespan. They want to really reach out to Gen Y as a primary audience. When Marketing and IT see these rough requirements, they&#8217;ll each see something different:</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Marketing View</td>
<td>IT View</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Project Need</td>
<td>Microsite to support a new sales campaign</td>
<td>Update to the website</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Deadline</td>
<td>Two weeks</td>
<td>&#8220;When it&#8217;s ready&#8221;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Content Management</td>
<td>Simple, easy, something an intern could use</td>
<td>Corporate standard implementation (large, usually unwieldy and expensive)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Creative vision</td>
<td>Rich media that engages user with branding and product</td>
<td>Flat HTML works best with the corporate standard</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="3">etc&#8230;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>There&#8217;s two places where IT falls short: understanding the creative aspect of marketing, and the need for flexibility. Marketing campaigns are highly creative, by sheer necessity &#8212; remove the creativity, and all you have is a message without hooks. The flexibility allow marketing to react to need, as well as attempt strategies to better broadcast a message. Such flexibility flies in the face of most standards, which strive for stringent consistency.<br />
In other words, marketing is not something an IT department should ever want to understand. I assure you, it can make your head hurt.<br />
So what are we left with? In my view, keep IT doing what IT does best: supporting the internal infrastructure of a company, and staying out of the website game.<br />
As for the website, it should never live with the company (unless the company itself is geared utterly around its website, but that also changes the game entirely). The website should live at an external location with a third-party hosting vendor. There are thousands to choose from in all sizes, shapes, securities, and softwares. You do this because you don&#8217;t want to have to deal with the infrastructure of a website that supports your business (either directly or indirectly), and because it allows a marketing department to do things that would scare the bejeebus out of an IT team.<br />
So, dear IT friends, do yourselves a favour: if someone ever tries to suggest you take on the task of managing the company&#8217;s website projects, do yourselves a favour: run. And leave behind a note with the five hosting sales reps who cold-called you last month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2010/04/marketing-is-from-mars-it-is-from-venus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
						<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2622</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
