<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>shinkansen &#8211; The Observer&#039;s Log</title>
	<atom:link href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/tag/shinkansen/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org</link>
	<description>A miscellany of know-it-all-isms by Geoff Sowrey</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 22:57:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">157010562</site>	<item>
		<title>A bullet train in Calgary?</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=a-bullet-train-in-calgary</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 22:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alberta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calgary transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edmonton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red deer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/2008/01/09/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train from here to Fort McMurray. Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks. Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A bullet train in Calgary?"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just came across a rather &#8230; well, odd article on CBC.ca. It&#8217;s a blueprint for 2018. Apparently, the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/canada/calgary/story/2008/01/09/10year-plan.html">Calgary City council thinks that there should be a bullet train</a> from here to Fort McMurray.<br />
Someone&#8217;s been sniffing oil fumes too much, methinks.<br />
<span id="more-887"></span>Yes, this is me, the Train Stalker, saying that a high-speed train in Alberta is insane. Completely. Why, you ask?</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is going to pay the $3-4 billion to build a dedicated grade-separated, high-speed rail network? Don&#8217;t look to either <a href="http://www.cp.ca/">CP</a> or <a href="http://www.cn.ca">CN</a>.</li>
<li>Similarly, who runs it? If it&#8217;s VIA, expect the service to have constant problems, since budgets to run high-speed are much higher than regular trains, and <a href="http://www.viarail.ca">VIA</a>&#8216;s got enough budgetary problems as it is.</li>
<li>Do we honestly think there would be enough use of the trains to make them even remotely cost-effective? <a href="http://www.westjet.com">WestJet</a> is pretty darn cheap, y&#8217;know&#8230;</li>
<li>The provincial government was looking to shore up the existing lines up north to help move heavy equipment by train. CN passed on the work (they own the lines) after realising the cost to build up the service wasn&#8217;t worth the revenue. Take that as a subtle hint for new lines.</li>
<li>It hits -40 in many places, with a lot of snow. I don&#8217;t know of many (read: any) high-speed lines that regularly go through such conditions. Hokkaido in Japan is the nearest, and even that&#8217;s not as severe.</li>
</ul>
<p>Politically, it strikes me as odd that anyone would stand up behind this as a good idea, since it&#8217;ll likely be a government that owns it, and it would probably become a white elephant. Very cool, and I&#8217;d ride it just for the sake of riding it &#8212; but governments have been voted out of office for stuff like this.<br />
All of that said, it&#8217;s totally the green option. Run the train often enough, and you have less cars (less automobile pollution) and less planes (less aviation pollution). It&#8217;s also a nicer way to travel long distances. And Canada&#8217;s full of that distance thing.<br />
Mind you, the bullet train wasn&#8217;t the only &#8220;odd&#8221; thing in that report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Building a ring road in Calgary. Um&#8230; <a href="http://content.calgary.ca/CCA/City+Hall/Office+of+the+Mayor/Press+Room/Archive/2006/February+2006/NE+Ring+Road.htm">aren&#8217;t we doing that already</a>?</li>
<li>Where is the mention of expanding Calgary Transit? For the love of Pete, people &#8212; why are you trying to link together cities when [[Calgary Transit Sucks|we can&#8217;t even sort ourselves out]]?</li>
<li>A covered skywalk or monorail between the Telus Convention Centre and the Stampede facilities. What, the C-Train isn&#8217;t good enough for you already? (See previous note about public transit.)</li>
<li>An international aerospace hub. If there was a way to eloquently describe my blank stare at this one, I would. But I&#8217;m simply not that good a writer.</li>
</ul>
<p>I offer one thought to the people who came up with this: Let&#8217;s blueprint something for success, please? Around my office, we ask people to set SMART goals. It&#8217;s an acronym, with the &#8220;R&#8221; standing for &#8220;realistic&#8221;. Which these blueprints really seem to be missing.<br />
If you want success, you needn&#8217;t look further than our own front door. We have three overloaded hospitals, our transit system is not keeping pace with the need, ambulances are running short on availability regularly, and if you haven&#8217;t thought about our water supply availability, you might want to consider that soon, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2008/01/a-bullet-train-in-calgary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">887</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nara is neat</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nara-is-neat</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2005 14:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[around the world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2005/06/18/nara-is-neat/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last time I was in Japan (a little over a year ago), I&#8217;d wanted to go to Nara. I&#8217;d quite a bit about it, but just hadn&#8217;t gotten the chance to go. So when we planned this out, and happened to be spinning through Japan on our way home, it was a very fortunate &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Nara is neat"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The last time I was in Japan (a little over a year ago), I&#8217;d wanted to go to Nara. I&#8217;d quite a bit about it, but just hadn&#8217;t gotten the chance to go. So when we planned this out, and happened to be spinning through Japan on our way home, it was a very fortunate happenstance that both of us wanted to be there.<br />
Nara, as it turns out, is a very neat little city. Make no mistake, this is most definitely no town. But it doesn&#8217;t feel large. At least, if you&#8217;re within the &#8220;walled&#8221; portion. (I&#8217;m not sure if there&#8217;s an actual wall, but that&#8217;s what it looks like on the maps we&#8217;ve seen.)<br />
<span id="more-583"></span>Our trip there was an adventure and a half. First, shinkansen to Shin-Osaka, Nozomi-class. (There are three classes: Kodama, Hikari, and Nozomi. Although JR Rail Pass holders aren&#8217;t allowed on Nozomi, the cost to buy a ticket isn&#8217;t much different (maybe 300 yen) between them. And you save almost an hour.) Originally, we were to go to Kyoto, but Amy convinced me to go all the way to Shin-Osaka. Once there, we switched to a local train to Osaka station, then to a regional train that took us all the way out to Nara. From the moment we got off at Shin-Osaka, all the way to a taxi that we finally climbed into in Nara, we stood. My feet were KILLING me.<br />
We&#8217;re staying at a ryokan, a small traditional Japanese guest house. Apparently, it used to be a geisha house. I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s Japanese geishas, or American geishas. (What&#8217;s the difference? A proper Japanese geisha is an entertainer. Their job was to placate and entertain powerful men who paid very highly for the services of a geisha. Despite beliefs, Japanese geishas were not prostitutes, unlike the American geishas. These were introduced by the U.S. Government after World War II as an effort to keep American soldiers from &#8220;disturbing&#8221; the Japanese people. These were prostitutes dressed up as geishas, and called as such for the exotic overtones.) I&#8217;d like to believe the house was a Japanese one. It&#8217;s nothing fancy &#8212; a pair of mattresses, a couple of chairs, and a noisy air conditioner. Toilets and showers are communal, but there doesn&#8217;t seem to be anyone around.<br />
Nara is full of temples. Aside from being a former capital (many Japanese cities seem to hold this title), this is still a religious centre. Thankfully, most of the neat stuff was in walking distance of the ryokan. (For the record, though, our &#8220;walking distance&#8221; is probably a lot further than some people&#8217;s definition. We&#8217;ve walked a <em>lot</em> in this trip.)<br />
Starting off at a pond near the Five Storied Pagoda, we found a healthy collection of turtles. Then we wandered through the Pagoda area and were introduced to the deer. Nara deer are &#8230; odd. They&#8217;re small, not as small as the ones on Miyajima Island near Hiroshima, but certainly smaller than the ones in Canada. They&#8217;re defined as &#8220;semi-wild&#8221;, meaning that while they are wild animals, they tolerate interaction with humans quite well. (Although there are a lot of signs telling you to be careful and not to enrage the deer.) It&#8217;s stuff like this that reminds me why many tourists in Banff (Bamf!) are told not to get too close to the elk.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03745.JPG" alt="Pond o' Turtles" width="300" /></a><br />
We were distracted by a rather nice park on the way to Tennoji Temple. Aside from the wonderful Japanese stone lanterns, the biggest attraction we saw was the botanical garden. Apparently designed off various literal works, the garden contains a wonderful collection of plants, arranged into very beautiful pockets of splendour. Of particular interest was a small red deck built over a lilypad-covered pond. The pond was home to a school of carp, which a trio of elderly photographers were taking turns snapping pictures.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03746.JPG" alt="Botanical Garden" width="300" /></a><br />
Tennoji Temple is quite impressive. Like other buildings I&#8217;ve been to that claim it&#8217;s &#8220;the largest wooden building in the world&#8221;, it&#8217;s big. Really big. And impressive. There&#8217;s a large Buddha that sits inside, sheltered by the building. Interestingly enough, the building is smaller than it once was (fire reconstruction), and the temple itself is smaller, having been reduced by similar damage.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03747.JPG" alt="Tennoji Temple" width="300" /></a><br />
We walked around through various alleys and laneways (Nara has many that are very picturesque. You&#8217;ll see something interesting down nearly every road, it seems.)<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03748.JPG" alt="Nara Cultural Hell" width="300" /></a><br />
Amy finally found some Japanese yarn. I thought she was going to have kittens when she found it. She couldn&#8217;t decide, either.<br />
<a><img src="http://www.howtogetlost.com/media/DSC03750.JPG" alt="Yarn, yarn, everywhere..." width="300" /></a><br />
I&#8217;d glad to have finally been to Nara. It&#8217;s a nice little place. If you&#8217;re thinking of coming to Japan, give it a thought. It&#8217;s an easy trip from Osaka &#8230; so long as you&#8217;re not carrying all your bags with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2005/06/nara-is-neat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">583</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2004 23:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/04/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much. Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Tokyo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More tofu for breakfast. Blech. Well, not so much blech as bland and really not what I&#8217;d like to eat first thing in the morning. Jen didn&#8217;t eat much.<br />
Today we&#8217;re back to Tokyo (and Yotsukaido). But first, we wanted to do a little touring around. And I do mean &#8220;little&#8221;. Specifically, two stops up the Karasuma line to the Kyoto Imperial Palace. I really wanted to see what it&#8217;s like in there.<br />
But first, we had to pack up and check out. Which wasn&#8217;t easy &#8212; we&#8217;d spread ourselves all over the room. Although it didn&#8217;t take me long to pack, Jen had to take a bit longer out of necessity. It&#8217;s safe to say that, either way, both of us officially have too much stuff.<br />
<span id="more-341"></span>I had some troubles at the front desk trying to pay for the bill. It came to about 85,000 yen for the four days (about CDN$1,000).<br />
Yes, this is what people refer to when they say that Japan is expensive. Last time, I hadn&#8217;t noticed this because I&#8217;d stayed with Chris. Now I know better.<br />
For whatever reason, my Mastercard wasn&#8217;t accepted. Neither was my VISA. Not by the hotel &#8212; by their system. Quite odd, and highly annoying. So it had to be cash, and I needed a post office for that. First, though, Jen and I brought our bags down to put into storage.<br />
Luckily, there&#8217;s a post office about a block and a half from the hotel, and unlike Canada&#8217;s post offices, was open on a weekend. But my financial woes didn&#8217;t end &#8212; for whatever reason, I couldn&#8217;t withdraw more than 60,000 yen, barely covering our hotel cost with the money I already had. I think I have only about 10,000 yen to get me through the weekend. I hope I make it.<br />
This prompted a long series of emails to and from North America (over the keitai), specifically to my sister, to try and figure out what happened to my bank account. My paycheque should have gone through two days ago (even with the time change). Thankfully, my money is still there, I just can&#8217;t get to it for some reason.<br />
We got to the Imperial Palace and walked over to the Household Agency, which governs the operation of the Palaces and grants the tours.<br />
On weekdays. We&#8217;d forgotten that it&#8217;s Saturday. I knew there was a reason I&#8217;d wanted to go to Osaka today and not yesterday.<br />
After taking a bit of a leisurely tour through the palace grounds, we returned to the hotel to collect our things and head off to the shinkansen. The 12:37 Hikaru would put us in Tokyo a little after 15:00, and have us at Chris&#8217; door by 16:30 or so. (As it stands, we arrived at 17:00.)<br />
Nearing Kyoto Station, the unmisstakable sound of women running in high heels echoed through the tiled hallways. (In the hotel room, women running down the road in high heels always seemed to sound like horses clip-clopping.) Women always seem to be running in heels here. If there was an Olympic event for running in high heels, Japan would capture the gold every time.<br />
The train ride out was mostly uneventful, Jen and I snoozing most of the trip from Kyoto to Tokyo. Arriving at Tokyo, we found our way down to Sobu underground track #4, where we waited for the 15:50 to Chiba. For the first time since I started taking trains in Japan, one was actually late.<br />
By five whole minutes.<br />
Chris and Kaz were kept appraised of our location at all times. Chris was off to work again, so Kaz would pick us up at the train station. How did I know all this? The rented cell phone, of course. Today, if anything, has proven why renting a cell phone in Japan is a good thing &#8212; being able to confirm a bank account balance or make sure you meet up with friends is not only extremely handy, but really cuts some of the guess work out of things. So if you&#8217;re planning to come to Japan and know people here, really consider renting a phone. It&#8217;s almost too convenient not to have one.<br />
Arriving at Yotsukaido, Kaz directed us to the taxi. I didn&#8217;t think Chris&#8217; apartment was so far away that we needed a taxi, but after a long trip, taking a ride seemed far more pleasant. As we would find out, however, we were not going to Chris&#8217; apartment. Suddenly, the slightly garbled phone conversation I&#8217;d had with Chris made sense. We were going to Kaz&#8217;s (and now also Chris&#8217;) new apartment.<br />
It you get off on the taxi/bus side of the station, and go down the road that runs perpendicular to the station for about three kilometres, hang a left at the Eneos station, and go up about a block, you&#8217;ve found their place. It&#8217;s not as convenient as Chris&#8217; old apartment, but it is really nice. Brand-new (it was finished only days before we left Canada) and full of gadgets (the hot water for the bath/shower is turned on from the kitchen/living space, all electronic, and actually says something &#8212; in Japanese, of course). It&#8217;s pretty sweet.<br />
It&#8217;s a bus ride from the station, or taxi, or a long walk. So we won&#8217;t be hoofing it all that often, especially after a long day. No big deal, especially for such a nice place &#8230; even if it is going to be a bit cramped for the next couple of days. (Tony&#8217;s here tonight, and probably tomorrow night, too.)<br />
Kaz and I took the bus back to the station after dumping our things out (Jen stayed behind to read and draw), and then walked to the local Home Depot-like store. They&#8217;d purchased a gas range so they could cook, but had to pick it up. Although a fairly light piece of equipment, it&#8217;s just awkward enough that you needed to borrow a truck to take it home. We took the opportunity to pick up a few things from the apartment.<br />
Like the heater&#8230;<br />
&#8230; the TV &#8230;<br />
&#8230; the VCR, DVD player, Playstation, movies, books, CDs, CD burner, a small cabinet, boxes of who-knows-what, and anything else we could pack in the back of the truck.<br />
I should point out that this is a *Japanese* truck. One that could fit in the bed of most large American pick-up trucks. So there wasn&#8217;t that much room for us to store stuff. Not that it was a big deal of any kind. It was weird to sit in because it was so small. You literally felt like the steel of the cab wrapped right around you to conserve space.<br />
Chris arrived just as we were finishing up, and we quickly packed the remainder. Kaz and I drove over in the truck while Chris biked. Due to rush hour traffic, Chris arrived before we did. A quick unpacking, and Chris and Kaz whipped off to take the truck back before they&#8217;d run out of time.<br />
Jen and I waited around, either drawing (in Jen&#8217;s case) or writing (in mine). It took a while, but they eventually returned to the apartment. They ran into Jen on her way back from coffee run (now that we&#8217;re in the Tokyo area, we&#8217;re actually able to find Georgia Max coffee again &#8212; the southern part of Japan seems to be devoid of it).<br />
With that, we were off to dinner at a nearby restaurant. We went for something called okonomiyaki, which is basically food that comes in a bowl, is mixed together, then cooked on a grill that&#8217;s built into the table. It&#8217;s sort of like a Japanese omelette or fritatta. It&#8217;s very tasty. We also had some grilled beef and pork, along with noodle and gyoza.<br />
Tony (yep, the Monkey Man) finally appeared around 22:00, after repeated attempts to try and get a hold of him. The five of us sat around, ate a little, before heading back to Kaz and Chris&#8217; apartment. We stopped first into a 24-hour drug/grocery store to pick up snacks and various things for around the house (they&#8217;re still moving in, so don&#8217;t have a lot of things). Jen bought three more Georgia Max coffees, and had downed two of them before we&#8217;d walked the block and a half to the apartment. She was still wired when we went to bed three hours later.<br />
Upon returning was the Great Soul Calibur II Matchup. Chris and Jen had been talking about this for a long time. Chris is very good at this game, as is Jen. Chris has a sort of &#8220;home field&#8221; advantage because this is a Playstation 2, whereas Jen plays on a GameCube. Doesn&#8217;t sound like it should matter, but it does. Jen won only a single game. Chris thoroughly trashed her in all the others. I just looked over at Jen, smiled, and said:<br />
&#8220;Now you know how I feel when I play you.&#8221;<br />
We called an end to Jen&#8217;s repeated &#8220;just one more!&#8221; requests, turning to the movie &#8220;Zatoichi&#8221;, a Japanese film about a blind master samurai and how he changes the lives of others. It&#8217;s a fairly violent film, but intermixed with comedy and some rather good rhythm (Stomp-like performances appear at various points in the movie). The ending&#8217;s a little disjointed, in my opinion, but it&#8217;s still a good film.<br />
And with that, we went to bed. Tomorrow is light: sleeping in, laundry, and the Fourth Party for Chris and Kaz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/04/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-tokyo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2004 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiroshima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kyoto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miyajima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/30/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We woke before 8:00 this morning, expecting breakfast. At least, that was the time they put on the reservation notice I got from the guest house reservation service. We didn&#8217;t eat until about 8:30, though, which was fine. Breakfast was mostly western: scrambled eggs, toast, orange juice, and the like. Nothing particularly fancy. Following breakfast, &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Kyoto"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We woke before 8:00 this morning, expecting breakfast. At least, that was the time they put on the reservation notice I got from the guest house reservation service. We didn&#8217;t eat until about 8:30, though, which was fine.<br />
Breakfast was mostly western: scrambled eggs, toast, orange juice, and the like. Nothing particularly fancy.<br />
<span id="more-337"></span>Following breakfast, Jen and I decided to do a quick hike up the mountain to the ropeway station, just to see what was up there. The walk was short, as we were most of the way up to the station from the ryokan, anyway. The ropeway (what North Americans would call a cable car) runs up to the top of Mt. Meisen, so tourists (and the faithful) can visit the shrines there.<br />
We returned to Momijiso to gather our bags and check out. We also purchased a small wad of postcards to mail back at our first opportunity. The house matron was exceedingly kind, as always, and we thanked her graciously for the stay. (Even though we did pay for it.) Her son appeared just as we were walking down the hill, and gave us a lift (and near-terrifying speeds) down to the ferry dock.<br />
But we didn&#8217;t leave right away. Even in the rain that had started overnight, Miyajima is too beautiful a place to leave so quickly. Besides, I had promised Jen a chance to run through all the stores she wanted &#8230; even if they all seemed to carry the same thing, over and over and over.<br />
We finally boarded the ferry at 12:25, quite a bit later than I had hoped for. I wanted to be in Kyoto early enough that we could get to the ryokan there and still have dinner. Fortunately, the ferry ride is short, the walk to the JR Miyajimaguichi station short, and the train ride to JR Hiroshima much shorter than the streetcar. (Although the JR train was near sauna in temperature.)<br />
Once at the station, we waited for our shinkansen to Shin-Osaka to come up on the board. However, the train I wanted wasn&#8217;t running. This posed a minor problem for connections, since we couldn&#8217;t take Nozomi trains, and the Kodamas were too awkward for getting to Kyoto. A slightly later Hikaru Rail Star soon solved the problem.<br />
Jen and I were separated on the train due to crowded seating. Not a huge deal, since we would be easily reunited once we got to Shin-Osaka, the end of that train&#8217;s run. We both snoozed a bit. At Shin-Osaka, we merely walked down the platform on the same track to board the next train, which took us to Kyoto.<br />
Once there, we found our way to the taxis (a little awkward, but not impossible). Having only a vague idea where we were going, and not speaking any Japanese, you&#8217;d think that perhaps it would be a little difficult to tell the driver where we were going, eh? Luckily, the guest house reservation service sent me the address of our new ryokan, not only in English but also in Japanese, which the driver understood completely.<br />
The drive was a little harrowing, even moreso than the drive on Miyajima. The taxi driver was all over the road, taking whatever spaces he could find to rush us through rush hour traffic. Luckily, taxis in Japan go on just distance and not also time.<br />
After what seemed an eternity, we finally arrived at our new ryokan, and we hastily exited the car. Unfortunately, a little too hasty, as Jen accidentally left behind a bag of souvenirs she&#8217;d bought in Miyajima, including a coffee mug, and a handkerchief for Nana. We don&#8217;t think she lost anything else. (We feared her wallet was in the bag, but thankfully, she had it in her pants.)<br />
The clerk who met us at the door spoke decent English, and ushered us to the tea area once I&#8217;d filled out the guest form. There, we were presented with traditional Japanese cakes (small, very sweet bite-sized cakes of what tasted like compressed sugar) and small bowls of heavy green tea. I think this might be a tradition for ryokans.<br />
We&#8217;re staying at the Hotel Matsui, which is a ryokan hotel. It&#8217;s more traditional Japanese than a regular hotel, but not like the inn-feel of Momijiso. We were shown to our room by the clerk and two small women in kimonos, who showed us a lot of things we didn&#8217;t understand. They asked us when we wanted dinner (18:00) and when we&#8217;d like breakfast (8:30).<br />
Jen immediately had a bath to wash off the sweat and grime of our day&#8217;s journey. I studied the guides for Kyoto and Osaka, trying to figure out what we needed to see over the next few days.<br />
Dinner arrived shortly after 18:00, on four separate trays (two for Jen and I to eat off of, another with rice and pickles, and a fourth with dessert and soup). We had more sushi, some different foods I can&#8217;t even begin to describe because there&#8217;s no North American equivalent, and something that was just amazing.<br />
We each got a little iron pot that sat on a little iron stand, under which looked like a little candle. This was a pot of broth in which we would cook slices of duck meat, green onions, daikon radish, and clear noodles. Once the broth was boiling, in when the ingredients. The resulting dish was absolutely delicious.<br />
After dinner, we went wandering around our area of Kyoto. This included a large covered pedestrian mall, a few side streets, and part of the Gion district, which is supposedly the old Geisha quarter (although it doesn&#8217;t look old, by any means). The streets that had cherry blossoms (which are currently in bloom) sometimes had lights that shone into the trees. We&#8217;d seen something like that not far from Momijiso, but was done with red lights, making the pink flowers glow in the darkness.<br />
We soon found ourselves quite tired (the events of the last few days were more draining than we&#8217;d like to admit) and found our way back to the hotel to get some much needed rest.<br />
Tomorrow: Kyoto and shrines!<br />
As a side note, today is the day Therese is due to give birth (see [[Flying to Montreal to visit friends]]). Due to the time difference and the fact that I doubt we&#8217;ll hear anything right away, I suspect that I&#8217;ll not know for a few days. I only hope that the birth is easy, and that their new family gets off to a good start.<br />
[flickr]tag:miyajima+march+2004+&#8221;30&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:kyoto+march+2004+&#8221;30&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-kyoto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">337</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2004 22:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiroshima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miyajima]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/29/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.) It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Hiroshima"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No hangovers. This was a good way to start the day, even if it was a lot earlier than Jen really would have liked. (Mind you, Jen likes noon as a wake-up time.)<br />
It was warm in the room. The Japanese seem to like it warm. Even trying to turn the heat down didn&#8217;t help. Twenty-four degrees is just uncomfortable. We rose, repacked our bags, and prepared for the trip to Hiroshima. Neither of us were particularly hungry, so would skip breakfast. Chris called to inform us of the paper shinkansen schedule, which we&#8217;d found out about the night before.<br />
<span id="more-336"></span>One thing the schedule had shown was the difference in shinkansen trains.There are three different types running between Tokyo and Hakata: Kodama, Hikaru, and Nozomi. Kodama shinkansen are local trains, hitting every station on their runs. Hikaru shinkansen are limited, hitting only some of the stations. Nozomi shinkansen are express, and run between only a few stations. Nozomi trains are the only ones that will run all the way from Tokyo to Hakata. The others terminate roughly half-way.<br />
We came to Toyohashi on a Kodama, but we left on a Hikaru. (We can&#8217;t take a Nozomi, as the rail pass doesn&#8217;t cover those trains.) It took us to Shin-Osaka, where we switched to another Hikaru that took us to Hiroshima.<br />
Getting a seat on the shinkansen wasn&#8217;t as easy as I&#8217;d hoped. I figured that when we got to Shin-Osaka, getting prime seats on the next Hiraku would be as simple as being the first in line. Except that when we got to Track 20 (no, there aren&#8217;t 20 shinkansen tracks &#8212; the track we were on just happened to be the last in the series of all tracks at the station), the lines were already quite full. Luckily, we still got good seats, although we were quite crammed in with our backpacks and day bags.<br />
It&#8217;s odd. On weekends, getting a seat is surprisingly easy on long-distance trains, when you&#8217;d figure most people would be travelling. But during the week, the seats are packed to the point of standing-room only, when people would normally not be travelling. This is an odd country&#8230;<br />
Jen slept most of the way between Toyohashi and Shin-Osaka, and between Shin-Osaka and Hiroshima. I did, too, opting for some much-needed rest. The last couple of days had taken their toll on me, and a short nap was much welcomed. Although I haven&#8217;t been here long, I&#8217;m already adapting to the Japanese way of riding the trains &#8212; fall asleep just enough to rest, but not enough that you don&#8217;t hear the call for the next station.<br />
Disembarking at Hiroshima, we went in search of lockers. The idea was to ditch our bags and lug around only our day bags. Sadly, the only lockers we could find weren&#8217;t large enough to store the big bags, so we were forced to continue with those. Instead, we put away some of the stuff we didn&#8217;t want to carry.<br />
Once outside, we found streetcars that would take us to the Atomic Bomb Dome. This is one of the major tourist spots of Japan, and is so well-featured that many signs bear the name. Even signs at the streetcar made it clear that you could take the streetcar to the Hiroshima Bomb Dome for 150 yen. It was almost too easy.<br />
Easy enough for us to realize that either we left our bags at the station, went to the dome, and then came back before going to Miyajima, or we took our bags with us, and then continued on the streetcar to the Miyajima ferry. We oped for the latter.<br />
The streetcar ride down was easy, requiring little more than to obtain a ticket, and wait for the station to appear. Once I realized that there was a digtal sign that read off station names in English, it was impossible to miss the dome. That, and the station stop is barely 100 metres from it. Very hard to miss.<br />
The Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome is the former Hiroshima Prefecture Industry Promotion Hall, barely 100 metres from the hypocentre of the blast. It has come to symbolize the destructive power of the atomic bomb, and is a constant reminder of what happened at 8:15, 6 August 1945.<br />
It was a strange moment for me. I&#8217;ve read all about the atomic bomb dropped on Hiroshima. I&#8217;ve read about the reasons for and against it. I&#8217;ve heard the debates and listened to the stories. It&#8217;s something to have a perspective on the event, but it&#8217;s entirely another to witness the actual building &#8212; or what&#8217;s left of it. Aside from excavations following its destruction, and some preservation work to keep it intact, the dome remains untouched from when it was destroyed nearly 60 years ago.<br />
As Jen and I walked taking photos, a little elderly woman came up to her and flashed a small sign that read: &#8220;Would you like to receive prayers for happiness?&#8221; I didn&#8217;t know this at first, because all I found was this tiny woman holding her hand up towards Jen&#8217;s bowed head. A little confused for a moment, another elderly woman came up to me and flashed a similar sign. Jen and I were blessed, in a way, to allow us to have a much happier day.<br />
Taking a photo of the two women, they directed us to the Peace Memorial Park, surrounded by the Ota-gawa River, the shores lined with sakura &#8212; cherry trees just entering full bloom. We could hardly pass that up.<br />
On the other side, we found more monuments to the tragedy of the a-bomb attack. One was a peace bell, the supports built of concrete, from which was suspended a traditional shinto bell. The chain used for the bell&#8217;s clapper had a metal origami crane. This is significant because next to the bell are several transparent plastic observation booths filled with hundreds of thousands of paper cranes, offered in peaceful remembrance of 6 August.<br />
Further into the park is the eternal flame, near the Peach Arch. Looking through the Peace Arch towards the flame, you can see directly to the dome. The Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum is past the Peace Arch, but we didn&#8217;t go there. Instead, I followed Jen over to something she saw off to one side. It was a concrete wall, inside of which looked like a clock surrounded by a bed of broken bricks.<br />
It was the top of the Hiroshima National Peace Memorial Hall for the Atomic Bomb Victims. The clock is a skylight into the middle of musem, and is fixed at the time of detonation, 8:15. The bricks were excavated from the Atomic Bomb Dome.<br />
Deciding that it might be an interesting thing to see (and because it was free), we headed down into the entrance. (The museum is underground.) Inside, we were handed English pamphlets, and directed down the walkway, which spirals further down into the earth. Every 20 feet or so, there is a glass panel with text about World War II and the atomic bomb and its affects on Hiroshima.<br />
The perspective is interesting. This should be the Japanese perspective. This is their view of (what is basically) an attack of unwarranted scale. But they&#8217;re not accusatory, not disdainful. The presentation is factual, and appeals to visitors to campaign against the use of nuclear weapons.<br />
At the bottom, you enter a huge round room. At the top is the skylight you see at ground level. Directly under the skylight is a fountain, also in the shape of the 8:15 clock. The water is offered as a consolation to all those who died begging for a drink. On the walls are the names of the neighbourhoods destroyed by the bomb, their proximity to the floor indicating how close they were to the hypocentre. Around the upper third of the room is a 360 panoramic view of the destroyed Hiroshima, as seen from the hypocentre, recreated with 140,000 hand-carved tiles. One tile for each person who died.<br />
Leaving the room, you come to a display of some of the victims. Each of the pamphlets accesses one of 9,606 photographs of a victim through a computer. Mine accessed the record of a 48 year-old woman by the name of Masayo Kubota. Suddenly, it wasn&#8217;t just a piece of paper. This was a real person.<br />
Sobered quite a lot by the museum, it was quite strange to come to the surface to be confronted by the sounds of a bustling metropolis (Hiroshima is quite large), the laughs of playing children, and the chatter of a people who most likely don&#8217;t think about the events of 6 August on a regular basis.<br />
Stopping briefly at the Tourist Information Office for a map and a drink (green tea slushie, anyone?), we continued back to the streetcar station to head down to Miyajimaguchi station, to catch the ferry to Miyajima.<br />
A note for anyone going from Hiroshima Atomic Bomb Dome to Miyajima. As soon as you can switch to the JR Sanyo line, do so. The trip by streetcar, although nice, is very long.<br />
At Miyajimaguchi station, I called the ryokan in Miyajima to let them know we were catching the next ferry to the island. (They offered a pickup service, and we were to call ahead.) The conversation was a bit difficult due to the language barrier, but the person I was speaking with had obviously taken the trouble to learn enough English to make herself understood.<br />
The ferry trip over was short, only about 10 minutes, and we were soon waiting out in front of the ferry station for our ride to the ryokan. A small white bus appeared in view, and an enthusiastic employee beckoned us to join him for a drive.<br />
The speed limit in Miyajima seems to be about 20 km/h. This guy was doing at least 60 in most places, narrowly missing people and other cars in his mad dash to get to the ryokan to drop us off. The ride, though confusing, was enough to make Jen and I suddenly wish that we didn&#8217;t have to go to Kyoto tomorrow (we have reservations, so don&#8217;t have much of a choice) and stay here a while longer.<br />
Hold on, you&#8217;re probably looking at that &#8220;ryokan&#8221; word and are wondering what that is. We&#8217;re staying at what&#8217;s called a ryokan &#8212; it&#8217;s a type of Japanese hotel. We&#8217;re at the Momijiso ryokan, which sits in the middle of Momijitani Park, up the hill from the town/village of Miyajima. In fact, the ryokan is on the way to the ropeway to the top of the mountain.<br />
Mimijiso is the only building in sight. (Mind you, with the forest, it&#8217;s hard to see the next ryokan down the side.) It&#8217;s also a cafe for travellers going up and down Mt. Meisen, a focus of religion in the area &#8212; there are many shrines at the top of the mountain. The isolation is glorious.<br />
We were greeted at the door by what I can only describe as the house matron, a wonderful elderly woman whom I can only assume was the one I had talked to earlier. She guided us to our room, ushered us in, and immediately served us maple leaf-shaped cakes (filled with red bean paste) and two cups of very strong green tea. She told us that dinner was at 18:30, and that breakfast was at 8:00 tomorrow morning.<br />
We had time to kill, so leaving most of our bags behind, Jen and I went to explore the town of Miyajima. The town centres on the shrine, which sits in a tidal area at the shoreline. Just offshore is a torii, a huge red gate that is the symbol for Miyajima. There are shrines all over this part of the island.<br />
One of the other symbols of Miyajima is the maple leaf. Not the same as the Canadian maple leaf, but a Japanese maple. (Jen described it as looking like a marijuana plant.) During the fall, apparently the entire area turns a bright red from the changing leaves. The symbol is found in everything from the cakes, cell phone (kaitei) baubles, markers on the roads and sewer grates, signs, and various tourist trinkets.<br />
As Jen and I walked around, we came realize that we really liked Miyajima. I might have trouble tomorrow when it comes time to leave. Jen and I might not want to get on the boat. I really wish I could change the reservation in Kyoto so we could stay another day. The architecture here is quaint and simple, the people nice, and the lifestyle laid back. And walking around in the park is a joy.<br />
Deer are everywhere. Miyajima has countless deer. They&#8217;re small, about the side of a large dog. And completely unafraid of humans. They probably eat a little too much from humans, so have no qualms about coming up to you for food. Jen refused one, and it whined.<br />
We wandered down to the shrine and torii, up to the pagoda, around the town and through the countless gift shops (my only complaint of Miyajima &#8212; it&#8217;s almost like an amusement park at times, though at least some of the stores aren&#8217;t too tacky), before arriving back just in time for dinner.<br />
The cooking was &#8230; exquisite. We were told it was mostly fish. The &#8220;appetizers&#8221; were sashimi (locally-caught whitefish, sea breem, and the most succulent tuna I&#8217;ve ever had), traditional sunomuno, and some egg thing that I can&#8217;t even begin to describe. Then it was a cooked piece of sea breem (that blew me away), rice, miso soup, pickled roots, and finally fresh strawberries and melon.<br />
Following dinner, Jen and I went exploring again. With all the tourists gone, it was easier to move around, and much quieter. The deer had gone to sleep. We took pictures of the torii (now lit up for night), walked around the town, and explored a few roads we hadn&#8217;t been down.<br />
I need a tranquilizer for Jen, though. She gets quite hyper.<br />
We returned for about 21:00, since the ryokan closes down around 21:30 for the night. Which was fine with us, since both of us were quite tired. It&#8217;s been a long day, but a very good one.<br />
I think those prayers worked, because tonight, Jen and I are very happy.<br />
[flickr]tag:toyohashi+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr] [flickr]tag:hiroshima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:miyajima+japan+march+2004+&#8221;29&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-hiroshima/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2004 22:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irako]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tokyo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yotsukaido]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/27/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone. Jen and I proceeded to get &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Turning Japanese Again, Shinkansen to Toyohashi and Irako"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slept a little oddly, considering we&#8217;d been up for over 24 hours straight. Woke up once around 3:00 (mostly to go to the bathroom), again at about 5:00, and finally at about 7:50. At that point, it was enough to say I&#8217;d probably adjusted to the time zone.<br />
Jen and I proceeded to get on with our morning. For me, showering and shaving (showering when it&#8217;s eight degrees in the shower room is a bit of an odd experience), gathering our things from the previous night, laying out Chris and Kaz&#8217;s wedding gifts (that they don&#8217;t yet know about), and getting breakfast.<br />
<span id="more-334"></span>This meant a trip to the 7-11. I knew what I wanted, but Jen really didn&#8217;t know. She was about to find out that her typical breakfast foods either don&#8217;t exist here, or are different enough to cause problems. This was most notable when she bought what she thought was normal milk (which bore the slogan: &#8220;Milk as milked&#8221;). Apparently, the Japanese like their milk sweetened, which Jen found thoroughly repulsive.<br />
About 9:45, we headed out to the train station to meet up with Tony, one of Chris&#8217; friends. Tony used to be a teacher with the same company Chris now works for. He&#8217;s since moved to Saipan (an American protectorate) where he works as a &#8220;beach boy&#8221; at a resort. Tony is trouble incarnate, at least as far as Chris has described him.<br />
After grabbing a bite to eat at the bakery (Tony hadn&#8217;t had breakfast yet), the three of us boarded the train for Tokyo. It was already standing room only when we boarded, and was crammed full until about two stops before Tokyo station. We stood the whole way.<br />
Once in Tokyo, we found our way up to the main level, where Tony bought something to eat for lunch, and then headed out to the Shinkansen area. Took a bit to find the right train (none of the signs were in English), and waited for our 12:23 departure. We took one row of two seats, flipped it 180 degrees so they faced the two seats behind them, and the three of us sat down to enjoy our 2.5 hour trip to Toyohashi.<br />
Tony and I talked almost the whole way. Jen slipped in and out of consciousness while listening to her music. The scenery zipped by at a leisurely 250 km/h. We even got a good look at Mount Fuji (it had decided not to hide itself from us). Shinichiro (another of Chris&#8217; friends) found us, and gabbed a bit with Tony. We would meet up with him and his girlfriend Riko again when we got to Toyohashi.<br />
Chris and Kaz were waiting for us when we arrived at the station. It was good to see them again, though it was a short-lived reunion with Kaz. Chris led us to the shuttle bus, where we found Chris&#8217; parents Tony and Carole, and Chris&#8217; uncle, Garth (Carole&#8217;s brother).<br />
I had thought that the hotel we were staying at was close to the train station. I was so wrong. The Iraku View Hotel isn&#8217;t even in Toyohashi &#8212; that&#8217;s just the nearest train station. We had another hour on a shuttle bus to the hotel. A long, albeit nice ride through and around the Aichi Prefecture&#8217;s countryside, which appears to be primarily agricultural.<br />
The hotel sits on top of a small mountain, overlooking a large bay. The view here is &#8230; well, let&#8217;s just say there&#8217;s a reason why &#8220;View&#8221; is in the hotel&#8217;s name. It&#8217;s amazing. Chris picked a heck of a location.<br />
The hotel room arrangements had changed from the last time I&#8217;d talked with Chris. Originally, Chris, Tony (friend, not father), and I were going to share a room, and Jen and Kaz would share another. Now it was Chris, Tony, and Garth, with Jen and I sharing a room. (We don&#8217;t see Kaz again until tomorrow.)<br />
Admittedly, I was a little disappointed. But I&#8217;m certainly not in a position to complain in any way. These are the way things have to be. It&#8217;s called &#8220;life&#8221; &#8212; you get used to it after a while. (Actually, I almost prefer it this way. At least Jen won&#8217;t be with a stranger. Admittedly, though, I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen if there is a desire to go out drinking.)<br />
The room is pretty nice. More western in style, there are twin beds, a desk, TV, small table, two chairs, Japanese-style bathrobes, a Japanese-style western toilet (complete with electronic bidet controls and seat warmer), and a complementary water heater and green tea bags.<br />
But I need an iron. My suit is a little wrinkled.<br />
&#8212;-<br />
Jen and I went exploring, to see what this hotel has to offer. It&#8217;s quite interesting. There&#8217;s a great view of the area from the hotel&#8217;s roof (you&#8217;re actually allowed up there), an arcade, a couple of restaurants, a kareoke bar, a bowling alley, and birds in the lobby. It&#8217;s a bit of an odd hotel.<br />
Following our exploration, Jen and I watched a bit of the local Japanese TV. Very odd things to watch, such as a commercial for what we think was a car, but featured two kids in cat costumes who steal fish from the back of a fish truck.<br />
We all met up and went for dinner just after 19:00, at the Sunset Restaurant, which features a buffet. It&#8217;s quite good (for a buffet), including such favourites as sashimi, seafood-flavoured miso, gyoza, and a few things I&#8217;d never even heard of before.<br />
Chris and his family sat at one table, while Shinichiro, Riko, Tony, Jen, and I sat at another. We talked, joked, learned a little more about each other, and drank. (Well, we did &#8230; Jen didn&#8217;t, for obvious reasons.)<br />
Following our dinner (we finished just after 21:00), the six of us (the rest of Chris&#8217; family headed to bed) went in search of the bowling alley. Chris&#8217; last night as a single man would be demonstrated on the lanes.<br />
Unfortunately, Chris didn&#8217;t do all that well &#8212; mind you, neither did I &#8212; as he was distracted by conversations with Kaz. I&#8217;m going to have to make sure that his cell phone is either left behind, or confiscated by either Tony or myself so he can actually enjoy tomorrow, and not spend it talking to others.<br />
The game finished (Shinichiro came first, Jen a close second), we adjourned to Shinichiro and Riko&#8217;s room for a bottle of melon wine. An odd flavour, to say the least, but still pleasant. Shinichiro and Chris took it upon themselves to try and teach Jen some new Japanese words. Tony tried to figure out how to use some of the features on his new phone.<br />
But it&#8217;s late, and we all need sleep. Tomorrow&#8217;s going to be a long day.<br />
[flickr]tag:tokyo+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr][flickr]tag:irako+japan+march+2004+&#8221;27&#8243;@Geoff S.[/flickr]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/turning-japanese-again-shinkansen-toyohashi-irako/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">334</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planning for a Return Trip to Japan</title>
		<link>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan</link>
					<comments>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2004 22:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shinkansen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyohashi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sowrey.org/index.php/2004/03/11/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fourteen days, and counting. Two weeks from today, I&#8217;m off to Japan. Again. Relax, this isn&#8217;t going to turn into a yearly thing. If I&#8217;d had a choice, I&#8217;d probably be going to Australia this year, maybe New Zealand. But I&#8217;ve got a good reason for going back to Japan. Chris is getting married. Of &#8230; <a href="https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Planning for a Return Trip to Japan"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fourteen days, and counting.<br />
Two weeks from today, I&#8217;m off to Japan. Again. Relax, this isn&#8217;t going to turn into a yearly thing. If I&#8217;d had a choice, I&#8217;d probably be going to Australia this year, maybe New Zealand. But I&#8217;ve got a good reason for going back to Japan.<br />
<span id="more-332"></span>Chris is getting married. Of course, you already knew that (see [[A Surprise Engagement]]). It was just a question of when and where. I&#8217;d been suggesting Hawaii, partly because it was (roughly) half-way between Japan and North America, but also because I&#8217;d never been there.<br />
But it ain&#8217;t my wedding. It&#8217;s going to be held in Toyohashi (about two hours south-west of Tokyo by shinkansen). So Down Under will have to wait for another time. For my closest friends, I&#8217;ll gladly travel halfway around the world.<br />
Last time I was in Japan (see [[My Trip to Japan, Calgary to Yotsukaido]]), I spent most of my time in the Tokyo area. This time, I want to see more of the country. The furthest away I got was Shizoika, which was in an effort to see Mount Fuji (see [[My Trip to Japan, Shinkansen to Mount Fuji]]). This time, I&#8217;m going all the way down to Hiroshima, then working my way back up to Tokyo, and even north to Nikko.<br />
But I won&#8217;t be travelling alone. Back in October, I gained a travel partner. This came about from a discussion we were having over dinner at my Aunt and Uncle&#8217;s, celebrating Nana&#8217;s six-month anniversary at being in Calgary. Most of my family knows Chris quite well, and were asking about Chris&#8217; then-recently-announced wedding. What was the date? What were the plans? Was I going?<br />
When I replied that I was going back (wouldn&#8217;t pass it up for anything), a voice suddenly chirped up: &#8220;Can I come?&#8221; It was Jen, my cousin (Uncle Mike and Aunt Brenda&#8217;s sole child). She had a giant, hopeful smile. For a brief moment, I thought against her coming along &#8212; I kind of wanted to travel solo. But then I realized that having a person to travel with would be a lot more fun.<br />
&#8220;Sure! Why not?&#8221;<br />
The look on Mike and Brenda&#8217;s faces was priceless.<br />
Needless to say, there were monetary issues to resolve before Jen could actually be allowed to go. My family is, if nothing else, very supportive. Nana chipped in for a sizable portion of Jen&#8217;s costs, her parents covering the rest. But by the time Jen&#8217;s 15th birthday rolled around in November, it was a done deal. Jen was going to Japan.<br />
We leave 25 March, going through Vancouver. Jen and I will be seated side-by-side the whole way out and back. (Heck, for over two weeks, we&#8217;ll be tied at the hip.) We arrive 26 March (owing to the International Date Line) and begin our little adventure.<br />
This adventure, unlike my previous one, needs a little planning. For example, we had to get Jen familiar with Japanese food. She&#8217;s going to be eating nothing but for two weeks. Then there&#8217;s the need for footwear. My shoes would not survive two weeks&#8217; of walking about.<br />
This is what I did last Saturday. I hadn&#8217;t really even thought about until I almost absent-mindedly walked into the R &#8216;n R store next to Sumo Sushi in Eau Claire Market. The odd little squeak emanating from my old shoes was enough to irk me into new shoes. The need for walking shoes, combined with a desire for something I can hike in, led me to a long afternoon of shoe shopping.<br />
Hey, when you&#8217;re going to spend $120 on a pair of shoes, you make sure you&#8217;re buying something that meets your needs.<br />
The next step of planning is the list of destinations and activities. I tasked Jen to pick out all the places she wanted to see in Japan, with the caveat that we wouldn&#8217;t likely be able to see it all. Far easier to whittle things down than it is to find more things to see and do. Her list was lengthy, but well thought out.<br />
I started looking at the lists on Sunday night. The list was long and organized by prefecture (the Japanese equivalent of a province or state), so while it wasn&#8217;t too hard to figure out where approximately Jen wanted to go, it wasn&#8217;t particularly obvious how easy it would be.<br />
Using a rather nice map from japanrailpass.net, I plotted out the key areas in the list on Monday night. Much to my delight, about 80% of them were on the shinkansen lines. This made them easy to get to. (There were a few that were quite some distance away, on what I can only assume are the much slower local lines.)<br />
Tuesday ended up being a complete waste of a day at the office. There was no work to be had at all. Luckily, this gave me a chance to sit down with the lists and the map, and try to figure out how the heck we were going to spending all of our time in Japan.<br />
I was delighted yet again to find that a first run-through of an itinerary produced something that not only covered a lot of ground but allowed us to attend the major events without difficulty. It&#8217;s a little tight in a couple of places (we&#8217;re spending only one day in Kyoto, for example), but has some flexibility if we want to play with things a bit.<br />
Well, at least that&#8217;s what I want myself to believe. This morning, Chris called me on the draft itinerary, saying: &#8220;You are out of your fucking tree.&#8221; While I had been fairly proud of the itinerary, there was a reason I&#8217;d CC&#8217;d Chris when I sent it out to Jen and Aunt Brenda. I needed a sanity check.<br />
Reality: Two weeks to experience a slice of Japan. Now, it&#8217;s possible to do the itinerary in two weeks. That doesn&#8217;t make it a good idea. We&#8217;d literally be spending hours in some places before going onto the next. As Chris so wisely pointed out, there&#8217;s no time to experience anything. Jen and I will be in parts of Japan even Chris hasn&#8217;t been to (some he hasn&#8217;t even heard of). If we&#8217;re going to actually *experience* something, then perhaps we need to slow down.<br />
Two weeks. I haven&#8217;t been looking this forward to a trip in a long time. It&#8217;s going to be an interesting one, to be sure. I just hope there&#8217;s enough time to finish planning before we leave.<br />
&#8216;Cuz there won&#8217;t be any time once we get there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://geoff.sowrey.org/2004/03/planning-for-a-return-trip-to-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">332</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
